<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:20:54Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-06-20" from="2016-06-19" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0810.5186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0810.5186</id><created>2008-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Lissauer</keyname><forenames>Jack J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubickyj</keyname><forenames>Olenka</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodenheimer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Models of Jupiter's Growth Incorporating Thermal and Hydrodynamic
  Constraints</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>17 pages 12 figures, 4 tables. To appear in the journal Icarus</comments><journal-ref>Icarus 199 (2009) 338-350</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2008.10.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  [Abridged] We model the growth of Jupiter via core nucleated accretion,
applying constraints from hydrodynamical processes that result from the
disk-planet interaction. We compute the planet's internal structure using a
Henyey-type stellar evolution code. The planet's interactions with the
protoplanetary disk are calculated using 3-D hydrodynamic simulations. Previous
models of Jupiter's growth have taken the radius of the planet to be
approximately one Hill sphere radius, Rhill. However, 3-D hydrodynamic
simulations show that only gas within 0.25Rhill remains bound to the planet,
with the more distant gas eventually participating in the shear flow of the
protoplanetary disk. Therefore in our new simulations, the planet's outer
boundary is placed at the location where gas has the thermal energy to reach
the portion of the flow not bound to the planet. We find that the smaller
radius increases the time required for planetary growth by ~5%. Thermal
pressure limits the rate at which a planet less than a few dozen times as
massive as Earth can accumulate gas from the protoplanetary disk, whereas
hydrodynamics regulates the growth rate for more massive planets. Within a
moderately viscous disk, the accretion rate peaks when the planet's mass is
about equal to the mass of Saturn. In a less viscous disk hydrodynamical limits
to accretion are smaller, and the accretion rate peaks at lower mass. To
account for disk dissipation, we perform some of our simulations of Jupiter's
growth within a disk whose surface gas density decreases on a timescale of
3Myr. According to our simulations, proto-Jupiter's distended and
thermally-supported envelope was too small to capture the planet's current
retinue of irregular satellites as advocated by Pollack et al. (1979).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1009.4148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1009.4148</id><created>2010-09-21</created><updated>2010-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubow</keyname><forenames>Stephen H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional Disk-Planet Torques in a Locally Isothermal Disk</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 figures. To appear in The Astrophysical Journal. Updated
  with changes and corrections added in proof</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 724 (2010) 730-747</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/724/1/730</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine an expression for the Type I planet migration torque involving a
locally isothermal disk, with moderate turbulent viscosity (~0.0005 &lt; alpha &lt;
~0.05), based on three-dimensional nonlinear hydrodynamical simulations. The
radial gradients (in a dimensionless logarithmic form) of density and
temperature are assumed to be constant near the planet. We find that the torque
is roughly equally sensitive to the surface density and temperature radial
gradients. Both gradients contribute to inward migration when they are
negative. Our results indicate that two-dimensional calculations with a
smoothed planet potential, used to account for the effects of the third
dimension, do not accurately determine the effects of density and temperature
gradients on the three-dimensional torque. The results suggest that
substantially slowing or stopping planet migration by means of changes in disk
opacity or shadowing is difficult and appears unlikely for a disk that is
locally isothermal. The scalings of the torque and torque density with planet
mass and gas sound speed follow the expectations of linear theory. We also
determine an improved formula for the torque density distribution that can be
used in one-dimensional long-term evolution studies of planets embedded in
locally isothermal disks. This formula can be also applied in the presence of
mildly varying radial gradients and of planets that open gaps. We illustrate
its use in the case of migrating super-Earths and determine some conditions
sufficient for survival.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.4520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.4520</id><created>2012-10-16</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Transverse momentum distribution and nuclear modification factor of
  charged particles in p-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}$ = 5.02 TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 captioned figures, 1 table, authors from page 11,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/2844</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2012-306</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 110 (2013) 082302</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.110.082302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transverse momentum ($p_{\mathrm T}$) distribution of primary charged
particles is measured in minimum bias (non-single-diffractive) p-Pb collisions
at $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}=5.02$ TeV with the ALICE detector at the LHC. The
$p_{\mathrm T}$ spectra measured near central rapidity in the range
$0.5&lt;p_{\mathrm T}&lt;20$ GeV/$c$ exhibit a weak pseudorapidity dependence. The
nuclear modification factor $R_{\mathrm{pPb}}$ is consistent with unity for
$p_{\mathrm T}$ above 2 GeV/$c$. This measurement indicates that the strong
suppression of hadron production at high $p_{\mathrm T}$ observed in Pb-Pb
collisions at the LHC is not due to an initial-state effect. The measurement is
compared to theoretical calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.2817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.2817</id><created>2013-08-13</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Birkhan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Matsubara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Research Center for Nuclear Physics, Osaka University, Ibaraki</affiliation><affiliation>Tokyo Women's Medical University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>von Neumann-Cosel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pietralla</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>GSI Helmholtzzemtrum f&#xfc;r Schwerionenforschung, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ponomarev</keyname><forenames>V. Yu.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tamii</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Research Center for Nuclear Physics, Osaka University, Ibaraki</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wambach</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Kernphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Darmstadt, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>GSI Helmholtzzemtrum f&#xfc;r Schwerionenforschung, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic M1 transition strengths from inelastic proton
  scattering: The cases of 48Ca and 208Pb</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 041302(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.041302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inelastic proton scattering at energies of a few hundred MeV and extreme
forward angles selectively excites the isovector spin-flip M1 (IVSM1)
resonance. A method based on isospin symmetry is presented to extract its
electromagnetic transition strength from the (p,p') cross sections. It is
applied to 48Ca, a key case for an interpretation of the quenching phenomenon
of the spin-isospin response, and leads to a M1 strength consistent with an
older (e,e') experiment excluding the almost two times larger value from a
recent (\gamma,n) experiment. Good agreement with electromagnetic probes is
observed in 208Pb suggesting the possibility to extract systematic information
on the IVSM1 resonance in heavy nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.3220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.3220</id><created>2014-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lan</keyname><forenames>Zhihao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lobo</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>A single impurity in an ideal atomic Fermi gas: current understanding
  and some open problems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atm-clus quant-ph</categories><comments>Review asked by Journal of the Indian Institute of Science, to appear
  in Vol. 94 No. 2 (Apr. - Jun. 2014) Cold Atom Quantum Emulators: From
  Condensed Matter to Filed Theory to Optical Clocks</comments><journal-ref>J. Indian Inst. Sci. 94, 179 (2014)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We briefly review some current theoretical and experimental aspects of the
problem of a single spinless impurity in a 3D polarised atomic Fermi gas at
zero temperature where the interactions can be tuned using a wide Feshbach
resonance. We show that various few-body states in vacuum composed of the
impurity and background gas atoms (single impurity, dimer, trimer, tetramer)
give rise to corresponding dressed states ({\em polaron}, {\em dimeron}, {\em
trimeron}, {\em tetrameron}) in the gas and inherit many of their
characteristics. We study the ground state focussing on the choice of wave
function and its properties. We raise a few unsolved problems: whether the
polaron and dimeron are really separate branches, what other few-body states
might exist, the nature of the groundstate for large numbers of particle-hole
pairs and why is the polaron ansatz so good. We then turn to the excited
states, and to the calculation of the effective mass. We examine the bounds on
the effective mass and raise a conjecture about that of composite quasiparticle
states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.6162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.6162</id><created>2014-04-29</created><updated>2014-07-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stratford</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>targetDP: an Abstraction of Lattice Based Parallelism with Portable
  Performance</title><categories>cs.DC hep-lat physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, to appear in proceedings of HPCC 2014 conference</comments><journal-ref>2014 IEEE Intl Conf on High Performance Computing and
  Communications, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/HPCC.2014.212</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To achieve high performance on modern computers, it is vital to map
algorithmic parallelism to that inherent in the hardware. From an application
developer's perspective, it is also important that code can be maintained in a
portable manner across a range of hardware. Here we present targetDP (target
Data Parallel), a lightweight programming layer that allows the abstraction of
data parallelism for applications that employ structured grids. A single source
code may be used to target both thread level parallelism (TLP) and instruction
level parallelism (ILP) on either SIMD multi-core CPUs or GPU-accelerated
platforms. targetDP is implemented via standard C preprocessor macros and
library functions, can be added to existing applications incrementally, and can
be combined with higher-level paradigms such as MPI. We present CPU and GPU
performance results for a benchmark taken from the lattice Boltzmann
application that motivated this work. These demonstrate not only performance
portability, but also the optimisation resulting from the intelligent exposure
of ILP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.7305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.7305</id><created>2014-05-28</created><updated>2014-08-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidenschilling</keyname><forenames>Stuart J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lissauer</keyname><forenames>Jack J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodenheimer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Growth of Jupiter: Enhancement of Core Accretion by a Voluminous
  Low-Mass Envelope</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in the journal Icarus. Final version</comments><journal-ref>Icarus 241 (2014) 298-312</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2014.06.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present calculations of the early stages of the formation of Jupiter via
core nucleated accretion and gas capture. The core begins as a seed body of
about 350 kilometers in radius and orbits in a swarm of planetesimals whose
initial radii range from 15 meters to 50 kilometers. The evolution of the swarm
accounts for growth and fragmentation, viscous and gravitational stirring, and
for drag-assisted migration and velocity damping. During this evolution, less
than 9% of the mass is in planetesimals smaller than 1 kilometer in radius; &lt;
~25% is in planetesimals with radii between 1 and 10 kilometers; and &lt; ~7% is
in bodies with radii larger than 100 kilometers. Gas capture by the core
substantially enhances the size-dependent cross-section of the planet for
accretion of planetesimals. The calculation of dust opacity in the planet's
envelope accounts for coagulation and sedimentation of dust particles released
as planetesimals are ablated. The calculation is carried out at an orbital
semi-major axis of 5.2 AU and the initial solids' surface density is 10 g/cm^2
at that distance. The results give a core mass of nearly 7.3 Earth masses
(Mearth) and an envelope mass of approximately 0.15 Mearth after about 4e5
years, at which point the envelope growth rate surpasses that of the core. The
same calculation without the envelope yields a core of only about 4.4 Mearth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.6486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.6486</id><created>2014-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mishchenko</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagaosa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Filippis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Candia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cataudella</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mobility of Holstein polaron: an unbiased approach</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett., vol. 114, 146401 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.114.146401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first unbiased results for the mobility $\mu$ of
one-dimensional Holstein polaron obtained by numerical analytic continuation
combined with diagrammatic and world-line Monte Carlo methods in the
thermodynamic limit. We have identified for the first time, by the
characteristic $\omega$ and $T$ dependence in the wide region of parameters,
several distinct regimes in the $\lambda-T$ plane including band conduction
region, incoherent metallic region, activated hopping region, and high
temperature saturation region. We observe for the first time that although
mobilities and mean free paths at different values of $\lambda$ differ by many
orders of magnitude at small temperatures, their values at $T$ larger than the
bandwidth become very close to each other.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.5657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.5657</id><created>2014-09-19</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Lishu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Zengxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Yaonan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Huili</forenames></author><author><keyname>Azarov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venkatachalapathy</keyname><forenames>Vishnukanthan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>Andrej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Xiaolong</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluorine doping: A feasible solution to enhancing the conductivity of
  high-resistance wide bandgap Mg0.51Zn0.49O active components</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><doi>10.1038/srep15516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  N-type doping of high-resistance wide bandgap semiconductors, wurtzite
high-Mg-content MgxZn1-xO for instance, has always been a fundamental
application-motivated research issue. Herein, we report a solution to enhancing
the conductivity of high-resistance Mg0.51Zn0.49O active components, which has
been reliably achieved by fluorine doping via radio-frequency plasma assisted
molecular beam epitaxial growth. Fluorine dopants were demonstrated to be
effective donors in Mg0.51Zn0.49O single crystal film having a solar-blind 4.43
eV bandgap, with an average concentration of 1.0E19 F/cm3.The dramatically
increased carrier concentration (2.85E17 cm-3 vs ~1014 cm-3) and decreased
resistivity (129 ohm.cm vs ~10E6 ohm cm) indicate that the electrical
properties of semi-insulating Mg0.51Zn0.49O film can be delicately regulated by
F doping. Interestingly, two donor levels (17 meV and 74 meV) associated with F
were revealed by temperature-dependent Hall measurements. A Schottky type
metal-semiconductor-metal ultraviolet photodetector manifests a remarkably
enhanced photocurrent, two orders of magnitude higher than that of the undoped
counterpart. The responsivity is greatly enhanced from 0.34 mA/W to 52 mA/W
under 10 V bias. The detectivity increases from 1.89E9 cm Hz1/2/W to 3.58eE10
cm Hz1/2/W under 10 V bias at room temperature.These results exhibit F doping
serves as a promising pathway for improving the performance of high-Mg-content
MgxZn1-xO-based devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0190</id><created>2014-11-01</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jingbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Chao-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>The Entropy of Nonrotating Isolated Horizons in Lovelock Theory from
  Loop Quantum Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C Vol. 40, No. 8 (2016) 083102</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/8/083102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the BF theory method is applied to the nonrotating isolated
horizons in Lovelock theory. The final entropy matches the Wald entropy formula
for this theory. We also confirm the conclusion got by Bodendorfer et. al. that
the entropy is related to the flux operator rather than the area operator in
general diffeomorphic-invariant theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08754</id><created>2015-03-30</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Welsch</keyname><forenames>Brian T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisher</keyname><forenames>George H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deriving Potential Coronal Magnetic Fields from Vector Magnetograms</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>25 pages, 11 figures, under review</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-0938-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The minimum-energy configuration for the magnetic field above the solar
photosphere is curl-free (hence, by Ampere's law, also current-free), so can be
represented as the gradient of a scalar potential. Since magnetic fields are
divergence free, this scalar potential obeys Laplace's equation, given an
appropriate boundary condition (BC). With measurements of the full magnetic
vector at the photosphere, it is possible to employ either Neumann or Dirichlet
BCs there. Historically, the Neumann BC was used with available line-of-sight
magnetic field measurements, which approximate the radial field needed for the
Neumann BC. Since each BC fully determines the 3D vector magnetic field, either
choice will, in general, be inconsistent with some aspect of the observed field
on the boundary, due to the presence of both currents and noise in the observed
field. We present a method to combine solutions from both Dirichlet and Neumann
BCs to determine a hybrid, &quot;least-squares&quot; potential field, which minimizes the
integrated square of the residual between the potential and actual fields. This
has advantages in both not overfitting the radial field used for the Neumann
BC, and maximizing consistency with the observations. We demonstrate our
methods with SDO/HMI vector magnetic field observations of AR 11158, and find
that residual discrepancies between the observed and potential fields are
significant, and are consistent with nonzero horizontal photospheric currents.
We also analyze potential fields for two other active regions observed with two
different vector magnetographs, and find that hybrid potential fields have
significantly less energy than the Neumann fields in every case --- by more
than 10^(32) erg in some cases. This has major implications for estimates of
free magnetic energy in coronal field models, e.g., non-linear force-free field
extrapolations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04364</id><created>2015-04-16</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podolak</keyname><forenames>Morris</forenames></author></authors><title>Capture and Evolution of Planetesimals in Circumjovian Disks</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>30 pages, 20 figures, 6 tables. Accepted for publication in The
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 806 (2015) 203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/806/2/203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the evolution of planetesimals in evolved gaseous disks, which orbit
a solar-mass star and harbor a Jupiter-mass planet at a_p~5AU. The gas dynamics
is modeled with a three-dimensional hydrodynamics code that employes
nested-grids and achieves a resolution of one Jupiter's radius in the
circumplanetary disk. The code models solids as individual particles.
Planetesimals are subjected to gravitational forces by the star and the planet,
drag force by the gas, disruption via ram pressure, and mass loss through
ablation. The mass evolution of solids is calculated self-consistently with
their temperature, velocity, and position. We consider icy and icy/rocky bodies
of radius 0.1-100km, initially deployed on orbits around the star within a few
Hill radii (Rhill) of the planet's orbit. Planetesimals are scattered inward,
outward, and toward disk regions of radius r&gt;&gt;a_p. Scattering can relocate
significant amounts of solids, provided that regions |r-a_p|~ 3Rhill are
replenished with planetesimals. Scattered bodies can be temporarily captured on
planetocentric orbits. Ablation consumes nearly all solids at gas temperatures
&gt; ~220K. Super-keplerian rotation around and beyond the outer edge of the gas
gap can segregate &lt; ~0.1km bodies, producing solid gap edges at size-dependent
radial locations. Capture, break-up, and ablation of solids result in a
dust-laden circumplanetary disk with low surface densities of km-size
planetesimals, implying relatively long timescales for satellite formation.
After a giant planet acquires most of its mass, accretion of solids is unlikely
to alter significantly its heavy-element content. The luminosity generated by
solids' accretion can be of a similar order of magnitude to the contraction
luminosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.08344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.08344</id><created>2015-04-30</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zatloukal</keyname><forenames>Vaclav</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical field theories from Hamiltonian constraint: Canonical
  equations of motion and local Hamilton-Jacobi theory</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Int. J. Geom. Methods Mod. Phys., 13, 1650072 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887816500729</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical field theory is considered as a theory of unparametrized surfaces
embedded in a configuration space, which accommodates, in a symmetric way,
spacetime positions and field values. Dynamics is defined by a (Hamiltonian)
constraint between multivector-valued generalized momenta, and points in the
configuration space. Starting from a variational principle, we derive local
equations of motion, that is, differential equations that determine classical
surfaces and momenta. A local Hamilton-Jacobi equation applicable in the field
theory then follows readily. The general method is illustrated with three
examples: non-relativistic Hamiltonian mechanics, De Donder-Weyl scalar field
theory, and string theory.
  Throughout, we use the mathematical formalism of geometric algebra and
geometric calculus, which allows to perform completely coordinate-free
manipulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00174</id><created>2015-05-01</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dom&#xe8;nech</keyname><forenames>Guillem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naruko</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Misao</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological disformal invariance</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>23 pages + Appendix, updated version</comments><report-no>YITP-15-22</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 1510, no. 10, 067 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/10/067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The invariance of physical observables under disformal transformations is
considered. It is known that conformal transformations leave physical
observables invariant. However, whether it is true for disformal
transformations is still an open question. In this paper, it is shown that a
pure disformal transformation without any conformal factor is equivalent to
rescaling the time coordinate. Since this rescaling applies equally to all the
physical quantities, physics must be invariant under a disformal
transformation, that is, neither causal structure, propagation speed nor any
other property of the fields are affected by a disformal transformation itself.
This fact is presented at the action level for gravitational and matter fields
and it is illustrated with some examples of observable quantities. We also find
the physical invariance for cosmological perturbations at linear and high
orders in perturbation, extending previous studies. Finally, a comparison with
Horndeski and beyond Horndeski theories under a disformal transformation is
made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06233</id><created>2015-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Patankar</keyname><forenames>Neelesh A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of sustaining gases in the roughness of submerged
  superhydrophobic surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Langmuir (June 8, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b01651</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rough surfaces submerged in a liquid can remain almost dry if the liquid does
not fully wet the roughness and gases are sustained in roughness grooves. Such
partially dry surfaces can help reduce drag or enhance boiling. Gases sustained
in roughness grooves would be composed of air and the vapor phase of the liquid
itself. The thermodynamics of sustaining vapor was considered in a prior work
[Patankar, Soft Matter, 2010, 6:1613]. Here, the thermodynamics of sustaining
gases (e.g. air) is considered. Governing equations are presented along with a
solution methodology to determine a critical condition to sustain gases. The
critical roughness scale to sustain gases is estimated for different degrees of
saturation of gases dissolved in the liquid. It is shown that roughness
spacings of less than a micron are essential to sustain gases on surfaces
submerged in water at atmospheric pressure. This is consistent with prior
empirical data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06453</id><created>2015-05-24</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grava</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shock formation in the dispersionless Kadomtsev-Petviashvili equation</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>Minor changes</comments><doi>10.1088/0951-7715/29/4/1384</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dispersionless Kadomtsev-Petviashvili (dKP) equation
$(u_t+uu_x)_x=u_{yy}$ is one of the simplest nonlinear wave equations
describing two-dimensional shocks. To solve the dKP equation we use a
coordinate transformation inspired by the method of characteristics for the
one-dimensional Hopf equation $u_t+uu_x=0$. We show numerically that the
solutions to the transformed equation do not develop shocks. This permits us to
extend the dKP solution as the graph of a multivalued function beyond the
critical time when the gradients blow up. This overturned solution is
multivalued in a lip shape region in the $(x,y)$ plane, where the solution of
the dKP equation exists in a weak sense only, and a shock front develops. A
local expansion reveals the universal scaling structure of the shock, which
after a suitable change of coordinates corresponds to a generic cusp
catastrophe. We provide a heuristic derivation of the shock front position near
the critical point for the solution of the dKP equation, and study the solution
of the dKP equation when a small amount of dissipation is added. Using
multiple-scale analysis, we show that in the limit of small dissipation and
near the critical point of the dKP solution, the solution of the dissipative
dKP equation converges to a Pearcey integral. We test and illustrate our
results by detailed comparisons with numerical simulations of both the
regularized equation, the dKP equation, and the asymptotic description given in
terms of the Pearcey integral.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02801</id><created>2015-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Hofer</keyname><forenames>Patrick P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasenbrook</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flindt</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron waiting times for the mesoscopic capacitor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, invited contribution to special issue in Physica
  E on &quot;Frontiers in quantum electronic transport - in memory of Markus
  B\&quot;uttiker&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 82, 3 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2015.08.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate the distribution of waiting times between electrons emitted by a
driven mesoscopic capacitor. Based on a wave packet approach we obtain analytic
expressions for the electronic waiting time distribution and the joint
distribution of subsequent waiting times. These semi-classical results are
compared to a full quantum treatment based on Floquet scattering theory and
good agreement is found in the appropriate parameter ranges. Our results
provide an intuitive picture of the electronic emissions from the driven
mesoscopic capacitor and may be tested in future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00630</id><created>2015-07-02</created><updated>2016-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yu-Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Pure geometric thick $f(R)$-branes: stability and localization of
  gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, improved version, accepted by Eur. Phys. J. C</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016) 321</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4163-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study two exactly solvable five-dimensional thick brane world models in
pure metric $f(R)$ gravity. Working in the Einstein frame, we show that these
solutions are stable against small linear perturbations, including the tensor,
vector, and scalar modes. For both models, the corresponding gravitational zero
mode is localized on the brane, which leads to the four-dimensional Newton's
law; while the massive modes are nonlocalized and only contribute a small
correction to the Newton's law at a large distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01145</id><created>2015-07-04</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hogg</keyname><forenames>Tad</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Dissipation by Metamorphic Micro-Robots in Viscous Fluids</title><categories>cs.RO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>J. of Micro-Bio Robotics 11:85-95 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12213-015-0086-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microscopic robots could perform tasks with high spatial precision, such as
acting on precisely-targeted cells in biological tissues. Some tasks may
benefit from robots that change shape, such as elongating to improve chemical
gradient sensing or contracting to squeeze through narrow channels. This paper
evaluates the energy dissipation for shape-changing (i.e., metamorphic) robots
whose size is comparable to bacteria. Unlike larger robots, surface forces
dominate the dissipation. Theoretical estimates indicate that the power likely
to be available to the robots, as determined by previous studies, is sufficient
to change shape fairly rapidly even in highly-viscous biological fluids.
Achieving this performance will require significant improvements in
manufacturing and material properties compared to current micromachines.
Furthermore, optimally varying the speed of shape change only slightly reduces
energy use compared to uniform speed, thereby simplifying robot controllers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06269</id><created>2015-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Dibyendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarzynski</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of slow transitions between nonequilibrium steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>(5 + 3) pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 063204</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/06/063204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transitions between nonequilibrium steady states obey a generalized Clausius
inequality, which becomes an equality in the quasistatic limit. For slow but
finite transitions, we show that the behavior of the system is described by a
response matrix whose elements are given by a far-from-equilibrium Green-Kubo
formula, involving the decay of correlations evaluated in the nonequilibrium
steady state. This result leads to a fluctuation-dissipation relation between
the mean and variance of the nonadiabatic entropy production, $\Delta s_{\rm
na}$. Furthermore, our results extend -- to nonequilibrium steady states -- the
thermodynamic metric structure introduced by Sivak and Crooks for analyzing
minimal-dissipation protocols for transitions between equilibrium states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04164</id><created>2015-08-17</created><updated>2015-12-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Yao-Lung L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baranger</keyname><forenames>Harold U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon Correlations Generated by Inelastic Scattering in a
  One-Dimensional Waveguide Coupled to Three-Level Systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>Published version, in memory of M. B\&quot;uttiker</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 82, 71 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2016.02.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study photon correlations generated by scattering from three-level systems
(3LS) in one dimension. The two systems studied are a 3LS in a semi-infinite
waveguide (3LS plus a mirror) and two 3LS in an infinite waveguide (double
3LS). Our two-photon scattering approach naturally connects photon correlation
effects with inelastically scattered photons; it corresponds to input-output
theory in the weak-probe limit. At the resonance where electromagnetically
induced transparency (EIT) occurs, we find that no photons are scattered
inelastically and hence there are no induced correlations. Slightly away from
EIT, the total inelastically scattered flux is large, being substantially
enhanced due to the additional interference paths. This enhancement carries
over to the two-photon correlation function, which exhibits non-classical
behavior such as strong bunching with a very long time-scale. The long time
scale originates from the slow-light effect associated with EIT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04305</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Munoz</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vives-Arias</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosquera</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jimenez-Vicente</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kochanek</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mediavilla</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of the Accretion Disk in the Lensed Quasar Q2237+0305 from
  Multi-Epoch and Multi-Wavelength Narrow Band Photometry</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, 1 table; accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/817/2/155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present estimates for the size and the logarithmic slope of the disk
temperature profile of the lensed quasar Q2237+0305, independent of the
component velocities. These estimates are based on six epochs of
multi-wavelength narrowband images from the Nordic Optical Telescope. For each
pair of lensed images and each photometric band, we determine the microlensing
amplitude and chromaticity using pre-existing mid-IR photometry to define the
baseline for no microlensing magnification. A statistical comparison of the
combined microlensing data (6 epochs $\times$ 5 narrow bands $\times$ 6 image
pairs) with simulations based on microlensing magnification maps gives Bayesian
estimates for the half-light radius of $R_{1/2}=8.5^{+7.5}_{-4.0}\sqrt{ \langle
M \rangle/0.3\, M_\odot}$ light-days, and $p=0.95\pm0.33$ for the exponent of
the logarithmic temperature profile $T\propto R^{ -1/p}$. This size estimate is
in good agreement with most recent studies. Other works based on the study of
single microlensing events predict smaller sizes, but could be statistically
biased by focusing on high-magnification events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04915</id><created>2015-09-16</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mineev</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antiferromagnetic order in CeCoIn5 oriented by spin-orbital coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages plus 2 pages with 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An incommensurate spin density wave ($Q$ phase) confined inside the
superconducting state at high basal plane magnetic field is an unique property
of the heavy fermion metal CeCoIn$_5$. The neutron scattering experiments and
the theoretical studies point out that this state come out from the soft mode
condensation of magnetic resonance excitations. We show that the fixation of
direction of antiferromagnetic modulations by a magnetic field reported by
Gerber et al., Nat. Phys. {\bf 10}, 126 (2014) is explained by spin-orbit
coupling. This result, obtained on the basis of quite general phenomenological
arguments, is supported by the microscopic derivation of the $\chi_{zz}$
susceptibility dependence on the mutual orientation of the basal plane magnetic
field and the direction of modulation of spin polarization in a multi-band
metal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06644</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moller</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadowski</keyname><forenames>Aleksander</forenames></author></authors><title>Acceleration of wind in optically thin and thick black hole accretion
  disks simulated in general relativity</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, proceedings of the Research Science Institute,
  2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the force balance and resulting acceleration of gas in general
relativity basing on simulations of accretion on a stellar-mass, non-rotating
black hole. We compare properties of acceleration in an optically thin,
radiatively inefficient disk, and in an optically thick, super-critical disk
accreting at 10 times the Eddington rate. We study both the average forces
acting at given location and forces acting on a gas parcel along its
trajectory. We show that the acceleration is not a continuous process - in most
cases gas is accelerated only in short-lasting episodes. We find that in the
case of optically thin disks gas is pushed out by magnetic field in the polar
region and by thermal pressure and centrifugal force below the disk surface. In
case of optically thick, radiative accretion, it is the radiation pressure
which accelerates the gas in the polar funnel and which compensates (together
with the centrifugal force) the gravity in the bulk of the disk. We also show
that the Newtonian formulae for the forces are inadequate in the innermost and
in the highly magnetized regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08183</id><created>2015-09-27</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Quan-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Impacts of complex behavioral responses on asymmetric interacting
  spreading dynamics in multiplex networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>28 pages, 15 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1405.1905</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 25617 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Information diffusion and disease spreading in communication-contact layered
network are typically asymmetrically coupled with each other, in which how an
individual being aware of disease responds to the disease can significantly
affect the disease spreading. Many recent studies have demonstrated that human
behavioral adoption is a complex and non-Markovian process, where the
probability of adopting one behavior is dependent on the cumulative times of
the received information and the social reinforcement effect of these
cumulative information. We study the impact of such a non-Markovian vaccination
adoption behavior on the epidemic dynamics and the control effects. We find
that this complex adoption behavior caused from the communication layer can
significantly increase the epidemic threshold and reduce the final infection
rate. By defining the social cost as the sum of the cost of vaccination and the
cost of treatment, we show that there exists an optimal social reinforcement
effect or optimal information transmission rate allowing the minimal social
cost. We also develop a mean field based theory to verify the correctness of
the simulation results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03379</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2016-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forn-D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harmans</keyname><forenames>C. J. P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mooij</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Broken selection rule in the quantum Rabi model</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 26720 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep26720</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the interaction between light and matter is very relevant for
fundamental studies of quantum electrodynamics and for the development of
quantum technologies. The quantum Rabi model captures the physics of a single
atom interacting with a single photon at all regimes of coupling strength. We
report the spectroscopic observation of a resonant transition that breaks a
selection rule in the quantum Rabi model, implemented using an $LC$ resonator
and an artificial atom, a superconducting qubit. The eigenstates of the system
consist of a superposition of bare qubit-resonator states with a relative sign.
When the qubit-resonator coupling strength is negligible compared to their own
frequencies, the matrix element between excited eigenstates of different sign
is very small in presence of a resonator drive, establishing a sign-preserving
selection rule. Here, our qubit-resonator system operates in the ultrastrong
coupling regime, where the coupling strength is 10\% of the resonator
frequency, allowing sign-changing transitions to be activated and, therefore,
detected. This work shows that sign-changing transitions are an unambiguous,
distinctive signature of systems operating in the ultrastrong coupling regime
of the quantum Rabi model. These results pave the way to further studies of
sign-preserving selection rules in multiqubit and multiphoton models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06651</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2016-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mendoza-Arenas</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angelakis</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksch</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond mean-field bistability in driven-dissipative lattices:
  bunching-antibunching transition and quantum simulation</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 023821 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.023821</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work we investigate the existence of multiple nonequilibrium
steady states in a coherently driven XY lattice of dissipative two-level
systems. A commonly used mean-field ansatz, in which spatial correlations are
neglected, predicts a bistable behavior with a sharp shift between low- and
high-density states. In contrast one-dimensional matrix product methods reveal
these effects to be artifacts of the mean-field approach, with both
disappearing once correlations are taken fully into account. Instead, a
bunching-antibunching transition emerges. This indicates that alternative
approaches should be considered for higher spatial dimensions, where classical
simulations are currently infeasible. Thus we propose a circuit QED quantum
simulator implementable with current technology to enable an experimental
investigation of the model considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08845</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sadowski</keyname><forenames>Aleksander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasota</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramowicz</keyname><forenames>Marek A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narayan</keyname><forenames>Ramesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy flows in thick accretion disks and their consequences for black
  hole feedback</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures, published in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2854</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study energy flows in geometrically thick accretion discs, both optically
thick and thin, using general relativistic, three-dimensional simulations of
black hole accretion flows. We find that for non-rotating black holes the
efficiency of the total feedback from thick accretion discs is $3\%$ - roughly
half of the thin disc efficiency. This amount of energy is ultimately
distributed between outflow and radiation, the latter scaling weakly with the
accretion rate for super-critical accretion rates, and returned to the
interstellar medium. Accretion on to rotating black holes is more efficient
because of the additional extraction of rotational energy. However, the jet
component is collimated and likely to interact only weakly with the
environment, whereas the outflow and radiation components cover a wide solid
angle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00220</id><created>2015-11-01</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khatibi</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Najafabadi</keyname><forenames>Mojtaba Mohammadi</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on top quark flavor changing neutral currents using diphoton
  events at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures, an EDM analysis included in addition to the
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B909 (2016) 607-618</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.06.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we show that the diphoton mass spectrum in proton-proton
collisions at the LHC is sensitive to the top quark flavor changing neutral
current in the vertices of $tu\gamma$ and $tc\gamma$. The diphoton mass
spectrum measured by the CMS experiment at the LHC at a center-of-mass energy
of 8 TeV and an integrated luminosity of 19.5 fb$^{-1}$ is used as an example
to set limits on these FCNC couplings. It is also shown that the angular
distribution of the diphotons is sensitive to anomalous $tu\gamma$ and
$tc\gamma$ couplings and it is a powerful tool to probe any value of the
branching fraction of top quark rare decay to an up-type quark plus a photon
down to the order of $10^{-4}$. We also show that the $tu\gamma$ FCNC coupling
has a significant contribution to the neutron electric dipole moment (EDM) and
the upper bound on neutron EDM can be used to constrain the $tu\gamma$ FCNC
coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03786</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Horikiri</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamide</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuo</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byrnes</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>Natsuko</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;ffler</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shikano</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>Tetsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forchel</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Yoshihisa</forenames></author></authors><title>High-energy side-peak emission of exciton-polariton condensates in high
  density regime</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures + 23 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 25655 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep25655</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a standard semiconductor laser, electrons and holes recombine via
stimulated emission to emit coherent light, in a process that is far from
thermal equilibrium. Exciton-polariton condensates -- sharing the same basic
device structure as a semiconductor laser, consisting of quantum wells coupled
to a microcavity -- have been investigated primarily at densities far below the
Mott density for signatures of Bose-Einstein condensation. At high densities
approaching the Mott density, exciton-polariton condensates are generally
thought to revert to a standard semiconductor laser, with the loss of strong
coupling. Here, we report the observation of a photoluminescence sideband at
high densities that cannot be accounted for by conventional semiconductor
lasing. This also differs from an upper-polariton peak by the observation of
the excitation power dependence in the peak-energy separation. Our
interpretation as a persistent coherent electron-hole-photon coupling captures
several features of this sideband whereas many remain elusive. Understanding
the observation will lead to a development in non-equilibrium many-body
physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03825</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2016-03-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rossatto</keyname><forenames>D. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eneriz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entangling polaritons via dynamical Casimir effect in circuit quantum
  electrodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Updated version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 094514 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.094514</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate how the dynamical Casimir effect can entangle quantum systems
in different coupling regimes of circuit quantum electrodynamics, and show the
robustness of such entanglement generation against dissipative effects with
current technology. We consider two qubit-resonator systems, which are coupled
by a SQUID driven with an external magnetic field, and explore the entire range
of coupling regimes between each qubit and its respective resonator. In this
scheme, we derive a semianalytic explanation for the entanglement generation
between both superconducting qubits when they are coupled to their resonators
in the strong coupling regime. For the ultrastrong and deep strong coupling
regimes, we design feasible protocols to generate maximally-entangled
polaritonic states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03898</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Azouit</keyname><forenames>Remi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlette</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouchon</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Well-posedness and convergence of the Lindblad master equation for a
  quantum harmonic oscillator with multi-photon drive and damping</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, submitted</comments><msc-class>37L99, 47B44, 81Q93, 81S22, 81V10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the model of a quantum harmonic oscillator governed by a Lindblad
master equation where the typical drive and loss channels are multi-photon
processes instead of single-photon ones; this implies a dissipation operator of
order 2k with integer k&gt;1 for a k-photon process. We prove that the
corresponding PDE makes the state converge, for large time, to an invariant
subspace spanned by a set of k selected basis vectors; the latter physically
correspond to so-called coherent states with the same amplitude and uniformly
distributed phases. We also show that this convergence features a finite set of
bounded invariant functionals of the state (physical observables), such that
the final state in the invariant subspace can be directly predicted from the
initial state. The proof includes the full arguments towards the well-posedness
of the corresponding dynamics in proper Banach spaces of Hermitian trace-class
operators equipped with adapted nuclear norms. It relies on the Hille-Yosida
theorem and Lyapunov convergence analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05319</id><created>2015-11-17</created><updated>2016-03-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maryasin</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhitomirsky</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moessner</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-field behavior of an XY pyrochlore antiferromagnet: emergent clock
  anisotropies</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, accepted version with supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 100406(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.100406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using $\rm Er_2Ti_2O_7$ as a motivation, we investigate finite-field
properties of $XY$ pyrochlore antiferromagnets. In addition to a
fluctuation-induced six-fold anisotropy present in zero field, an external
magnetic field induces a combination of two-, three-, and six-fold clock terms
as a function of its orientation providing for a rich and controllable
magnetothermodynamics. For $\rm Er_2Ti_2O_7$, we predict a new phase transition
for ${\bf H}\parallel [001]$. Re-entrant transitions are also found for ${\bf
H}\parallel [111]$. We extend these results to the whole family the $XY$
pyrochlore antiferromagnets and show that presence and number of low-field
transitions for different orientations can be used for locating a given
material in the parameter space of anisotropic pyrochlores. Finite-temperature
classical Monte Carlo simulations serve to confirm and illustrate these
analytic predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06163</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawashima</keyname><forenames>I. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helene</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Carvalho</keyname><forenames>R. S. Marques</forenames></author></authors><title>What statistics can tell us about strategy in tennis</title><categories>physics.pop-ph physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Rev. Bras. Ensino F\'is. 38, e3316 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1590/1806-9126-RBEF-2016-0048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we analyse tiebreak results from some tennis players in order
to investigate whether we are able to identify some strategy in this crucial
moment of the game. We compared the observed results with a binomial
distribution considering that the probabilities of winning or losing a point
are equal. Using a $\chi^2$ test we found that, excepting some players, the
greatest part of the results agrees with our hypothesis that there is no hidden
strategy and the points in tiebreaks are merely aleatory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06424</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaul</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeSalvo</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aman</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunning</keyname><forenames>F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Killian</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant Rydberg Dressing of Alkaline-Earth Atoms via
  Electromagnetically Induced Transparency</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 243001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.243001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop an approach to generate finite-range atomic interactions via
optical Rydberg-state excitation and study the underlying excitation dynamics
in theory and experiment. In contrast to previous work, the proposed scheme is
based on resonant optical driving and the establishment of a dark state under
conditions of electromagnetically induced transparency (EIT). Analyzing the
driven dissipative dynamics of the atomic gas, we show that the interplay
between coherent light coupling, radiative decay and strong Rydberg-Rydberg
atom interactions leads to the emergence of sizeable effective interactions
while providing remarkably long coherence times. The latter are studied
experimentally in a cold gas of strontium atoms for which the proposed scheme
is most efficient. Our measured atom loss is in agreement with the theoretical
prediction based on binary effective interactions between the driven atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09361</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rammelm&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drut</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ground state of the two-dimensional attractive Fermi gas: essential
  properties from few- to many-body</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 033639 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.033639</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the ground-state properties of unpolarized two-dimensional
attractive fermions in the range from few to many particles. Using
first-principles lattice Monte Carlo methods, we determine the ground-state
energy, Tan's contact, momentum distribution, and single-particle correlation
function. We investigate those properties for systems of $N=4,8,...,40$
particles and for a wide range of attractive couplings. As the attractive
coupling is increased, the thermodynamic limit is reached at progressively
lower $N$ due to the dominance of the two-body sector. At large momenta $k$,
the momentum distribution displays the expected $k^{-4}$ behavior, but its
onset shifts from $k \simeq 1.8 k^{}_F$ at weak coupling towards higher $k$ at
strong coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01071</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wolkanowski</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soltysiak</keyname><forenames>Milena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacosa</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>$K_{0}^{\ast}(800)$ as a companion pole of $K_{0}^{\ast}(1430)$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.05.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the light scalar sector up to $1.8$ GeV by using a quantum field
theoretical approach which includes a single kaonic state in a Lagrangian with
both derivative and non-derivative interactions. By performing a fit to $\pi K$
phase shift data in the $I=1/2,$ $J=0$ channel, we show that
$K_{0}^{\ast}(800)$ (or $\kappa$) emerges as a dynamically generated companion
pole of $K_{0}^{\ast }(1430)$. This is a result of investigating quantum
fluctuations with one kaon and one pion circulating in the loops dressing
$K_{0}^{\ast}(1430)$. We determine the position of the poles on the complex
plane in the context of our approach: for $K_{0}^{\ast}(1430)$ we get
$(1.413\pm0.002)-i{0.02cm}(0.127\pm0.003)$ (in GeV), while for $\kappa$ we get
$(0.746\pm0.019)-i{0.02cm}(0.262\pm0.014)$ (in GeV). The model-dependence of
these results and related uncertainties are discussed in the paper. A
large-$N_{c}$ study confirms that $K_{0}^{\ast}(1430)$ is predominantly a
quarkonium and that $K_{0}^{\ast}(800)$ is a molecular-like dynamically
generated state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06479</id><created>2015-12-20</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>Ryan G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnett</keyname><forenames>Nix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crutchfield</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Information Flows? A Critique of Transfer Entropies</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cs.IT math.IT math.ST nlin.AO q-bio.MN stat.TH</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures; http://csc.ucdavis.edu/~cmg/compmech/pubs/if.htm</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 238701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.238701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A central task in analyzing complex dynamics is to determine the loci of
information storage and the communication topology of information flows within
a system. Over the last decade and a half, diagnostics for the latter have come
to be dominated by the transfer entropy. Via straightforward examples, we show
that it and a derivative quantity, the causation entropy, do not, in fact,
quantify the flow of information. At one and the same time they can
overestimate flow or underestimate influence. We isolate why this is the case
and propose several avenues to alternate measures for information flow. We also
address an auxiliary consequence: The proliferation of networks as a now-common
theoretical model for large-scale systems, in concert with the use of
transfer-like entropies, has shoehorned dyadic relationships into our
structural interpretation of the organization and behavior of complex systems.
This interpretation thus fails to include the effects of polyadic dependencies.
The net result is that much of the sophisticated organization of complex
systems may go undetected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06745</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gandilo</keyname><forenames>Natalie N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>Peter A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angil&#xe8;</keyname><forenames>Francesco E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashton</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benton</keyname><forenames>Steven J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devlin</keyname><forenames>Mark J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dober</keyname><forenames>Bradley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fissel</keyname><forenames>Laura M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Yasuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galitzki</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkov</keyname><forenames>Andrei L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>Tristan G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moncelsi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Fumitaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Netterfield</keyname><forenames>Calvin B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novak</keyname><forenames>Giles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascale</keyname><forenames>Enzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poidevin</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;rick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fabio P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savini</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Douglas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shariff</keyname><forenames>Jamil A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soler</keyname><forenames>Juan Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Nicholas E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Carole E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Gregory S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward-Thompson</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author></authors><title>Submillimeter Polarization Spectrum in the Vela C Molecular Cloud</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 824, Number 2, p.84 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/824/2/84</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarization maps of the Vela C molecular cloud were obtained at 250, 350,
and 500um during the 2012 flight of the balloon-borne telescope BLASTPol. These
measurements are used in conjunction with 850um data from Planck to study the
submillimeter spectrum of the polarization fraction for this cloud. The
spectrum is relatively flat and does not exhibit a pronounced minimum at
\lambda ~350um as suggested by previous measurements of other molecular clouds.
The shape of the spectrum does not depend strongly on the radiative environment
of the dust, as quantified by the column density or the dust temperature
obtained from Herschel data. The polarization ratios observed in Vela C are
consistent with a model of a porous clumpy molecular cloud being uniformly
heated by the interstellar radiation field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07645</id><created>2015-12-23</created><updated>2016-06-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Allanach</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dev</keyname><forenames>P. S. Bhupal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renner</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>Kazuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Di-photon Excess Explained by a Resonant Sneutrino in R-parity Violating
  Supersymmetry</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Added more discussion on WW, version accepted in PRD, 11 pages, 5
  figures</comments><report-no>DAMTP-2015-92, IPPP/15/80, DCPT/15/160</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 115022 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.115022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explain the recent excess seen by ATLAS and CMS experiments at around 750
GeV in the di-photon invariant mass as a narrow width sneutrino decaying to
di-photons via a stau loop in R-parity violating Supersymmetry. The stau mass
is predicted to be somewhere between half the resonant sneutrino mass and half
the sneutrino mass plus 14 GeV. The scenario also predicts further signal
channels at an invariant mass of 750 GeV, the most promising being into di-jets
and $WW$. We also predict a left handed charged slepton decaying into $WZ$ and
$W \gamma$ at a mass 750-754 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08223</id><created>2015-12-27</created><updated>2016-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ominato</keyname><forenames>Yuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshino</keyname><forenames>Mikito</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetotransport in the Weyl semimetal in the quantum limit - the role
  of the topological surface states</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 245304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.245304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study the magnetoconductivity of the Weyl semimetal having a
surface boundary under $E$ || $B$ geometry and demonstrate that the topological
surface state plays an essential role in the magnetotransport. In the
long-range disorder limit where the scattering between the two Weyl nodes
vanishes, the conductivity diverges in the bulk model (i.e., periodic boundary
condition) as usually expected, since the direct inter-node relaxation is
absent. In the presence of the surface, however, the inter-node relaxation
always takes place through the mediation by the surface states, and that
prevents the conductivity divergence. The magnetic-field dependence becomes
also quite different between the two cases, where the conductivity linearly
increases in $B$ in the surface boundary case, in contrast to $B$-independent
behavior in the bulk-periodic case. This is an interesting example in which the
same system exhibits completely different properties in the surface boundary
condition and the periodic boundary condition even in the macroscopic size
limit. In the short-range regime where the direct intervalley scattering is
dominant, the surface states are irrelevant and the conductivity approaches
that of the bulk periodic model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00622</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kurkov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent spontaneous symmetry breaking and emergent symmetry restoration
  in rippling gravitational background</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>slightly amended file to match published version; references
  corrected. 8 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4178-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study effects of a rippling gravitational background on a scalar field
with a double well potential, focusing on the analogy with the well known
dynamics of the Kapitza's pendulum. The ripples are rendered as infinitesimal
but rapidly oscillating perturbations of the scale factor. We find that the
resulting dynamics crucially depends on a value of the parameter $\xi$ in the
$\xi \,R\, \phi^2$ vertex. For the time-dependent perturbations of a proper
form the resulting effective action is generally covariant, and at a high
enough frequency at $\xi&lt;0$ and at $\xi&gt;1/6$ the effective potential has a
single minimum at zero, thereby restoring spontaneously broken symmetry of the
ground state. On the other side, at $0&lt;\xi&lt; 1/6$ spontaneous symmetry breaking
emerges even when it is absent in the unperturbed case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02092</id><created>2016-01-09</created><updated>2016-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>The hidden-charm pentaquark and tetraquark states</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>Review accepted by Physics Reports, 152 pages, 66 figures, and 29
  tables</comments><journal-ref>Physics Reports 639, 1-121 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2016.05.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the past decade many charmonium-like states were observed experimentally.
Especially those charged charmonium-like $Z_c$ states and bottomonium-like
$Z_b$ states can not be accommodated within the naive quark model. These
charged $Z_c$ states are good candidates of either the hidden-charm tetraquark
states or molecules composed of a pair of charmed mesons. Recently, the LHCb
Collaboration discovered two hidden-charm pentaquark states, which are also
beyond the quark model. In this work, we review the current experimental
progress and investigate various theoretical interpretations of these
candidates of the multiquark states. We list the puzzles and theoretical
challenges of these models when confronted with the experimental data. We also
discuss possible future measurements which may distinguish the theoretical
schemes on the underlying structures of the hidden-charm multiquark states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03228</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jiangping</forenames></author></authors><title>Relationship between Pairing Symmetries and Interaction Parameters in
  Iron-Based Superconductors from Functional Renormalization Group Calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 113 67005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/113/67005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pairing symmetries of iron-based superconductors are investigated
systematically in a five-orbital model within the different regions of
interaction parameters by functional renormalization group(FRG). Even for a
fixed Fermi surface with both hole and electron pockets, it is found that
depending on interaction parameters, a variety of pairing symmetries, including
two types of $d$-wave and two types of $s$-wave pairing symmetries, can emerge.
Only the $d_{x^2-y^2}$ and the $s\pm$ waves are robustly supported by the
nearest-neighbor(NN) intra-orbital $J_1$ and the next-nearest-neighbor(NNN)
intra-orbital $J_2$ antiferromagnetic(AFM) exchange couplings respectively.
This study suggests that the accurate initial input of interaction parameters
are essential to make FRG an useful method to determine the leading channel of
superconducting instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03747</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Kyusung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong Baek</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of triplon dynamics in the quantum magnet BiCu$_2$PO$_6$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables. Updated with the published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235130 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a theory of triplon dynamics in the valence bond solid ground
state of the coupled spin-ladders modelled for BiCu$_2$PO$_6$. Utilizing the
recent high quality neutron scattering data [Nature Physics (2015), DOI:
10.1038/NPHYS3566] as guides and a theory of interacting triplons via the bond
operator formulation, we determine a minimal spin Hamiltonian for this system.
It is shown that the splitting of the low energy triplon modes and the peculiar
magnetic field dependence of the triplon dispersions can be explained by
including substantial Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya and symmetric anisotropic spin
interactions. Taking into account the interactions between triplons and the
decay of the triplons to the two-triplon continuum via anisotropic spin
interactions, we provide a theoretical picture that can be used to understand
the main features of the recent neutron scattering experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05828</id><created>2016-01-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartalucci</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertolucci</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berucci</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bragadireanu</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cargnelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clozza</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curceanu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Paolis</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Matteo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>d'Uffizi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egger</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guaraldo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iliescu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishiwatari</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laubenstein</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milotti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietreanu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piscicchia</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>A. Romero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sbardella</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scordo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirghi</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirghi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperandio</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doce</keyname><forenames>O. Vazquez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widmann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmeskal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Searches for the Violation of Pauli Exclusion Principle at LNGS in
  VIP(-2) experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. Conference proceedings for oral
  presentation at TAUP 2015, Torino</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/718/4/042055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The VIP (Violation of Pauli exclusion principle) experiment and its follow-up
experiment VIP-2 at the Laboratori Nazionali del Gran Sasso (LNGS) search for
X-rays from Cu atomic states that are prohibited by the Pauli Exclusion
Principle (PEP). The candidate events, if they exist, will originate from the
transition of a $2p$ orbit electron to the ground state which is already
occupied by two electrons. The present limit on the probability for PEP
violation for electron is 4.7 $\times10^{-29}$ set by the VIP experiment. With
upgraded detectors for high precision X-ray spectroscopy, the VIP-2 experiment
will improve the sensitivity by two orders of magnitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08036</id><created>2016-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahnert</keyname><forenames>Carolina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buss</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Herranz</keyname><forenames>Nuria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoefer</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porsch</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving PWR core simulations by Monte Carlo uncertainty analysis and
  Bayesian inference</title><categories>nucl-th physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Nuclear Energy 95 (2016), pages 148-156</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.anucene.2016.05.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Monte Carlo-based Bayesian inference model is applied to the prediction of
reactor operation parameters of a PWR nuclear power plant. In this
non-perturbative framework, high-dimensional covariance information describing
the uncertainty of microscopic nuclear data is combined with measured reactor
operation data in order to provide statistically sound, well founded
uncertainty estimates of integral parameters, such as the boron letdown curve
and the burnup-dependent reactor power distribution. The performance of this
methodology is assessed in a blind test approach, where we use measurements of
a given reactor cycle to improve the prediction of the subsequent cycle. As it
turns out, the resulting improvement of the prediction quality is impressive.
In particular, the prediction uncertainty of the boron letdown curve, which is
of utmost importance for the planning of the reactor cycle length, can be
reduced by one order of magnitude by including the boron concentration
measurement information of the previous cycle in the analysis. Additionally, we
present first results of non-perturbative nuclear-data updating and show that
predictions obtained with the updated libraries are consistent with those
induced by Bayesian inference applied directly to the integral observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06154</id><created>2016-02-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Siomau</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural Complexity Of Quantum Networks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1742, 030017 (2016), Proceeding of the 5th Saudi
  International Meeting on Frontiers of Physics, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum network is a set of nodes connected with channels, through which the
nodes communicate photons and classical information. Classical structural
complexity of a quantum network may be defined through its physical structure,
i.e. mutual position of nodes and channels connecting them. We show here that
the classical structural complexity of a quantum network does not restrict the
structural complexity of entanglement graphs, which may be created in the
quantum network with local operations and classical communication. We show, in
particular, that 1D quantum network can simulate both simple entanglement
graphs such as lattices and random graphs and complex small-world graphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00094</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-04-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bazzi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellotti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berucci</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bragadireanu</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosnar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cargnelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curceanu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butt</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>d'Uffizi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorini</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghio</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guaraldo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayanao</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iliescu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishiwatari</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandri</keyname><forenames>P. Levi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okada</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietreanu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piscicchia</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>A. Romero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sbardella</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scordo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirghi</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirghi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatsuno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doce</keyname><forenames>O. Vazquez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widmann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmeskal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>$K$-series X-ray yield measurement of kaonic hydrogen atoms in a gaseous
  target</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures. Submitted to Nuclear Physics A, Special Issue on
  Strangeness and Charm</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics A 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.03.047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measured the $K$-series X-rays of the $K^{-}p$ exotic atom in the
SIDDHARTA experiment with a gaseous hydrogen target of 1.3 g/l, which is about
15 times the $\rho_{\rm STP}$ of hydrogen gas. At this density, the absolute
yields of kaonic X-rays, when a negatively charged kaon stopped inside the
target, were determined to be 0.012$^{+0.004}_{-0.003}$ for $K_{\alpha}$ and
0.043$^{+0.012}_{-0.011}$ for all the $K$-series transitions $K_{tot}$. These
results, together with the KEK E228 experiment results, confirm for the first
time a target density dependence of the yield predicted by the cascade models,
and provide valuable information to refine the parameters used in the cascade
models for the kaonic atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00914</id><created>2016-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Salazar-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ojeda-Guill&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mota</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Algebraic approach and coherent states for a relativistic quantum
  particle in cosmic string spacetime</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 372 (2016) 283-296</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.05.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a relativistic quantum particle in cosmic string spacetime in the
presence of a uniform magnetic field and a Coulomb-type scalar potential. It is
shown that the radial part of this problem possesses the $su(1,1)$ symmetry. We
obtain the energy spectrum and eigenfunctions of this problem by using two
algebraic methods: the Schr\&quot;odinger factorization and the tilting
transformation. Finally, we give the explicit form of the relativistic coherent
states for this problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02083</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Maitreyee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Sumit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choudhury</keyname><forenames>Subikash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Tapan K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluctuations in Charged Particle Multiplicities in Relativistic
  Heavy-Ion Collisions</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43 085102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/8/085102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multiplicity distributions of charged particles and their event-by-event
fluctuations have been compiled for relativistic heavy-ion collisions from the
available experimental data at Brookhaven National Laboratory and CERN and also
by the use of an event generator. Multiplicity fluctuations are sensitive to
QCD phase transition and to the presence of critical point in the QCD phase
diagram. In addition, multiplicity fluctuations provide baselines for other
event-by-event measurements. Multiplicity fluctuation expressed in terms of the
scaled variance of the multiplicity distribution is an intensive quantity, but
is sensitive to the volume fluctuation of the system. The importance of the
choice of narrow centrality bins and the corrections of centrality bin width
effect for controlling volume fluctuations have been discussed. It is observed
that the mean and width of the multiplicity distributions monotonically
increase as a function of increasing centrality at all collision energies,
whereas the multiplicity fluctuations show minimal variations with centrality.
The beam energy dependence shows that the multiplicity fluctuations have a slow
rise at lower collision energies and remain constant at higher energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02728</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yuanjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millis</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge transfer and electron-phonon coupling in monolayer FeSe on Nb
  doped SrTiO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 224506 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.224506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Monolayer films of FeSe grown on SrTiO$_3$ substrates are electron doped
relative to bulk and exhibit a significantly higher superconducting transition
temperatures. We present density functional calculations and a modified
Schottky model incorporating the strong paraelectricity of SrTiO$_3$ which
demonstrate that the doping may be due to charge transfer from SrTiO$_3$
impurity bands driven by work function mismatch. Physically relevant levels of
Nb doping are shown to lead to doping of the FeSe compatible with observation.
The coupling of electrons in FeSe to polar phonons in the depletion regime of
the SrTiO$_3$ is calculated. A $\lambda\sim 0.4$ is found; the coupling to
long-wavelength phonons is found to be dominant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03684</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Dounas-Frazer</keyname><forenames>Dimitri R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van De Bogart</keyname><forenames>Kevin L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stetzer</keyname><forenames>MacKenzie R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewandowski</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating the role of model-based reasoning while troubleshooting an
  electric circuit</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures, 4 tables; Submitted to Physical Review PER</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 12, 010137 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.12.010137</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the overlap of two nationally-recognized learning outcomes for
physics lab courses, namely, the ability to model experimental systems and the
ability to troubleshoot a malfunctioning apparatus. Modeling and
troubleshooting are both nonlinear, recursive processes that involve using
models to inform revisions to an apparatus. To probe the overlap of modeling
and troubleshooting, we collected audiovisual data from think-aloud activities
in which eight pairs of students from two institutions attempted to diagnose
and repair a malfunctioning electrical circuit. We characterize the cognitive
tasks and model-based reasoning that students employed during this activity. In
doing so, we demonstrate that troubleshooting engages students in the core
scientific practice of modeling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04008</id><created>2016-03-13</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sazhina</keyname><forenames>Olga S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhaeva</keyname><forenames>Alfiia I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observational constraints on cosmological superstrings</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures; submitted to JCAP</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From theoretical point of view and not being in contradiction with current
observational data, the cosmic strings should have fundamentally different
origin and are characterized by wide range of energies. The paper is devoted to
search for possible cosmological observational tests on superstring theory,
among them to identification of observational characteristics to distinguish
between cosmological superstring of different types. In the brane-world
scenario with an assumption of creation of cosmological superstrings it was
obtained the lower limit on the superstring tension as function of deficit
angle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05663</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lozanov</keyname><forenames>Kaloian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amin</keyname><forenames>Mustafa A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The charged inflaton and its gauge fields: preheating and initial
  conditions for reheating</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>48 pages, 6 figures, 2 appendices, v3: references added, minor
  changes to text, to appear in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP06(2016)032</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/06/032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate particle production during inflation and in the early stages of
reheating after inflation in models with a charged scalar field coupled to
Abelian and non-Abelian gauge fields. A detailed analysis of the power spectra
of primordial electric fields, magnetic fields and charge fluctuations at the
end of inflation and preheating is provided. We carefully account for the Gauss
constraints during inflation and preheating, and clarify the role of the
longitudinal components of the electric field. We calculate the timescale for
the back-reaction of the produced gauge fields on the inflaton condensate,
marking the onset of non-linear evolution of the fields. We provide a
prescription for initial conditions for lattice simulations necessary to
capture the subsequent nonlinear dynamics. On the observational side, we find
that the primordial magnetic fields generated are too small to explain the
origin of magnetic fields on galactic scales and the charge fluctuations are
well within observational bounds for the models considered in this paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06027</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yichao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author></authors><title>First-principles study of the terahertz third-order nonlinear response
  of metallic armchair graphene nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>36 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235430 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the terahertz third-order nonlinear conductance of metallic
armchair graphene nanoribbons using time-dependent perturbation theory.
Significant enhancement of the intrinsic third-order conductance over the
result for instrinsic 2D single-layer graphene is observed over a wide range of
temperatures. We also investigate the nonlinear response of extrinsic metallic
acGNR with |E_F|&lt;&lt;200 meV. We find that the third-order conductance exhibits a
strong Fermi level dependence at low temperatures. A third-order critical field
strength of between 1 and 5 kV/m is computed for the Kerr conductance as a
function of temperature. For the third-harmonic conductance, the minimum
critical field is computed to be about about 5 kV/m.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06369</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carrega</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solinas</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sassetti</keyname><forenames>Maura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy exchange in driven open quantum systems at strong coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 240403 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.240403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The time-dependent energy transfer in a driven quantum system strongly
coupled to a heat bath is studied within an influence functional approach.
Exact formal expressions for the statistics of energy dissipation into the
different channels are derived. The general method is applied to the driven
dissipative two-state system. It is shown that the energy flows obey a balance
relation, and that, for strong coupling, the interaction may constitute the
major dissipative channel. Results in analytic form are presented for a
particular value of strong Ohmic dissipation. The energy flows show interesting
behaviors including driving-induced coherences and quantum stochastic
resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08532</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shin-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budroni</keyname><forenames>Costantino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Yeong-Cherng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yueh-Nan</forenames></author></authors><title>Natural Framework for Device-Independent Quantification of Quantum
  Steerability, Measurement Incompatibility, and Self-Testing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>The core of these results were already presented at the Workshop on
  Quantum Nonlocality, Causal Structure and Device-independent Quantum
  Information on 14/12/2016; v2: closely approximates journal version; v3:
  title is updated as journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 240401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.240401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the concept of assemblage moment matrices, i.e., a collection of
matrices of expectation values, each associated with a conditional quantum
state obtained in a steering experiment. We demonstrate how it can be used for
quantum states and measurements characterization in a device-independent
manner, i.e., without invoking any assumption about the measurement or the
preparation device. Specifically, we show how the method can be used to lower
bound the steerability of an underlying quantum state directly from the
observed correlation between measurement outcomes. Combining such
device-independent quantifications with earlier results established by Piani
and Watrous [Phys. Rev. Lett. 114, 060404 (2015)], our approach immediately
provides a device-independent lower bound on the generalized robustness of
entanglement, as well as the usefulness of the underlying quantum state for a
type of subchannel discrimination problem. In addition, by proving a
quantitative relationship between steering robustness and the recently
introduced incompatibility robustness, our approach also allows for a
device-independent quantification of the incompatibility between various
measurements performed in a Bell-type experiment. Explicit examples where such
bounds provide a kind of self-testing of the performed measurements are
provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08657</id><created>2016-03-29</created><updated>2016-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kopylov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orekhov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petukhov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On a Search for Hidden Photon CDM by a Multi-Cathode Counter</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures; v.2: minor changes/corrections made, following
  referee's recommendations; accepted for publication in &quot;Advances in High
  Energy Physics&quot;, open special issue. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1512.04675</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, vol. 2016, Article ID 2058372</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/2058372</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a new technique of a Multi-Cathode Counter (MCC) developed to
search for hidden photon (HP) cold dark matter (CDM) with a mass from 5 to 500
eV. The method is suggested in the assumption that HP-photon mixing causes
emission of single electrons from a metal cathode if the mass of hidden photon
is greater than a work function of the metal. The measured effect from HP
should be dependent on work function of the metal and on the structure of
electronic shells of the metal used as a cathode. Potentially this can be used
for a verification of the results obtained. Some preliminary results for the
upper limit for mixing parameter X have been obtained for HP with a mass from 5
eV to 10 keV as a pure illustration of the potential of this technique. The
efforts are continued to refine the procedure of data treatment and to improve
the work of MCC. A new detector with a more developed design is under
construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00196</id><created>2016-04-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nousch</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;mpfer</keyname><forenames>D. Seipt B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panferov</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolyansky</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Titov</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pair production by Schwinger and Breit-Wheeler processes in bi-frequent
  fields</title><categories>hep-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Plasma Phys. (2016), vol. 82, 655820301</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0022377816000428</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Counter-propagating and suitably polarized light (laser) beams can provide
conditions for pair production. Here, we consider in more detail the following
two situations: (i) In the homogeneity regions of anti-nodes of linearly
polarized ultra-high intensity laser beams, the Schwinger process is
dynamically assisted by a second high-frequency field, e.g. by a XFEL beam.
(ii) A high-energy probe photon beam colliding with a superposition of
co-propagating intense laser and XFEL beams gives rise to the laser assisted
Breit-Wheeler process. Prospects of such bi-frequent field constellations with
respect to the feasibility of conversion of light into matter are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03950</id><created>2016-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Scheie</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanders</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krizan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broholm</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalar Chiral Spin-1/2 Order on Kagome Lattices in Nd3Sb3Mg2O14</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 180407 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.180407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce $\mathrm{Nd_{3}Sb_{3}Mg_{2}O_{14}}$ with ideal kagome lattices
of neodymium ions in ABC stacking. Thermodynamic measurements show a
Curie-Weiss temperature of $\Theta_{CW}=-0.12~$K, a Nd$^{3+}$ spin-1/2 Kramers
doublet ground state, and a second order phase transition at $T_N=0.56(2)~$K.
Neutron scattering reveals non-coplanar scalar chiral ${\bf k} =0$ magnetic
order with a correlation length exceeding 400 \AA = 55 $a$ and an ordered
moment of $1.79(5)~\mu_B$. This order includes a canted ferromagnetic component
perpendicular to the kagome planes favored by Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04690</id><created>2016-04-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Charalampidis</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frantzeskakis</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuevas-Maraver</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>$SO(2)$-induced breathing patterns in multi-component Bose-Einstein
  condensates</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.063623</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we employ the $SO(2)$-rotations of a two-component, one-, two-
and three-dimensional nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger system at and near the Manakov
limit, to construct vector solitons and vortex structures. This way, stable
stationary dark-bright solitons and their higher-dimensional siblings are
transformed into robust oscillatory dark-dark solitons (and generalizations
thereof), with and without a harmonic confinement. By analogy to the
one-dimensional case, vector higher-dimensional structures take the form of
vortex-vortex states in two dimensions and, e.g., vortex ring-vortex ring ones
in three dimensions. We consider the effects of unequal (self- and cross-)
interaction strengths, where the $SO(2)$ symmetry is only approximately
satisfied, showing the dark-dark soliton oscillation is generally robust.
Similar features are found in higher dimensions too, although our case examples
suggest that phenomena such as phase separation may contribute to the
associated dynamics. These results, in connection with the experimental
realization of one-dimensional variants of such states in optics and
Bose-Einstein condensates (BECs), suggest the potential observation of the
higher-dimensional bound states proposed herein.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07148</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Haro</keyname><forenames>Mariano L&#xf3;pez</forenames></author></authors><title>Radial distribution function for hard spheres in fractal dimensions: A
  heuristic approximation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures; v2: new paragraph added at the end of the
  conclusion section</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 062126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.062126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analytic approximations for the radial distribution function, the structure
factor, and the equation of state of hard-core fluids in fractal dimension $d$
($1 \leq d \leq 3$) are developed as heuristic interpolations from the
knowledge of the exact and Percus-Yevick results for the hard-rod and
hard-sphere fluids, respectively. In order to assess their value, such
approximate results are compared with those of recent Monte Carlo simulations
and numerical solutions of the Percus-Yevick equation for fractal dimension [M.
Heinen et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. \textbf{115}, 097801 (2015)], a good agreement
being observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05128</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mihalik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><suffix>jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Jaglicic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fitta</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavecansky</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csach</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budziak</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brianccin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zentkova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihalik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural and magnetic study of PrMn$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$O$_3$ $(0 \leq x \leq
  1)$ compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structural and magnetic study of PrMn1-xFexO3(0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1) substitutional
orthorhombical system, was performed on polycrystalline (x &lt;= 0.5) as well as
on the single crystalline (0.5 &lt;= x &lt;= 1) samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01395</id><created>2016-06-04</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>McCaughan</keyname><forenames>Adam N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abebe</keyname><forenames>Nathnael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Qing-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berggren</keyname><forenames>Karl K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensing supercurrents using geometric effects</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a superconducting three-terminal device that uses a simple
geometric effect known as current crowding to sense the flow of current and
actuate a readout signal. The device consists of a &quot;Y&quot;-shaped current combiner,
with two currents (sense and bias) entering through the top arms of the &quot;Y&quot;,
intersecting, and then exiting through the bottom leg of the &quot;Y&quot;'. This
geometry--mixing two inputs at a sharp intersection point--takes its
inspiration from Y-shaped combiners in fluid flow systems, where variations in
the input pressures can produce at turbulence and mixing at the intersection.
When current is added to or removed from one of the arms (the sense arm), the
superconducting critical current in the other arm (the bias arm) is modulated.
The current in the sense arm can thus be determined by measuring the critical
current of the bias arm. The dependence of the bias critical current on the
sense current is possible because current crowding causes the sense current to
interact locally with the bias arm. Measurement of the critical current in the
bias arm does not break the superconducting state of the sense arm or of the
bottom leg, and thus the signal to be sensed is fully restored after the
measurement process. This device thus has potential for broad applicability
across superconducting technologies and materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04497</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duffty</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>Zack</forenames></author></authors><title>A priority based noise tolerant jet framework and algorithm</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pgs, 4 figs, corrected typo in Eq. 2.3</comments><report-no>IIT-CAPP-16-03</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new framework for jet definitions called p-jets that matches
the computational speed of the currently used anti-k_T jet algorithm, but
avoids combining much of the energy from background pileup events with signal
jets. As a first illustration of the p-jet framework, we compare the
effectiveness of a p-jet algorithm to the anti-k_T algorithm in reconstructing
low energy jets from resonant Z boson production and 50 pileup events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04504</id><created>2016-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chauvin</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Miranda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawano</keyname><forenames>Takafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiss</keyname><forenames>M&#xf3;zsi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kole</keyname><forenames>Merlin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhalev</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Hiromitsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimising a balloon-borne polarimeter in the hard X-ray domain: from
  the PoGOLite Pathfinder to PoGO+</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2016.06.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PoGOLite is a balloon-borne hard X-ray polarimeter dedicated to the study of
point sources. Compton scattered events are registered using an array of
plastic scintillator units to determine the polarisation of incident X-rays in
the energy range 20 - 240 keV. In 2013, a near circumpolar balloon flight of 14
days duration was completed after launch from Esrange, Sweden, resulting in a
measurement of the linear polarisation of the Crab emission. Building on the
experience gained from this Pathfinder flight, the polarimeter is being
modified to improve performance for a second flight in 2016. Such
optimisations, based on Geant4 Monte Carlo simulations, take into account the
source characteristics, the instrument response and the background environment
which is dominated by atmospheric neutrons. This paper describes the
optimisation of the polarimeter and details the associated increase in
performance. The resulting design, PoGO+, is expected to improve the Minimum
Detectable Polarisation (MDP) for the Crab from 19.8% to 11.1% for a 5 day
flight. Assuming the same Crab polarisation fraction as measured during the
2013 flight, this improvement in MDP will allow a 5{\sigma} constrained result.
It will also allow the study of the nebula emission only (Crab off-pulse) and
Cygnus X-1 if in the hard state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04707</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schweitzer</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanumyan</keyname><forenames>Vahan</forenames></author></authors><title>A conceptual approach to model co-evolution of urban structures</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.MA nlin.AO</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures, for a special issue dedicated to Frei Otto</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Space Structures 2016, Vol. 31(1) 43-51</journal-ref><doi>10.1177/0266351116642075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Urban structures encompass settlements, characterized by the spatial
distribution of built-up areas, but also transportation structures, to connect
these built-up areas. These two structures are very different in their origin
and function, fulfilling complementary needs: (i) to access space, and (ii) to
occupy space. Their evolution cannot be understood by looking at the dynamics
of urban aggregations and transportation systems separately. Instead, existing
built-up areas feed back on the further development of transportation
structures, and the availability of the latter feeds back on the future growth
of urban aggregations. To model this co-evolution, we propose an agent-based
approach that builds on existing agent-based models for the evolution of trail
systems and of urban settlements. The key element in these separate approaches
is a generalized communication of agents by means of an adaptive landscape.
This landscape is only generated by the agents, but once it exists, it feeds
back on their further actions. The emerging trail system or urban aggregation
results as a self-organized structure from these collective interactions. In
our co-evolutionary approach, we couple these two separate models by means of
meta-agents that represent humans with their different demands for housing and
mobility. We characterize our approach as a statistical ensemble approach,
which allows to capture the potential of urban evolution in a bottom-up manner,
but can be validated against empirical observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05016</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banfield</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andernach</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapinska</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudnick</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardcastle</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotter</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaughan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heywood</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wing</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>O. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matorny</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terentev</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez-Sanchez</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seymour</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shabala</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willett</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radio Galaxy Zoo: discovery of a poor cluster through a giant wide-angle
  tail radio galaxy</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 460, 2376 - 2384 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have discovered a previously unreported poor cluster of galaxies (RGZ-CL
J0823.2+0333) through an unusual giant wide-angle tail radio galaxy found in
the Radio Galaxy Zoo project. We obtained a spectroscopic redshift of
$z=0.0897$ for the E0-type host galaxy, 2MASX J08231289+0333016, leading to
M$_r = -22.6$ and a $1.4\,$GHz radio luminosity density of $L_{\rm 1.4} =
5.5\times10^{24}$ W Hz$^{-1}$. These radio and optical luminosities are typical
for wide-angle tailed radio galaxies near the borderline between Fanaroff-Riley
(FR) classes I and II. The projected largest angular size of $\approx8\,$arcmin
corresponds to $800\,$kpc and the full length of the source along the curved
jets/trails is $1.1\,$Mpc in projection. X-ray data from the XMM-Newton archive
yield an upper limit on the X-ray luminosity of the thermal emission
surrounding RGZ J082312.9+033301,at $1.2-2.6\times10^{43}$ erg s$^{-1}$ for
assumed intra-cluster medium temperatures of $1.0-5.0\,$keV. Our analysis of
the environment surrounding RGZ J082312.9+033301 indicates that RGZ
J082312.9+033301 lies within a poor cluster. The observed radio morphology
suggests that (a) the host galaxy is moving at a significant velocity with
respect to an ambient medium like that of at least a poor cluster, and that (b)
the source may have had two ignition events of the active galactic nucleus with
$10^7\,$yrs in between. This reinforces the idea that an association between
RGZ J082312.9+033301, and the newly discovered poor cluster exists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05069</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asanuma</keyname><forenames>Nobu-Hiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Misunderstanding that the Effective Action is Convex under Broken
  Symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The widespread belief that the effective action is convex and has a flat
bottom under broken global symmetry is shown to be wrong. We show spontaneous
symmetry breaking necessarily accompanies non-convexity in the effective action
for quantum field theory, or in the free energy for statistical mechanics, and
clarify the magnitude of non-convexity. For quantum field theory, it is also
proved that translational invariance breaks spontaneously when the system is in
the non-convex region, and that different vacua of spontaneously broken
symmetry cannot be superposed.
  As applications of non-convexity, we study the first-order phase transition
which happens at the zero field limit of spontaneously broken symmetry, and we
propose a simple model of phase coexistence which obeys the Born rule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05136</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abdelsadek</keyname><forenames>Youcef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelghoum</keyname><forenames>Kamel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>Francine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kacem</keyname><forenames>Imed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otjacques</keyname><forenames>Beno&#xee;t</forenames></author></authors><title>Triangles as basis to detect communities: an application to Twitter's
  network</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nowadays, the interest given by the scientific community to the investigation
of the data generated by social networks is increasing as much as the
exponential increasing of social network data. The data structure complexity is
one among the snags, which slowdown their understanding. On the other hand,
community detection in social networks helps the analyzers to reveal the
structure and the underlying semantic within communities. In this paper we
propose an interactive visualization approach relying on our application
NLCOMS, which uses synchronous and related views for graph and community
visualization. Additionally, we present our algorithm for community detection
in networks. A computation study is conducted on instances generated with the
LFR [9]-[10] benchmark. Finally, in order to assess our approach on real-world
data, we consider the data of the ANR-Info-RSN project. The latter addresses
community detection in Twitter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05368</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Morandi</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum atomistic approach for interacting spins</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phenomenological Landau theory of the spin precession has been used to
reproduce the out-of-equilibrium properties of many magnetic systems. However,
such an approach suffers from some serious limitations. The main reason is that
the spin and the angular momentum of the atoms are described by the classical
theory of the angular momentum. We derive a discrete model that extends the
Landau theory to the quantum mechanical framework. Our approach is based on the
application of the quantification procedure to the classical hamiltonian of an
array of interacting spins. The connection with the classical dynamics is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05370</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>En</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zuwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arora</keyname><forenames>Hitesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Tsai-wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayanoor-Vitikkate</keyname><forenames>Vipin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spoddig</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bedau</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grobis</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurney</keyname><forenames>Bruce A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>Thomas R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terris</keyname><forenames>Bruce</forenames></author></authors><title>Template-Assisted Direct Growth of 1Td/in$^2$ Bit Patterned Media</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano Letters (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b02345</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method for growing bit patterned magnetic recording media using
directed growth of sputtered granular perpendicular magnetic recording media.
The grain nucleation is templated using an epitaxial seed layer which contains
Pt pillars separated by amorphous metal oxide. The scheme enables the creation
of both templated data and servo regions suitable for high density hard disk
drive operation. We illustrate the importance of using a process that is both
topographically and chemically driven to achieve high quality media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05371</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Ronald L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirtain</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sterling</keyname><forenames>Alphonse C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Babcock Redux: An Ammendment of Babcock's Schematic of the Sun's
  Magnetic Cycle</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>24 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We amend Babcock's original scenario for the global dynamo process that
sustains the Sun's 22-year magnetic cycle. The amended scenario fits
post-Babcock observed features of the magnetic activity cycle and convection
zone, and is based on ideas of Spruit and Roberts (1983) about magnetic flux
tubes in the convection zone. A sequence of four schematic cartoons lays out
the proposed evolution of the global configuration of the magnetic field above,
in, and at the bottom of the convection zone through sunspot Cycle 23 and into
Cycle 24. Three key elements of the amended scenario are: (1) as the net
following-polarity field from the sunspot-region omega-loop fields of an
ongoing sunspot cycle is swept poleward to cancel and replace the
opposite-polarity polar-cap field from the previous sunspot cycle, it remains
connected to the ongoing sunspot cycle's toroidal source-field band at the
bottom of the convection zone; (2) topological pumping by the convection zone's
free convection keeps the horizontal extent of the poleward-migrating
following-polarity field pushed to the bottom, forcing it to gradually cancel
and replace old horizontal field below it that connects the ongoing-cycle
source-field band to the previous-cycle polar-cap field; (3) in each polar
hemisphere, by continually shearing the poloidal component of the settling new
horizontal field, the latitudinal differential rotation low in the convection
zone generates the next-cycle source-field band poleward of the ongoing-cycle
band. The amended scenario is a more-plausible version of Babcock's scenario,
and its viability can be explored by appropriate kinematic flux-transport
solar-dynamo simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05373</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuanzhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Ruhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Folding and Stabilization of Native-Sequence-Reversed Proteins</title><categories>q-bio.BM cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep25138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Though the problem of sequence-reversed protein folding is largely
unexplored, one might speculate that reversed native protein sequences should
be significantly more foldable than purely random heteropolymer sequences. In
this article, we investigate how the reverse-sequences of native proteins might
fold by examining a series of small proteins of increasing structural
complexity ({\alpha}-helix, \b{eta}-hairpin, {\alpha}-helix bundle, and
{\alpha}/\b{eta}-protein). Employing a tandem protein structure prediction
algorithmic and molecular dynamics simulation approach, we find that the
ability of reverse sequences to adopt native-like folds is strongly in
influenced by protein size and the flexibility of the native hydrophobic core.
For \b{eta}-hairpins with reverse-sequences that fail to fold, we employ a
simple mutational strategy for guiding stable hairpin formation that involves
the insertion of amino acids into the \b{eta}-turn region. This systematic look
at reverse sequence duality sheds new light on the problem of protein
sequence-structure mapping and may serve to inspire new protein design and
protein structure prediction protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05375</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05375</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Crossover between fast and slow excitation of magnetization by spin
  torque</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Express 9, 073003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/APEX.9.073003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A crossover between two mechanisms destabilizing the magnetization in
equilibrium by the spin transfer effect is found in a ferromagnetic multilayer
consisting of an in-plane magnetized free layer and a perpendicularly
magnetized pinned layer, where an in-plane magnetic field is applied, and
electric current flows from the pinned to the free layer. A fast transition
from the in-plane to the out-of-plane state occurs in the low-field region,
whereas a slow transition with small-amplitude oscillation becomes dominant in
the high-field region. On the other hand, only the fast transition mechanism
appears for the opposite current direction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05400</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Comin</keyname><forenames>Cesar H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peron</keyname><forenames>Thomas K. DM.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Filipi N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amancio</keyname><forenames>Diego R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Francisco A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Luciano da F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex systems: features, similarity and connectivity</title><categories>physics.soc-ph physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The increasing interest in complex networks research has been a consequence
of several intrinsic features of this area, such as the generality of the
approach to represent and model virtually any discrete system, and the
incorporation of concepts and methods deriving from many areas, from
statistical physics to sociology, which are often used in an independent way.
Yet, for this same reason, it would be desirable to integrate these various
aspects into a more coherent and organic framework, which would imply in
several benefits normally allowed by the systematization in science, including
the identification of new types of problems and the cross-fertilization between
fields. More specifically, the identification of the main areas to which the
concepts frequently used in complex networks can be applied paves the way to
adopting and applying a larger set of concepts and methods deriving from those
respective areas. Among the several areas that have been used in complex
networks research, pattern recognition, optimization, linear algebra, and time
series analysis seem to play a more basic and recurrent role. In the present
manuscript, we propose a systematic way to integrate the concepts from these
diverse areas regarding complex networks research. In order to do so, we start
by grouping the multidisciplinary concepts into three main groups, namely
features, similarity, and network connectivity. Then we show that several of
the analysis and modeling approaches to complex networks can be thought as a
composition of maps between these three groups, with emphasis on nine main
types of mappings, which are presented and illustrated. Such a systematization
of principles and approaches also provides an opportunity to review some of the
most closely related works in the literature, which is also developed in this
article.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05401</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Acevedo</keyname><forenames>W. Rom&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lecourt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;ders</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Marlasca</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Granell</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golmar</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Manganite-based three level memristive devices with self-healing
  capability</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures, to appear in Phys. Lett. A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on non-volatile memory devices based on multifunctional manganites.
The electric field induced resistive switching of
Ti/$La_{1/3}$$Ca_{2/3}$Mn$O_3$/n-Si devices is explored using different
measurement protocols. We show that using current as the electrical stimulus
(instead of standard voltage-controlled protocols) improves the electrical
performance of our devices and unveils an intermediate resistance state. We
observe three discrete resistance levels (low, intermediate and high), which
can be set either by the application of current-voltage ramps or by means of
single pulses. These states exhibit retention and endurance capabilities
exceeding $10^4$ s and 70 cycles, respectively. We rationalize our experimental
observations by proposing a mixed scenario were a metallic filament and a
Si$O_x$ layer coexist, accounting for the observed resistive switching. Overall
electrode area dependence and temperature dependent resistance measurements
support our scenario. After device failure takes place, the system can be
turned functional again by heating up to low temperature (120 C), a feature
that could be exploited for the design of memristive devices with self-healing
functionality. These results give insight into the existence of multiple
resistive switching mechanisms in manganite-based memristive systems and
provide strategies for controlling them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05402</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xingxing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shao-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xutao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Ruonan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tianxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Interference-aided spectrum fitting method for accurately film thickness
  determination</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new approach was proposed to accurately determine the thickness of film,
especially for ultra-thin film, through spectrum fitting with the assistance of
interference layer. The determination limit can reach even less than 1 nm. Its
accuracy is far better than traditional methods. This determination method is
verified by experiments and the determination limit is at least 3.5 nm compared
with the results of AFM. Furthermore, double-interference-aided spectra fitting
method is proposed to reduce the requirements of determination instruments,
which allow one to determine the film thickness with a low precision common
spectrometer and largely lower the cost. It is a very high precision
determination method for on-site and in-situ applications, especially for
ultra-thin films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05408</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Liming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective information spreading based on local information in correlated
  networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using network-based information to facilitate information spreading is an
essential task for spreading dynamics in complex networks, which will benefit
the promotion of technical innovations, healthy behaviors, new products, etc.
Focusing on degree correlated networks, we propose a preferential contact
strategy based on the local network structure and local informed density to
promote the information spreading. During the spreading process, an informed
node will preferentially select a contact target among its neighbors, basing on
their degrees or local informed densities. By extensively implementing
numerical simulations in synthetic and empirical networks, we find that when
only consider the local structure information, the convergence time of
information spreading will be remarkably reduced if low-degree neighbors are
favored as contact targets. Meanwhile, the minimum convergence time depends
non-monotonically on degree-degree correlation, and moderate correlation
coefficients result in most efficient information spreading. Incorporating the
informed density information into contact strategy, the convergence time of
information spreading can be further reduced. Finally, we show that by using
local informed density is more effective as compared with the global case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05428</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jingwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yunxin</forenames></author></authors><title>How does a protein reach its binding locus: sliding along DNA chain or
  not?</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.SC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In gene expression, various kinds of proteins need to bind to specific locus
of DNA. It is still not clear how these proteins find their target locus. In
this study, the mean first-passage time (FPT) of protein binding to its target
locus on DNA chain is discussed by a chain-space coupled model. Our results
show that the 1-dimensional diffusion constant has a critical value, with which
the mean time spent by a protein to find its target locus is almost independent
of the binding rate of protein to DNA chain and the detachment rate from DNA
chain. Which implies that, the frequency of protein binding to DNA and the
sliding time on DNA chain have little influence on the search efficiency, and
therefore whether or not the 1-dimensional sliding on DNA chain increases the
search efficiency depends on the 1-dimensional diffusion constant of the
protein on DNA chain. This study also finds that only protein bindings to DNA
loci which are close to the target locus help to increase the search
efficiency, while bindings to those loci which are far from the target locus
might delay the target binding process. As expected, the mean FPT increases
with the distance between the initial position of protein in cell space and its
target locus on DNA chain. The direct binding probability, which can be
regarded as one index to describe if the 1-dimensional sliding along DNA chain
is helpful to increase the search efficiency is calculated. Our results show
that the influence of 1-dimensional sliding along DNA chain on the search
process depends on both diffusion constants of protein in cell space and on the
1-dimensional DNA chain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05442</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Grigoriev</keyname><forenames>Pavel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lejay</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadj-Azzem</keyname><forenames>Abdellali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balay</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leynaud</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zverev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monceau</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Bilayer splitting versus Fermi-surface warping as an origin of slow
  oscillations of in-plane magnetoresistance in rare-earth tritellurides</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1504.06064</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 89, 151 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70159-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Slow oscillations (SlO) of the in-plane magnetoresistance with a frequency
less than 4 T are observed in the rare-earth tritellurides and proposed as an
effective tool to explore the electronic structure in various strongly
anisotropic quasi-two-dimensional compounds. Contrary to the usual
Shubnikov-de-Haas oscillations, SlO originate not from small Fermi-surface
pockets, but from the entanglement of close frequencies due to a finite
interlayer transfer integral, either between the two Te planes forming a
bilayer or between two adjacent bilayers. From the observed angular dependence
of the frequency and the phase of SlO we argue that they originate from the
bilayer splitting rather than from the Fermi-surface warping. The SlO frequency
gives the value of the interlayer transfer integral $\approx 1$ meV for
TbTe$_3$ and GdTe$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05450</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Shijun</forenames></author></authors><title>A Simple Method to Make the Wang-Landau Sampling Converge</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a histogram maintained throughout the Wang-Landau (WL) sampling
for the energy entries visited during the simulation could be used to make the
simulated density of states (DOS) converge. The method is easy to be
implemented to the WL sampling with no extra computational cost and bears the
advantages of both the WL method and the multicanonical method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05482</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Elias Torres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karkera</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Gareth Francis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craciun</keyname><forenames>Monica Felicia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russo</keyname><forenames>Saverio</forenames></author></authors><title>Homogeneously bright, flexible and foldable lighting devices with
  functionalised graphene electrodes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Published on ACS Materials and Interfaces</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Alternating current electroluminescent technology allows the fabrication of
large area, flat and flexible lights. Presently the maximum size of a
continuous panel is limited by the high resistivity of available transparent
electrode materials causing a visible gradient of brightness. Here, we
demonstrate that the use of the best known transparent conductor
FeCl$_{3}$-intercalated few-layer graphene boosts the brightness of
electroluminescent devices by 49$\%$ compared to pristine graphene. Intensity
gradients observed for high aspect ratio devices are undetectable when using
these highly conductive electrodes. Flat lights on polymer substrates are found
to be resilient to repeated and flexural strains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05517</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>Kristin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krellner</keyname><forenames>Cornelius</forenames></author></authors><title>Crystal growth by Bridgman and Czochralski method of the ferromagnetic
  quantum critical material YbNi$_4$P$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Crystal Growth (2016), pp. 129-133</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2016.05.042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The tetragonal YbNi$_4$P$_2$ is one of the rare examples of compounds that
allow the investigation of a ferromagnetic quantum critical point. We report in
detail on two different methods which have been used to grow YbNi$_4$P$_2$
single crystals from a self-flux. The first, a modified Bridgman method, using
a closed crucible system yields needle-shaped single crystals oriented along
the $[001]$-direction. The second method, the Czochralski growth from a
levitating melt, yields large single crystals which can be cut in any desired
orientation. With this crucible-free method, samples without flux inclusions
and a resistivity ratio at 1.8 K of RR$_{1.8\rm K}= 17$ have been grown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05533</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Parganlija</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames><affiliation>Vienna UT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Giacosa</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames><affiliation>Kielce U</affiliation></author></authors><title>Excited Scalar Mesons and the Search for Glueballs</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure. Prepared for Proceedings of the 12th International
  Conference on Low Energy Antiproton Physics (LEAP), Kanazawa/Japan, March
  6-11, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the importance of mixing between glueballs -- bound states of
gluons -- and excited $\bar{q}q$ states for the glueball search. A preliminary
study of the excited states in the Extended Linear Sigma Model (eLSM) suggests
their masses in the scalar channel to be in the vicinity of the scalar-glueball
mass found in Lattice QCD. This could have implications for future glueball
searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05534</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Meroni</keyname><forenames>Aurora</forenames></author></authors><title>A Radiatively induced Elementary Goldstone Higgs in SU(4)/Sp(4)</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages. To appear in the proceedings of the 51st Rencontres de
  Moriond EW 2016, 12-19 March 2016 in La Thuile, Italy. Based on
  arXiv:1507.06666</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a $SU(4)\rightarrow Sp(4)$ pattern of chiral symmetry breaking, we
investigate the pseudo-Goldstone nature of the Higgs boson in an elementary
realisation that at the same time provides an ultraviolet completion. The
renormalizability of the model together with the perturbative corrections
determine dynamically the direction of vacuum of the theory and the
corresponding Higgs chiral symmetry breaking scale $ f \sim 14~$TeV. The Higgs
boson is radiatively generated and the scalar mass spectrum, together with a
second massive Higgs boson, lie in the multi-TeV range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05541</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Delagnes</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>What is the theoretical time precision achievable using a dCFD algorithm
  ?</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><report-no>IRFU 16-01</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The time precision achievable using standard analog methods is well known.
Several expressions for timing methods using digitized signals have been
recently proposed in workshops, conferences or training courses. Most of them
are only partially exact. This paper presents a comprehensive calculation of
the timing precision for algorithms using digital treatment of digitized signal
to mimic analog discriminator-based methods. The results of these calculations
are discussed for various cases of correlation between samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05559</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Donghia</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Mu2e Calorimeter</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Mu2e experiment at Fermilab</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Submitted to Nuovo Cimento</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Mu2e experiment searches for the neutrino-less muon to electron
conversion in the field of a nucleus, which is a charged lepton flavor
violating process. The goal of the experiment is to reach a single event
sensitivity of 2.8 x 10^{-17}, setting an upper limit on the muon conversion
rate at 6.7 x 10^{-17}. This corresponds to a four order of magnitude
improvement with respect to the existing limits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05605</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakin</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction of axions with relativistic spinning particles</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>JPCS 718 (2016) 042047</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/718/4/042047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a covariant phenomenological model, which describes an
interaction between a pseudoscalar (axion) field and massive spinning
particles. The model extends the Bagrmann-Michel-Telegdy approach in
application to the axion electrodynamics. We present some exact solutions and
discuss them in the context of experimental tests of the model and axion
detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05618</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chulaevsky</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Density of States under non-local interactions II. Simplified
  polynomially screened interactions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following [5], we analyze regularity properties of single-site probability
distributions of the random potential and of the Integrated Density of States
(IDS) in the Anderson models with infinite-range interactions. In the present
work, we study in detail a class of polynomially decaying interaction
potentials of rather artificial (piecewise-constant) form, and give a complete
proof of infinite smoothness of the IDS in an arbitrarily large finite domain
subject to the fluctuations of the entire, infinite random environment. A
variant of this result, based as in [5] on the harmonic analysis of probability
measures, results in a proof of spectral and dynamical Anderson localization in
the considered models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05623</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Livanas</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigrist</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varelogiannis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Alternative paths to realize Majorana Fermions in
  Superconductor-Ferromagnet Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental obstacle for achieving quantum computation is local
decoherence. One way to circumvent this problem rests on the concepts of
topological quantum computation using non-local information storage, for
example on pairs of Majorana fermions (MFs). The arguably most promising way to
generate MFs relies at present on spin-triplet p-wave states of superconductors
(SC), which are not abundant in nature, unfortunately. Thus, proposals for
their engineering in devices, usually via proximity effect from a conventional
SC into materials with strong spinorbit coupling (SOC), are intensively
investigated nowadays. Here we take an alternative path, exploiting the
different connections between fields based on a quartet coupling rule for
fields introduced by one of us, we demonstrate that, for instance, coexisting
Zeeman field with a charge current would provide the conditions to induce
p-wave pairing in the presence of singlet superconductivity. This opens new
avenues for the engineering of robust MFs in various, not necessarily
(quasi-)one-dimensional, superconductor-ferromagnet heterostructures, including
such motivated by recent pioneering experiments that report MFs, in particular,
without the need of any exotic materials with special structures of intrinsic
SOC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05637</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Lu-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Xian-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-classical photon correlation in a two-dimensional photonic lattice</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 24, 12607-12616 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.012607</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum interference and quantum correlation, as two main features of quantum
optics, play an essential role in quantum information applications, such as
multi-particle quantum walk and boson sampling. While many experimental
demonstrations have been done in one-dimensional waveguide arrays, it remains
unexplored in higher dimensions due to tight requirement of manipulating and
detecting photons in large-scale. Here, we experimentally observe non-classical
correlation of two identical photons in a fully coupled two-dimensional
structure, i.e. photonic lattice manufactured by three-dimensional femtosecond
laser writing. Photon interference consists of 36 Hong-Ou-Mandel interference
and 9 bunching. The overlap between measured and simulated distribution is up
to $0.890\pm0.001$. Clear photon correlation is observed in the two-dimensional
photonic lattice. Combining with controllably engineered disorder, our results
open new perspectives towards large-scale implementation of quantum simulation
on integrated photonic chips.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0112429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0112429</id><created>2001-12-18</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kley</keyname><forenames>Wilhelm</forenames></author></authors><title>Nested-grid calculations of disk-planet interaction</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 55 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astron.Astrophys. 385 (2002) 647-670</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361:20020173</doi><abstract>  We study the evolution of embedded protoplanets in a protostellar disk using
very high resolution nested-grid computations. This method allows us to perform
global simulations of planets orbiting in disks and, at the same time, to
resolve in detail the dynamics of the flow inside the Roche lobe of the planet.
The primary interest of this work lies in the analysis of the gravitational
torque balance acting on the planet. For this purpose we study planets of
different masses, ranging from one Earth-mass up to one Jupiter-mass, assuming
typical parameters of the protostellar disk. The high resolution of the method
allows a precise determination of the mass flow onto the planet and the
resulting torques. The obtained migration time scales are in the range from few
times 10^4 years, for intermediate mass planets, to 10^6 years, for very low
and high mass planets. Typical growth time scales depend strongly on the
planetary mass, ranging from a few hundred years, in the case of Earth-type
planets, to several ten thousand years, in the case of Jupiter-type planets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0308055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0308055</id><created>2003-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kley</keyname><forenames>Willy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbital Migration and Mass Accretion of Protoplanets in 3D Global
  Computations with Nested Grids</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 12 figures. To appear in The Astrophysical Journal vol.586
  (March 20, 2003 issue)</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 586 (2003) 540-561</journal-ref><doi>10.1086/367555</doi><abstract>  We investigate the evolution of protoplanets with different masses embedded
in an accretion disk, via global fully three-dimensional hydrodynamical
simulations. We consider a range of planetary masses extending from one and a
half Earth's masses up to one Jupiter's mass, and we take into account
physically realistic gravitational potentials of forming planets. In order to
calculate accurately the gravitational torques exerted by disk material and to
investigate the accretion process onto the planet, the flow dynamics has to be
thoroughly resolved on long as well as short length scales. We achieve this
strict resolution requirement by applying a nested-grid refinement technique
which allows to greatly enhance the local resolution. Our results from
altogether 51 simulations show that for large planetary masses, approximately
above a tenth of the Jupiter's mass, migration rates are relatively constant,
as expected in type II migration regime and in good agreement with previous
two-dimensional calculations. In a range between seven and fifteen Earth's
masses, we find a dependency of the migration speed on the planetary mass that
yields time scales considerably longer than those predicted by linear
analytical theories. This property may be important in determining the overall
orbital evolution of protoplanets. The growth time scale is minimum around
twenty Earth-masses, but it rapidly increases for both smaller and larger mass
values. Significant differences between two- and three-dimensional calculations
are found in particular for objects with masses smaller than ten Earth-masses.
We also derive an analytical approximation for the numerically computed mass
growth rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0309236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0309236</id><created>2003-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kley</keyname><forenames>Willy</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermo-Hydrodynamics of Circumstellar Disks with High-mass Planets</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>31 pages 26 figures. To appear in The Astrophysical Journal vol.599
  (December 10, 2003 issue)</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 599 (2003) 548-576</journal-ref><doi>10.1086/379224</doi><abstract>  With a series of numerical simulations, we analyze the thermo-hydrodynamical
evolution of circumstellar disks containing Jupiter-size protoplanets. In the
framework of the two-dimensional approximation, we consider an energy equation
that includes viscous heating and radiative effects in a simplified, yet
consistent form. Multiple nested grids are used in order to study both global
and local features around the planet. By means of different viscosity
prescriptions, we investigate various temperature regimes. A planetary mass
range from 0.1 to 1 Mj is examined. Computations show that gap formation is a
general property which affects density, pressure, temperature, optical
thickness, and radiated flux distributions. However, it remains a prominent
feature only when the kinematic viscosity is on the order of 10^(15) cm^2/s or
lower. Around accreting planets, a circumplanetary disk forms that has a
surface density profile decaying exponentially with the distance and whose mass
is 5-6 orders of magnitudes smaller than Jupiter's mass. Circumplanetary disk
temperature profiles decline roughly as the inverse of the distance from the
planet. Temperatures range from some 10 to ~1000 K. Planetary accretion and
migration rates depend on the viscosity regime, with discrepancies within an
order of magnitude. Estimates of growth and migration time scales inferred by
these models are on the same orders of magnitude as those previously obtained
with locally isothermal simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0512292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-06-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0512292</id><created>2005-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lubow</keyname><forenames>Steve H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas Flow Across Gaps in Protoplanetary Disks</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. To appear in The Astrophysical Journal</comments><report-no>STScI Eprint #1707</report-no><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 641 (2006) 526-533</journal-ref><doi>10.1086/500356</doi><abstract>  We analyze the gas accretion flow through a planet-produced gap in a
protoplanetary disk. We adopt the alpha disk model and ignore effects of
planetary migration. We develop a semi-analytic, one-dimensional model that
accounts for the effects of the planet as a mass sink and also carry out
two-dimensional hydrodynamical simulations of a planet embedded in a disk. The
predictions of the mass flow rate through the gap based on the semi-analytic
model generally agree with the hydrodynamical simulations at the 25% level.
Through these models, we are able to explore steady state disk structures and
over large spatial ranges. The presence of an accreting Jupiter-mass planet
significantly lowers the density of the disk within a region of several times
the planet's orbital radius. The mass flow rate across the gap (and onto the
central star) is typically 10% to 25% of the mass accretion rate outside the
orbit of the planet, for planet-to-star mass ratios that range from 5e-5 to
1e-3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
