<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:38:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-04-14" from="2017-04-14" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0802.3194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0802.3194</id><created>2008-02-21</created><updated>2008-03-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>McKagan</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkins</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieman</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Deeper Look at Student Learning of Quantum Mechanics: the Case of
  Tunneling</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>v2, v3 updated with more detailed analysis of data and discussion;
  submitted to Phys. Rev. ST: PER</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Special Topics: PER 4, 020103 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevSTPER.4.020103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a large-scale study of student learning of quantum tunneling in
4 traditional and 4 transformed modern physics courses. In the transformed
courses, which were designed to address student difficulties found in previous
research, students still struggle with many of the same issues found in other
courses. However, the reasons for these difficulties are more subtle, and many
new issues are brought to the surface. By explicitly addressing how to build
models of wave functions and energy and how to relate these models to real
physical systems, we have opened up a floodgate of deep and difficult questions
as students struggle to make sense of these models. We conclude that the
difficulties found in previous research are the tip of the iceberg, and the
real issue at the heart of student difficulties in learning quantum tunneling
is the struggle to build the complex models that are implicit in experts'
understanding but often not explicitly addressed in instruction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1006.4069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1006.4069</id><created>2010-06-21</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Ranjeev</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bora</keyname><forenames>Archana</forenames><affiliation>Gauhati Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dewangan</keyname><forenames>Gulab</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Estimation of error on the cross-correlation, phase and time lag between
  evenly sampled light curves</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Temporal analysis of radiation from Astrophysical sources like Active
Galactic Nuclei, X-ray Binaries and Gamma-ray bursts provide information on the
geometry and sizes of the emitting regions. Establishing that two light-curves
in different energy bands are correlated and measuring the phase and time-lag
between them is an important and frequently used temporal diagnostic. In the
present work, expressions to estimate the errors on the cross-correlation,
phase and time-lag between two light-curves are presented and the same have
been verified using simulations. Earlier estimates depended upon numerically
expensive simulations or on dividing the light-curves in large number of
segments to find the variance. The estimates presented here allow for analysis
of light-curves with relatively small (~1000) number of points, as well as to
obtain information on the longest time-scales available. The error estimation
is verified using simulations of light-curves derived from both white and 1/f
stochastic processes with measurement errors. As a demonstration, we apply this
technique to the XMM-Newton light-curves of the Active Galactic Nucleus, Akn
564.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.3627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.3627</id><created>2013-05-15</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borodin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorin</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author></authors><title>General beta Jacobi corners process and the Gaussian Free Field</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>59 pages, 4 figures. v4: corrected inaccuracy in the definition of
  the pullback of the GFF</comments><journal-ref>Communications on Pure and Applied Mathematics, 68, no. 10 (2015),
  1774-1844</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the two-dimensional Gaussian Free Field describes the
asymptotics of global fluctuations of a multilevel extension of the general
beta Jacobi random matrix ensembles. Our approach is based on the connection of
the Jacobi ensembles to a degeneration of the Macdonald processes that
parallels the degeneration of the Macdonald polynomials to to the Heckman-Opdam
hypergeometric functions (of type A). We also discuss the beta goes to infinity
limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.1292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.1292</id><created>2013-07-04</created><updated>2016-02-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Verbiest</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oosterkamp</keyname><forenames>T. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rost</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Friction as Contrast Mechanism in Heterodyne Force Microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall physics.ins-det</categories><comments>7 pages main paper + 11 pages supplementary materials</comments><msc-class>65Z05</msc-class><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 28 (2017) 085704</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa53f2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nondestructive imaging of subsurface structures on the nanometer scale
has been a long-standing desire in both science and industry. A few impressive
images were published so far that demonstrate the general feasibility by
combining ultrasound with an Atomic Force Microscope. From different excitation
schemes, Heterodyne Force Microscopy seems to be the most promising candidate
delivering the highest contrast and resolution. However, the physical contrast
mechanism is unknown, thereby preventing any quantitative analysis of samples.
Here we show that friction at material boundaries within the sample is
responsible for the contrast formation. This result is obtained by performing a
full quantitative analysis, in which we compare our experimentally observed
contrasts with simulations and calculations. Surprisingly, we can rule out all
other generally believed responsible mechanisms, like Rayleigh scattering,
sample (visco)elasticity, damping of the ultrasonic tip motion, and ultrasound
attenuation. Our analytical description paves the way for quantitative
SubSurface-AFM imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1615</id><created>2014-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Winn</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames><affiliation>the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Inclusive J/psi and psi(2S) production in p-Pb collisions at sqrt(s_NN)
  = 5.02 TeV with ALICE at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>To appear in the proceedings of Hard-Probes 2013, the 6th
  International Conference on Hard and Electromagnetic Probes of High-Energy
  Nuclear Collisions, Nov. 2013</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. A932 (2014) 472-477</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2014.09.062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the inclusive J/psi nuclear modification factor in p-Pb
collisions at sqrt(s_NN) = 5.02 TeV as a function of rapidity y and transverse
momentum p_T. The experimental coverage extends down to p_T = 0 GeV/c in the
three rapidity ranges accessible by ALICE (-4.46 &lt; y_cms &lt; -2.96, -1.37 &lt; y_cms
&lt; 0.46, 2.03 &lt; y_cms &lt; 3.53). The obtained results as a function of rapidity
are in agreement with theory predictions based only on shadowing or on coherent
energy loss. At forward and backward rapidity, the psi(2S) measurement
complements the J/psi results. The ratio between the psi(2S) and J/psi cross
section is significantly smaller in p-Pb than in pp collisions in both rapidity
regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.8002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.8002</id><created>2014-07-30</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunduri</keyname><forenames>Hari K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucietti</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Black hole non-uniqueness via spacetime topology in five dimensions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>24 pages. v2: minor additions, published version. v3: corrected
  physical quantities, results unaffected, differs from published version</comments><report-no>EMPG-14-13</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2014)082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The domain of outer communication of five-dimensional asymptotically flat
stationary spacetimes may possess non-trivial 2-cycles. We discuss how this may
lead to a gross violation of black hole uniqueness, beyond the existence of
black rings, even for solutions with two commuting rotational symmetries. We
illustrate this with a simple example in minimal supergravity; a four parameter
family of supersymmetric black hole solutions, with spherical horizon topology
and a 2-cycle in the exterior. We show there are black holes in this family
with identical conserved changes to the BMPV black hole, thereby demonstrating
black hole non-uniqueness in this context. We find a decoupling limit of this
family of black holes that yields spacetimes asymptotic to the near-horizon
geometry of a BMPV black hole which contain a black hole and an exterior
2-cycle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.5041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.5041</id><created>2014-09-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Spekkens</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-quantization: classical statistical theories with an epistemic
  restriction</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 15 figures, comments welcome</comments><doi>10.1007/978-94-017-7303-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A significant part of quantum theory can be obtained from a single innovation
relative to classical theories, namely, that there is a fundamental restriction
on the sorts of statistical distributions over physical states that can be
prepared. This is termed an &quot;epistemic restriction&quot; because it implies a
fundamental limit on the amount of knowledge that any observer can have about
the physical state of a classical system. This article provides an overview of
epistricted theories, that is, theories that start from a classical statistical
theory and apply an epistemic restriction. We consider both continuous and
discrete degrees of freedom, and show that a particular epistemic restriction
called classical complementarity provides the beginning of a unification of all
known epistricted theories. This restriction appeals to the symplectic
structure of the underlying classical theory and consequently can be applied to
an arbitrary classical degree of freedom. As such, it can be considered as a
kind of quasi-quantization scheme; &quot;quasi&quot; because it generally only yields a
theory describing a subset of the preparations, transformations and
measurements allowed in the full quantum theory for that degree of freedom, and
because in some cases, such as for binary variables, it yields a theory that is
a distortion of such a subset. Finally, we propose to classify quantum
phenomena as weakly or strongly nonclassical by whether or not they can arise
in an epistricted theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.5535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.5535</id><created>2014-12-17</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Broedel</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mafra</keyname><forenames>Carlos R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthes</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlotterer</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author></authors><title>Elliptic multiple zeta values and one-loop superstring amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th math.NT</categories><comments>39 pages, 1 figure, v2: minor corrections, published version, v3:
  minor corrections in eqs.(4.5) to (4.9), (4.31) and (4.36)</comments><report-no>AEI-2014-066, DAMTP-2014-95</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1507 (2015) 112</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2015)112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate iterated integrals on an elliptic curve, which are a natural
genus-one generalization of multiple polylogarithms. These iterated integrals
coincide with the multiple elliptic polylogarithms introduced by Brown and
Levin when constrained to the real line. At unit argument they reduce to an
elliptic analogue of multiple zeta values, whose network of relations we start
to explore. A simple and natural application of this framework are one-loop
scattering amplitudes in open superstring theory. In particular, elliptic
multiple zeta values are a suitable language to express their low energy limit.
Similar to the techniques available at tree-level, our formalism allows to
completely automatize the calculation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00774</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Camosso</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Logic and Geometric quantization</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><msc-class>03G12, 03G10, 81P10, 53D50</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Quantum Information Science , 2017, vol. 7, 35-42</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jqis.2017.71003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assume that M is a phase space and H an Hilbert space yielded by a
quantization scheme. In this paper we consider the set of all &quot;experimental
propositions&quot; of M and we look for a model of quantum logic in relation to the
quantization of the base manifold M. In particular we give a new interpretation
about previous results of the author in order to build an &quot;asymptotic quantum
probability space&quot; for the Hilbert lattice L(H).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04022</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rusconi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero-Isart</keyname><forenames>Oriol</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Rigid Rotor in the Quantum Regime: Theoretical Toolbox</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Typos found in the published version are corrected. 15 pages, 3
  figures and 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 054427 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.054427</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the quantum dynamics of a magnetic rigid rotor in the mesoscopic
scale where the Einstein-De Haas effect is predominant. In particular, we
consider a single-domain magnetic nanoparticle with uniaxial anisotropy in a
magnetic trap. Starting from the basic Hamiltonian of the system under the
macrospin approximation, we derive a bosonized Hamiltonian describing the
center-of-mass motion, the total angular momentum, and the macrospin degrees of
freedom of the particle treated as a rigid body. This bosonized Hamiltonian can
be approximated by a simple quadratic Hamiltonian that captures the rich
physics of a nanomagnet tightly confined in position, nearly not spinning, and
with its macrospin anti-aligned to the magnetic field. The theoretical tools
derived and used here can be applied to other quantum mechanical rigid rotors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09357</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jatuviriyapornchai</keyname><forenames>Watthanan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosskinsky</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Coarsening dynamics in condensing zero-range processes and size-biased
  birth death chains</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>In addition to some minor changes, Figure 7(a) and the text below
  have been adapted to correct a mistake in the published version, pointed out
  to us by C. Godreche</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49(18), 185005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/18/185005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zero-range processes with decreasing jump rates are well known to exhibit a
condensation transition under certain conditions on the jump rates, and the
dynamics of this transition continues to be a subject of current research
interest. Starting from homogeneous initial conditions, the time evolution of
the condensed phase exhibits an interesting coarsening phenomenon of mass
transport between cluster sites characterized by a power law. We revisit the
approach in [C. Godreche, J. Phys. A: Math. Gen., 36(23) 6313 (2003)] to derive
effective single site dynamics which form a non-linear birth death chain
describing the coarsening behaviour. We extend these results to a larger class
of parameter values, and introduce a size-biased version of the single site
process, which provides an effective tool to analyze the dynamics of the
condensed phase without finite size effects and is the main novelty of this
paper. Our results are based on a few heuristic assumptions and exact
computations, and are corroborated by detailed simulation data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06069</id><created>2015-12-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Rist&#xe8;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>Marcus P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryan</keyname><forenames>Colm A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cross</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolin</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambetta</keyname><forenames>Jay M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chow</keyname><forenames>Jerry M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Blake R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Demonstration of quantum advantage in machine learning</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, including 4 figures and methods. 7 supplementary figures, 1
  supplementary table</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 3, Article number: 16 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0017-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main promise of quantum computing is to efficiently solve certain
problems that are prohibitively expensive for a classical computer. Most
problems with a proven quantum advantage involve the repeated use of a black
box, or oracle, whose structure encodes the solution. One measure of the
algorithmic performance is the query complexity, i.e., the scaling of the
number of oracle calls needed to find the solution with a given probability.
Few-qubit demonstrations of quantum algorithms, such as Deutsch-Jozsa and
Grover, have been implemented across diverse physical systems such as nuclear
magnetic resonance, trapped ions, optical systems, and superconducting
circuits. However, at the small scale, these problems can already be solved
classically with a few oracle queries, and the attainable quantum advantage is
modest. Here we solve an oracle-based problem, known as learning parity with
noise, using a five-qubit superconducting processor. Running classical and
quantum algorithms on the same oracle, we observe a large gap in query count in
favor of quantum processing. We find that this gap grows by orders of magnitude
as a function of the error rates and the problem size. This result demonstrates
that, while complex fault-tolerant architectures will be required for universal
quantum computing, a quantum advantage already emerges in existing noisy
systems
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04030</id><created>2016-01-15</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bouchard</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Creutzig</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaconescu</keyname><forenames>Duiliu-Emanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doran</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quigley</keyname><forenames>Callum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheshmani</keyname><forenames>Artan</forenames></author></authors><title>Vertical D4-D2-D0 bound states on K3 fibrations and modularity</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>v2. 56 pages, some formulas corrected, modularity statement improved</comments><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 350 (2017), no. 3, 1069--1121</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2772-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An explicit formula is derived for the generating function of vertical
D4-D2-D0 bound states on smooth K3 fibered Calabi-Yau threefolds, generalizing
previous results of Gholampour and Sheshmani. It is also shown that this
formula satisfies strong modularity properties, as predicted by string theory.
This leads to a new construction of vector valued modular forms which exhibits
some of the features of a generalized Hecke transform.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00416</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forn-D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Ripoll</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peropadre</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurtalan</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orgiazzi</keyname><forenames>J. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belyansky</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupascu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrastrong coupling of a single artificial atom to an electromagnetic
  continuum in the nonperturbative regime</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures (main text), 11 figures (supplementary
  information). Updated title</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 13, 39 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3905</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of light-matter interaction has led to many fundamental discoveries
as well as numerous important technologies. Over the last decades, great
strides have been made in increasing the strength of this interaction at the
single-photon level, leading to a continual exploration of new physics and
applications. Recently, a major achievement has been the demonstration of the
so-called strong coupling regime, a key advancement enabling great progress in
quantum information science. Here, we demonstrate light-matter interaction over
an order of magnitude stronger than previously reported, reaching the
nonperturbative regime of ultrastrong coupling (USC). We achieve this using a
superconducting artificial atom tunably coupled to the electromagnetic
continuum of a one-dimensional waveguide. For the largest coupling, the
spontaneous emission rate of the atom exceeds its transition frequency. In this
USC regime, the description of atom and light as distinct entities breaks down,
and a new description in terms of hybrid states is required. Our results open
the door to a wealth of new physics and applications. Beyond light-matter
interaction itself, the tunability of our system makes it a promising tool to
study a number of important physical systems such as the well-known spin-boson
and Kondo models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05206</id><created>2016-03-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Teixeira</keyname><forenames>Rafael M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Wesley B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractal scattering of Gaussian solitons in directional couplers with
  logarithmic nonlinearities</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 380 (2016) 2738-2749</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.06.041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the interaction of Gaussian solitons in a dispersive
and nonlinear media with log-law nonlinearity. The model is described by the
coupled logarithmic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equations, which is a nonintegrable
system that allows the observation of a very rich scenario in the collision
patterns. By employing a variational approach and direct numerical simulations,
we observe a fractal-scattering phenomenon from the exit velocities of each
soliton as a function of the input velocities. Furthermore, we introduce a
linearization model to identify the position of the reflection/transmission
window that emerges within the chaotic region. This enable us the possibility
of controlling the scattering of solitons as well as the lifetime of bound
states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05960</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2017-03-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vagnozzi</keyname><forenames>Sunny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freese</keyname><forenames>Katherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zurbuchen</keyname><forenames>Thomas H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solar models in light of new high metallicity measurements from solar
  wind data</title><categories>astro-ph.SR hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys. J. 839 (2017) 55</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6931</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the impact of new metallicity measurements, from solar wind data, on
the solar model. The &quot;solar modelling problem&quot; refers to the persisting
discrepancy between helioseismological observations and predictions of solar
models computed implementing state-of-the-art photospheric abundances. We
critically reassess the problem, in particular considering the new set of
abundances of von Steiger \&amp; Zurbuchen 2016, determined through the \textit{in
situ} collection of solar wind samples from polar coronal holes. This new set
of abundances indicates a solar metallicity $Z_{\odot} \geq 0.0196 \pm 0.0014$,
significantly higher than the currently established value. The new values hint
at an abundance of volatile elements (i.e. C, N, O, Ne) close to previous
results of Grevesse \&amp; Sauval 1998, whereas the abundance of refractory
elements (i.e. Mg, Si, S, Fe) is considerably increased. Using the Linear Solar
Model formalism, we determine the variation of helioseismological observables
in response to the changes in elemental abundances, in order to explore the
consistency of these new measurements with constraints from helioseismology. We
find that, for observables that are particularly sensitive to the abundance of
volatile elements, in particular the radius of the convective zone boundary
(CZB) and the sound speed around the radius of CZB, improved agreement over
previous models is obtained. Conversely, the high abundance of refractories
correlates with a higher core temperature, resulting in an overproduction of
neutrinos and a huge increase in the surface Helium abundance. We conclude that
the &quot;solar modelling problem&quot; remains unsolved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03828</id><created>2016-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>Is classical flat Kasner spacetime flat in quantum gravity?</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures. Prepared for IJMPD special issue on Loop Quantum
  Cosmology</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys D, 25, 1642001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271816420013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum nature of classical flat Kasner spacetime is studied using effective
spacetime description in loop quantum cosmology. We find that even though the
spacetime curvature vanishes at the classical level, non-trivial quantum
gravitational effects can arise. For the standard loop quantization of
Bianchi-I spacetime, which uniquely yields universal bounds on expansion and
shear scalars and results in a generic resolution of strong singularities, we
find that a flat Kasner metric is not a physical solution of the effective
spacetime description, except in a limit. The lack of a flat Kasner metric at
the quantum level results from a novel feature of the loop quantum Bianchi-I
spacetime: quantum geometry induces non-vanishing spacetime curvature
components, making it not Ricci flat even when no matter is present. The
non-curvature singularity of the classical flat Kasner spacetime is avoided,
and the effective spacetime transits from a flat Kasner spacetime in asymptotic
future, to a Minkowski spacetime in asymptotic past. Interestingly, for an
alternate loop quantization which does not share some of the fine features of
the standard quantization, flat Kasner spacetime with expected classical
features exists. In this case, even with non-trivial quantum geometric effects,
the spacetime curvature vanishes. These examples show that the character of
even a flat classical vacuum spacetime can alter in a fundamental way in
quantum gravity and is sensitive to the quantization procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08673</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2017-03-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>Katrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jordan</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gay</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchiat</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sellier</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sac&#xe9;p&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable transmission of quantum Hall edge channels with full degeneracy
  lifting in split-gated graphene devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>New data in the fractional quantum Hall regime added</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8:14983 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms14983</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Charge carriers in the quantum Hall regime propagate via one-dimensional
conducting channels that form along the edges of a two-dimensional electron
gas. Controlling their transmission through a gate-tunable constriction, also
called quantum point contact (QPC), is fundamental for many coherent transport
experiments. However, in graphene, tailoring a QPC with electrostatic gates
remains challenging due to the formation of p-n junctions below gate electrodes
along which electron and hole edge channels co-propagate and mix,
short-circuiting the constriction. Here we show that this electron-hole mixing
is drastically reduced in high mobility boron-nitride/graphene/boron-nitride
van-der-Waals heterostructures thanks to the full degeneracy lifting of the
Landau levels, enabling QPC operation with full channel pinch-off. We
demonstrate gate-tunable selective transmission of quantum Hall edge channels
through the QPC, both in the integer and the fractional quantum Hall regimes.
This gate-control of edge channel propagation in graphene van-der-Waals
heterostructures opens the door to quantum Hall interferometry and electron
quantum optics experiments in the integer and fractional quantum Hall regimes
of graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04013</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Allen-Perkins</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galeano</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastor</keyname><forenames>Juan Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Inducing Self-Organized Criticality in a network toy model by
  neighborhood assortativity</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures, resubmitted to PRE</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex networks are a recent type of frameworks used to study complex
systems with many interacting elements, such as Self-Organized Criticality
(SOC). The network node's tendency to link to other nodes of similar type is
characterized by assortative mixing. Real networks exhibit assortative mixing
by vertex degree, however typical random network models, such as Erdos-Renyi or
Barabasi-Albert, show no assortative arrangements. In this paper we introduce
the neighborhood assortativity notion, as the tendency of a node to belong to a
community (its neighborhood) showing an average property similar to its own.
Imposing neighborhood assortative mixing by degree in a network toy model, SOC
dynamics can be found. The long-range correlations resulting from the
criticality have been characterized by means of fluctuation analysis and show
an anticorrelation in the node's activity. The model contains only one
parameter and its statistics plots for different values of the parameter can be
collapsed into a single curve. The simplicity of the model allows performing
numerical simulations and also to study analytically the statistics for a
specific value of the parameter, making use of the Markov chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04932</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saini</keyname><forenames>Sahil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>Geodesic completeness and the lack of strong singularities in effective
  loop quantum Kantowski-Sachs spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Revised version. Discussion in the proof on absence of strong
  singularities expanded. References added. To appear in CQG</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 245019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/24/245019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Resolution of singularities in the Kantowski-Sachs model due to
non-perturbative quantum gravity effects is investigated. Using the effective
spacetime description for the improved dynamics version of loop quantum
Kantowski-Sachs spacetimes, we show that even though expansion and shear
scalars are universally bounded, there can exist events where curvature
invariants can diverge. However, such events can occur only for very exotic
equations of state when pressure or derivatives of energy density with respect
to triads become infinite at a finite energy density. In all other cases
curvature invariants are proved to remain finite for any evolution in finite
proper time. We find the novel result that all strong singularities are
resolved for arbitrary matter. Weak singularities pertaining to above potential
curvature divergence events can exist. The effective spacetime is found to be
geodesically complete for particle and null geodesics in finite time evolution.
Our results add to a growing evidence for generic resolution of strong
singularities using effective dynamics in loop quantum cosmology by
generalizing earlier results on isotropic and Bianchi-I spacetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07464</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ryter</keyname><forenames>Dietrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic differential equations: loss of the Markov property by
  multiplicative noise</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Revised version with a new outcome</comments><msc-class>60H</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The solutions of SDEs with multiplicative noise are not Markovian. On a
coarse-grained time scale they still are, but only in the &quot;anti-Ito&quot; case. This
allows a simple computation of the most likely path. Any density peak moves
along such a path, and its shape evolves according to further analytical
formulas. This even provides some new insights into the asymptotic densities
for large times, e.g. the criterion for attaining a quiescent steady state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07504</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Lazo</keyname><forenames>Matheus J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>Delfim F. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational Calculus with Conformable Fractional Derivatives</title><categories>math.OC math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This is a preprint of a paper whose final and definite form will
  appear in the IEEE/CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica, ISSN 2329-9266.
  Submitted 01-Oct-2015; Revised 20-April-2016; Accepted 22-June-2016</comments><msc-class>26A33, 34A08, 49K05, 49K10, 49S05</msc-class><journal-ref>IEEE/CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica 4 (2017), no. 2, 340--352</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/JAS.2016.7510160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Invariant conditions for conformable fractional problems of the calculus of
variations under the presence of external forces in the dynamics are studied.
Depending on the type of transformations considered, different necessary
conditions of invariance are obtained. As particular cases, we prove fractional
versions of Noether's symmetry theorem. Invariant conditions for fractional
optimal control problems, using the Hamiltonian formalism, are also
investigated. As an example of potential application in Physics, we show that
with conformable derivatives it is possible to formulate an Action Principle
for particles under frictional forces that is far simpler than the one obtained
with classical fractional derivatives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08257</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krivec</keyname><forenames>Rajmund</forenames></author></authors><title>On detecting Higgs coupling in transitions of light atoms</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In light of the known Higgs mass and the current constraints on the
quark-lepton Higgs coupling, we derive conditions for extracting upper limits
on the lepton-nucleon Higgs coupling from light atoms and ions, assuming the
availability of locally precise two- and three-body methods might be
beneficial. A recent work has proposed to extract these limits in heavy atoms
where the Higgs term is enhanced by $\approx 10^3 AZ$, due to both the large
coupling modifier and large $A$, $Z$, and assuming sufficiently precise
relativistic electron wave functions. We first revisit the old idea of using
the Lamb shift in light muonic ions where the coupling is enhanced by about
$201^3 AZ^3$ primarily due to the concentration of the muon wave function at
the origin, the muon coupling modifier already being close to 1. For the muonic
helium an experimental precision below 0.1 ppm is required to reach the
constraints on Higgs couplings. However, theoretical uncertainty is large due
to nuclear potential dependence of the finite size terms enhanced by the small
muon orbit, and their elimination by using several states is precluded due to
the Lamb shift being the only precisely measurable state. In normal
(electronic) light systems transitions between low-lying states lie near the
optical region allowing precise experiments, and extraction may be possible by
eliminating the finite-size, polarization and Zemach moment terms from a set of
transitions, e.g. $1S-2S$ and improved $2^3S-2^3P$ and $2^1S-2^3S$ in ${\rm
He}^+$, while isotope shifts could be used if additional transitions are
measured as precisely.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01049</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2017-03-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Storm</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeltema</keyname><forenames>Tesla E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Splettstoesser</keyname><forenames>Megan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Profumo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchrotron Emission from Dark Matter Annihilation: Predictions for
  Constraints from Non-detections of Galaxy Clusters with New Radio Surveys</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>accepted to ApJ; removal of LOFAR Tier 2 limits; other minor text
  changes; conclusions largely unchanged</comments><journal-ref>ApJ (2017) 839, 33</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6748</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The annihilation of dark matter particles is expected to yield a broad
radiation spectrum via the production of Standard Model particles in
astrophysical environments. In particular, electrons and positrons from dark
matter annihilation produce synchrotron radiation in the presence of magnetic
fields. Galaxy clusters are the most massive collapsed structures in the
universe, and are known to host $\sim\mu$G-scale magnetic fields. They are
therefore ideal targets to search for, or to constrain the synchrotron signal
from dark matter annihilation. In this work we use the expected sensitivities
of several planned surveys from the next generation of radio telescopes to
predict the constraints on dark matter annihilation models which will be
achieved in the case of non-detections of diffuse radio emission from galaxy
clusters. Specifically, we consider the Tier 1 survey planned for the Low
Frequency Array (LOFAR) at 120 MHz, the EMU survey planned for the Australian
Square Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP) at 1.4 GHz, and planned surveys for
APERTIF at 1.4 GHz. We find that, for massive clusters and dark matter masses
$\lesssim 100$ GeV, the predicted limits on the annihilation cross section
would rule out vanilla thermal relic models for even the shallow LOFAR Tier 1,
ASKAP, and APERTIF surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03386</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bielby</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Crighton</keyname><forenames>N. H. M.</forenames><affiliation>Swinburne</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fumagalli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stott</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames><affiliation>Oxford</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tejos</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Millenium Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cantalupo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author></authors><title>Probing the intra-group medium of a z = 0.28 galaxy group</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures, published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 468, 1373 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx528</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new MUSE observations of a galaxy group probed by a background
quasar. The quasar sightline passes between multiple $z=0.28$ galaxies, whilst
showing at the same redshift low ionised metal line species, including Ca II,
Mg I, Mg II and Fe II. Based on the galaxy redshifts measured from the MUSE
data, we estimate the galaxies to be part of a small galaxy group with a halo
mass of $\approx6\times10^{12}$ M$_{\odot}$. We use the MUSE data to reveal the
two dimensional dynamical properties of the gas and stars in the group
galaxies, and relate these to the absorber kinematics. With these data we
consider a number of scenarios for the nature of the gas probed by the
sightline absorbers: a co-rotating gas halo associated with a single galaxy
within the group; outflowing material from a single group member powered by
recent star-formation; and cool dense gas associated with an intra-group
medium. We find that the dynamics, galaxy impact parameters, star-formation
rates, and the absorber strength suggest the cool gas can not be clearly
associated with any single galaxy within the group. Instead we find that the
observations are consistent with a superposition of cool gas clouds originating
with the observed galaxies as they fall into the group potential, and are now
likely in the process of forming the intra-group medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05358</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lepori</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trombettoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vodola</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Singular dynamics and emergence of nonlocality in long-range quantum
  models</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 033102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa569d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss how nonlocality originates in long-range quantum systems and how
it affects their dynamics at and out of the equilibrium. We focus in particular
on the Kitaev chains with long-range pairings and on the quantum Ising chain
with long-range antiferromagnetic coupling (both having a power-law decay with
exponent \alpha). By studying the dynamic correlation functions, we find that
for every finite \alpha two different behaviours can be identified, one typical
of short-range systems and the other connected with locality violation. The
latter behaviour is shown related also with the known power-law decay tails
previously observed in the static correlation functions, and originated by
modes, having in general energies far from the minima of the spectrum, where
particular singularities develop as a consequence of the long-rangedness of the
system. We refer to these modes as to &quot;singular&quot; modes, and as to &quot;singular
dynamics&quot; to their dynamics. For the Kitaev model they are manifest, at finite
\alpha, in derivatives of the quasiparticle energy, the order of the derivative
at which the singularity occurs increasing with \alpha. The features of the
singular modes and their physical consequences are clarified by studying an
effective theory for them and by a critical comparison of the results from this
theory with the lattice ones. Moreover, a numerical study of the effects of the
singular modes on the time evolution after various types of global quenches is
performed. We finally present and discuss the presence of singular modes and
their consequences in interacting long-range systems by investigating in the
long-range Ising quantum chain, both in the deep paramagnetic regime and at
criticality, where they also play a central role for the breakdown of conformal
invariance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08247</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sadoun</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miralda-Escud&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Jordi</forenames></author></authors><title>On the decreasing fraction of Strong Ly$\alpha$ Emitters around $z$
  $\sim$ $6$-$7$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, submitted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 839 44 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa683b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fraction of galaxies with strong Ly$\alpha$ emission has been observed to
decrease rapidly with redshift at $z \ge 6$, after a gradual increase at $z&lt;
6$. This has been interpreted as a hint of the reionization of the
intergalactic medium (IGM): the emitted Ly$\alpha$ photons would be scattered
by an increasingly neutral IGM at $z&gt;6$. We study this effect by modeling the
ionization and Ly$\alpha$ radiative transfer in the infall region and the IGM
around a Ly$\alpha$ emitting galaxy (LAE), for a spherical halo model with the
mean density and radial velocity profiles in the standard $\Lambda$CDM
cosmological scenario. We find that the expected fast increase of the ionizing
background intensity toward the end of the reionization epoch implies a rapid
evolution of halo infall regions from being self-shielded against the external
ionizing background to being mostly ionized. Whereas self-shielded infall
regions can scatter the Ly$\alpha$ photons over a much larger area than the
commonly used apertures for observing LAEs, the same infalling gas is no longer
optically thick to the Ly$\alpha$ emission line after it is ionized by the
external background, making the Ly$\alpha$ emission more compact and brighter
within the observed apertures. Based on this simple model, we show that the
observed drop in the abundance of LAEs at $z&gt;6$ does not imply a rapid increase
with redshift of the fraction of the whole IGM volume that is atomic, but is
accounted for by a rapid increase of the neutral fraction in the infall regions
around galaxy host halos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02429</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lahini</keyname><forenames>Yoav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gottesman</keyname><forenames>Omer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amir</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubinstein</keyname><forenames>Shmuel M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonmonotonic Aging and Memory Retention in Disordered Mechanical Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 085501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.085501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We observe non-monotonic aging and memory effects, two hallmarks of glassy
dynamics, in two disordered mechanical systems: crumpled thin sheets and
elastic foams. Under fixed compression, both systems exhibit monotonic
non-exponential relaxation. However, when after a certain waiting time the
compression is partially reduced, both systems exhibit a non-monotonic
response: the normal force first increases over many minutes or even hours
until reaching a peak value, and only then relaxation is resumed. The peak-time
scales linearly with the waiting time, indicating that these systems retain
long-lasting memory of previous conditions. Our results and the measured
scaling relations are in good agreement with a theoretical model recently used
to describe observations of monotonic aging in several glassy systems,
suggesting that the non-monotonic behavior may be generic and that a-thermal
systems can show genuine glassy behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04359</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harte</keyname><forenames>Abraham I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vines</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author></authors><title>Generating exact solutions to Einstein's equation using linearized
  approximations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 1 figure. Corrected coefficients in Sect. VC</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 084009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.084009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that certain solutions to the linearized Einstein equation can---by
the application of a particular type of linearized gauge transformation---be
straightforwardly transformed into solutions of the exact Einstein equation. In
cases with nontrivial matter content, the exact stress-energy tensor of the
transformed metric has the same eigenvalues and eigenvectors as the linearized
stress-energy tensor of the initial approximation. When our gauge exists, the
tensorial structure of transformed metric perturbations identically eliminates
all nonlinearities in Einstein's equation. As examples, we derive the exact
Kerr and gravitational plane wave metrics from standard harmonic-gauge
approximations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05662</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dzhunushaliev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonperturbative quantization \`a la Heisenberg for non-Abelian gauge
  theories: two-equation approximation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>1 section about flux tube with zero color longitudinal electric field
  is added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonperturbative quantization technique \`{a} la Heisenberg is applied for
non-Abelian gauge theories. The operator Yang-Mills equation is written, which
on the corresponding averaging gives an infinite set of equations for all Green
functions. We split all degrees of freedom into two groups: in the former, we
have $A^a_\mu \in \mathcal G \subset SU(N)$, and in the second group we have
coset degrees of freedom $SU(N) / \mathcal G$. Using such splitting and some
assumptions about 2- and 4-point Green functions, we truncate the infinite set
of equations to two equations. The first equation is for the gauge fields from
the subgroup $\mathcal G$, and the second equation is for a gluon condensate
which is the dispersion of quantum fluctuations of the coset fields. Two
examples are considered: The first one is a flux tube solution describing
longitudinal color electric fields stretched between quark and antiquark
located at the $\pm$ infinities. The second one is a flux tube stretched
between two quarks (antiquarks) located at $\pm \infty$. A special case is
considered when the longitudinal electric field produced by a quark located at
$+ \infty$ is equal and oppositely directed to the field generated by a quark
located at $- \infty$ that leads to zero total electric field. Both solutions
represents the dual Meissner effect: the electric field is pushed out from the
gluon condensate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07772</id><created>2016-08-28</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dupuy</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of quantum ambiguities in k=1 loop quantum cosmology:
  distinct quantum turnarounds and the super-Planckian regime</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Revised version with expanded results and discussion on the role of
  inverse volume effects. Four figures added. To appear in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 023510 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.023510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spatially closed Friedmann-Lema\^{i}tre-Robertson-Walker model in loop
quantum cosmology admits two inequivalent consistent quantizations: one based
on expressing the field strength in terms of the holonomies over closed loops,
and, another using a connection operator and open holonomies. Using the
effective dynamics, we investigate the phenomenological differences between the
two quantizations for the single fluid and the two fluid scenarios with various
equations of state, including the phantom matter. We show that a striking
difference between the two quantizations is the existence of two distinct
quantum turnarounds, either bounces or recollapses, in the connection
quantization, in contrast to a single distinct quantum bounce or a recollapse
in the holonomy quantization. These results generalize an earlier result on the
existence of two distinct quantum bounces for stiff matter by Corichi and
Karami. However, we find that in certain situations two distinct quantum
turnarounds can become virtually indistinguishable. And depending on the
initial conditions, a pure quantum cyclic universe can also exist undergoing a
quantum bounce and a quantum recollapse. We show that for various equations of
states, connection based quantization leads to super-Planckian values of the
energy density and the expansion scalar at quantum turnarounds. Interestingly,
we find that very extreme energy densities can also occur for the holonomy
quantization, breaching the maximum allowed density in the spatially flat loop
quantized model. However, the expansion scalar in all these cases is bounded by
a universal value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01135</id><created>2016-09-05</created><updated>2016-11-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Winn</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Prospects for quarkonium measurements in p--A and A--A collisions at the
  LHC</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, extended proceedings for talk at the &quot;New Observables in
  Quarkonium Production&quot; workshop in Trento, Italy, 04.03.2016, revised
  versions (typos and update on recent measurements)</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst (2017) 58: 53</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-016-1189-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The potential of the ALICE, ATLAS, CMS and LHCb detectors for the measurement
of quarkonium in heavy-ion collisions, both in nucleus-nucleus (A-A) and in
proton-nucleus (p-A) interactions, in the years 2015 until about 2030 in the
LHC Runs 2, 3 and 4 with larger statistics and detector upgrades is described.
A selection of newly available observables is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07099</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adhikari</keyname><forenames>Lekha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkardt</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular Momentum Distribution in the Transverse Plane</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114021 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several possibilities to relate the $t$-dependence of Generalized Parton
Distributions (GPDs) to the distribution of angular momentum in the transverse
plane are discussed. Using a simple spectator model we demonstrate that non of
them correctly describes the orbital angular momentum distribution that for a
longitudinally polarized nucleon obtained directly from light-front
wavefunctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08041</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>D&#xed;az-Rubio</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asadchy</keyname><forenames>Viktar</forenames></author><author><keyname>and</keyname><forenames>Amr Elsakka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyakov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>From the generalized reflection law to the realization of perfect
  anomalous reflectors</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>27 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The use of the generalized Snell's law opens wide possibilities for the
manipulation of transmitted and reflected wavefronts. However, known structures
designed to shape reflection wave fronts suffer from significant parasitic
reflections in undesired directions: In fact, the desired field distributions
do not satisfy Maxwell's equations if the boundary conditions are specified in
accordance with the generalized Snell's law. In this work, we explore the
limitations of the existing solutions for the design of passive planar
reflectors and demonstrate that strongly non-local response is required for
perfect performance. Ideal reflective surfaces capable of steering the energy
into any desired direction have to localize and carry energy along the
inhomogeneous reflective surface. A new paradigm for the design of perfect
reflectors based on energy surface channeling is introduced. We realize and
experimentally verify a theoretically perfect design of an anomalously
reflective surface using an array of rectangular metal patches backed by a
metallic plate. This conceptually new mechanism for wavefront manipulation
allows the design of thin perfect reflectors, offering a versatile design
method applicable to other scenarios such as focusing reflectors or surface
wave manipulations, extendible to other frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09073</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leja</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Benjamin D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conroy</keyname><forenames>Charlie</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dokkum</keyname><forenames>Pieter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byler</keyname><forenames>Nell</forenames></author></authors><title>Deriving Physical Properties from Broadband Photometry with Prospector:
  Description of the Model and a Demonstration of its Accuracy Using 129
  Galaxies in the Local Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>39 pages, 29 figures, accepted to ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa5ffe</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Broadband photometry of galaxies measures an unresolved mix of complex
stellar populations, gas, and dust. Interpreting these data is a challenge for
models: many studies have shown that properties derived from modeling galaxy
photometry are uncertain by a factor of two or more, and yet answering key
questions in the field now requires higher accuracy than this. Here, we present
a new model framework specifically designed for these complexities. Our model,
Prospector-$\alpha$, includes dust attenuation and re-radiation, a flexible
attenuation curve, nebular emission, stellar metallicity, and a 6-component
nonparametric star formation history. The flexibility and range of the
parameter space, coupled with MCMC sampling within the Prospector inference
framework, is designed to provide unbiased parameters and realistic error bars.
We assess the accuracy of the model with aperture-matched optical spectroscopy,
which was excluded from the fits. We compare spectral features predicted solely
from fits to the broadband photometry to the observed spectral features. Our
model predicts H$\alpha$ luminosities with a scatter of $\sim$0.18 dex and an
offset of $\sim$0.1 dex across a wide range of morphological types and stellar
masses. This agreement is remarkable, as the H$\alpha$ luminosity is dependent
on accurate star formation rates, dust attenuation, and stellar metallicities.
The model also accurately predicts dust-sensitive Balmer decrements,
spectroscopic stellar metallicities, PAH mass fractions, and the age- and
metallicity-sensitive features D$_{\mathrm{n}}$4000 and H$\delta$. Although the
model passes all these tests, we caution that we have not yet assessed its
performance at higher redshift or the accuracy of recovered stellar masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01460</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Currie</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glover</keyname><forenames>E. W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pires</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author></authors><title>NNLO QCD predictions for single jet inclusive production at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures (version accepted for publication in PRL)</comments><report-no>IPPP/16/110, MPP-2016-322</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 072002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.072002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the first calculation of fully differential jet production in all
partonic channels at next-to-next-to leading order (NNLO) in perturbative QCD
and compare to the available ATLAS 7 TeV data. We discuss the size and shape of
the perturbative corrections along with their associated scale variation across
a wide range in jet transverse momentum, $p_{T}$, and rapidity, $y$. We find
significant effects, especially at low $p_{T}$, and discuss the possible
implications for Parton Distribution Function fits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04084</id><created>2016-11-13</created><updated>2017-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Komatsu</keyname><forenames>Nobuyoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological model from the holographic equipartition law with a
  modified R\'{e}nyi entropy</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>Final version accepted for publication in EPJC. The titile is revised
  and references are added. [12 pages, 4 figures]</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 229 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4800-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmological equations were recently derived by Padmanabhan from the
expansion of cosmic space due to the difference between the degrees of freedom
on the surface and in the bulk in a region of space. In this study, a modified
R\'{e}nyi entropy is applied to Padmanabhan's `holographic equipartition law',
by regarding the Bekenstein--Hawking entropy as a nonextensive Tsallis entropy
and using a logarithmic formula of the original R\'{e}nyi entropy.
Consequently, the acceleration equation including an extra driving term (such
as a time-varying cosmological term) can be derived in a homogeneous,
isotropic, and spatially flat universe. When a specific condition is
mathematically satisfied, the extra driving term is found to be constant-like
as if it is a cosmological constant. Interestingly, the order of the
constant-like term is naturally consistent with the order of the cosmological
constant measured by observations, because the specific condition constrains
the value of the constant-like term.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08808</id><created>2016-11-27</created><updated>2017-03-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Chandrachur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocherlakota</keyname><forenames>Prashant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patil</keyname><forenames>Mandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Sudip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Pankaj S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xf3;lak</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Distinguishing Kerr naked singularities and black holes using the spin
  precession of a test gyro in strong gravitational fields</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories><comments>LaTex; 26 pages including 51 figures, thoroughly revised version, new
  sections and new references added, results and conclusions remain unchanged,
  accepted for publication in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 084024 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study here the precession of the spin of a test gyroscope attached to a
stationary observer in the Kerr spacetime, specifically, to distinguish naked
singularity (NS) from black hole (BH). It was shown recently that for gyros
attached to static observers, their precession frequency became arbitrarily
large in the limit of approach to the ergosurface. For gyros attached to
stationary observers that move with non-zero angular velocity $\Omega$, this
divergence at the ergosurface can be avoided. Specifically, for such gyros, the
precession frequencies diverge on the event horizon of a BH, but are finite and
regular for NS everywhere except at the singularity itself. Therefore a genuine
detection of the event horizon becomes possible in this case. We also show that
for a near-extremal NS ($1&lt;a_* &lt; 1.1$), characteristic features appear in the
radial profiles of the precession frequency, using which we can further
distinguish a near-extremal NS from a BH, or even from NS with larger angular
momentum. We then investigate the Lense-Thirring (LT) precession or nodal plane
precession frequency of the accretion disk around a BH and NS to show that
clear distinctions exist for these configurations in terms of radial variation
features. The LT precession in equatorial circular orbits increases with
approach to a BH, whereas for NS it increases, attains a peak and then
decreases. Interestingly, for $a_*=1.089$, it decreases until it vanishes at a
certain radius, and acquires negative values for $a_* &gt; 1.089$ for a certain
range of $r$. For $1&lt;a_*&lt;1.089$, a peak appears, but the LT frequency remains
positive definite. There are important differences in accretion disk LT
frequencies for BH and NS and since LT frequencies are intimately related to
observed QPOs, these features might allow us to determine whether a given
rotating compact astrophysical object is BH or NS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00929</id><created>2016-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge symmetry breaking in the adiabatic self-consistent collective
  coordinate method</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>26 pages, no figure</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2017) 2017 033D01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study gauge symmetry breaking by adiabatic approximation in the adiabatic
self-consistent collective coordinate (ASCC) method. In the previous study, we
found that the gauge symmetry of the equation of collective submanifold is
(partially) broken by its decomposition into the three moving-frame equations
depending on the order of $p$. In this study, we discuss the gauge symmetry
breaking by the truncation of the adiabatic expansion. A particular emphasis is
placed on the symmetry under the gauge transformations which are not point
transformations. We also discuss a possible version of the ASCC method
including the higher-order operators which can keep the gauge symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05949</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>IceCube Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Aartsen</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ackermann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguilar</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahlers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahrens</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altmann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andeen</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ansseau</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anton</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Archinger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arg&#xfc;elles</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auffenberg</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Axani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barwick</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baum</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bay</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beatty</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tjus</keyname><forenames>J. Becker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>K. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>BenZvi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berley</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernardini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Besson</keyname><forenames>D. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binder</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bindig</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bissok</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaufuss</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blot</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohm</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;rner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bos</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;ser</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botner</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brayeur</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bretz</keyname><forenames>H. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bron</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carver</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheung</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chirkin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Classen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coenders</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collin</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cowen</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cross</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Day</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Andr&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>J. P. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Clercq</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosendo</keyname><forenames>E. del Pino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dembinski</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Ridder</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desiati</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Vries</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Wasseige</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de With</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeYoung</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xed;az-V&#xe9;lez</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>di Lorenzo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dujmovic</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumm</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunkman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberhardt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ehrhardt</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichmann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Euler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evenson</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fahey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazely</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feintzeig</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felde</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filimonov</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finley</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xf6;sig</keyname><forenames>C. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franckowiak</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedman</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaisser</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerhardt</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghorbani</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gladstone</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glauch</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gl&#xfc;senkamp</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldschmidt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffith</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haack</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallgren</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halzen</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hebecker</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heereman</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helbing</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hellauer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hickford</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hignight</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoshina</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hultqvist</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>In</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishihara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Japaridze</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jero</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>B. J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kappes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karg</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karle</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katz</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kauer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keivani</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelley</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheirandish</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kintscher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiryluk</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kittler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohnen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koirala</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolanoski</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konietz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;pke</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopper</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopper</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koskinen</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krings</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kroll</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ckl</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunnen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunwar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurahashi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuwabara</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labare</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanfranchi</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larson</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauber</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lennarz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesiak-Bzdak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuermann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;nemann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahn</keyname><forenames>K. B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mancina</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandelartz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maruyama</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mase</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maunu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McNally</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meagher</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medici</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menne</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meures</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miarecki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montaruli</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moulai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nahnhauer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumann</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niederhausen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowicki</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nygren</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollmann</keyname><forenames>A. Obertacke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Murchadha</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palczewski</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pankova</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peiffer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penek</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepper</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heros</keyname><forenames>C. P&#xe9;rez de los</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pieloth</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinat</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>P. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przybylski</keyname><forenames>G. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quinnan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raab</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xe4;del</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rameez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rawlins</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reimann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Relethford</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Relich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Resconi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhode</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riedel</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robertson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rongen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rott</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruhe</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryckbosch</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rysewyk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabbatini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>S. E. Sanchez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandrock</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandroos</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satalecka</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlunder</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoenen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;neberg</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumacher</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seckel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seunarine</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soldin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiczak</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiering</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanev</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stasik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stettner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steuer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stezelberger</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stokstad</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xf6;&#xdf;l</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Str&#xf6;m</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strotjohann</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>G. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutherland</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taavola</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taboada</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatar</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tenholt</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ter-Antonyan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terliuk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Te&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tilav</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toale</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobin</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toscano</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tosi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tselengidou</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turcati</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandenbroucke</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Eijndhoven</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanheule</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Rossem</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Santen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vehring</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voge</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vraeghe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walck</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallace</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallraff</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandkowsky</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weaver</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendt</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westerhoff</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whelan</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wickmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebusch</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wille</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wills</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woolsey</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woschnagg</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanez</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yodh</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoll</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for annihilating dark matter in the Sun with 3 years of IceCube
  data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ex</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 146</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4689-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from an analysis looking for dark matter annihilation in
the Sun with the IceCube neutrino telescope. Gravitationally trapped dark
matter in the Sun's core can annihilate into Standard Model particles making
the Sun a source of GeV neutrinos. IceCube is able to detect neutrinos with
energies &gt;100 GeV while its low-energy infill array DeepCore extends this to
&gt;10 GeV. This analysis uses data gathered in the austral winters between May
2011 and May 2014, corresponding to 532 days of livetime when the Sun, being
below the horizon, is a source of up-going neutrino events, easiest to
discriminate against the dominant background of atmospheric muons. The
sensitivity is a factor of two to four better than previous searches due to
additional statistics and improved analysis methods involving better background
rejection and reconstructions. The resultant upper limits on the spin-dependent
dark matter-proton scattering cross section reach down to $1.46\times10^{-5}$
pb for a dark matter particle of mass 500 GeV annihilating exclusively into
$\tau^{+}\tau^{-}$ particles. These are currently the most stringent limits on
the spin-dependent dark matter-proton scattering cross section for WIMP masses
above 50 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07776</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07776</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alt</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erdos</keyname><forenames>Laszlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>Torben</forenames></author></authors><title>Local inhomogeneous circular law</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>37 pages, 3 figures. We added some more properties of the density of
  states in Proposition 2.4</comments><msc-class>60B20, 15B52</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider large random matrices $X$ with centered, independent entries
which have comparable but not necessarily identical variances. Girko's circular
law asserts that the spectrum is supported in a disk and in case of identical
variances, the limiting density is uniform. In this special case, the local
circular law by Bourgade et. al. [11,12] shows that the empirical density
converges even locally on scales slightly above the typical eigenvalue spacing.
In the general case, the limiting density is typically inhomogeneous and it is
obtained via solving a system of deterministic equations. Our main result is
the local inhomogeneous circular law in the bulk spectrum on the optimal scale
for a general variance profile of the entries of $X$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00050</id><created>2016-12-30</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Isaac H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kastoryano</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement renormalization, quantum error correction, and bulk
  causality</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures. typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 04 (2017) 40</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement renormalization can be viewed as an encoding circuit for a
family of approximate quantum error correcting codes. The logical information
becomes progressively more well-protected against erasure errors at larger
length scales. In particular, an approximate variant of holographic quantum
error correcting code emerges at low energy for critical systems. This implies
that two operators that are largely separated in scales behave as if they are
spatially separated operators, in the sense that they obey a Lieb-Robinson type
locality bound under a time evolution generated bya local Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02041</id><created>2017-01-08</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bougiatioti</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiss</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuschel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Wees</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlocal magnon spin transport in NiFe$_2$O$_4$ thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 132406 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report magnon spin transport in nickel ferrite (NiFe$_2$O$_4$, NFO)/
platinum (Pt) bilayer systems at room temperature. A nonlocal geometry is
employed, where the magnons are excited by the spin Hall effect or by the Joule
heating induced spin Seebeck effect at the Pt injector, and detected at a
certain distance away by the inverse spin Hall effect at the Pt detector. The
dependence of the nonlocal magnon spin signals as a function of the magnetic
field is closely related to the NFO magnetization behavior. In contrast, we
observe that the magnetoresistance measured locally at the Pt injector does not
show a clear relation with the average NFO magnetization. We estimate the
magnon spin relaxation length to be 3.1 $\pm$ 0.2 $\mu$m in the investigated
NFO samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04390</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Qianshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melko</keyname><forenames>Roger G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jeff Z. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying polymer states by machine learning</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 032504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.032504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability of a feed-forward neural network to learn and classify different
states of polymer configurations is systematically explored. Performing
numerical experiments, we find that a simple network model can, after adequate
training, recognize multiple structures, including gas-like coil, liquid-like
globular, and crystalline anti-Mackay and Mackay structures. The network can be
trained to identify the transition points between various states, which compare
well with those identified by independent specific-heat calculations. Our study
demonstrates that neural network provides an unconventional tool to study the
phase transitions in polymeric systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04412</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04412</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames><affiliation>Durham, MSSL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Massey</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jauzac</keyname><forenames>Mathilde</forenames><affiliation>Durham, ACRU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Courbin</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames><affiliation>EPFL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Harvey</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>EPFL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Joseph</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;my</forenames><affiliation>EPFL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Robertson</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author></authors><title>A test for skewed distributions of dark matter and a possible detection
  in galaxy cluster Abell 3827</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx855</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simulations of self-interacting dark matter (SIDM) predict that dark matter
should lag behind galaxies during a collision. If the interaction is mediated
by a high-mass force carrier, the distribution of dark matter can also develop
asymmetric dark matter tails. To search for this asymmetry, we compute the
gravitational lensing properties of a mass distribution with a free {\em
skewness} parameter. We apply this to the dark matter around the four central
galaxies in cluster Abell~3827. In the galaxy whose dark matter peak has
previously been found to be offset, we tentatively measure a skewness
$s=0.23^{+0.05}_{-0.22}$ in the same direction as the peak offset. Our method
may be useful in future gravitational lensing analyses of colliding galaxy
clusters and merging galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05824</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-03-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diener</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joe</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Megevand</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical simulations of loop quantum Bianchi-I spacetimes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Discussion of results expanded. Two figures added. To appear in the
  focus issue on Applications of Loop Quantum Gravity to Cosmology in CQG</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 094004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa68b5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to the numerical complexities of studying evolution in an anisotropic
quantum spacetime, in comparison to the isotropic models, the physics of loop
quantized anisotropic models has remained largely unexplored. In particular,
robustness of bounce and the validity of effective dynamics have so far not
been established. Our analysis fills these gaps for the case of vacuum
Bianchi-I spacetime. To efficiently solve the quantum Hamiltonian constraint we
perform an implementation of the Cactus framework which is conventionally used
for applications in numerical relativity. Using high performance computing,
numerical simulations for a large number of initial states with a wide variety
of fluctuations are performed. Big bang singularity is found to be replaced by
anisotropic bounces for all the cases. We find that for initial states which
are sharply peaked at the late times in the classical regime and bounce at a
mean volume much greater than the Planck volume, effective dynamics is an
excellent approximation to the underlying quantum dynamics. Departures of the
effective dynamics from the quantum evolution appear for the states probing
deep Planck volumes. A detailed analysis of the behavior of this departure
reveals a non-monotonic and subtle dependence on fluctuations of the initial
states. We find that effective dynamics in almost all of the cases
underestimates the volume and hence overestimates the curvature at the bounce,
a result in synergy with earlier findings in isotropic case. The expansion and
shear scalars are found to be bounded throughout the evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07039</id><created>2017-01-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Valiviita</keyname><forenames>Jussi</forenames></author></authors><title>Power Spectra Based Planck Constraints on Compensated Isocurvature, and
  Forecasts for LiteBIRD and CORE Space Missions</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures, 4 tables. JCAP format. ArXiv txt abstract
  abridged</comments><report-no>HIP-2017-2/TH</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 04 (2017) 014</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/04/014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Compensated isocurvature perturbations (CIP), where the baryon and cold dark
matter perturbations cancel, do not cause total matter isocurvature
perturbation. Consequently, at the linear order in the baryon density contrast
$\Delta$, CIP is not detectable by the CMB power spectra. At the second order
CIP smoothes the power spectra in a similar manner as lensing, causing a
degeneracy between the CIP variance $\Delta^2_{rms}=&lt;\Delta^2&gt;$ and lensing
parameter $A_L$. We show that the CMB lensing data breaks this degeneracy.
Nested sampling of the LCDM+CIP(+$A_L$) model, the Planck 2015 temperature,
polarization, and lensing data give $\Delta^2_{rms}=0.0069\pm0.0030$ at 68% CL.
A non-zero value is favored at 2.3$\sigma$. CIP with $\Delta^2_{rms}=0.007$
improves the bestfit $\chi^2$ by 3.6 compared to the adiabatic LCDM model. In
contrast, although the temperature data favor $A_L=1.22$, allowing $A_L\ne1$
does not improve the joint fit, since the lensing data disfavor $A_L\ne1$.
Indeed, CIP provides a rare example of a simple model, which can reduce the
Planck lensing anomaly by fitting well simultaneously the high multipole
temperature and lensing data, as well as the polarization data. Finally, we
derive forecasts for future satellite missions (LiteBIRD proposal to JAXA and
Exploring Cosmic Origins with CORE proposal to ESA's M5 call). Due to its
coarse angular resolution, LiteBIRD is not able to improve the constraints on
CIP or $A_L$, but CORE-M5 approaches the cosmic variance limit and improves the
CIP constraint to $\Delta^2_{rms}&lt;0.0006\ (0.0014)$ at 68% (95%) CL, which is 9
times better than the current trispectrum based upper bound and 6 times better
than obtained from the simulated Planck data. In addition, CORE-M5 will
exquisitely distinguish between CIP and $A_L$. No matter whether CIP is allowed
for or not, the uncertainty of the lensing parameter will be
$\sigma(A_L)=0.012$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07443</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertuzzo</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deppisch</keyname><forenames>Frank F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Suchita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Yuber F. Perez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Funchal</keyname><forenames>Renata Zukanovich</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter and Exotic Neutrino Interactions in Direct Detection
  Searches</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>One figure, comments and references added. Version published in the
  JHEP</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of new physics interacting with both Dark Matter
(DM) and neutrinos at DM direct detection experiments. Working within a
simplified model formalism, we consider vector and scalar mediators to
determine the scattering of DM as well as the modified scattering of solar
neutrinos off nuclei. Using existing data from LUX as well as the expected
sensitivity of LUX-ZEPLIN and DARWIN, we set limits on the couplings of the
mediators to quarks, neutrinos and DM. Given the current limits, we also assess
the true DM discovery potential of direct detection experiments under the
presence of exotic neutrino interactions. In the case of a vector mediator, we
show that the DM discovery reach of future experiments is affected for DM
masses $m_\chi \lesssim 10$ GeV or DM scattering cross sections $\sigma_\chi
\lesssim 10^{-47}$ cm$^2$. On the other hand, a scalar mediator will not affect
the discovery reach appreciably.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08770</id><created>2017-01-30</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chianese</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Grezia</keyname><forenames>Elisabetta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfredonia</keyname><forenames>Mattia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miele</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterising exotic matter driving wormhole</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages. Version published in EPJP</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132: 164</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11475-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we develop an iterative approach to span the whole set of
exotic matter models able to drive a traversable wormhole. The method, based on
a Taylor expansion of metric and stress-energy tensor components in a
neighbourhood of the wormhole throat, reduces the Einstein equations to an
infinite set of algebraic conditions, which can be satisfied order by order.
The approach easily allows the implementation of further conditions linking the
stress-energy tensor components among each other, like symmetry conditions or
equations of state. The method is then applied to some relevant examples of
exotic matter characterised by a constant energy density and that also show an
isotropic behaviour in the stress-energy tensor or obeying to a
quintessence-like equation of state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.09169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.09169</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsukamoto</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author></authors><title>Retrolensing by a wormhole at deflection angles $\pi$ and $3\pi$</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures, title changed, minor correction, accepted for
  publication in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 084021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deflection angle of a light ray can be arbitrarily large near a light
sphere. The time-symmetrical shape of light curves of a pair of light rays
reflected by a light sphere of a lens object does not depend on the details of
the lens object. We consider retrolensing light curves of sunlight with
deflection angles $\pi$ and $3\pi$ by an Ellis wormhole, which is the simplest
Morris-Thorne wormhole. If an Ellis wormhole with a throat parameter
$a=10^{11}$ km is $100$ pc away from an observer and if the Ellis wormhole, the
observer, and the sun are aligned perfectly in this order, the apparent
magnitudes of a pair of light rays with deflection angles $\pi$ and $3\pi$
become $11$ and $18$, respectively. The two pairs of light rays make a
superposed light curve with two separable peaks and they break down time
symmetry of a retrolensing light curve. The observation of the two separated
peaks of the light curves gives us information on the details of the lens
object. If the observer can also separate the pair of the images with the
deflection angle $\pi$ into a double image, he or she can say whether the
retrolensing is caused by an Ellis wormhole or a Schwarzschild black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00359</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nerl</keyname><forenames>Hannah Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winther</keyname><forenames>Kirsten Tr&#xf8;strup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hage</keyname><forenames>Fredrik Sydow</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thygesen</keyname><forenames>Kristian Sommer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houben</keyname><forenames>Lothar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Backes</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>Jonathan N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramasse</keyname><forenames>Quentin M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolosi</keyname><forenames>Valeria</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the local nature of excitons and plasmons in few-layer MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Main paper: 19 pages, 5 figures Accepted for publication, Manuscript
  number: NPJ2DMATERIALS-00006, ISSN 2397-7132</comments><journal-ref>npj 2D Materials and Applications 1 2 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41699-017-0003-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Excitons and plasmons are the two most fundamental types of collective
electronic excitations occurring in solids. Traditionally, they have been
studied separately using bulk techniques that probe their average energetic
structure over large spatial regions. However, as the dimensions of materials
and devices continue to shrink, it becomes crucial to understand how these
excitations depend on local variations in the crystal- and chemical structure
on the atomic scale. Here we use monochromated low-loss
scanning-transmission-electron-microscopy electron-energy-loss (LL-STEM-EEL)
spectroscopy, providing the best simultaneous energy and spatial resolution
achieved to-date to unravel the full set of electronic excitations in few-layer
MoS2 nanosheets over a wide energy range. Using first-principles many-body
calculations we confirm the excitonic nature of the peaks at ~2eV and ~3eV in
the experimental EEL spectrum and the plasmonic nature of higher energy-loss
peaks. We also rationalise the non-trivial dependence of the EEL spectrum on
beam and sample geometry such as the number of atomic layers and distance to
steps and edges. Moreover, we show that the excitonic features are dominated by
the long wavelength (q=0) components of the probing field, while the plasmonic
features are sensitive to a much broader range of q-vectors, indicating a
qualitative difference in the spatial character of the two types of collective
excitations. Our work provides a template protocol for mapping the local nature
of electronic excitations that open new possibilities for studying
photo-absorption and energy transfer processes on a nanometer scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02021</id><created>2017-01-30</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chuprikov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Only in the standard representation the Dirac theory is a quantum theory
  of a single fermion</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, thoroughly rewritten</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that the relativistic quantum mechanics of a single fermion can
be developed only on the basis of the standard representation of the Dirac
bispinor. As in the nonrelativistic quantum mechanics, the arbitrariness in
defining the bispinor, as a four-component wave function, is restricted by its
multiplication by an arbitrary phase factor. We reveal the role of the large
and small components of the bispinor, establish their link in the
nonrelativistic limit with the Pauli spinor, as well as explain the role of
states with negative energies. The Klein tunneling is treated here as a
physical phenomenon analogous to the propagation of the electromagnetic wave in
a medium with negative dielectric permittivity and permeability. For the case
of localized stationary states we define the effective one-particle operators
which act in the space of the large component but contain the contributions of
both components. The effective operator of energy is presented in a compact
analytical form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04729</id><created>2017-02-15</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scoville</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bout</keyname><forenames>P. Vanden</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Santos</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanders</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darvish</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bongiorno</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casey</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murchikova</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlahakis</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilbert</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheth</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morokuma-Matsui</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivison</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aussel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laigle</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCracken</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armus</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pope</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toft</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masters</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of Interstellar Medium, Star Formation, and Accretion at High
  Redshift</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa61a0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ALMA observations of the long wavelength dust continuum are used to estimate
the interstellar medium (ISM) masses in a sample of 708 galaxies at z = 0.3 to
4.5 in the COSMOS field. The galaxy sample has known far-infrared luminosities
and, hence, star formation rates (SFRs), and stellar masses (M$_{\rm *}$) from
the optical-infrared spectrum fitting. The galaxies sample SFRs from the main
sequence (MS) to 50 times above the MS. The derived ISM masses are used to
determine the dependence of gas mass on redshift, M$_{\rm *}$, and specific SFR
(sSFR) relative to the MS. The ISM masses increase approximately 0.63 power of
the rate of increase in SFRs with redshift and the 0.32 power of the
sSFR/sSFR$_MS$. The SF efficiencies also increase as the 0.36 power of the SFR
redshift evolutionary and the 0.7 power of the elevation above the MS; thus the
increased activities at early epochs are driven by both increased ISM masses
and SF efficiency. Using the derived ISM mass function we estimate the
accretion rates of gas required to maintain continuity of the MS evolution
($&gt;100$ \msun yr$^{-1}$ at z $&gt;$ 2.5). Simple power-law dependences are
similarly derived for the gas accretion rates. We argue that the overall
evolution of galaxies is driven by the rates of gas accretion. The cosmic
evolution of total ISM mass is estimated and linked to the evolution of SF and
AGN activity at early epochs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05483</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hallakoun</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maoz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>V. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhillon</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bours</keyname><forenames>M. C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kerry</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rengaswamy</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pravec</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku&#x161;nir&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku&#x10d;&#xe1;kov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armstrong</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerard</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanzi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Once in a blue moon: detection of 'bluing' during debris transits in the
  white dwarf WD1145+017</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>MNRAS, in press</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx924</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first transiting planetesimal orbiting a white dwarf was recently
detected in K2 data of WD1145+017 and has been followed up intensively. The
multiple, long, and variable transits suggest the transiting objects are dust
clouds, probably produced by a disintegrating asteroid. In addition, the system
contains circumstellar gas, evident by broad absorption lines, mostly in the
u'-band, and a dust disc, indicated by an infrared excess. Here we present the
first detection of a change in colour of WD1145+017 during transits, using
simultaneous multi-band fast-photometry ULTRACAM measurements over the
u'g'r'i'-bands. The observations reveal what appears to be 'bluing' during
transits; transits are deeper in the redder bands, with a u'-r' colour
difference of up to ~-0.05 mag. We explore various possible explanations for
the bluing. 'Spectral' photometry obtained by integrating over bandpasses in
the spectroscopic data in- and out-of-transit, compared to the photometric
data, shows that the observed colour difference is most likely the result of
reduced circumstellar absorption in the spectrum during transits. This
indicates that the transiting objects and the gas share the same line-of-sight,
and that the gas covers the white dwarf only partially, as would be expected if
the gas, the transiting debris, and the dust emitting the infrared excess, are
part of the same general disc structure (although possibly at different radii).
In addition, we present the results of a week-long monitoring campaign of the
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05315</id><created>2017-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Gurtug</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazharimousavi</keyname><forenames>S. Habib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halilsoy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical and quantum analysis of an Einstein-Scalar solution in $2+1$
  dimensions</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages one figure, final version accepted for publication in EPJP</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus 132, 161 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11446-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classical and quantum properties of a new solution obtained in $2+1$%
-dimensional gravity coupled with a real scalar field is analyzed in detail.
The considered new solution is a one-parameter generalization of a previously
known solution. We investigate the solution classically by calculating exact
null and null circular geodesics which correspond to a typical particle probe
of the correspondsing black hole spacetime. The solution admitting naked
singularity is investigated within the context of quantum mechanics. The
timelike naked singularity is probed with spin-zero and spin-half quantum
particles. We show that the curvature singularity in the new solution is
stronger and hence in general the spacetime remains quantum singular with
respect to a quantum particle probe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06068</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jaeha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsutsui</keyname><forenames>Izumi</forenames></author></authors><title>On Quantisations, Quasi-probabilities and the Weak Value</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>35 pages</comments><report-no>KEK-TH-1962</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a general framework of the quantum/quasi-classical transformations
by introducing the concept of quasi-joint-spectral distribution (QJSD).
Specifically, we show that the QJSDs uniquely yield various pairs of
quantum/quasi-classical transformations, including the Wigner-Weyl transform.
We also discuss the statistical behaviour of combinations of generally
non-commutin quantum observables by introducing the concept of quantum
correlations and conditional expectations defined analogously to the classical
counterpart. Based on these, Aharonov's weak value is given a statistical
interpretation as one realisation of the quantum conditional expectations
furnished in our formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08467</id><created>2017-03-24</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Houston</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric, fermionic solutions in three-dimensional supergravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages. Typo corrected, reference added, some points clarified</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Building upon known supersymmetric backgrounds, we derive novel half-BPS
fermionic solutions in three-dimensional supergravity. By virtue of an
essential dependence on fermionic degrees of freedom, they possess no purely
bosonic analogue. In the Anti de Sitter case this notably includes nonsingular
solutions for which the corresponding Chern-Simons gauge field
$\mathcal{A}=\omega\pm e/L$ vanishes, providing access to configurations which
are ordinarily singular in pure gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00435</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>Zhun-Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Thickness-dependent Kapitza resistance in multilayered graphene and
  other two-dimensional crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kapitza or thermal boundary resistance (TBR), which limits heat
dissipation from a thin film to its substrate, is a major factor in the thermal
management of ultrathin nanoelectronic devices and is widely assumed to be a
property of only the interface. However, data from experiments and molecular
dynamics simulations suggest that the TBR between a multilayer 2-dimensional
(2D) crystal and its substrate decreases with increasing film thickness. To
explain this thickness dependence, we generalize the recent theory for
single-layer 2D crystals by Ong, Cai and Zhang [Phys. Rev. B 94, 165427
(2016)], which is derived from the theory by Persson, Volokitin, and Ueba [J.
Phys.: Condens. Matter 23, 045009 (2011)], and use it to evaluate the TBR
between bare $N$-layer graphene and SiO$_{2}$. Our calculations reproduce
quantitatively the TBR thickness dependence seen in experiments and simulations
as well as its asymptotic convergence, and predict that the low-temperature TBR
scales as $T^{-4}$ in few-layer graphene. Analysis of the interfacial
transmission coefficient spectrum shows that the TBR reduction in few-layer
graphene is due to the additional contribution from higher flexural phonon
branches. Our theory sheds light on the role of flexural phonons in
substrate-directed heat dissipation and provides the framework for optimizing
the thermal management of multilayered 2D devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01623</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Henriques</keyname><forenames>C. A. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freitas</keyname><forenames>E. D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Azevedo</keyname><forenames>C. D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez-D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mano</keyname><forenames>R. D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jorge</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>L. M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monteiro</keyname><forenames>C. M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Cadenas</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benlloch-Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borges</keyname><forenames>F. I. G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xe1;rcel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carri&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cebri&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conde</keyname><forenames>C. A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diesburg</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escada</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esteve</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felkai</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrario</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldschmidt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauptman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morata</keyname><forenames>J. A. Hernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrero</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>B. J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labarga</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laing</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebrun</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liubarsky</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-March</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Losada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n-Albo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Lema</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDonald</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monrabal</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moutinho</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>J. Mu&#xf1;oz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nebot-Guinot</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nygren</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmeiro</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Para</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Querol</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ripoll</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>F. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>J. M. F. dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sim&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sofka</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stiegler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toledo</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torrent</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsamalaidze</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veloso</keyname><forenames>J. F. C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yahlali</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Secondary scintillation yield of Xenon with sub-percent levels of CO2
  additive: efficiently reducing electron diffusion in HPXe optical TPCs for
  rare-event detection</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the electroluminescence (EL) yield of Xe-CO2 mixtures, with
sub-percent CO2 concentrations. We demonstrate that the EL production is still
high in these mixtures, 70% and 35% relative to that produced in pure xenon,
for CO2 concentrations around 0.05% and 0.1%, respectively. The contribution of
the statistical fluctuations in EL production to the energy resolution
increases with increasing CO2 concentration and, for our gas proportional
scintillation counter, it is smaller than the contribution of the Fano factor
for concentrations below 0.1% CO2. Xe-CO2 mixtures are important alternatives
to pure xenon in TPCs based on EL signal amplification with applications in the
important field of rare event detection such as directional dark matter, double
electron capture and double beta decay detection. The addition of CO2 to pure
xenon at the level of 0.05-0.1% can reduce significantly the scale of electron
diffusion from 10 mm/sqrt(m) to 2.5 mm/sqrt(m), with high impact on the HPXe
TPC discrimination efficiency of the events through pattern recognition of the
topology of primary ionisation trails.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02139</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf6;tze</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xe9;vy-Bertrand</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harima</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheikin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Drastic change of the Fermi surface across the metamagnetic transition
  in CeRh$_2$Si$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B Rapid. Comm</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 161107(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.161107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report high field de Haas-van Alphen (dHvA) effect measurements in
CeRh$_2$Si$_2$ both below and above the first-order 26 T metamagnetic
transition from an antiferromagnetic to a polarized paramagnetic state. The
dHvA frequencies observed above the transition are much higher than those
observed below, implying a drastic change of the Fermi-surface size. The dHvA
frequencies above the transition and their angular dependence are in good
agreement with band-structure calculations for LaRh$_2$Si$_2$, which correspond
to CeRh$_2$Si$_2$ with localized $f$ electrons. Given that the $f$ electrons
are also localized at low fields in CeRh$_2$Si$_2$, the Fermi-surface
reconstruction is due to the suppression of antiferromagnetism and the
restoration of the crystallographic Brillouin zone rather than the
delocalization of the $f$ electrons. This example suggests that the intuitive
notation of &quot;small&quot; and &quot;large&quot; Fermi surfaces commonly used for localized and
itinerant $f$ electrons, respectively, requires careful consideration, taking
into account the modification of the Brillouin zone in the antiferromagnetic
state, when interpreting experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02184</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Jolos</keyname><forenames>R. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolganova</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic energy in the collective quadrupole Hamiltonian from the
  experimental data</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 769 (2017) 368-371</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dependence of the kinetic energy term of the collective nuclear Hamiltonian
on collective momentum is considered. It is shown that the fourth order in
collective momentum term of the collective quadrupole Hamiltonian generates a
sizable effect on the excitation energies and the matrix elements of the
quadrupole moment operator. It is demonstrated that the results of calculation
are sensitive to the values of some matrix elements of the quadrupole moment.
It stresses the importance for a concrete nucleus to have the experimental data
for the reduced matrix elements of the quadrupole moment operator taken between
all low lying states with the angular momenta not exceeding 4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03276</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Papoutsellis</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Athanassoulis</keyname><forenames>Gerassimos</forenames></author></authors><title>A new efficient Hamiltonian approach to the nonlinear water-wave problem
  over arbitrary bathymetry</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new Hamiltonian formulation for the fully nonlinear water-wave problem over
variable bathymetry is derived, using an exact, vertical series expansion of
the velocity potential, in conjunction with Luke's variational principle. The
obtained Euler-Lagrange equations contain infinite series and can rederive
various existing model equations upon truncation. In this paper, the infinite
series are summed up, resulting in two exact Hamiltonian equations for the
free-surface elevation and the free-surface potential, coupled with a
time-independent horizontal system of equations. The Dirichlet to Neumann
operator is given by a simple and versatile representation, which is valid for
any smooth fluid domain, not necessarily periodic in the horizontal
direction(s), without limitations on the steepness and deformation of the
seabed and the free surface. An efficient numerical scheme is presented and
applied to the case of one horizontal dimension, establishing the ability of
the new formulation to simulate strongly nonlinear and dispersive wave-bottom
interactions by comparison with experimental measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03770</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Konar</keyname><forenames>Sushan</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity Defied (from potato asteroids to magnetised neutron stars) II :
  The failed stars</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Second of a 4-article series (see arXiv:1703.09799)</comments><journal-ref>Resonance - Journal of Science Education, 22(4), 389 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitation, the universal attractive force, acts upon all matter (and
radiation) relentlessly. Stable extended structures can exist only when gravity
is held off by other forces of nature. This series of articles explores this
interplay, looking at objects that just missed being stars in this particular
instalment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03830</id><created>2017-04-12</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silber</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hocking</keyname><forenames>Wayne K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niculescu</keyname><forenames>Mihai L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gritsevich</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silber</keyname><forenames>Reynold E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Shock Waves and the Role of Hyperthermal Chemistry in the Early
  Diffusion of Overdense Meteor Trains</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>48 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS (April 12,
  2017)</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx923</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studies of meteor trails have until now been limited to relatively simple
models, with the trail often being treated as a conducting cylinder, and the
head (if considered at all) treated as a ball of ionized gas. In this article,
we bring the experience gleaned in other fields to the domain of meteor
studies, and adapt this prior knowledge to give a much clearer view of the
microscale physics and chemistry involved in meteor-trail formation, with
particular emphasis on the first 100 or so milliseconds of the trail formation.
We discuss and examine the combined physico-chemical effects of
meteor-generated and ablationally amplified cylindrical shock waves which
appear in the ambient atmosphere immediately surrounding the meteor train, as
well as the associated hyperthermal chemistry on the boundaries of the high
temperature postadiabatically expanding meteor train. We demonstrate that the
cylindrical shock waves produced by overdense meteors are sufficiently strong
to dissociate molecules in the ambient atmosphere when it is heated to
temperatures in the vicinity of 6,000 K, which substantially alters the
considerations of the chemical processes in and around the meteor train. We
demonstrate that some ambient O2, along with O2 that comes from the shock
dissociation of O3, survives the passage of the cylindrical shock wave, and
these constituents react thermally with meteor metal ions, thereby subsequently
removing electrons from the overdense meteor train boundary through fast,
temperature independent, dissociative recombination governed by the second
Damkohler number. Possible implications for trail diffusion and lifetimes are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03875</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>de Groote</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verlinde</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonnenschein</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flanagan</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neyens</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient, high-resolution resonance laser ionization spectroscopy using
  weak transitions to long-lived excited states</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 032502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.032502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Laser spectroscopic studies on minute samples of exotic radioactive nuclei
require very efficient experimental techniques. In addition, high resolving
powers are required to allow extraction of nu- clear structure information.
Here we demonstrate that by using weak atomic transitions, resonance laser
ionization spectroscopy is achieved with the required high efficiency (1-10%)
and precision (linewidths of tens of MHz). We illustrate experimentally and
through the use of simulations how the narrow experimental linewidths are
achieved and how distorted resonance ionization spec- troscopy lineshapes can
be avoided. The role of the delay of the ionization laser pulse with respect to
the excitation laser pulse is crucial: the use of a delayed ionization step
permits the best resolving powers and lineshapes. A high efficiency is
maintained if the intermediate level has a lifetime that is at least of the
order of the excitation laser pulse width. A model that describes this process
re- produces well the observed features and will help to optimize the
conditions for future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03880</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Ringel</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovrizhin</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantized gravitational responses and the sign problem</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is believed that not all quantum systems can be simulated efficiently
using classical computational resources. This notion is supported by the fact
that in quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) simulations for a large number of important
problems it is not known how to express the partition function in a sign-free
manner. The answer to the question --- whether there is an fundamental
obstruction to such a sign-free representation in generic quantum systems ---
remains unclear. Here, focussing on systems with bosonic degrees of freedom, we
show that quantized gravitational responses appear as obstructions to local
sign-free QMC. In condensed matter physics settings these responses, such as
thermal Hall conductance, are associated with fractional quantum Hall effects.
We show that similar arguments hold also in the case of spontaneously broken
time-reversal (TR) symmetry such as in the chiral phase of a perturbed quantum
Kagome antiferromagnet. The connection between quantized gravitational
responses and the sign problem is also clearly manifested in certain vertex
models, where TR symmetry is preserved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03887</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Karnas</keyname><forenames>Katarzyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawicki</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Products of finite order rotations and quantum gates universality</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP math.NT</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><msc-class>12E10, 12F05</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a product of two finite order quantum $SU(2)$-gates $U_1$, $U_2$
and ask when $U_1\cdot U_2$ has an infinite order. Using the fact that $SU(2)$
is a double cover of $SO(3)$ we actually study the product
$O(\gamma,\vec{k}_{12})$ of two rotations $O(\phi,\vec{k}_1)\in SO(3)$ and
$O(\phi,\vec{k}_2)\in SO(3)$ about axes $\vec{k}_1$, $\vec{k}_2\in
\mathbb{R}^3$. In particular we focus on the case when
$\vec{k}_1\cdot\vec{k}_2=0$, and $\phi_1=\phi=\phi_2$ are rational multiple of
$\pi$ and show that $\gamma$ is not a rational multiple of $\pi$ unless
$\phi\in\{\frac{k\pi}{2}:k\in\mathbb{Z}\}$. The proof presented in this paper
boils down to finding all pairs $\gamma,\phi\in \{a\pi : a\in\mathbb{Q}\}$ that
are solutions of $\cos\frac{\gamma}{2}=\cos^2\frac{\phi}{2}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03922</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>Jean Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papaderos</keyname><forenames>Polychronis</forenames></author></authors><title>Fitting Analysis using Differential Evolution Optimization (FADO):
  Spectral population synthesis through genetic optimization under
  self-consistency boundary conditions</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>25 pages, 12 figures, A&amp;A accepted</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628986</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The goal of population spectral synthesis (PSS) is to decipher from the
spectrum of a galaxy the mass, age and metallicity of its constituent stellar
populations. This technique has been established as a fundamental tool in
extragalactic research. It has been extensively applied to large spectroscopic
data sets, notably the SDSS, leading to important insights into the galaxy
assembly history. However, despite significant improvements over the past
decade, all current PSS codes suffer from two major deficiencies that inhibit
us from gaining sharp insights into the star-formation history (SFH) of
galaxies and potentially introduce substantial biases in studies of their
physical properties (e.g., stellar mass, mass-weighted stellar age and specific
star formation rate). These are i) the neglect of nebular emission in spectral
fits, consequently, ii) the lack of a mechanism that ensures consistency
between the best-fitting SFH and the observed nebular emission characteristics
of a star-forming (SF) galaxy. In this article, we present FADO (Fitting
Analysis using Differential evolution Optimization): a conceptually novel,
publicly available PSS tool with the distinctive capability of permitting
identification of the SFH that reproduces the observed nebular characteristics
of a SF galaxy. This so-far unique self-consistency concept allows us to
significantly alleviate degeneracies in current spectral synthesis. The
innovative character of FADO is further augmented by its mathematical
foundation: FADO is the first PSS code employing genetic differential evolution
optimization. This, in conjunction with other unique elements in its
mathematical concept (e.g., optimization of the spectral library using
artificial intelligence, convergence test, quasi-parallelization) results in
key improvements with respect to computational efficiency and uniqueness of the
best-fitting SFHs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03932</id><created>2017-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Brox</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Reliable Information Transmission along QCA Wires in the Presence of
  Non-Adiabatic Transitions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum dot cellular automata (QCA) computing schemes use arrays of quantum
dots as computational devices. Typically, these operate ideally by maintaining
arrays in their ground state to ensure correct computational output. For large
QCA circuits, thermal fluctuations make this impossible, so adiabatic clocking
has been proposed as a means of dividing large circuit computations into
subcircuit computations that are more reliable. In this report, it is shown
that wires and inverters can transmit information correctly via their excited
states just as well as their ground states. A characteristic example of a 4
cell wire is simulated, and a theoretical derivation of this result is given.
When, non-nearest neighbor interactions are included in the Hamiltonian, this
result still holds true. On the other hand, QCA majority gates and more complex
circuits give incorrect results when operated in excited states. These results
suggest that gates of reliable QCA circuits should be contained in smaller
clocking zones, while wires relaying information can be contained in larger
clocking zones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03943</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Allen-Perkins</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastor</keyname><forenames>Juan Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Estrada</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-walks degree assortativity in graphs and networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><msc-class>05C82, 05C75, 91D30, 92C42</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Degree ssortativity is the tendency for nodes of high degree (resp.low
degree) in a graph to be connected to high degree nodes (resp. to low degree
ones). It is sually quantified by the Pearson correlation coefficient of the
degree-degree correlation. Here we extend this concept to account for the
effect of second neighbours to a given node in a graph. That is, we consider
the two-walks degree of a node as the sum of all the degrees of its adjacent
nodes. The two-walks degree assortativity of a graph is then the Pearson
correlation coefficient of the two-walks degree-degree correlation. We found
here analytical expression for this two-walks degree assortativity index as a
function of contributing subgraphs. We then study all the 261,000 connected
graphs with 9 nodes and observe the existence of assortative-assortative and
disassortative-disassortative graphs according to degree and two-walks degree,
respectively. More surprinsingly, we observe a class of graphs which are degree
disassortative and two-walks degree assortative. We explain the existence of
some of these graphs due to the presence of certain topological features, such
as a node of low-degree connected to high-degree ones. More importantly, we
study a series of 49 real-world networks, where we observe the existence of the
disassortative-assortative class in several of them. In particular, all
biological networks studied here were in this class. We also conclude that no
graphs/networks are possible with assortative-disassortative structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03948</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Simenog</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grinyuk</keyname><forenames>B. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmenko</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On inefficiency of repulsive $\delta$-potentials in multidimensional
  spaces</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Ukrainian Journal of Physics, 2014, Vol. 59, No 12, p.1177-1182</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ujpe59.12.1177</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A complete account of correlations has been shown to make $\delta$-like
repulsive interaction potentials inefficient for any $N$-particle quantum
system in the $D$-dimensional space with $D\geq2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03950</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Zuo</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author></authors><title>Connections between transport of intensity equation and two-dimensional
  phase unwrapping</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>This paper was initially sumbitted to Applied Optics in March, 2016
  as a COMMENT. Unfortunately, it was rejected due to the strong opposition
  from one reviewer. However, I believe the points raised in the COMMENT is
  interesting and meaningful. So here I just want to share it with you all</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent publication [Appl. Opt. 55, 2418 (2016)], a method for
two-dimensional phase unwrapping based on the transport of intensity equation
(TIE) was studied. We wish to show that this approach is associated with the
standard least squares phase unwrapping algorithm, but with additional
numerical errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03957</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Ullah</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gluschke</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krogstrup</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xf8;rensen</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nyg&#xe5;rd</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micolich</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards low-dimensional hole systems in Be-doped GaAs nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 28, 134005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa6067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  GaAs was central to the development of quantum devices but is rarely used for
nanowire-based quantum devices with InAs, InSb and SiGe instead taking the
leading role. p-type GaAs nanowires offer a path to studying strongly-confined
0D and 1D hole systems with strong spin-orbit effects, motivating our
development of nanowire transistors featuring Be-doped p-type GaAs nanowires,
AuBe alloy contacts and patterned local gate electrodes towards making
nanowire-based quantum hole devices. We report on nanowire transistors with
traditional substrate back-gates and EBL-defined metal/oxide top-gates produced
using GaAs nanowires with three different Be-doping densities and various AuBe
contact processing recipes. We show that contact annealing only brings small
improvements for the moderately-doped devices under conditions of lower anneal
temperature and short anneal time. We only obtain good transistor performance
for moderate doping, with conduction freezing out at low temperature for
lowly-doped nanowires and inability to reach a clear off-state under gating for
the highly-doped nanowires. Our best devices give on-state conductivity 95 nS,
off-state conductivity 2 pS, on-off ratio ~$10^{4}$, and sub-threshold slope 50
mV/dec at T = 4 K. Lastly, we made a device featuring a moderately-doped
nanowire with annealed contacts and multiple top-gates. Top-gate sweeps show a
plateau in the sub-threshold region that is reproducible in separate cool-downs
and indicative of possible conductance quantization highlighting the potential
for future quantum device studies in this material system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03981</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xianyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Shengping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author></authors><title>A method for classifying orbits near asteroids</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Mechanica Sinica 30(3), 316-325, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10409-014-0034-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method for classifying orbits near asteroids under a polyhedral
gravitational field is presented, and may serve as a valuable reference for
spacecraft orbit design for asteroid exploration. The orbital dynamics near
asteroids are very complex. According to the variation in orbit characteristics
after being affected by gravitational perturbation during the periapsis
passage, orbits near an asteroid can be classified into 9 categories: (1)
surroundingto-surrounding, (2) surrounding-to-surface, (3)
surroundingto-infinity, (4) infinity-to-infinity, (5) infinity-to-surface, (6)
infinity-to-surrounding, (7) surface-to-surface, (8) surfaceto-surrounding, and
(9) surface-to- infinity. Assume that the orbital elements are constant near
the periapsis, the gravitation potential is expanded into a harmonic series.
Then, the influence of the gravitational perturbation on the orbit is studied
analytically. The styles of orbits are dependent on the argument of periapsis,
the periapsis radius, and the periapsis velocity. Given the argument of
periapsis, the orbital energy before and after perturbation can be derived
according to the periapsis radius and the periapsis velocity. Simulations have
been performed for orbits in the gravitational field of 216 Kleopatra. The
numerical results are well consistent with analytic predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03983</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Eivari</keyname><forenames>Hossein Asnaashari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghasemi</keyname><forenames>S. Alireza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tahmasbi</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rostami</keyname><forenames>Samare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faraji</keyname><forenames>Somayeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rasoulkhani</keyname><forenames>Robabe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goedecker</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amsler</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author></authors><title>A two-dimensional hexagonal sheet of TiO$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the ab initio discovery of a novel putative ground state for
quasi two-dimensional TiO$_2$ through a structural search using the minima
hopping method with an artificial neural network potential. The structure is
based on a honeycomb lattice and is energetically lower than the experimentally
reported lepidocrocite sheet by 7~meV/atom, and merely 13~meV/atom higher in
energy than the ground state rutile bulk structure. According to our
calculations, the hexagonal sheet is stable against mechanical stress, it is
chemically inert and can be deposited on various substrates without disrupting
the structure. Its properties differ significantly from all known TiO$_2$ bulk
phases with a large gap of 5.05~eV that can be tuned through strain
engineering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03985</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leng</keyname><forenames>Yong-bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Lu-yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Long-wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Ren-xian</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the Crosstalk Evaluation for Cavity BPM</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to pursue high-precision beam position measurements for the
free-electron laser (FEL) facilities, cavity beam position monitor (CBPM) is
employed to measure the transverse position which can meet the requirement of
position resolution with a sub-micrometer or even nanometer scale. But for the
pill-box cavity BPM, the possible existed crosstalk between the cavities will
have effects on the accurate measurement of beam position. Two methods, the
principle component analysis (PCA) method and the method of harmonic analysis,
are proposed in this paper to evaluate the crosstalk based on the experiment
dates from the low quality CBPM prototype in Shanghai Deep ultraviolet free
electron laser (SDUV-FEL) facility and high quality CBPM in Dalian Coherent
Light Source (DCLS), respectively. The results demonstrated that these two
methods are feasible in evaluating the crosstalk between the cavities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03990</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Tinggui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li-Jost</keyname><forenames>Xianqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Uniform Quantification of Correlations for Bipartite Systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95 (2017) 042316</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the relative entropy, we give a unified characterization of quantum
correlations for nonlocality, steerability, discord and entanglement for any
bipartite quantum states. For two-qubit states we show that the quantities
obtained from quantifying nonlocality, steerability, entanglement and discord
have strictly monotonic relationship. As for examples, the Bell diagonal states
are studied in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04005</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Makridin</keyname><forenames>Zakhar V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>Maxim V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-Dimensional Conservation Laws and Integrable Systems</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce a new property of two-dimensional integrable
systems -- existence of infinitely many local three-dimensional conservation
laws for pairs of integrable two-dimensional commuting flows. Infinitely many
three-dimensional local conservation laws for the Korteweg de Vries pair of
commuting flows and for the Benney commuting hydrodynamic chains are
constructed. As a by-product we established a new method for computation of
local conservation laws for three-dimensional integrable systems. The Mikhalev
equation and the dispersionless limit of the Kadomtsev--Petviashvili equation
are investigated. All known local and infinitely many new quasi-local
three-dimensional conservation laws are presented. Also four-dimensional
conservation laws are considered for couples of three-dimensional integrable
quasilinear systems and for triples of corresponding hydrodynamic chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04015</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Mongin</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Elise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berti</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasparian</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas-solid phase transition in laser multiple filamentation</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.stat-mech physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 133902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.133902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While propagating in transparent media, near-infrared multi-terawatt (TW)
laser beams break up in a multitude of filaments of typically 100-200 um
diameter with peak intensities as high as 10 to 100~TW/cm$^{2}$. We observe a
phase transition at incident beam intensities of 0.4~TW/cm$^2$, where the
interaction between filaments induce solid-like 2-dimensional crystals with a
2.7 mm lattice constant, independent of the initial beam diameter. Below
0.4~TW/cm$^2$, we evidence a mixed phase state in which some filaments are
closely packed in localized clusters, nucleated on inhomogeneities (seeds) in
the transverse intensity profile of the beam, and other are sparse with almost
no interaction with their neighbors, similar to a gas. This analogy with a
thermodynamic gas-solid phase transition is confirmed by calculating the
interaction Hamiltonian between neighboring filaments, which takes into account
the effect of diffraction, Kerr self-focusing and plasma generation. The shape
of the effective potential is close to a Morse potential with an equilibrium
bond length close to the observed value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04016</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruban</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation for waves on a nonuniform
  current</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 10 figures, published in 2012</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, 2012, Vol. 95, No. 9, pp. 486-491</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S002136401209010X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation with variable coefficients for surface
waves on a large-scale steady nonuniform current has been derived without the
assumption of a relative smallness of the velocity of the current. This
equation can describe with good accuracy the loss of modulation stability of a
wave coming to a counter current, leading to the formation of so called rogue
waves. Some theoretical estimates are compared to the numerical simulation with
the exact equations for a two-dimensional potential motion of an ideal fluid
with a free boundary over a nonuniform bottom at a nonzero average horizontal
velocity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04028</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Grimaldi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Signal coverage approach to the detection probability of hypothetical
  extraterrestrial emitters in the Milky Way</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 46273 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep46273</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The lack of evidence for the existence of extraterrestrial life, even the
simplest forms of animal life, makes it is difficult to decide whether the
search for extraterrestrial intelligence (SETI) is more a high-risk,
high-payoff endeavor than a futile attempt. Here we insist that even if
extraterrestrial civilizations do exist and communicate, the likelihood of
detecting their signals crucially depends on whether the Earth lies within a
region of the galaxy covered by such signals. By considering possible
populations of independent emitters in the galaxy, we build a statistical model
of the domain covered by hypothetical extraterrestrial signals to derive the
detection probability that the Earth is within such a domain. We show that for
general distributions of the signal longevity and directionality, the mean
number of detectable emitters is less than one even for detection probabilities
as large as 50\%, regardless of the number of emitters in the galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04041</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Shradha</forenames></author></authors><title>Flocking in one dimension: effect of update rules</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study the effect of parallel and random-sequential updates on the
dynamical properties of flocks in one dimension is considered. It is found that
the frequency of directional switching is increased for random-sequential
updates as compared to a parallel update. The nature of disorder to order
transition is also affected by the difference of updating mechanism:
discontinuous for parallel and continuous for random-sequential updates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04044</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Goyal</keyname><forenames>Anuj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathew</keyname><forenames>Kiran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hennig</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernatynskiy</keyname><forenames>Aleksandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stank</keyname><forenames>Christopher R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Samuel T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillpot</keyname><forenames>Simon R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uberuaga</keyname><forenames>Blas P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The conundrum of relaxation volumes in first-principles calculations of
  charge defects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The defect relaxation volumes obtained from density-functional theory (DFT)
calculations of charged vacancies and interstitials are much larger than their
neutral counterparts, seemingly unphysically large. In this work, we
investigate the possible reasons for this and revisit the methods that address
the calculation of charged defect structures in periodic DFT. We probe the
dependence of the proposed energy corrections to charged defect formation
energies on relaxation volumes and find that corrections such as the image
charge correction and the alignment correction, which can lead to sizable
changes in defect formation energies, have an almost negligible effect on the
charged defect relaxation volume. We also investigate the volume for the net
neutral defect reactions comprised of individual charged defects, and find that
the aggregate formation volumes have reasonable magnitudes. This work
highlights an important issue that, as for defect formation energies, the
defect formation volumes depend on the choice of reservoir. We show that
considering the change in volume of the electron reservoir in the formation
reaction of the charged defects, analogous to how volumes of atoms are
accounted for in defect formation volumes, can renormalize the formation
volumes of charged defects such that they are comparable to neutral defects.
This approach enables the description of the elastic properties of isolated
charged defects within the overall neutral material, beyond the context of the
overall defect reactions that produce the charged defect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04046</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xianyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Shengping</forenames></author></authors><title>Bifurcation of equilibrium points in the potential field of asteroid
  101955 Bennu</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 455 (4),
  3724-3734, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stability and topological structure of equilibrium points in the
potential field of the asteroid 101955 Bennu have been investigated with a
variable density and rotation period. A dimensionless quantity is introduced
for the nondimensionalization of the equations of motion, and this quantity can
indicate the effect of both the rotation period and bulk density of the
asteroid. Using the polyhedral model of the asteroid Bennu, the number and
position of the equilibrium points are calculated and illustrated by a contour
plot of the gravitational effective potential field. The topological structure
and the stability of the equilibrium points are also investigated using the
linearized method. The results show that there are nine equilibrium points in
the potential field of the asteroid Bennu, eight in the exterior of the body
and one in the interior of the body. Moreover, bifurcation will occur with a
variation of the density and rotation period. Different equilibrium points will
encounter each other and mix together. Thus, the number of equilibrium points
will change. The stability and topological structure of the equilibrium points
will also change because of the variation of the density and rotation period of
the asteroid. When considering the error of the density of Bennu, the range of
the dimensionless quantity covers the critical values that will lead to
bifurcation. This means that the stability of the equilibrium points is
uncertain, making the dynamical environment of Bennu much more complicated.
These bifurcations can help better understand the dynamic environment of an
irregular-shaped asteroid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04048</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Naudts</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Emergence of the Coulomb Forces in Quantum Electrodynamics</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Presented at the 5th Winter Workshop on Non-Perturbative Quantum
  Field Theory, 22-24 March 2017, Sophia-Antipolis (France)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple transformation of field variables eliminates Coulomb forces from the
theory of quantum electrodynamics. This suggests that Coulomb forces may be an
emergent phenomenon rather than being fundamental. This possibility is
investigated in the context of reducible quantum electrodynamics. It is shown
that states exist which bind free photon and free electron fields. The binding
energy peaks in the long-wavelength limit. This makes it plausible that Coulomb
forces result from the interaction of the electron/positron field with
long-wavelength transversely polarized photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04065</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Scheffel</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindvall</keyname><forenames>Kristoffer</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing time-spectral solution of initial-value problems</title><categories>physics.comp-ph math.NA</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time-spectral solution of ordinary and partial differential equations is
often regarded as an inefficient approach. The associated extension of the time
domain, as compared to finite difference methods, is believed to result in
uncomfortably many numerical operations and high memory requirements. It is
shown in this work that performance is substantially enhanced by the
introduction of algorithms for temporal and spatial subdomains in combination
with sparse matrix methods. The accuracy and efficiency of the recently
developed time spectral, generalized weighted residual method (GWRM) is
compared to that of the explicit Lax-Wendroff method and the implicit
Crank-Nicolson method. Three initial-value PDEs are employed as model problems;
the 1D Burger equation, a forced 1D wave equation and a coupled system of 14
linearized ideal magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) equations. It is found that the GWRM
is more efficient than the time-stepping methods at high accuracies. For
time-averaged solution of the two-time-scales, forced wave equation GWRM
performance exceeds the finite difference methods by an order of magnitude both
in terms of CPU time and memory requirement. Favourable scaling of CPU time and
memory usage with the number of temporal and spatial subdomains is demonstrated
for the MHD equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04074</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Scheffel</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindvall</keyname><forenames>Kristoffer</forenames></author></authors><title>SIR - an Efficient Solver for Systems of Equations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Semi-Implicit Root solver (SIR) is an iterative method for globally
convergent solution of systems of nonlinear equations. Since publication, SIR
has proven robustness for a great variety of problems. We here present MATLAB
and MAPLE codes for SIR, that can be easily implemented in any application
where linear or nonlinear systems of equations need be solved efficiently. The
codes employ recently developed efficient sparse matrix algorithms and improved
numerical differentiation. SIR convergence is quasi-monotonous and approaches
second order in the proximity of the real roots. Global convergence is usually
superior to that of Newtons method, being a special case of the method.
Furthermore the algorithm cannot land on local minima, as may be the case for
Newtons method with linesearch.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04088</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tennyson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahimi</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tse</keyname><forenames>Lisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vibhakar</keyname><forenames>Anuradha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akello-Egwel</keyname><forenames>Dolica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Daniel B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzarasova</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamilton</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksch</keyname><forenames>Dagmar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wren-Little</keyname><forenames>Keir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruckmeier</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>Ankur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartschat</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogaerts</keyname><forenames>Annemie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Booth</keyname><forenames>Jean-Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goeckner</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassouni</keyname><forenames>Khaled</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itikawa</keyname><forenames>Yukikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braams</keyname><forenames>Bastiaan J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krishnakumar</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laricchiuta</keyname><forenames>Annarita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Nigel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sumeet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrovic</keyname><forenames>Zoran Lj.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Kang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranjan</keyname><forenames>Alok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauf</keyname><forenames>Shahid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulze</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Miles M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ventzek</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitehead</keyname><forenames>J. Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Jung-Sik</forenames></author></authors><title>QDB: a new database of plasma chemistries and reactions</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 7 figures, 10 tables</comments><journal-ref>Plasma Phys. Sci. Tech., 26, 055014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6595/aa6669</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most challenging and recurring problems when modelling plasmas is
the lack of data on key atomic and molecular reactions that drive plasma
processes. Even when there are data for some reactions, complete and validated
datasets of chemistries are rarely available. This hinders research on plasma
processes and curbs development of industrial applications. The QDB project
aims to address this problem by providing a platform for provision, exchange,
and validation of chemistry datasets. A new data model developed for QDB is
presented. QDB collates published data on both electron scattering and
heavy-particle reactions. These data are formed into reaction sets, which are
then validated against experimental data where possible. This process produces
both complete chemistry sets and identifies key reactions that are currently
unreported in the literature. Gaps in the datasets can be filled using
established theoretical methods. Initial validated chemistry sets for
SF$_6$/CF$_4$/O$_2$ and SF$_6$/CF$_4$/N$_2$/H$_2$ are presented as examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04090</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Naseem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tutkun</keyname><forenames>Murat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cal</keyname><forenames>Ra&#xfa;l Bayo&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent Boundary Layer Features via Lagrangian Coherent Structures,
  Proper Orthogonal Decomposition and Dynamic Mode Decomposition</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-speed stereo PIV-measurements have been performed in a turbulent
boundary layer at Re$_{\theta}$ of 9800 in order to elucidate the coherent
structures. Snapshot proper orthogonal decomposition (POD) and dynamic mode
decomposition (DMD) are used to visualize the flow structure depending on the
turbulent kinetic energy and frequency content. The first six POD and DMD modes
show the largest and the lowest amount of energy and frequency, respectively.
Lagrangian coherent structure (LCS) based on the algorithm developed using the
variational theory is also applied to track the flow via attracting and
repelling trajectories. The shapes and the length of the trajectories show
variation with increasing advection time. LCS trajectories are overlayed with
the individual POD and DMD modes. Repelling and attracting lines cover the
structure of these modes. Reconstructed flow fields from individual POD modes
are also used to generate new LCS trajectories. The energy and frequency
content have a direct impact on the length of the trajectories, where the
longest reconstructed trajectories associate with the higher energy and lower
frequency modes, and vise verse. The multiple intersection points between the
repelling and attracting lines marked the low momentum regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04092</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kazim</keyname><forenames>Shafaq</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Alka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Sachin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gajar</keyname><forenames>Bikash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Lalit M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Monu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Govind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husale</keyname><forenames>Sudhir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Anurag</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Sangeeta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ojha</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Induced Electron-Phonon Scattering Mediated Resistive Switching in
  Nanostructured Nb Thin Film Superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports, 7, 881 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-00976-1</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The elemental Nb is mainly investigated for its eminent superconducting
properties. In contrary, we report of a relatively unexplored property, namely,
its superior optoelectronic property in reduced dimension. We demonstrate here
that nanostructured Nb thin films (NNFs), under optical illumination, behave as
room temperature photo-switches and exhibit bolometric features below its
superconducting critical temperature. Both photo-switch and superconducting
bolometric behavior are monitored by its resistance change with light in
visible and near infrared (NIR) wavelength range. Unlike the conventional
photodetectors, the NNF devices switch to higher resistive states with light
and the corresponding resistivity change is studied with thickness and grain
size variations. At low temperature in its superconducting state, the light
exposure shifts the superconducting transition towards lower temperature. The
room temperature photon sensing nature of the NNF is explained by the photon
assisted electron-phonon scattering mechanism while the low temperature light
response is mainly related to the heat generation which essentially changes the
effective temperature for the device and the device is capable of sensing a
temperature difference of few tens of milli-kelvins. The observed
photo-response on the transport properties of NNFs can be very important for
future superconducting photon detectors, bolometers and phase slip based device
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04093</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Elettro</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandgeorge</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neukirch</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Elastocapillary coiling of an elastic rod inside a drop</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>J Elast (2017) 127: 235</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10659-016-9611-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Capillary forces acting at the surface of a liquid drop can be strong enough
to deform small objects and recent studies have provided several examples of
elastic instabilities induced by surface tension. We present such an example
where a liquid drop sits on a straight fiber, and we show that the liquid
attracts the fiber which thereby coils inside the drop. We derive the
equilibrium equations for the system, compute bifurcation curves, and show the
packed fiber may adopt several possible configurations inside the drop. We use
the energy of the system to discriminate between the different configurations
and find a intermittent regime between two-dimensional and three-dimensional
solutions as more and more fiber is driven inside the drop.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04096</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Mizus</keyname><forenames>Irina I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alijah</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zobov</keyname><forenames>Nikolai F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lodi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyuberis</keyname><forenames>Aleksandra A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurchenko</keyname><forenames>Sergei N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennyson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polyansky</keyname><forenames>Oleg L.</forenames></author></authors><title>ExoMol molecular line lists XX: a comprehensive line list for H$_3^+$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 7 tables</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not Ras Astron. Soc. 468, 1717-1725 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  H$_3^+$ is a ubiquitous and important astronomical species whose spectrum has
been observed in the interstellar medium, planets and tentatively in the
remnants of supernova SN1897a. Its role as a cooler is important for gas giant
planets and exoplanets, and possibly the early Universe. All this makes the
spectral properties, cooling function and partition function of H$_3^+$ key
parameters for astronomical models and analysis. A new high-accuracy, very
extensive line list for H$_3^+$ called MiZATeP was computed as part of the
ExoMol project alongside a temperature-dependent cooling function and partition
function as well as lifetimes for %individual excited states. These data are
made available in electronic form as supplementary data to this article and at
http://www.exomol.com
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04101</id><created>2017-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Dimple</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>Bhupendra Nath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Nunu</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractional Order Heat Equation in Higher Space-Time Dimensions</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, Keywords: Fractional Calculus, Fractional Solutions,
  Fractional Heat Equation</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Basic and Applied Engineering Research, p-ISSN:
  2350-0077; e-ISSN: 2350-0255; Volume 3, Issue 8; April-June, 2016, pp.
  724-727</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study fractional order heat equation in higher space-time
dimensions and offer specific role of heat flows in various fractional
dimensions. We offer fractional solutions of the heat equations thus obtained,
and examine the associated implications in various limiting cases. We
anticipate perspective applications of fractional heat flow solutions in
physical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04104</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Moulson</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental determination of $V_{us}$ from kaon decays</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 tables, 2 figures. Proceedings of the 9th International
  Workshop on the CKM Unitarity Triangle, 28 November-3 December 2016, Tata
  Institute for Fundamental Research (TIFR), Mumbai, India</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The status of the experimental determination of $V_{us}$ from $K_{\ell3}$ and
$K_{\mu2}$ decays is reviewed. Factors currently limiting the precision of the
evaluation of $V_{us}$ from kaon decays and prospects for new measurements
within the next few years are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04108</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Truebenbacher</keyname><forenames>Egon</forenames></author></authors><title>The Klein Paradox: A New Treatment</title><categories>physics.gen-ph hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. J. Phys. 36 (2015) 055015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac equation requires a treatment of the step potential that differs
fundamentally from the traditional treatment, because the Dirac plane waves,
besides momentum and spin, are characterized by a quantum number with the
physical meaning of sign of charge. Since the Hermitean operator corresponding
to this quantum number does not commute with the step potential, the time
displacement parameter used in the ansatz of the stationary state does not have
the physical meaning of energy. Therefore there are no paradoxal values of the
energy. The new solution of the Dirac equation with a step potential is
obtained. This solution, again, allows for phenomena of the Klein paradox type,
but in addition it contains a positron amplitude localized at the threshold
point of the step potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04113</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Devizorova</keyname><forenames>Zh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-valve effect in S/F/F and F/S/F structures of atomic thickness</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the peculiarities of the electron band structure strongly affect
the spin-valve effect in heterostructures consisting of a superconductor (S)
and two ferromagnetic layers F1 and F2. For the S/F1/F2 systems the energy
shift between the electron bands in the S and F2 layers determines wether the
critical temperature $T_c$ of the superconductor increases or decreases as a
function of the angle $\theta$ between the magnetic moments in the
ferromagnets. In the case of half-metallic F2 layer the type of the spin-valve
effect becomes dependent on the position of the only occupied spin-band and the
minimum of $T_c$ may correspond to the anti-parallel, parallel or non-collinear
orientations of magnetic moments. Also, for the first time, we analytically
demonstrate the possibility of the triplet spin-valve effect in the
F/S/half-metal structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04120</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lagos</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paredes</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retamal</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;sar</forenames></author></authors><title>High Precision Energy Measurements from the Analysis of Wide Spectral
  Features. Application to the fluorescence of YAG:Ce3+</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, short paper written for submission to a
  scientific journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Advantage is taken of a complete and precise experimental study of the
luminescent properties of yttrium aluminium garnet doped with Ce, previously
accomplished by other authors, to confirm the accuracy of the invoked
theoretical methods for dealing with the realistic calculation of the
electromagnetic spectra of condensed phases. The fluorescent spectra at T=0 and
T=250 K of YAG:Ce(3+) were calculated with no adjustable parameter, giving
complete agreement with experiment. The energy released by the electronic
transitions was determined with precision better than 5\% the full width at
half maximum of the spectral features. Thermal quenching of the fluorescent
yield is discussed and calculated in a less accurate way, but anyway showing
good agreement with experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04121</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>S C</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on 'Relativistic electron wavepackets carrying angular momentum'</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a comment on arXiv:1611.04445 (PRL, 118, 114801 (2017)). It is
pointed out that the fundamental problems in light beam vortices and the
relativistic electron vortices are not identical and have subtle differences.
The significance of two length scales is underlined for the electron vortices.
Local gauge transformation on the Gordon current admits vortex structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04122</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Saurabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication of Simple Apparatus for Resistivity Measurement in High
  Temperature Range 300-620 K</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple and low cost apparatus has been designed and built to measure the
electrical resistivity, ($\rho$), of metal and semiconductors in 300-620 K
temperature range. The present design is suitable to do measurement on
rectangular bar sample by using conventional four-probe dc method. A small
heater is made on the sample mounting copper block to achieve the desired
temperature. Heat loss from sample holder is minimize by using very low thermal
conductive insulator block. This unique design of heater and minimized heat
loss from sample platform provide uniform sample temperature and also have very
good thermal stability during the measurement. The electrical contacts of
current leads and potential probes on the sample are done by using very thin
(42 SWG) copper wires and high temperature silver paste. The use of limited
components and small heater design make present instrument very simple, light
weight, easy to sample mount, small in size, and low cost. To calibrate the
instrument pure nickel sample was used, and two other materials
La$_{0.7}$Sr$_{0.3}$MnO$_{3}$ (LSMO) and LaCoO$_{3}$ (LCO) were also
characterized to demonstrate the accuracy of this set-up. $\rho$(T) behavior on
these samples were found to be in good agreement with the reported data. The
metal-insulator transition for LSMO (T$_{MI}$ = $\sim$358 K) and the
insulator-metal transition for LCO (T$_{IM}$ = $\sim$540 K) were clearly
observed and these transitions temperature were also consistent with those
reported in literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04123</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzdin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous currents in superconducting systems with strong spin-orbit
  coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 077001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.077001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Rashba spin-orbit coupling at the interface between a
superconductor and a ferromagnet should produce a spontaneous current in the
atomic thickness region near the interface. This current is counter-balanced by
the superconducting screening current flowing in the region of the width of the
London penetration depth near the interface. Such current carrying state
creates a magnetic field near the superconductor surface, generates a stray
magnetic field outside the sample edges, changes the slope of the temperature
dependence of the critical field $H_{c3}$ and may generate the spontaneous
Abrikosov vortices near the interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04125</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Olson</keyname><forenames>S. Jay</forenames></author></authors><title>Life-hostile conditions in the early universe can increase the
  present-day odds of observing extragalactic life</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-energy astrophysical events that cause galaxy-scale extinctions have
been proposed as a way to explain or mollify the Fermi Paradox, by making the
universe at earlier times more dangerous for evolving life, and reducing its
present-day prevalence. Here, we present an anthropic argument that a more
dangerous early universe can have the opposite effect, actually increasing
estimates for the amount of visible extragalactic life at the present cosmic
time. This occurs when civilizations are assumed to expand and displace
possible origination sites for the evolution of life, and estimates are made by
assuming that humanity has appeared at a typical time. The effect is not seen
if advanced life is assumed to always remain stationary, with no displacement
of habitable worlds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04140</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Blumenhagen</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herschmann</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author></authors><title>Challenges for Moduli Stabilization and String Cosmology near the
  Conifold</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Proceedings prepared for the &quot;Workshop on Geometry and Physics&quot;,
  November 2016, Ringberg Castle, Germany</comments><report-no>MPP-2017-74</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This brief article reviews a recently proposed scenario of moduli
stabilization constructed in the vicinity of a conifold locus in the complex
structure moduli space. We discuss typical features of moduli stabilization due
to the logarithmic structure of the periods over the Calabi-Yau threefold.
Integrating out heavy moduli implies exponential terms in the superpotential
very reminiscent of non-perturbative contributions. Ultimately, these terms can
lead to an alignment of axions potentially realizing large-field inflation. Our
goal is to investigate common issues appearing for moduli stabilization near
the conifold and subsequent applications to string cosmology. Even though this
setup needs to be understood as a toy model, a closer look at the validity of
the effective theories reveals characteristic obstacles, which are likely to
occur in more serious scenarios as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04147</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolyansky</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panferov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juchnowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle Production in Strong Time-dependent Fields</title><categories>hep-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures, Lecture Notes based on arXiv:hep-ph/9809227 and
  arxiv:1607.08775; to appear in Proceedings of the Helmholtz International
  Summer School on &quot;Quantum Field Theory at the Limits: From Strong Fields to
  Heavy Quarks&quot;, July 18-30, 2016, Dubna, Russia</comments><report-no>DESY-PROC-2016-04</report-no><doi>10.3204/DESY-PROC-2016-04/Blaschke</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In these lecture notes we give an introduction to the kinetic equation
approach to pair production form the vacuum in strong, time-dependent external
fields (dynamical Schwinger process). We first give a derivation of the kinetic
equation with the source term for the case of fermions starting from the Dirac
equation and for bosons from the Klein-Gordon equation. In a second part we
discuss the application of the approach to the situation of external field
pulses as single-sheeted functions of time (like the Sauter-pulse) and as
multi- sheeted functions approximating the situation in the focal point of
counter-propagating laser beams. Special emphasis is on the discussion of the
time evolution of the system that exhibits the characteristics of a
field-induced phase transition for which we discuss the behaviour of the
entropy and particle density of the system. We give an outlook to applications
of the approach in describing particle production in strong fields formed in
particle and nuclear collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04158</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Barbier</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macris</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>I-MMSE relations in random linear estimation and a sub-extensive
  interpolation method</title><categories>cs.IT cond-mat.dis-nn math.IT</categories><comments>Presented at the International Symposium on Information Theory (ISIT)
  2017, Aachen, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Consider random linear estimation with Gaussian measurement matrices and
noise. One can compute infinitesimal variations of the mutual information under
infinitesimal variations of the signal-to-noise ratio or of the measurement
rate. We discuss how each variation is related to the minimum mean-square error
and deduce that the two variations are directly connected through a very simple
identity. The main technical ingredient is a new interpolation method called
&quot;sub-extensive interpolation method&quot;. We use it to provide a new proof of an
I-MMSE relation recently found by Reeves and Pfister [1] when the measurement
rate is varied. Our proof makes it clear that this relation is intimately
related to another I-MMSE relation also recently proved in [2]. One can
directly verify that the identity relating the two types of variation of mutual
information is indeed consistent with the one letter replica symmetric formula
for the mutual information, first derived by Tanaka [3] for binary signals, and
recently proved in more generality in [1,2,4,5] (by independent methods).
However our proof is independent of any knowledge of Tanaka's formula.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04185</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Hai-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Zi-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wei-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aihara</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ying-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Partially unstable attractors in networks of forced integrate-and-fire
  oscillators</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/s11071-017-3490-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The asymptotic attractors of a nonlinear dynamical system play a key role in
the long-term physically observable behaviors of the system. The study of
attractors and the search for distinct types of attractor have been a central
task in nonlinear dynamics. In smooth dynamical systems, an attractor is often
enclosed completely in its basin of attraction with a finite distance from the
basin boundary. Recent works have uncovered that, in neuronal networks,
unstable attractors with a remote basin can arise, where almost every point on
the attractor is locally transversely repelling. Herewith we report our
discovery of a class of attractors: partially unstable attractors, in
pulse-coupled integrate-and-fire networks subject to a periodic forcing. The
defining feature of such an attractor is that it can simultaneously possess
locally stable and unstable sets, both of positive measure. Exploiting the
structure of the key dynamical events in the network, we develop a symbolic
analysis that can fully explain the emergence of the partially unstable
attractors. To our knowledge, such exotic attractors have not been reported
previously, and we expect them to arise commonly in biological networks whose
dynamics are governed by pulse (or spike) generation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04196</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Mercati</keyname><forenames>Flavio</forenames></author></authors><title>Thin shells of dust in a compact universe</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages + 8 pages of appendices</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I present the first analytical study of gravitational collapse in a compact
CMC foliation with $S^3$ spatial topology. The solutions I find, in this
context, will be both solutions of Shape Dynamics and General Relativity. The
aim is to describe a system undergoing gravitational collapse in Shape
Dynamics, so a well-justified and useful simplification is to assume spherical
symmetry. This kills all the local gravitational degrees of freedom, but some
nontrivial degrees of freedom are recovered by introducing matter. The simplest
form of matter is infinitely thin spherical shells of dust, of which I need at
least two in order to have a nontrivial dynamics. With a single shell the
system is dynamically trivial, but it nevertheless admits a solution which
represents a `frozen' shell at equilibrium in a globally de Sitter universe.
Such a solution is, to my knowledge, new. I am able to solve analytically also
the case with two shells, which has a nontrivial dynamics. When the rest mass
of one shell is much smaller than the other, the system is suitable to model a
compact universe in which one subsystem (the `light' shell) undergoes
gravitational collapse while the rest of the matter (the `heavy' shell) plays
the role of spectator. It turns out that, if the cosmological constant is zero
or positive but small, and the rest mass of the two shells are sufficiently
different, when the `light' shells collapses the ADM equations become
ill-defined and cease to admit a solution. The shape-dynamical description,
however, seems still well defined and can be continued past this point,
possibly signalling a departure of Shape Dynamics from exact equivalence with
General Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04202</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holec</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunstan</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Graphite Under Compression: Shift of Layer Breathing and Shear Modes
  Frequencies with Interlayer Spacing</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Layered materials have huge potential in various applications due to their
extraordinary properties. To determine the interlayer interaction (or
equivalently the layer spacing under different perturbations) is of critical
importance. In this letter, we focus on one of the most prominent layered
materials, graphite, and theoretically quantify the relationship between its
interlayer spacing and the vibrational frequencies of its layer breathing and
shear modes, which are measures of the interlayer interaction. The method used
here to determine the interlayer interaction can be further applied to other
layered materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
