<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:38:31Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-02-08" from="2016-02-07" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0808.1490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0808.1490</id><created>2008-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chesnokov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries and exact solutions of the rotating shallow water equations</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>35C05; 76B15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lie symmetry analysis is applied to study the nonlinear rotating shallow
water equations. The 9-dimensional Lie algebra of point symmetries admitted by
the model is found. It is shown that the rotating shallow water equations are
related with the classical shallow water model with the change of variables.
The derived symmetries are used to generate new exact solutions of the rotating
shallow equations. In particular, a new class of time-periodic solutions with
quasi-closed particle trajectories is constructed and studied. The symmetry
reduction method is also used to obtain some invariant solutions of the model.
Examples of these solutions are presented with a brief physical interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.0842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.0842</id><created>2012-08-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naruse</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsui</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuyama</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of Self-binding in Monolayer $^3$He</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 109, 235306 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.235306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report clear experimental signatures of the theoretically unexpected
gas-liquid transition in the first three monolayers of $^3$He adsorbed on
graphite. The transition is inferred from the linear density dependence of the
$\gamma$-coefficient of the heat capacity measured in the degenerate region (2
$\le T \le$80 mK) below a critical liquid density ($\rho_{c0}$). Surprisingly,
the measured $\rho_{c0}$ values (0.6$\sim$0.9 nm$^{-2}$) are nearly the same
for all these monolayers in spite of their quite different environments. We
conclude that the ground-state of $^3$He in strict two dimensions is not a
dilute quantum gas but a self-bound quantum liquid with the lowest density ever
found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.0936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.0936</id><created>2012-10-02</created><updated>2012-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ru</keyname><forenames>Eric C. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Somerville</keyname><forenames>Walter R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augui&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative correction in approximate treatments of electromagnetic
  scattering by point and body scatterers</title><categories>physics.optics math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 87, 012504 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.87.012504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transition-matrix ($T$-matrix) approach provides a general formalism to
study scattering problems in various areas of physics, including acoustics
(scalar fields) and electromagnetics (vector fields), and is related to the
theory of the scattering matrix ($S$-matrix) used in quantum mechanics and
quantum field theory. Focusing on electromagnetic scattering, we highlight an
alternative formulation of the $T$-matrix approach, based on the use of the
reactance matrix or $K$-matrix, which is more suited to formal studies of
energy conservation constraints (such as the optical theorem). We show in
particular that electrostatics or quasi-static approximations can be corrected
within this framework to satisfy the energy conservation constraints associated
with radiation. A general formula for such a radiative correction is explicitly
obtained, and empirical expressions proposed in earlier studies are shown to be
special cases of this general formula. This work therefore provides a
justification of the empirical radiative correction to the dipolar
polarizability and a generalization of this correction to any types of point or
body scatterers of arbitrary shapes, including higher multipolar orders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.2601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.2601</id><created>2012-12-11</created><updated>2015-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stoica</keyname><forenames>Ovidiu Cristinel</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Measurement and Initial Conditions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Theor. Phys., 55(3), 1897-1911 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-015-2829-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum measurement finds the observed system in a collapsed state, rather
than in the state predicted by the Schr\&quot;odinger equation. Yet there is a
relatively spread opinion that the wavefunction collapse can be explained by
unitary evolution (for instance in the decoherence approach, if we take into
account the environment).
  In this article it is proven a mathematical result which severely restricts
the initial conditions for which measurements have definite outcomes, if pure
unitary evolution is assumed. This no-go theorem remains true even if we take
the environment into account. The result does not forbid a unitary description
of the measurement process, it only shows that such a description is possible
only for very restricted initial conditions.
  The existence of such restrictions of the initial conditions can be
understood in the four-dimensional block universe perspective, as a requirement
of global self-consistency of the solutions of the Schr\&quot;odinger equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.0112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.0112</id><created>2013-09-30</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>H&#xe9;bert-Dufresne</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allard</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Jean-Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dub&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Louis J.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the constrained growth of complex scale-independent systems</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages and 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scale independence is a ubiquitous feature of complex systems which implies a
highly skewed distribution of resources with no characteristic scale. Research
has long focused on why systems as varied as protein networks, evolution and
stock actions all feature scale independence. Assuming that they simply do, we
focus here on describing how this behaviour emerges, in contrast to more
idealized models usually considered. We arrive at the conjecture that a minimal
model to explain the growth towards scale independence involves only two
coupled dynamical features: the first is the well-known preferential attachment
principle and the second is a general form of delayed temporal scaling. While
the first is sufficient, the second is present in all studied data and appears
to maximize the speed of convergence to true scale independence. The delay in
this temporal scaling acts as a coupling between population growth and
individual activity. Together, these two dynamical properties appear to pave a
precise evolution path, such that even an instantaneous snapshot of a
distribution is enough to reconstruct the past of the system and predict its
future. We validate our approach and confirm its usefulness on diverse spheres
of human activities ranging from scientific and artistic productivity, to
sexual relations and online traffic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.0384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.0384</id><created>2013-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Sucheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Huanyang</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation optics with Fabry-P\'erot resonances</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 19 figures, submitted to Nature Photonics</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 5: 8680 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep08680</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transformation optics is a powerful tool to design various novel devices,
such as invisibility cloak. Fantastic effects from this technique are usually
accompanied with singular mappings, resulting in challenging implementations
and narrow bands of working frequencies. Here in this article, we find that
Fabry-P\'erot resonances can be used to design various transformation optical
devices that are not only easy to realize but also can work well for a set of
resonant frequencies (multiple frequencies). As an example, we fabricate a
prototype for a cylindrical concentrator for microwaves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7396</id><created>2014-01-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Chesnokov</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>Maxim V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of nonlinear waves in a rarefied bubbly flow</title><categories>nlin.SI physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>35Q83, 35Q35, 35L60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The one-dimension Russo--Smereka kinetic equation describing the propagation
of nonlinear concentration waves in a rarefied bubbly fluid is considered.
Reductions of the model to finite component systems are derived. Stability of
the bubbly flow in terms of hyperbolicity of the kinetic equation is studied.
Conservation form of the model is proposed and numerical solution of the Cauchy
problem with discontinuous initial data is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.6187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.6187</id><created>2014-02-25</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drissi</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the spreading of large-scale wildland fires</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 8 figures, presented in CFM Bordeaux,France(August 2013)
  and at Large scale wildland fires conference in Missoula, USA(May, 2014)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The objective of the present study is twofold. First, the last developments
and validation results of a hybrid model designed to simulate fire patterns in
heterogeneous landscapes are presented. The model combines the features of a
stochastic small-world network model with those of a deterministic
semi-physical model of the interaction between burning and non-burning cells
that strongly depends on local conditions of wind, topography, and vegetation.
Radiation and convection from the flaming zone, and radiative heat loss to the
ambient are considered in the preheating process of unburned cells. Second, the
model is applied to an Australian grassland fire experiment as well as to a
real fire that took place in Corsica in 2009. Predictions compare favorably to
experiments in terms of rate of spread, area and shape of the burn. Finally,
the sensitivity of the model outcomes (here the rate of spread) to six input
parameters is studied using a two-level full factorial design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.7523</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.7523</id><created>2014-04-29</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Haihu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Qinjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leonardi</keyname><forenames>Christopher R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmieschek</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narv&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Bruce D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valocchi</keyname><forenames>Albert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harting</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiphase lattice Boltzmann simulations for porous media applications
  -- a review</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.comp-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>50 pages, 13 figures in Computational Geosciences (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Over the last two decades, lattice Boltzmann methods have become an
increasingly popular tool to compute the flow in complex geometries such as
porous media. In addition to single phase simulations allowing, for example, a
precise quantification of the permeability of a porous sample, a number of
extensions to the lattice Boltzmann method are available which allow to study
multiphase and multicomponent flows on a pore scale level. In this article we
give an extensive overview on a number of these diffuse interface models and
discuss their advantages and disadvantages. Furthermore, we shortly report on
multiphase flows containing solid particles, as well as implementation details
and optimization issues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.6110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.6110</id><created>2014-06-23</created><updated>2015-02-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bradler</keyname><forenames>Kamil</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent information of one-mode Gaussian channels -- the general case
  of nonzero added classical noise</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2: better terminology, some parts rewritten, to appear in Journal of
  Physics A</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics A 48, 125301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/12/125301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that whenever the coherent information of a one-mode Gaussian
channel is non-zero its supremum is achieved for the infinite input power. This
is a well established fact for the zero added classical noise, whereas the
nonzero case has not been studied in detail. The presented analysis fills the
gap for three canonical classes of one-mode Gaussian channels: the lossy,
amplifying and additive classical noise channel class. For the remaining
one-mode Gaussian channel classes the coherent information is known to vanish.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.2086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.2086</id><created>2014-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Moffat</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Gravity and the Cosmological Constant Problem</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>To be published in the proceedings of the First Karl Schwarzschild
  Meeting at FIAS, Frankfurt am Main, Germany 22-26 July, 2014, by
  Springer-Verlag</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the 1st Karl Schwarzschild Meeting on Gravitational
  Physics, Springer, 2016, p. 299</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A finite and unitary nonlocal formulation of quantum gravity is applied to
the cosmological constant problem. The entire functions in momentum space at
the graviton-standard model particle loop vertices generate an exponential
suppression of the vacuum density and the cosmological constant to produce
agreement with their observational bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3242</id><created>2014-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixed quantal-semiquantal dynamics with stochastic particles for
  backreaction</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 141, 144106 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4897532</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mixed quantal-semiquantal theory is presented in which the semiquantal
squeezed-state wave packet describes the heavy degrees of freedom. We first
derive mean-field equations of motion from the time-dependent variational
principle. Then, in order to take into account the interparticle correlation,
in particular the 'quantum backreaction' beyond the mean-field approximation,
we introduce the stochastic particle description for both the quantal and
semiquantal parts. A numerical application on a model of O2 scattering from a
Pt surface demonstrates that the proposed scheme gives correct asymptotic
behavior of the scattering probability, with improvement over the mixed
quantum-classical scheme with Bohmian particles, which is comprehended by
comparing the Bohmian and the stochastic trajectories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.0173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.0173</id><created>2014-10-01</created><updated>2015-09-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kiselev</keyname><forenames>Arthemy V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The right-hand side of the Jacobi identity: to be naught or not to be?</title><categories>math-ph math.DG math.MP math.SG nlin.SI</categories><comments>Proc. XXIII Int. conference &quot;Integrable systems &amp; quantum symmetries&quot;
  (22-28 June 2015, CVUT Prague, Czech Republic); illustration to
  arXiv:1312.1262 [math-ph] and arXiv:1312.4140 [math-ph]; 17 pages. Main
  example (sec.2) = [previously unpublished] Appendix in arXiv:1312.4140 (pp.
  i-iii), main counterexample (sec.4) rephrased from arXiv:1302.4388 (joint
  with S.Ringers)</comments><msc-class>37K10, 53D17, 70S05, secondary 35A15, 37K25, 81S10</msc-class><journal-ref>J.Phys.: Conf.Ser. 670 (2016) 012030, 1-17</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/670/1/012030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The geometric approach [1312.1262] to iterated variations of local
functionals -- e.g., of the (master-)action functional -- resulted in an
extension of the deformation quantisation technique to the set-up of Poisson
models of field theory [IHES/M/15/13]. It also allowed of a rigorous proof
([1312.1262],[1210.0726]) for the main inter-relations between the
Batalin-Vilkovisky (BV) Laplacian $\Delta$ and variational Schouten bracket.
The ad hoc use of these relations had been a known analytic difficulty in the
BV-formalism for quantisation of gauge systems; now achieved, the proof does
actually not require the assumption of graded-commutativity [1210.0726].
Explained in our previous work, geometry's self-regularisation is rendered by
Gel'fand's calculus of singular linear integral operators supported on the
diagonal.
  We now illustrate that analytic technique by inspecting the validity
mechanism [1312.4140] for the graded Jacobi identity which the variational
Schouten bracket does satisfy (whence $\Delta^2=0$, i.e., the BV-Laplacian is a
differential acting in the algebra of local functionals). By using one tuple of
three variational multi-vectors twice, we contrast the new logic of iterated
variations -- when the right-hand side of Jacobi's identity vanishes altogether
-- with the old method: interlacing its steps and stops, it could produce some
non-zero representative of the trivial class in the top-degree horizontal
cohomology. But we then show at once by an elementary counterexample why, in
the frames of the old approach that did not rely on Gel'fand's calculus, the
BV-Laplacian failed to be a graded derivation of the variational Schouten
bracket.
  Keywords: Variational multi-vectors, Schouten bracket, Jacobi identity,
Batalin-Vilkovisky Laplacian, symbolic computations.
  PACS: 02.40.-k, 11.10.-z; also 02.30.Ik, 02.30.Jr, 11.15.-q, 11.30.-j
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0608</id><created>2014-11-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Auguie</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruchhausen</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fainstein</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical coupling to Tamm plasmons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/17/3/035003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conditions of critical coupling of light to Tamm plasmons are
investigated with comprehensive numerical simulations, highlighting the
parameters that maximise absorption of incident light in the metal layer. The
asymmetric response in reflection and absorption with respect to the direction
of incidence is discussed, the two cases yielding different optimal coupling
conditions. These findings are relevant for the design of optimised Tamm
structures, particularly in applications such as narrow-band thermal emitters,
field-enhanced spectroscopy and refractive-index sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.6915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.6915</id><created>2014-12-22</created><updated>2015-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Gaveshna</forenames><affiliation>Phys. Res. Lab. Ahmedabad</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rangarajan</keyname><forenames>Raghavan</forenames><affiliation>Phys. Res. Lab. Ahmedabad</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Anjan A.</forenames><affiliation>Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi</affiliation></author></authors><title>Thawing quintessence from the inflationary epoch to today</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures; replaced some figures and expanded discussion to
  include general monomial potentials. Accepted for publication in Physical
  Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D92 (2015) 12, 123003</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.123003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the latest observational data we obtain a lower bound on the initial
value of the quintessence field in thawing quintessence models of dark energy.
For potentials of the form V(\phi) \phi^{\pm2} we find that the initial value
|\phi_i|&gt;7x10^{18}\gev. We then relate \phi_i to the duration of inflation by
assuming that the initial value of the quintessence field is determined by
quantum fluctuations of the quintessence field during inflation. From the lower
bound on $\phi_i$ we obtain a lower bound on the number of e-foldings of
inflation, namely, N&gt;2x10^{11}. We obtain similar bounds for other power law
potentials for which too we obtain |\phi_{i}|&gt;O(M_{P}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02865</id><created>2015-01-12</created><updated>2015-06-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bradler</keyname><forenames>Kamil</forenames></author></authors><title>Hiking a generalized Dyck path: A tractable way of calculating multimode
  boson evolution operators</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v4: published version</comments><journal-ref>Computer Physics Communications 196, 80 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2015.05.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A time evolution operator in the interaction picture is given by
exponentiating an interaction Hamiltonian $H$. Important examples of
Hamiltonians, often encountered in quantum optics, condensed matter and high
energy physics, are of a general form $H=r(A^\dagger-A)$, where $A$ is a
multimode boson operator and $r$ is the coupling constant. If no simple
factorization formula for the evolution operator exists, the calculation of the
evolution operator is a notoriously difficult problem. In this case the only
available option may be to Taylor expand the operator in $r$ and act on a state
of interest $\psi$. But this brute-force method quickly hits the complexity
barrier since the number of evaluated expressions increases exponentially. We
relate a combinatorial structure called Dyck paths to the action of a boson
word (monomial) and a large class of monomial sums on a quantum state $\psi$.
This allows us to cross the exponential gap and make the problem of a boson
unitary operator evaluation computationally tractable by achieving
polynomial-time complexity for an extensive family of physically interesting
multimode Hamiltonians. We further test our method on a cubic boson Hamiltonian
whose Taylor series is known to diverge for all nonzero values of the coupling
constant and an analytic continuation via a Pad\'e approximant must be
performed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02113</id><created>2015-02-07</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kagan</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitskan</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korovushkin</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagram of the Kohn-Luttinger superconducting state for bilayer
  graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 88, 157 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60198-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of the intersite and interplane Coulomb interactions between the
Dirac fermions on the formation of the Kohn-Luttinger superconductivity in
bilayer doped graphene is studied disregarding the effects of the van der Waals
potential of the substrate and both magnetic and non-magnetic impurities. The
phase diagram determining the boundaries of superconductive domains with
different types of symmetry of the order parameter is built using the extended
Hubbard model in the Born weak-coupling approximation with allowance for the
intratomic, interatomic, and interlayer Coulomb interactions between electrons.
It is shown that the Kohn-Luttinger polarization contributions up to the second
order of perturbation theory in the Coulomb interaction inclusively and an
account for the long-range intraplane Coulomb interactions significantly affect
the competition between the superconducting $f-$, $p+ip-$, and $d+id-$wave
pairings. It is demonstrated that the account for the interplane Coulomb
interaction enhances the critical temperature of the transition to the
superconducting phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03361</id><created>2015-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>R. Navarro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arriola</keyname><forenames>E. Ruiz</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Elvira</keyname><forenames>J. Ruiz</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-consistent statistical error analysis of $\pi\pi$ scattering</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>17 pg, 22 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D91 (2015) 074014</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.074014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the conditions under which a statistical error analysis can be
carried out in the case of $\pi\pi$ scattering, namely the normality of
residuals in the conventional $\chi^2$-fit method. Here we check that the
current and benchmarking analyses only present very small violations of the
normality requirements. In particular, we show how it is possible to amend
slightly the selection of the experimental data, and improve the normality of
residuals.
  As an example, we discuss the $0^{++}$ channel and the implications for the
$f_0(500)$ and $f_0(980)$ resonances, obtaining that the new selection of data
provides very similar and compatible results. In addition, the effect on the
$f_0(500)$ and $f_0(980)$ resonance pole parameters is almost negligible, which
reinforces the central results and the uncertainty analysis performed in these
benchmarking determinations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04857</id><created>2015-03-16</created><updated>2015-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asplund</keyname><forenames>Curtis T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berenstein</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement entropy converges to classical entropy around periodic
  orbits</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages + appendices. v2: Added one figure and one reference</comments><report-no>DAMTP-2015-15</report-no><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 366 (2016) 113-132</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2015.12.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider oscillators evolving subject to a periodic driving force that
dynamically entangles them, and argue that this gives the linearized evolution
around periodic orbits in a general chaotic Hamiltonian dynamical system. We
show that the entanglement entropy, after tracing over half of the oscillators,
generically asymptotes to linear growth at a rate given by the sum of the
positive Lyapunov exponents of the system. These exponents give a classical
entropy growth rate, in the sense of Kolmogorov, Sinai and Pesin. We also
calculate the dependence of this entropy on linear mixtures of the oscillator
Hilbert space factors, to investigate the dependence of the entanglement
entropy on the choice of coarse-graining. We find that for almost all choices
the asymptotic growth rate is the same.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06987</id><created>2015-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Chao-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Lu-Hsing</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of Two-Loop Neutrino Mass Generation Models</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>20 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 365 (2016) 210-222</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2015.11.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the models with the Majorana neutrino masses generated radiatively
by two-loop diagrams due to the Yukawa $\rho \bar \ell_R^c \ell_R$ and
effective $\rho^{\pm\pm} W^\mp W^\mp$ couplings along with a scalar triplet
$\Delta$, where $\rho$ is a doubly charged singlet scalar, $\ell_R$ the charged
lepton and $W$ the charged gauge boson. A generic feature in these types of
models is that the neutrino mass spectrum has to be a normal hierarchy.
Furthermore, by using the neutrino oscillation data and comparing with the
global fitting result in the literature, we find a unique neutrino mass matrix
and predict the Dirac and two Majorana CP phases to be $1.40\pi$, $1.11\pi$ and
$1.47\pi$, respectively. We also discuss the model parameters constrained by
the lepton flavor violating processes and electroweak oblique parameters. In
addition, we show that the rate of the neutrinoless double beta decay
$(0\nu\beta\beta)$ can be as large as the current experimental bound as it is
dominated by the short-range contribution at tree level, whereas the
traditional long-range one is negligible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03908</id><created>2015-04-15</created><updated>2016-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Higgs Channel for FERMI GeV $\gamma$-ray Excess</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, 1 table, JCAP accepted version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP02(2016)011</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/02/011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark Higgs is very generic in dark matter models where DM is stabilized by
some spontaneously broken dark gauge symmetries. Motivated by the FERMI
observation of $\sim$GeV scale $\gamma$-ray excess from the galactic center
(GC), we investigate a scenario that a pair of dark matter $X$ annihilates into
a pair of dark Higgs $H_2$, which subsequently decays into standard model
particles through its mixing with SM Higgs boson. Besides the two-body decay of
$H_2$, we also include multibody decay channels of the dark Higgs. We find that
the best-fit point is around $M_X\simeq 95.0$GeV, $M_{H_2}\simeq 86.7$GeV,
$\langle \sigma v\rangle\simeq 4.0\times 10^{-26}\textrm{cm}^3\textrm{/s}$ and
gives a p-value $\simeq 0.40$. Implication of this result is described in the
context of dark matter models with dark gauge symmetries. Since such a dark
Higgs boson is very difficult to produce at colliders, indirect DM detections
of cosmic $\gamma$-rays could be an important probe of dark sectors,
complementary to collider searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.07251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.07251</id><created>2015-04-27</created><updated>2015-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sutter</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fawzi</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renner</keyname><forenames>Renato</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal recovery map for approximate Markov chains</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math-ph math.IT math.MP</categories><comments>v3: 31 pages, 1 figure, application to topological order of quantum
  systems added (Section 3). v2: 29 pages, relation to [Wilde,
  arXiv:1505.04661] clarified (Remark 2.5)</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society A, vol. 472, no. 2186, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspa.2015.0623</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A central question in quantum information theory is to determine how well
lost information can be reconstructed. Crucially, the corresponding recovery
operation should perform well without knowing the information to be
reconstructed. In this work, we show that the quantum conditional mutual
information measures the performance of such recovery operations. More
precisely, we prove that the conditional mutual information $I(A:C|B)$ of a
tripartite quantum state $\rho_{ABC}$ can be bounded from below by its distance
to the closest recovered state $\mathcal{R}_{B \to BC}(\rho_{AB})$, where the
$C$-part is reconstructed from the $B$-part only and the recovery map
$\mathcal{R}_{B \to BC}$ merely depends on $\rho_{BC}$. One particular
application of this result implies the equivalence between two different
approaches to define topological order in quantum systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05803</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2015-11-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patteson</keyname><forenames>Alison E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopinath</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purohit</keyname><forenames>Prashant K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arratia</keyname><forenames>Paulo E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle diffusion in active fluids is non-monotonic in size</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 Figures</comments><doi>10.1039/C5SM02800K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally investigate the effect of particle size on the motion of
passive polystyrene spheres in suspensions of Escherichia coli. Using particles
covering a range of sizes from 0.6 to 39 microns, we probe particle dynamics at
both short and long time scales. In all cases, the particles exhibit
super-diffusive ballistic behavior at short times before eventually
transitioning to diffusive behavior. Surprisingly, we find a regime in which
larger particles can diffuse faster than smaller particles: the particle
long-time effective diffusivity exhibits a peak in particle size, which is a
deviation from classical thermal diffusion. We also find that the active
contribution to particle diffusion is controlled by a dimensionless parameter,
the Peclet number. A minimal model qualitatively explains the existence of the
effective diffusivity peak and its dependence on bacterial concentration. Our
results have broad implications on characterizing active fluids using concepts
drawn from classical thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07830</id><created>2015-05-28</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keeler</keyname><forenames>Cynthia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knodel</keyname><forenames>Gino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>James T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal features of Lifshitz Green's functions from holography</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>32 pages, 4 figures, v2: reference added, v3: fixed bug in
  bibliography</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2015)057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the behavior of the retarded Green's function in theories with
Lifshitz scaling symmetry, both through dual gravitational models and a direct
field theory approach. In contrast with the case of a relativistic CFT, where
the Green's function is fixed (up to normalization) by symmetry, the generic
Lifshitz Green's function can a priori depend on an arbitrary function
$\mathcal G(\hat\omega)$, where $\hat\omega=\omega/|\vec k|^z$ is the
scale-invariant ratio of frequency to wavenumber, with dynamical exponent $z$.
Nevertheless, we demonstrate that the imaginary part of the retarded Green's
function (i.e. the spectral function) of scalar operators is exponentially
suppressed in a window of frequencies near zero. This behavior is universal in
all Lifshitz theories without additional constraining symmetries. On the
gravity side, this result is robust against higher derivative corrections,
while on the field theory side we present two $z=2$ examples where the
exponential suppression arises from summing the perturbative expansion to
infinite order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07908</id><created>2015-05-28</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guimond</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roulet</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>Huy Nguyen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarani</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author></authors><title>Rabi oscillation in a quantum cavity: Markovian and non-Markovian
  dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 023808 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.023808</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the Rabi oscillation of an atom placed inside a quantum cavity
where each mirror is formed by a chain of atoms trapped near a one-dimensional
waveguide. This proposal was studied previously with the use of Markov
approximation, where the delay due to the finite travel time of light between
the two cavity mirrors is neglected. We show that Rabi oscillation analogous to
that obtained with high-finesse classical cavities is achieved only when this
travel time is much larger than the time scale that characterizes the
collective response of the atomic chain. Therefore, the delay must be taken
into account and the dynamics of the problem is inherently non-Markovian.
Parameters of interest such as the Rabi frequency and the cavity loss rate due
to photon leakage through the mirrors are obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06742</id><created>2015-06-20</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Bhabani Prasad</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaginary Interactions with Minimum Length</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Accepted in Gravitation and Cosmology</comments><journal-ref>Grav. Cosmol. 21, 4, 270 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0202289315040064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the effect of having minimum length on a two dimensional
anisotropic simple harmonic oscillator with PT symmetric imaginary interaction
perturbatively. First order correction to the general state is calculated
analytically to show that it remains real as long as PT symmetry is unbroken.
The characteristics of PT phase transition remain unaltered in this deformed
formulation of quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00960</id><created>2015-07-03</created><updated>2015-11-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borah</keyname><forenames>Debasish</forenames></author></authors><title>Relating Lepton Mixing Angles with Lepton Mass Hierarchy</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>v2: 18 pages, 4 figures, to appear in IJMPA</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A, 31, 1650002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16500020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the possibility of relating lepton mixing angles with lepton mass
hierarchies in a model-independent way. Guided by the existence of such
relations in the quark sector, we first consider all the mixing angles, both in
charged lepton and neutrino sectors to be related to the respective mass
ratios. This allows us to calculate the leptonic mixing angles observed in
neutrino oscillations as functions of the lightest neutrino mass. We show that
for both normal and inverted hierarchical neutrino masses, this scenario does
not give rise to correct leptonic mixing angles. We then show that correct
leptonic mixing angles can be generated with normal hierarchical neutrino
masses if the relation between mixing angle and mass ratio is restricted to 1-2
and 1-3 mixing in both charged lepton and neutrino sectors leaving the 2-3
mixing angles as free parameters. We then restrict the lightest neutrino mass
as well as the difference between 2-3 mixing angles in charged lepton and
neutrino sectors from the requirement of producing correct leptonic mixing
angles. We constrain the lightest neutrino mass to be around $0.002$ eV and
leptonic Dirac CP phase $\delta_{CP}$ such that
$\sin^2{\delta_{CP}}\sim(0.35-0.50)$. We also construct the leptonic mass
matrices in terms of $2-3$ mixing angles and lightest neutrino mass and briefly
comment on the possibility of realizing texture zeros in the neutrino mass
matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03651</id><created>2015-07-13</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iancu</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madrigal</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soyez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triantafyllopoulos</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collinearly-improved BK evolution meets the HERA data</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures; minor corrections to fit results and few
  comments added</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.09.071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous publication, we have established a collinearly-improved version
of the Balitsky-Kovchegov (BK) equation, which resums to all orders the
radiative corrections enhanced by large double transverse logarithms. Here, we
study the relevance of this equation as a tool for phenomenology, by
confronting it to the HERA data. To that aim, we first improve the perturbative
accuracy of our resummation, by including two classes of single-logarithmic
corrections: those generated by the first non-singular terms in the DGLAP
splitting functions and those expressing the one-loop running of the QCD
coupling. The equation thus obtained includes all the next-to-leading order
corrections to the BK equation which are enhanced by (single or double)
collinear logarithms. We then use numerical solutions to this equation to fit
the HERA data for the electron-proton reduced cross-section at small Bjorken x.
We obtain good quality fits for physically acceptable initial conditions. Our
best fit, which shows a good stability up to virtualities as large as Q^2=400
GeV^2 for the exchanged photon, uses as an initial condition the
running-coupling version of the McLerran-Venugopalan model, with the QCD
coupling running according to the smallest dipole prescription.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04061</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04061</id><created>2015-07-14</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Liqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Yunhe</forenames></author></authors><title>Hom-Big Brackets: Theory and Applications</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 014, 18 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.014</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce the notion of hom-big brackets, which is a
generalization of Kosmann-Schwarzbach's big brackets. We show that it gives
rise to a graded hom-Lie algebra. Thus, it is a useful tool to study
hom-structures. In particular, we use it to describe hom-Lie bialgebras and
hom-Nijenhuis operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04629</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bresch</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jabin</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Global Existence of Weak Solutions for Compresssible Navier--Stokes
  Equations: Thermodynamically unstable pressure and anisotropic viscous stress
  tensor</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>35Q30, 35D30, 54D30, 42B37, 35Q86, 92B05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove global existence of appropriate weak solutions for the compressible
Navier--Stokes equations for more general stress tensor than those covered by
P.-L. Lions and E. Feireisl's theory. More precisely we focus on more general
pressure laws which are not thermodynamically stable; we are also able to
handle some anisotropy in the viscous stress tensor. To give answers to these
two longstanding problems, we revisit the classical compactness theory on the
density by obtaining precise quantitative regularity estimates: This requires a
more precise analysis of the structure of the equations combined to a novel
approach to the compactness of the continuity equation. These two cases open
the theory to important physical applications, for instance to describe solar
events (virial pressure law), geophysical flows (eddy viscosity) or biological
situations (anisotropy).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06699</id><created>2015-07-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Phang</keyname><forenames>Sendy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vukovic</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Creagh</keyname><forenames>Stephen C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sewell</keyname><forenames>Phillip D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradoni</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benson</keyname><forenames>Trevor M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localized Single Frequency Lasing States in a Finite Parity-Time
  Symmetric Resonator Chain</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>8 Figures and 12 pages</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 20499 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep20499</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper a practical case of a finite periodic Parity Time chain made of
resonant dielectric cylinders is considered. The paper analyzes a more general
case where PT symmetry is achieved by modulating both the real and imaginary
part of the material refractive index along the resonator chain. The
band-structure of the finite periodic PT resonator chains is compared to
infinite chains in order to understand the complex interdependence of the Bloch
phase and the amount of the gain/loss in the system that causes the PT symmetry
to break. The results show that the type of the modulation along the unit cell
can significantly affect the position of the threshold point of the PT system.
In all cases the lowest threshold is achieved near the end of the Brillouin
zone. In the case of finite PT-chains, and for a particular type of modulation,
early PT symmetry breaking is observed and shown to be caused by the presence
of termination states localized at the edges of the finite chain resulting in
localized lasing and dissipative modes at each end of the chain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07029</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07029</id><created>2015-07-24</created><updated>2016-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Opazo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustamante</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labb&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of the fluid density on the statistics of power fluctuations
  in von K\'arm\'an swirling flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures. Accepted in Physics of Fluids</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Fluids 28, 025105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4941051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we report experimental results on the fluctuations of injected power in
confined turbulence. Specifically, we have studied a von K\'arm\'an swirling
flow with constant external torque applied to the stirrers. Two experiments
were performed at nearly equal Reynolds numbers, in geometrically similar
experimental setups. Air was utilized in one of them and water in the other.
With air, it was found that the probability density function of power
fluctuations is strongly asymmetric, while with water, it is nearly Gaussian.
This suggests that the outcome of a big change of the fluid density in the
flow-stirrer interaction is not simply a change in the amplitude of stirrers'
response. In the case of water, with a density roughly 830 times greater than
air density, the coupling between the flow and the stirrers is stronger, so
that they follow more closely the fluctuations of the average rotation of the
nearby flow. When the fluid is air, the coupling is much weaker. The result is
not just a smaller response of the stirrers to the torque exerted by the flow;
the PDF of the injected power becomes strongly asymmetric and its spectrum
acquires a broad region that scales as $f^{-2}$. Thus, the asymmetry of the
probability density functions of torque or angular speed could be related to
the inability of the stirrers to respond to flow stresses. This happens, for
instance, when the torque exerted by the flow is weak, due to small fluid
density, or when the stirrers' moment of inertia is large. Moreover, a
correlation analysis reveals that the features of the energy transfer dynamics
with water are qualitatively and quantitatively different to what is observed
with air as working fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08940</id><created>2015-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Diakonova</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicosia</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latora</keyname><forenames>Vito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miguel</keyname><forenames>Maxi San</forenames></author></authors><title>Irreducibility of multilayer network dynamics: the case of the voter
  model</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.SI nlin.AO</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 023010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/023010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the issue of the reducibility of the dynamics on a multilayer
network to an equivalent process on an aggregated single-layer network. As a
typical example of models for opinion formation in social networks, we
implement the voter model on a two-layer multiplex network, and we study its
dynamics as a function of two control parameters, namely the fraction of edges
simultaneously existing in both layers of the network (edge overlap), and the
fraction of nodes participating in both layers (interlayer connectivity or
degree of multiplexity). We compute the asymptotic value of the number of
active links (interface density) in the thermodynamic limit, and the time to
reach an absorbing state for finite systems, and we compare the numerical
results with the analytical predictions on equivalent single-layer networks
obtained through various possible aggregation procedures. We find a large
region of parameters where the interface density of large multiplexes gives
systematic deviations from that of the aggregates. We show that neither of the
standard aggregation procedures is able to capture the highly nonlinear
increase in the lifetime of a finite size multiplex at small interlayer
connectivity. These results indicate that multiplexity should be appropriately
taken into account when studying voter model dynamics, and that, in general,
single-layer approximations might be not accurate enough to properly understand
processes occurring on multiplex networks, since they might flatten out
relevant dynamical details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00366</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunitomo</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okawa</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete action for open superstring field theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>44 pages, no figures; v2: minor corrections and improvement; v3:
  minor changes including a change in the title, version published in PTEP</comments><report-no>UT-Komaba/15-4, YITP-15-65</report-no><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2016) 023B01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptv189</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a complete action for open superstring field theory that
includes the Neveu-Schwarz sector and the Ramond sector. For the Neveu-Schwarz
sector, we use the string field in the large Hilbert space of the
superconformal ghost sector, and the action in the Neveu-Schwarz sector is the
same as the Wess-Zumino-Witten-like action of the Berkovits formulation. For
the Ramond sector, it is known that the BRST cohomology on an appropriate
subspace of the small Hilbert space reproduces the correct spectrum, and we use
the string field projected to this subspace. We show that the action is
invariant under gauge transformations that are consistent with the projection
for the string field in the Ramond sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00768</id><created>2015-08-04</created><updated>2015-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>OBrien</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEvoy</keyname><forenames>Niall</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanlon</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallam</keyname><forenames>Toby</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>Jonathan N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duesberg</keyname><forenames>Georg S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mapping of Low-Frequency Raman Modes in CVD-Grown Transition Metal
  Dichalcogenides: Layer Number, Stacking Orientation and Resonant Effects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1038/srep19476</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Layered inorganic materials, such as the transition metal dichalcogenides
(TMDs), have attracted much attention due to their exceptional electronic and
optical properties. Reliable synthesis and characterization of these materials
must be developed if these properties are to be exploited. Herein, we present
low-frequency Raman analysis of MoS2, MoSe2, WSe2 and WS2 grown by chemical
vapour deposition (CVD). Raman spectra are acquired over large areas allowing
changes in the position and intensity of the shear and layer-breathing modes to
be visualized in maps. This allows detailed characterization of mono- and
few-layered TMDs which is complementary to well-established (high-frequency)
Raman and photoluminescence spectroscopy. This study presents a major stepping
stone in fundamental understanding of layered materials as mapping the
low-frequency modes allows the quality, symmetry, stacking configuration and
layer number of 2D materials to be probed over large areas. In addition, we
report on anomalous resonance effects in the low-frequency region of the WS2
Raman spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00785</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mirizzi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames><affiliation>Bari Univ. &amp; INFN, Bari</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tamborra</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames><affiliation>GRAPPA Inst., Amsterdam</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Janka</keyname><forenames>Hans-Thomas</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Inst. for Astrophysics, Garching</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Saviano</keyname><forenames>Ninetta</forenames><affiliation>IPPP, Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Scholberg</keyname><forenames>Kate</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, Duke Univ., Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bollig</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames><affiliation>TUM, Munich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hudepohl</keyname><forenames>Lorenz</forenames><affiliation>MPCDF, Garching</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sovan</forenames><affiliation>MPI, Munich</affiliation></author></authors><title>Supernova Neutrinos: Production, Oscillations and Detection</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>(revised version:116 pages, 46 pdf figures. References updated and
  typos removed. Matches the version published on La Rivista del Nuovo Cimento)</comments><journal-ref>Rivista del Nuovo Cimento Vol. 39, N. 1-2 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1393/ncr/i2016-10120-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutrinos play a crucial role in the collapse and explosion of massive stars,
governing the infall dynamics of the stellar core, triggering and fueling the
explosion and driving the cooling and deleptonization of the newly formed
neutron star. Due to their role neutrinos carry information from the heart of
the explosion and, due to their weakly interacting nature, offer the only
direct probe of the dynamics and thermodynamics at the center of a supernova.
In this paper, we review the present status of modelling the neutrino physics
and signal formation in collapsing and exploding stars. We assess the
capability of current and planned large underground neutrino detectors to yield
faithful information of the time and flavor dependent neutrino signal from a
future Galactic supernova. We show how the observable neutrino burst would
provide a benchmark for fundamental supernova physics with unprecedented
richness of detail. Exploiting the treasure of the measured neutrino events
requires a careful discrimination of source-generated properties from signal
features that originate on the way to the detector. As for the latter, we
discuss self-induced flavor conversions associated with neutrino-neutrino
interactions that occur in the deepest stellar regions; matter effects that
modify the pattern of flavor conversions in the dynamical stellar envelope;
neutrino-oscillation signatures that result from structural features associated
with the shock-wave propagation as well as turbulent mass motions in post-shock
layers. Finally, we highlight our current understanding of the formation of the
diffuse supernova neutrino background and we analyse the perspectives for a
detection of this relic signal that integrates the contributions from all past
core-collapse supernovae in the Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02049</id><created>2015-08-09</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zdziarski</keyname><forenames>Andrzej A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segreto</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pooley</keyname><forenames>Guy G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The radio/X-ray correlation in Cyg X-3 and the nature of its hard
  spectral state</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>An error in the BAT light curve shown in Fig. A2 corrected. Published
  in MNRAS + erratum</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 456, 775 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2647</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the radio/X-ray correlation in Cyg X-3. It has been known that the
soft and hard X-ray fluxes in the hard spectral state are correlated positively
and negatively, respectively, with the radio flux. We show that this implies
that the observed $\sim$1--100 keV flux (which is a fair approximation to the
bolometric flux) is completely uncorrelated with the radio flux. We can recover
a positive correlation (seen in other sources and expected theoretically) if
the soft X-rays are strongly absorbed by a local medium. Then, however, the
intrinsic X-ray spectrum of Cyg X-3 in its hard state becomes relatively soft,
similar to that of an intermediate spectral state of black-hole binaries, but
not to their true hard state. We also find the radio spectra in the hard state
of Cyg X-3 are hard on average, and the flux distributions of the radio
emission and soft X-rays can be described by sums of two log-normal functions.
We compare Cyg X-3 with other X-ray binaries using colour-colour,
colour-Eddington ratio and Eddington ratio-radio flux diagrams. We find Cyg X-3
to be spectrally most similar to GRS 1915+105, except that Cyg X-3 is
substantially more radio loud, which appears to be due to its jet emission
enhanced by interaction with the powerful stellar wind from the Wolf-Rayet
donor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05397</id><created>2015-08-21</created><updated>2015-11-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>NLO Corrections to Double Higgs Production in the Higgs Singlet Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 22 figures. References updated, typos fixed, and discussion
  added to introduction, Section IVB, and conclusion. Version to appear in PRD</comments><report-no>SLAC-PUB-16335</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 094023 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.094023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Higgs pair production at the LHC from gluon fusion is small in the Standard
Model, but can be enhanced in models where a resonant enhancement is allowed.
We examine the effect of a resonant contribution from a second scalar arising
in a model with a gauge singlet scalar field in addition to the usual SU(2)
scalar doublet, with mass up to $M_H$~600 GeV and discuss the interference
effects in double Higgs production. We compute the NLO QCD corrections in the
large $m_t$ limit and show that they can significantly distort kinematic
distributions near the resonance peak.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07204</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naboka</keyname><forenames>V. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpenko</keyname><forenames>Iu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinyukov</keyname><forenames>Yu. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermalization, evolution and LHC observables in an integrated
  hydrokinetic model of A+A collisions</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A further development of the evolutionary picture of A+A collisions, which we
call the integrated HydroKinetic Model (iHKM), is proposed. The model comprises
a generator of the initial state GLISSANDO, pre-thermal dynamics of A+A
collisions leading to thermalization, subsequent relativistic viscous
hydrodynamic expansion of quark-gluon and hadron medium (vHLLE), its
particlization, and finally hadronic cascade ultrarelativistic QMD. We
calculate mid-rapidity charged-particle multiplicities, pion, kaon, and
antiproton spectra, charged-particle elliptic flows, and pion interferometry
radii for Pb+Pb collisions at the energies available at the CERN Large Hadron
Collider, $\sqrt{s} = 2.76$ TeV, at different centralities. We find that the
best description of the experimental data is reached when the initial states
are attributed to the very small initial time 0.1 fm/c, the pre-thermal stage
(thermalization process) lasts at least until 1 fm/c, and the shear viscosity
at the hydrodynamic stage of the matter evolution has its minimal value,
$\eta/s = \frac{1}{4\pi}$. At the same time it is observed that the various
momentum anisotropies of the initial states, different initial and relaxation
times, as well as even a treatment of the pre-thermal stage within just viscous
or ideal hydrodynamic approach, leads sometimes to worse but nevertheless
similar results, if the normalization of maximal initial energy density in most
central events is adjusted to reproduce the final hadron multiplicity in each
scenario. This can explain a good enough data description in numerous variants
of hybrid models without a prethermal stage when the initial energy densities
are defined up to a common factor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01311</id><created>2015-09-03</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishik</keyname><forenames>Inna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shuolong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhongkai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Sudi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebec</keyname><forenames>Slavko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuenberger</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zong</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jefferson</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirchmann</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merriam</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhixun</forenames></author></authors><title>High Resolution Angle Resolved Photoemission with Tabletop 11eV Laser</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 87, 011301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We developed a table-top vacuum ultraviolet (VUV) laser with $113.778$nm
wavelength (10.897eV) and demonstrated its viability as a photon source for
high resolution angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES). This
sub-nanosecond pulsed VUV laser operates at a repetition rate of 10MHz,
provides a flux of 2$\times$10$^{12}$ photons/second, and enables photoemission
with energy and momentum resolutions better than 2meV and 0.012\AA$^{-1}$,
respectively. Space-charge induced energy shifts and spectral broadenings can
be reduced below 2meV. The setup reaches electron momenta up to 1.2\AA$^{-1}$,
granting full access to the first Brillouin zone of most materials. Control
over the linear polarization, repetition rate, and photon flux of the VUV
source facilitates ARPES investigations of a broad range of quantum materials,
bridging the application gap between contemporary low energy laser-based ARPES
and synchrotron-based ARPES. We describe the principles and operational
characteristics of this source, and showcase its performance for rare earth
metal tritellurides, high temperature cuprate superconductors and iron-based
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05786</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bazavov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H. -T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hegde</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaczmarek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karsch</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laermann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Swagato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petreczky</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soeldner</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The curvature of the freeze-out line in heavy ion collisions</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 014512 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.014512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the mean and variance of net-baryon number and net-electric
charge distributions from Quantum Chromodynamics (QCD) using a next-to-leading
order Taylor expansion in terms of temperature and chemical potentials. We
compare these expansions with experimental data from STAR and PHENIX, determine
the freeze-out temperature in the limit of vanishing baryon chemical potential,
and, for the first time, constrain the curvature of the freeze-out line through
a direct comparison between experimental data on net-charge fluctuations and a
QCD calculation. We obtain a bound on the curvature coefficient, kappa_2^f &lt;
0.011, that is compatible with lattice QCD results on the curvature of the QCD
transition line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06861</id><created>2015-09-23</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Markhof</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meden</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The spectral function of the Tomonaga-Luttinger model revisited: power
  laws and universality</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reinvestigate the momentum-resolved single-particle spectral function of
the Tomonaga-Luttinger model. In particular, we focus on the role of the
momentum-dependence of the two-particle interaction V(q). Usually, V(q) is
assumed to be a constant and integrals are regularized in the ultraviolet `by
hand' employing an ad hoc procedure. As the momentum dependence of the
interaction is irrelevant in the renormalization group sense this does not
affect the universal low-energy properties of the model, e.g. exponents of
power laws, if all energy scales are sent to zero. If, however, the momentum k
is fixed away from the Fermi momentum k_F, with |k-k_F| setting a nonvanishing
energy scale, the details of V(q) start to matter. We provide strong evidence
that any curvature of the two-particle interaction at small transferred
momentum q destroys power-law scaling of the momentum resolved spectral
function as a function of energy. Even for |k-k_F| much smaller than the
momentum space range of the interaction the spectral line shape depends on the
details of V(q). The significance of our results for universality in the
Luttinger liquid sense, for experiments on quasi one-dimensional metals, and
for recent attempts to compute the spectral function of one-dimensional
correlated systems taking effects of the curvature of the single-particle
dispersion into account (nonlinear Luttinger liquid phenomenology) is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07216</id><created>2015-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Darby</keyname><forenames>Brendan L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augui&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pantoja</keyname><forenames>Andres E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ru</keyname><forenames>Eric C. Le</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified optical absorption of molecules on metallic nanoparticles at
  sub-monolayer coverage</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 10, 40--45 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2015.205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Enhanced optical absorption of molecules in the vicinity of metallic
nanostructures is key to a number of surface-enhanced spectroscopies and of
great general interest to the fields of plasmonics and nano-optics. Yet,
experimental access to this absorbance has long proven elusive. We here present
direct measurements of the intrinsic absorbance of dye-molecules adsorbed onto
silver nanospheres, and crucially, at sub-monolayer concentrations where
dye--dye interactions become negligible. With a large detuning from the plasmon
resonance, distinct shifts and broadening of the molecular resonances reveal
the intrinsic properties of the dye in contact with the metal colloid, in
contrast to the often studied strong-coupling regime where the optical
properties of the dye-molecules cannot be isolated. The observation of these
shifts together with the ability to routinely measure them has broad
implications in the interpretation of experiments involving resonant molecules
on metallic surfaces, such as surface-enhanced spectroscopies and many aspects
of molecular plasmonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00096</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>GEPI, Observatoire de Paris, Meudon, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames><affiliation>GEPI, Observatoire de Paris, Meudon, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>GEPI, Observatoire de Paris, Meudon, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Puech</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>GEPI, Observatoire de Paris, Meudon, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fouquet</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Magellanic Stream System: I. Ram-pressure tails and the relics of
  the collision between the Magellanic Clouds</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 Figures, 3 Tables, Astrophysical Journal, 813, 110,
  updated to be essentially identical to the published version, Figures 10 and
  13 are available in video format at
  http://lia-origins.obspm.fr/images/videos/</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/813/2/110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analyzed the Magellanic Stream (MS) using the deepest and the most
resolved H I survey of the Southern Hemisphere (the Galactic All-Sky Survey).
The overall Stream is structured into two filaments, suggesting two
ram-pressure tails lagging behind the Magellanic Clouds (MCs), and resembling
two close, transonic, von Karman vortex streets. The past motions of the Clouds
appear imprinted in them, implying almost parallel initial orbits, and then a
radical change after their passage near the N(H I) peak of the MS. This is
consistent with a recent collision between the MCs, $200-300$ Myr ago, which
has stripped their gas further into small clouds, spreading them out along a
gigantic bow shock, perpendicular to the MS. The Stream is formed by the
interplay between stellar feedback and the ram pressure exerted by hot gas in
the Milky Way (MW) halo with $\rho_{hot}$= $10^{-4}$ $cm^{-3}$ at 50-70 kpc, a
value necessary to explain the MS multiphase high-velocity clouds. The
corresponding hydrodynamic modeling provides the currently most accurate
reproduction of the whole H I Stream morphology, of its velocity, and column
density profiles along $L_{MS}$. The 'ram pressure plus collision' scenario
requires tidal dwarf galaxies, which are assumed to be the Cloud and dSph
progenitors, to have left imprints in the MS and the Leading Arm, respectively.
The simulated LMC and SMC have baryonic mass, kinematics and proper motions
consistent with observations. This supports a novel paradigm for the MS System,
which could have its origin in material expelled toward the MW by the ancient
gas-rich merger that formed M31.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00758</id><created>2015-10-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Cox</keyname><forenames>Paul H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harms</keyname><forenames>Benjamin C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Shaoqi</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of Einstein-Maxwell-Kalb-Ramond Wormholes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1108.1184</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 044014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.044014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper investigates a particular type of wormhole. The wormhole solutions
studied are obtained by sewing together two static, spherically symmetric,
charged black-hole metrics at their horizons. The charged wormholes are in a
background Kalb-Ramond field, which is the source of the necessary tension in
the gravitational field. The metric-tensor elements are studied by numerically
solving Einstein's equations with stress-energy-tensor elements given by the
combination of static electric and Kalb-Ramond fields. For a certain range of
electric charge the tension is positive away from the wormhole throat, but the
tension is negative near the throat, making it non-traversable. The wormholes
are found to be quasi-stable against decay via gravitational instanton
tunnelling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02841</id><created>2015-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ojeda-Guill&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salazar-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mota</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>The number radial coherent states for the generalized MICZ-Kepler
  problem</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><journal-ref>J.Math.Phys. 57 (2016) 021704</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4940719</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the radial part of the MICZ-Kepler problem in an algebraic way by
using the $su(1,1)$ Lie algebra. We obtain the energy spectrum and the
eigenfunctions of this problem from the $su(1,1)$ theory of unitary
representations and the tilting transformation to the stationary Schr\&quot;odinger
equation. We construct the physical Perelomov number coherent states for this
problem and compute some expectation values. Also, we obtain the time evolution
of these coherent states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04280</id><created>2015-10-14</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hassan</keyname><forenames>Sultan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dav&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Romeel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finlator</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Mario G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulating the 21-cm signal from reionisation including non-linear
  ionisations and inhomogeneous recombinations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>20 pages, 14 figues, accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv3001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the impact of incorporating physically motivated ionisation and
recombination rates on the history and topology of cosmic reionisation, by
incorporating inputs from small-volume hydrodynamic simulations into a
semi-numerical code, SimFast21, that evolves reionisation on large scales. We
employ radiative hydrodynamic simulations to parameterize the ionisation rate
Rion and recombination rate Rrec as functions of halo mass, overdensity and
redshift. We find that Rion is super-linearly dependent on halo mass (Rion ~
Mh^1.41), in contrast to previous assumptions. We implement these scalings into
SimFast21 to identify the ionized regions. We tune our models to be consistent
with recent observations of the optical depth, ionizing emissivity, and neutral
fraction by the end of reionisation. We require an average photon escape
fraction fesc=0.04 within ~ 0.5 cMpc cells, independent of halo mass or
redshift, to simultaneously match these data. We present predictions for the
21cm power spectrum, and show that it is converged with respect to simulation
volume. We find that introducing superlinearly mass-dependent ionisations
increases the duration of reionisation and boosts the small-scale 21cm power by
~ 2-3 at intermediate phases of reionisation. Introducing inhomogeneous
recombinations reduces ionised bubble sizes and suppresses large-scale 21cm
power by ~ 2-3. Moreover, gas clumping on sub-cell scales has a minimal effect
on the 21cm power, indicating that robust predictions do not depend on the
behaviour of kpc-scale structures. The superlinear ionisations significantly
increase the median halo mass scale for ionising photon output to &gt;10^10 Mo,
giving greater hope for detecting most of ionising sources with next-generation
facilities. These results highlight the importance of more accurately treating
ionising sources and recombinations for modeling reionisation and its 21cm
signal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04397</id><created>2015-10-15</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jefferson</keyname><forenames>Fl&#xf3;rez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juan-Rafael</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvarez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omar</keyname><forenames>Calder&#xf3;n-Losada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luis-Jos&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Salazar-Serrano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alejandra</keyname><forenames>Valencia</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial interference of light: transverse coherence and the Alford and
  Gold effect</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interference between two parallel-propagating Gaussian beams,
originated from the same source, as their transverse separation is tuned. The
interference pattern as a function of such separation lead us to determine the
spatial coherence length of the original beam, in a similar way that a
Michelson-Morley interferometer can be employed to measure the temporal
coherence of a transform limited pulse. Moreover, performing a Fourier
transform of the two-beam transverse plane, we observe an intensity modulation
in the transverse momentum variable. This observation resembles the Alford and
Gold Effect reported in time and frequency variables so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06842</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Errandonea</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacomba-Perales</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polian</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>In-situ high-pressure Raman scattering studies in PbWO4 up to 48 GPa</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Alloys and Compounds 667 (2016) 36 - 43</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jallcom.2016.01.082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of pressure on the Raman spectrum of PbWO4 has been investigated
up to 48 GPa in a diamond-anvil cell using neon as pressure-transmitting
medium. Changes are detected in the Raman spectrum at 6.8 GPa as a consequence
of a structural phase transition from the tetragonal scheelite structure to the
monoclinic PbWO4-III structure. Two additional phase transitions are detected
at 15.5 and 21.2 GPa to the previously unknown crystalline phases IV and V. The
last one remains stable up to 43.3 GPa. At 47.7 GPa all Raman modes disappear,
which could be caused by a pressure-induced amorphization. All structural
changes are reversible, being the scheelite phase recovered at ambient
pressure. However, the two most intense modes of the PbWO4-III phase are still
present after full decompression, indicating that this phase coexists as a
minority metastable phase with the scheelite phase after pressure release. The
wavenumber of the Raman modes and their pressure dependencies are reported for
the four crystalline phases. The present reported results are compared with
previous studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08815</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>Aaron R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining cosmology and ionization history with combined 21 cm power
  spectrum and global signal measurements</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures. Revised to match accepted MNRAS version:
  expanded discussion of covariances between astrophysics and cosmology in
  Section 2.2, including two new figures; short discussion relating to KL modes
  added to Section 4; final results unchanged</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 457, 1864 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Improvements in current instruments and the advent of next-generation
instruments will soon push observational 21 cm cosmology into a new era, with
high significance measurements of both the power spectrum and the mean
(&quot;global&quot;) signal of the 21 cm brightness temperature. In this paper we use the
recently commenced Hydrogen Epoch of Reionization Array as a worked example to
provide forecasts on astrophysical and cosmological parameter constraints. In
doing so we improve upon previous forecasts in a number of ways. First, we
provide updated forecasts using the latest best-fit cosmological parameters
from the Planck satellite, exploring the impact of different Planck datasets on
21 cm experiments. We also show that despite the exquisite constraints that
other probes have placed on cosmological parameters, the remaining
uncertainties are still large enough to have a non-negligible impact on
upcoming 21 cm data analyses. While this complicates high-precision constraints
on reionization models, it provides an avenue for 21 cm reionization
measurements to constrain cosmology. We additionally forecast HERA's ability to
measure the ionization history using a combination of power spectrum
measurements and semi-analytic simulations. Finally, we consider ways in which
21 cm global signal and power spectrum measurements can be combined, and
propose a method by which power spectrum results can be used to train a compact
parameterization of the global signal. This parameterization reduces the number
of parameters needed to describe the global signal, increasing the likelihood
of a high significance measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00259</id><created>2015-11-01</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennes</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meden</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Current noise of the interacting resonant level model</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085306 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the zero-frequency current noise of the interacting resonant level
model for arbitrary bias voltages using a functional renormalization group
approach. For this we extend the existing nonequilibrium scheme by deriving and
solving flow equations for the current-vertex functions. On-resonance
artificial divergences of the latter found in lowest-order perturbation theory
in the two-particle interaction are consistently removed. Away from resonance
they are shifted to higher orders. This allows us to gain a comprehensive
picture of the current noise in the scaling limit. At high bias voltages, the
current noise exhibits a universal power-law decay, whose exponent is to
leading order in the interaction identical to that of the current. The
effective charge on resonance is analyzed in detail employing properties of the
vertex correction. We find that it is only modified to second or higher order
in the two-particle interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00798</id><created>2015-11-03</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Somerville</keyname><forenames>W. R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augui&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ru</keyname><forenames>E. C. Le</forenames></author></authors><title>SMARTIES: user-friendly codes for fast and accurate calculations of
  light scattering by spheroids</title><categories>physics.optics physics.comp-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jqsrt.2016.01.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a detailed user guide for SMARTIES, a suite of Matlab codes for
the calculation of the optical properties of oblate and prolate spheroidal
particles, with comparable capabilities and ease-of-use as Mie theory for
spheres. SMARTIES is a Matlab implementation of an improved T-matrix algorithm
for the theoretical modelling of electromagnetic scattering by particles of
spheroidal shape. The theory behind the improvements in numerical accuracy and
convergence is briefly summarised, with reference to the original publications.
Instructions of use, and a detailed description of the code structure, its
range of applicability, as well as guidelines for further developments by
advanced users are discussed in separate sections of this user guide. The code
may be useful to researchers seeking a fast, accurate and reliable tool to
simulate the near-field and far-field optical properties of elongated
particles, but will also appeal to other developers of light-scattering
software seeking a reliable benchmark for non-spherical particles with a
challenging aspect ratio and/or refractive index contrast.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06060</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kittaka</keyname><forenames>Shunichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Yusei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakakibara</keyname><forenames>Toshiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haga</keyname><forenames>Yoshinori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Etsuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onuki</keyname><forenames>Yoshichika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsutsumi</keyname><forenames>Yasumasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomoto</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machida</keyname><forenames>Kazushige</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence for chiral d-wave superconductivity in URu2Si2 from the
  field-angle variation of its specific heat</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, published in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 033704 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.033704</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-energy quasiparticle (QP) excitations in the heavy-fermion superconductor
URu$_2$Si$_2$ were investigated by specific-heat $C(T, H, \phi, \theta)$
measurements of a high-quality single crystal. The occurrence of QP excitations
due to the Doppler-shift effect was detected regardless of the field direction
in $C(H)$ of the present clean sample, which is in sharp contrast to a previous
report. Furthermore, the polar-angle-dependent $C(\theta)$ measured under a
rotating magnetic field within the ac plane exhibits a shoulder-like anomaly at
$\theta \sim 45$ deg and a sharp dip at $\theta = 90$ deg ($H \parallel a$) in
the moderate-field region. These features are supported by theoretical analyses
based on microscopic calculations assuming the gap symmetry of $k_z(k_x+ik_y)$,
whose gap structure is characterized by a combination of a horizontal line node
at the equator and point nodes at the poles. The present results have settled
the previous controversy over the gap structure of URu$_2$Si$_2$ and have
authenticated its chiral $d$-wave superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06685</id><created>2015-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Thomas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robbins</keyname><forenames>Mark O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chain Ends and the Ultimate Strength of Polyethylene Fibers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>ACS Macro Lett., 2016, 5, pp 263-267</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsmacrolett.5b00838</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use large scale molecular dynamics (MD) simulations to determine the
tensile yield mechanism of orthorhombic polyethylene (PE) crystals with finite
chains spanning $10^2-10^4$ carbons in length. We find the yield stress
$\sigma_y$ saturates for long chains at 6.3 GPa, agreeing well with
experiments. We show chains do not break but always yield by slip, after
nucleation of 1D dislocations at chain ends. Dislocations are accurately
described by a Frenkel-Kontorova model parametrized by the mechanical
properties of an ideal crystal. We compute a dislocation core size
$\xi\approx25$\AA\ and determine the high and low strain rate limits of
$\sigma_y$. Our results suggest characterizing the 1D dislocations of polymer
crystals as an efficient method for numerically predicting the ultimate tensile
strength of aligned fibers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06800</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liuzzo-Scorpo</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Rebecca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of quantum feedback cooling</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP physics.atom-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures. Published in &quot;Entropy&quot; Special Issue on &quot;Quantum
  Thermodynamics&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 18, 48 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e18020048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to initialize quantum registers in pure states lies at the core
of many applications of quantum technologies, from sensing to quantum
information processing and computation. In this paper, we tackle the problem of
increasing the polarization bias of an ensemble of two-level register spins by
means of joint coherent manipulations, involving a second ensemble of ancillary
spins and energy dissipation into an external heat bath. We formulate this spin
refrigeration protocol, akin to algorithmic cooling, in the general language of
quantum feedback control, and identify the relevant thermodynamic variables
involved. Our analysis is two-fold: on the one hand, we assess the optimality
of the protocol by means of suitable figures of merit, accounting for both its
work cost and effectiveness; on the other hand, we characterise the nature of
correlations built up between the register and the ancilla. In particular, we
observe that neither the amount of classical correlations nor the quantum
entanglement seem to be key ingredients fuelling our spin refrigeration
protocol. We report instead that a more general indicator of quantumness beyond
entanglement, the so-called quantum discord, is closely related to the cooling
performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04406</id><created>2015-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Gaoyong</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Phases of Fermionic Ladders with Periodic Magnetic Fields</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 023608 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.023608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent experiments bosonic [Atala et al., Nat. Phys. 10, 588 (2014), B. K.
Stuhl et al., Science 349, 1514 (2015)] as well as fermionic ladders [M.
Mancini et al., Science 349, 1510 (2015)] with a uniform flux were studied and
different interesting many-body states were observed. Motivated by these
experiments, we extend the uniform synthetic magnetic field to a periodic case
and show that a commensurate synthetic magnetic field offers an alternative
scheme to realize topological phases in many-body systems of ultra-cold Fermi
gases in ladder-like optical lattices. Using the exact diagonalization, we
numerically determine the topological band structure, edge states, non-zero
Chern numbers, Hofstadter-like-butterfly spectrum, and a complete phase diagram
of non-interacting fermionic ladders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04920</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zirke</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Evaluation of Two-Loop Integrals in FDR</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures, v2: minor corrections, citations added</comments><report-no>MPP-2015-301</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 02 (2016) 029</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method to numerically evaluate infrared-finite one- and two-loop
integrals within the Four-Dimensional Regularization/Renormalization approach,
in which a small mass serves as regulator. Typical integrals exhibit a
logarithmic dependence on this mass, which we extract with the aid of suitable
subtraction terms that can easily be integrated analytically until the
logarithmic structure is revealed. As first physical applications to test the
method, we calculate QCD corrections to the decay rates of scalar and
pseudoscalar Higgs bosons into two photons in the limit of an infinite
top-quark mass as well as to the $\rho$ parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02383</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02383</id><created>2016-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Tovmassian</keyname><forenames>Gagik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>Mercedes-Stephania</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochoa</keyname><forenames>Jose Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ernenwein</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandat</keyname><forenames>Dusan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pech</keyname><forenames>Miroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frayn</keyname><forenames>Ilse Plauchu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colorado</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murillo</keyname><forenames>Jose Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cesena</keyname><forenames>Urania</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>William H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bulik</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garczarczyk</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fruck</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costantini</keyname><forenames>Heide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cieslar</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aune</keyname><forenames>Taylor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vincent</keyname><forenames>Stephane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carr</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serre</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janecek</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haefner</keyname><forenames>Dennis</forenames></author></authors><title>Astroclimatic Characterization of Vallecitos: A candidate site for the
  Cherenkov Telescope Array at San Pedro Martir</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures, Publication of the Astronomical Society of the
  Pacific, accepted</comments><doi>10.1088/1538-3873/128/961/035004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We conducted an 18 month long study of the weather conditions of the
Vallecitos, a proposed site in Mexico to harbor the northern array of the
Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA). It is located in Sierra de San Pedro Martir
(SPM) a few kilometers away from Observatorio Astron\'omico Nacional. The study
is based on data collected by the ATMOSCOPE, a multi-sensor instrument
measuring the weather and sky conditions, which was commissioned and built by
the CTA Consortium. Additionally, we compare the weather conditions of the
optical observatory at SPM to the Vallecitos regarding temperature, humidity,
and wind distributions. It appears that the excellent conditions at the optical
observatory benefit from the presence of microclimate established in the
Vallecitos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03694</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kowalewski</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>Kochise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukamel</keyname><forenames>Shaul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-adiabatic dynamics of molecules in optical cavities</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 054309 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4941053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong coupling of molecules to the vacuum field of micro cavities can modify
the potential energy surfaces opening new photophysical and photochemical
reaction pathways. While the influence of laser fields is usually described in
terms of classical field, coupling to the vacuum state of a cavity has to be
described in terms of dressed photon-matter states (polaritons) which require
quantized fields. We present a derivation of the non-adiabatic couplings for
single molecules in the strong coupling regime suitable for the calculation of
the dressed state dynamics. The formalism allows to use quantities readily
accessible from quantum chemistry codes like the adiabatic potential energy
surfaces and dipole moments to carry out wave packet simulations in the dressed
basis. The implications for photochemistry are demonstrated for a set of model
systems representing typical situations found in molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04395</id><created>2016-01-17</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tam</keyname><forenames>Luen-Fai</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasilocal Energy in Kerr Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>There are some contents added in section 4 and also some refinement
  on abstract and introduction</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the quasilocal energy as in [11] for a constant radius
surface in Kerr spacetime in Boyer-Lindquist coordinates. We show that under
suitable conditions for isometric embedding, for a stationary observer the
quasilocal energy defined in [11] for constant radius in a Kerr like spacetime
is exactly equal to the Brown-York quasilocal energy [2]. By some careful
estimations, we show that for a constant radius surface in the Kerr spacetime
which is outside the ergosphere the embedding conditions for the previous
result are satisfied. We discuss extremal solutions as described in [14]. We
prove a uniqueness result. We find all extremal solutions in the Minkowski
spacetime. Finally, we show that near the horizon of the Kerr spacetime for the
small rotation case the extremal solutions are trivial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04560</id><created>2016-01-18</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beir&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panisson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tizzoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cattuto</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting human mobility through the assimilation of social media
  traces into mobility models</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Predicting human mobility flows at different spatial scales is challenged by
the heterogeneity of individual trajectories and the multi-scale nature of
transportation networks. As vast amounts of digital traces of human behaviour
become available, an opportunity arises to improve mobility models by
integrating into them proxy data on mobility collected by a variety of digital
platforms and location-aware services. Here we propose a hybrid model of human
mobility that integrates a large-scale publicly available dataset from a
popular photo-sharing system with the classical gravity model, under a stacked
regression procedure. We validate the performance and generalizability of our
approach using two ground-truth datasets on air travel and daily commuting in
the United States: using two different cross-validation schemes we show that
the hybrid model affords enhanced mobility prediction at both spatial scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05938</id><created>2016-01-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Azhar</keyname><forenames>Feraz</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of conditionalization and typicality in the multiverse</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures. Accepted for publication in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review D, 93, 043506, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.043506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An approach to testing theories describing a multiverse, that has gained
interest of late, involves comparing theory-generated probability distributions
over observables with their experimentally measured values. It is likely that
such distributions, were we indeed able to calculate them unambiguously, will
assign low probabilities to any such experimental measurements. An alternative
to thereby rejecting these theories, is to conditionalize the distributions
involved by restricting attention to domains of the multiverse in which we
might arise. In order to elicit a crisp prediction, however, one needs to make
a further assumption about how typical we are of the chosen domains. In this
paper, we investigate interactions between the spectra of available assumptions
regarding both conditionalization and typicality, and draw out the effects of
these interactions in a concrete setting; namely, on predictions of the total
number of species that contribute significantly to dark matter. In particular,
for each conditionalization scheme studied, we analyze how correlations between
densities of different dark matter species affect the prediction, and explicate
the effects of assumptions regarding typicality. We find that the effects of
correlations can depend on the conditionalization scheme, and that in each case
atypicality can significantly change the prediction. In doing so, we
demonstrate the existence of overlaps in the predictions of different
&quot;frameworks&quot; consisting of conjunctions of theory, conditionalization scheme
and typicality assumption. This conclusion highlights the acute challenges
involved in using such tests to identify a preferred framework that aims to
describe our observational situation in a multiverse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07585</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bolliet</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battye</keyname><forenames>Richard A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Equation of State Approach to Cosmological Perturbations in f(R)
  Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This short article is to appear in the Conference Proceedings of the
  XIV Marcel Grossmann Meeting (July 2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discovery of apparent cosmological acceleration has spawned a huge number
of dark energy and modified gravity theories. The f(R) models of gravity are
obtained when one replaces the Ricci scalar in the Einstein-Hilbert action by
an arbitrary function of the Ricci scalar. In this work we provide expressions
for the equations of state (EoS) for perturbations which completely
characterize the linearized perturbations in f(R) gravity, including the
scalar, vector, and tensor modes. The EoS formalism is a powerful and elegant
parametrization where the modification to General Relativity are treated as a
dark-energy-fluid. The perturbed dark-energy-fluid variables such as the
anisotropic stress or the entropy perturbation are explicitly given in terms of
parameters of the model of interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07991</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>RM</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paliathanasis</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leach</keyname><forenames>PGL</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries, Lagrangians and conserved vectors for forms of the
  complex-valued Klein-Gordon Equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This article has been withdrawn because the coauthors did not agree
  with the first submission</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the complex-valued Klein-Gordon Equation from an integrability
perspective by the implementation of the Lie Theory of Continuous Groups, where
this equation is governed by power-law nonlinearity. We write the equations in
terms of real dependent variables and examine both the two-dimensional and
three-dimensional models. In the case of the two-dimensional model the analysis
is extended by the determination of Noether point symmetries and conserved
vectors via the construction of a Lagrangian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00433</id><created>2016-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Etesami</keyname><forenames>Seyyed Ruhollah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berakdar</keyname><forenames>Jamal</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient thermal energy harvesting using nanoscale magnetoelectric
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, Accepted in Applied Physics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 108, 053903 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermomechanical cycles with a ferroelectric working substance convert heat
to electrical energy. As shown here, magnetoelectrically coupled
ferroelectric/ferromangtic composites (also called multiferroics) add new
functionalities and allow for an efficient thermal energy harvesting at room
temperature by exploiting the pyroelectric effect. By virtue of the
magnetoelectric coupling, external electric and magnetic fields can steer the
operation of these heat engines. Our theoretical predictions are based on a
combination of Landau-Khalatnikov-Tani approach (with a
Ginzburg-Landau-Devonshire potential) to simulate the ferroelectric dynamics
coupled to the magnetic dynamics. The latter is treated via the
electric-polarization-dependent Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation. Performing an
adapted Olsen cycle we show that a multiferroic working substance is
potentially much more superior to sole ferroelectrics, as far as thermal energy
harvesting using pyroelectric effect is concerned. Our proposal holds promise
not only for low-energy consuming devices but also for cooling technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00516</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Busoni</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Extra Dimensions at LHC Run 2</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures. References added, corrected figure 3, added
  projected sensitivity for parameter M_T</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I extract new limits on the coefficient of the effective operator generated
by tree-level graviton exchange in large extra dimensions from $pp \rightarrow
jj$ angular distributions at LHC: $M_T &gt; 6.8$ TeV (CMS after $2.6 fb^{-1}$ of
integrated luminosity) and $M_T &gt; 8.3$ TeV (ATLAS after $3.6 fb^{-1}$). I also
compare such limits to the ones obtained using the full graviton amplitude, and
discuss the impact of additional constrains arising from other datasets, such
as Mono-Jet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00583</id><created>2016-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ablinger</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behring</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mlein</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Freitas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasselhuhn</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Manteuffel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raab</keyname><forenames>C. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Round</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wi&#xdf;brock</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>3-Loop Corrections to the Heavy Flavor Wilson Coefficients in
  Deep-Inelastic Scattering</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>13 pages Latex, 8 Figures, Contribution to the Proceedings of EPS
  2015 Wien</comments><report-no>DESY 16/002, DO-TH 16/02, MITP/16-016, also Contribution to the
  RADCOR2015 Proceedings</report-no><journal-ref>PoS (EPS-HEP2015) 504</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A survey is given on the status of 3-loop heavy flavor corrections to
deep-inelastic structure functions at large enough virtualities $Q^2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01204</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Suhas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graves</keyname><forenames>Catherine E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strachan</keyname><forenames>John Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grafals</keyname><forenames>Emmanuelle Merced</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilcoyne</keyname><forenames>Arthur L. David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyliszczak</keyname><forenames>Tolek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weker</keyname><forenames>Johanna Nelson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishi</keyname><forenames>Yoshio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>R. Stanley</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Observation of Localized Radial Oxygen Migration in Functioning
  Tantalum Oxide Memristors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, Advanced Materials (2016); updated abstract</comments><doi>10.1002/adma.201505435</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oxygen migration in tantalum oxide, a promising next-generation storage
material, is studied using in-operando x-ray absorption spectromicroscopy and
is used to microphysically describe accelerated evolution of conduction channel
and device failure. The resulting ring-like patterns of oxygen concentration
are modeled using thermophoretic forces and Fick diffusion, establishing the
critical role of temperature-activated oxygen migration that has been under
question lately.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01563</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nigam</keyname><forenames>Kushagra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Kinjal</forenames></author></authors><title>A Brief Review of Helmholtz Conditions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 Pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that the equations of motion obtained from Newtons second
law of motion can be obtained from a Lagrangian via the Euler-Lagrangian
formulation if and only if the equations of motion satisfy the Helmholtz
conditions. In this pedagogical article we give a simple proof of the above
statement and show its application to simple mechanical and dissipative
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01624</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Procopio</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozema</keyname><forenames>Lee A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Zi Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamel</keyname><forenames>Deny R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dakic</keyname><forenames>Borivoje</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walther</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Test of Hyper-Complex Quantum Theories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In standard quantum mechanics, complex numbers are used to describe the
wavefunction. Although complex numbers have proven sufficient to predict the
results of existing experiments, there is no apparent theoretical reason to
choose them over real numbers or generalizations of complex numbers, i.e.
hyper-complex numbers. Experiments performed to date have proven that real
numbers are insufficient, but whether or not hyper-complex numbers are required
remains an open question. Quantum theories based on hyper-complex numbers are
one example of a post-quantum theory, which must be put on a firm experimental
foundation. Here we experimentally probe hyper-complex quantum theories, by
studying one of their deviations from complex quantum theory: the
non-commutativity of phases. We do so by passing single photons through a
Sagnac interferometer containing two physically different phases, having
refractive indices of opposite sign. By showing that the phases commute with
high precision, we place limits on a particular prediction of hyper-complex
quantum theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01830</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Bl&#xe1;zquez</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Benito</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ibarra-Mede</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosales-Ortega</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Menguiano</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ascasibar</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bitsakis</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cano-D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Cob&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Paz</keyname><forenames>A. Gil</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrera-Ballesteros</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galbany</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mast</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abril-Melgarejo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roman-Lopes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pipe3D, a pipeline to analyse integral field spectroscopy data: II.
  Analysis sequence and CALIFA dataproducts</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>53 pages, 17 figures, accepted for publishing in RevMxAA</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present Pipe3D, an analysis pipeline based on the FIT3D fitting tool,
devel- oped to explore the properties of the stellar populations and ionized
gas of Integral Field Spectroscopy data. Pipe3D was created to provide with
coherent, simple to distribute, and comparable dataproducts, independently of
the origin of the data, focused on the data of the most recent IFU surveys
(e.g., CALIFA, MaNGA, and SAMI), and the last generation IFS instruments (e.g.,
MUSE). Along this article we describe the different steps involved in the
analysis of the data, illustrating them by showing the dataproducts derived for
NGC 2916, observed by CALIFA and P-MaNGA. As a practical use of the pipeline we
present the complete set of dataproducts derived for the 200 datacubes that
comprises the V500 setup of the CALIFA Data Release 2 (DR2), making them freely
available through the network
(ftp://ftp.caha.es/CALIFA/dataproducts/DR2/Pipe3D). Finally, we explore the
hypothesis that the properties of the stellar populations and ionized gas of
galaxies at the effective radius are representative of the overall average
ones, finding that this is indeed the case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01844</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Shogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashikawa</keyname><forenames>Nobunari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toshikawa</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onoue</keyname><forenames>Masafusa</forenames></author></authors><title>The very wide-field $gzK$ galaxy survey -- I. Details of the clustering
  properties of star-forming galaxies at $z \sim 2$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures, published in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1927</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of clustering analysis on the $z \sim 2$ star-forming
galaxies. By combining our data with data from publicly available archives, we
collect $g$-, $\zb / z$-, and $K$-band imaging data over 5.2 deg$^{2}$, which
represents the largest area BzK/gzK survey. We apply colour corrections to
translate our filter-set to those used in the original BzK selection for the
gzK selection. Because of the wide survey area, we obtain a sample of 41,112
star-forming gzK galaxies at $z \sim 2$ (sgzKs) down to $\KAB &lt; 23.0$, and
determine high-quality two-point angular correlation functions (ACFs). Our ACFs
show an apparent excess from power-law behaviour at small angular scale
$(\theta \la 0.01^{\circ})$, which corresponds the virial radius of a dark halo
at $z \sim 2$ with a mass of $\sim 10^{13} \Msun$. We find that the correlation
lengths are consistent with the previous estimates over all magnitude range;
however, our results are evaluated with a smaller margin of error than that in
previous studies. The large amount of data enables us to determine ACFs
differentially depending on the luminosity of the subset of the data. The mean
halo mass of faint sgzKs $(22.0 &lt; K \leq 23.0)$ was found to be $\Mh =
(1.32^{+0.09}_{-0.12}) \times 10^{12} h^{-1} \Msun$, whereas bright sgzKs
($18.0 \leq K \leq 21.0)$ were found to reside in dark haloes with a mass of
$\Mh = (3.26^{+1.23}_{-1.02}) \times 10^{13} h^{-1} \Msun$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01845</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Shogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashikawa</keyname><forenames>Nobunari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamana</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toshikawa</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onoue</keyname><forenames>Masafusa</forenames></author></authors><title>The very wide-field $gzK$ galaxy survey -- II. The relationship between
  star-forming galaxies at $z \sim 2$ and their host haloes based upon HOD
  modelling</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of an halo occupation distribution (HOD) analysis of
star-forming galaxies at $z \sim 2$. We obtained high-quality angular
correlation functions based on a large sgzK sample, which enabled us to carry
out the HOD analysis. The mean halo mass and the HOD mass parameters are found
to increase monotonically with increasing $K$-band magnitude, suggesting that
more luminous galaxies reside in more massive dark haloes. The luminosity
dependence of the HOD mass parameters was found to be the same as in the local
Universe; however, the masses were larger than in the local Universe over all
ranges of magnitude. This implies that galaxies at $z \sim 2$ tend to form in
more massive dark haloes than in the local Universe, a process known as
downsizing. By analysing the dark halo mass evolution using the extended
Press--Schechter formalism and the number evolution of satellite galaxies in a
dark halo, we find that faint Lyman break galaxies at $z \sim 4$ could evolve
into the faintest sgzKs $(22.0 &lt; K \leq 23.0)$ at $z \sim 2$ and into the
Milky-Way-like galaxies or elliptical galaxies in the local Universe, whereas
the most luminous sgzKs $(18.0 \leq K \leq 21.0)$ could evolve into the most
massive systems in the local Universe. The stellar-to-halo mass ratio (SHMR) of
the sgzKs was found to be consistent with the prediction of the model, except
that the SHMR of the faintest sgzKs was smaller than the prediction at $z \sim
2$. This discrepancy may be attributed that our samples are confined to
star-forming galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01859</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Vervoort</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Significant-Loophole-Free Test of Bell's Theorem with
  Entangled Photons&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent article Giustina et al. [Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 250401 (2015)]
report on an advanced Bell experiment, simultaneously closing loopholes for
local hidden-variable theories. The authors claim that 'local realism' has been
refuted, unless 'truly exotic hypotheses' are made. Here I argue that a
particularly wide and natural class of local hidden-variable theories survives,
for instance when the hidden variables describe a background field. Such
background-based theories exploit the freedom-of-choice loophole, which cannot
be closed for this type of hidden variables. The dynamics of such models can be
illustrated by existing systems, e.g. from fluid mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01862</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozbek</keyname><forenames>Melih</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croft</keyname><forenames>Rupert A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khandai</keyname><forenames>Nishikanta</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-scale 3D mapping of the intergalactic medium using the Lyman Alpha
  Forest</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 13 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (March 11, 2016) 456 (4): 3610-3623</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2894</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Maps of the large-scale structure of the Universe at redshifts 2-4 can be
made with the Lyman-alpha forest which are complementary to low redshift galaxy
surveys. We apply the Wiener interpolation method of Caucci et al. to construct
three-dimensional maps from sets of Lyman-alpha forest spectra taken from
cosmological hydrodynamic simulations. We mimic some current and future quasar
redshift surveys (BOSS, eBOSS and MS-DESI) by choosing similar sightline
densities. We use these appropriate subsets of the Lyman-alpha absorption
sightlines to reconstruct the full three dimensional Lyman-alpha flux field and
perform comparisons between the true and the reconstructed fields. We study
global statistical properties of the intergalactic medium (IGM) maps with
auto-correlation and cross-correlation analysis, slice plots, local peaks and
point by point scatter. We find that both the density field and the statistical
proper- ties of the IGM are recovered well enough that the resulting IGM maps
can be meaningfully considered to represent large-scale maps of the Universe in
agreement with Caucci et al., on larger scales and for sparser sightlines than
had been tested previously. Quantitatively, for sightline parameters comparable
to current and near future surveys the correlation coefficient between true and
reconstructed fields is r &gt; 0.9 on scales &gt; 30 h^-1 Mpc. The properties of the
maps are relatively insensitive to the precise form of the covariance matrix
used. The final BOSS quasar Lyman-alpha forest sample will allow maps to be
made with a resolution of ~ 30 h^-1 Mpc over a volume of ~ 15 h^-3 Gpc^3
between redshifts 1.9 and 2.3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01882</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Duclou&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallon</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double scattering contribution to small-x processes: Mueller-Navelet
  jets at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on
  Multiple Partonic Interactions at the LHC (MPI@LHC'15), ICTP, Trieste, 23-27
  November 2015</comments><report-no>LPT-Orsay-16-08</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the importance of double parton scattering (DPS) in Mueller-Navelet
jets production at the LHC. We evaluate this contribution in kinematics
corresponding to existing and possible future measurements at the LHC, for the
cross section and the azimuthal correlation of the jets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01893</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruneau</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksic</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Last</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pillet</keyname><forenames>C. -A.</forenames></author></authors><title>What is absolutely continuous spectrum?</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This note is an expanded version of the author's contribution to the
Proceedings of the ICMP Santiago, 2015, and is based on a talk given by the
second author at the same Congress. It concerns a research program devoted to
the characterization of the absolutely continuous spectrum of a self-adjoint
operator H in terms of the transport properties of a suitable class of open
quantum systems canonically associated to H.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01897</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Swan</keyname><forenames>Jesse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Andrew A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tolstoy</keyname><forenames>Eline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Mike J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ca II triplet spectroscopy of RGB stars in NGC 6822: kinematics and
  metallicities</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures, includes tabular data</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 456, 4315 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2774</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed analysis of the chemistry and kinematics of red giants
in the dwarf irregular galaxy NGC 6822. Spectroscopy at 8500 Angstroms was
acquired for 72 red giant stars across two fields using FORS2 at the VLT. Line
of sight extinction was individually estimated for each target star to
accommodate the variable reddening across NGC 6822. The mean radial velocity
was found to be v_helio = (52.8 +/- 2.2) km/s with dispersion rms = 24.1 km/s,
in agreement with other studies. Ca II triplet equivalent widths were converted
into [Fe/H] metallicities using a V magnitude proxy for surface gravity. The
average metallicity was [Fe/H] = (-0.84 +/- 0.04) with dispersion rms = 0.31
dex and interquartile range 0.48. Our assignment of individual reddening values
makes our analysis more sensitive to spatial variations in metallicity than
previous studies. We divide our sample into metal-rich and metal-poor stars;
the former are found to cluster towards small radii with the metal-poor stars
more evenly distributed across the galaxy. The velocity dispersion of the
metal-poor stars is higher than that of the metal-rich stars; combined with the
age-metallicity relation this indicates that older populations have either been
dynamically heated or were born in a less disclike distribution. The low ratio
(v_rot/v_rms) suggests that within the inner 10', NGC 6822's stars are
dynamically decoupled from the HI gas, possibly in a thick disc or spheroid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01898</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirkamali</keyname><forenames>Ashrafalsadat S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muminov</keyname><forenames>Khikmat Kh.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of the Efficiency of CdS/CIGS Tandem Multi-Junction Solar
  Cells Using AMPS-1D</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we conduct numerical simulation of CdS/CIGS solar cells by use
of the AMPS-1D software aiming to formulate the optimal design of the new
multi-junction tandem solar cell providing its most efficient operation. We
start with the numerical simulation of single-junction CdS/CIGS solar cells,
which shows that its highest efficiency of 17.3% could be achieved by the
thickness of CIGS p-layer of 200 nm. This result is in a good agreement with
experimental data where the highest efficiency was 17.1% with the solar cell
thickness of 1 micron. By use of the results of the numerical simulation of the
single-junction solar cells we developed the design and conducted optimization
of the new multi-junction tandem CdS/CIGS solar cell structure. Numerical
simulation shows that the maximum efficiency of this solar cell is equal to
48.3%, which could be obtained with the thickness of the CIGS p-layer of 600 nm
at a standard illumination of AM 1.5.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01909</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Howard</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the flare activity of Sgr A*</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on
  the dark side of the Universe, 5 June 2009, Melbourne. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1602.00818</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conference Proceedings; 10/27/2009, Vol. 1178 Issue 1, pp.
  50-56</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.3264556</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Latest observational data provides evidence that the emissions from Sgr A*
originate from an accretion disc within ten gravitational radii of the
dynamical centre of Milky Way. We investigate the physical processes
responsible for the variable observed emissions from the compact radio source
Sgr A*. We study the evolution of the variable emission region and analyse
light curves and time-resolved spectra of emissions originated at the surface
of the accretion disk, close to the event horizon, near the marginally stable
orbit of a Kerr black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01914</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tothill</keyname><forenames>N. F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filipovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>The ATLAS-SPT Radio Survey of Cluster Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures. Submitted to Proceedings of Science for &quot;The many
  facets of extragalactic radio surveys: towards new scientific challenges&quot;,
  Bologna, Italy 20-23 October 2015 (EXTRA-RADSUR2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a high-performance computing cluster to mosaic 4,787 pointings, we have
imaged the 100 sq. deg. South Pole Telescope (SPT) deep-field at 2.1 GHz using
the Australian Telescope Compact Array to an rms of 80 $\mu$Jy and a resolution
of 8&quot;. Our goal is to generate an independent sample of radio-selected galaxy
clusters to study how the radio properties compare with cluster properties at
other wavelengths, over a wide range of redshifts in order to construct a
timeline of their evolution out to $z \sim 1.3$. A preliminary analysis of the
source catalogue suggests there is no spatial correlation between the clusters
identified in the SPT-SZ catalogue and our wide-angle tail galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01928</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Foram M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshipura</keyname><forenames>K N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaudhari</keyname><forenames>Asha S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modi</keyname><forenames>Hitesh S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pindaria</keyname><forenames>Manish J</forenames></author></authors><title>Completing electron scattering studies with the inert gas column:e - Rn
  scattering and Ionization</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interest in the inert or noble- gas atoms in general arises because they are
ideal as test systems for various theoretical models of electron scattering and
also since their interaction processes serve as reference for the determination
of instrumental responses in electron scattering experiments. The ionization
cross section data of ground state inert gas atoms He through Xe are considered
to be benchmark data. Our aim in this paper is to provide theoretical results
on electron scattering with Radon atoms, as it would complete the studies on
the entire inert gas column. That is possible with this particular column only,
in view of the preceding literature on He through Xe . Inert gas radon is
radioactive, and would be a difficult target for electron scattering
experiments. In the present calculations, the complications arising from
radioactivity are not considered. We provide hitherto unavailable cross
sections on atomic radon, and also provide opportunity of the comparison of
electron impact cross sections over all the inert gas targets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01936</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Manoj K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Jeewan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karmakar</keyname><forenames>Subhajeet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savanov</keyname><forenames>Igor S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Broad-band linear polarization in late-type active dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>MNRAS in press, 11 pages, 8 figures, 4 tabbles</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw195</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present recent polarimetric results of magnetically active late-type
dwarfs. The polarization in these stars is found to be wavelength dependent,
decreasing towards the longer wavelength. The average values of degree of
polarization in these active dwarfs are found to be 0.16+/-0.01, 0.080+/-0.006,
0.056+/-0.004 and 0.042+/-0.003 per cent in B, V, R, and I bands, respectively.
Present results indicate that polarization in the majority of active dwarfs are
primarily due to sum of the polarization by magnetic intensification and
scattering. However, supplementary sources of the polarization are also found
to be present in some active stars. The correlations between the degree of
polarization and various activity parameters like Rossby number, chromospheric
activity indicator and coronal activity indicator are found to be stronger in B
band and weaker in I band.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01970</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mikkelsen</keyname><forenames>Kaare B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bach</keyname><forenames>Lars A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Threshold games and cooperation on multiplayer graphs</title><categories>cs.GT cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>in PLOS ONE, 4th Feb 2016</comments><msc-class>91A06, 91A12, 91A15, 91A22, 91A43</msc-class><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0147207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Objective: The study investigates the effect on cooperation in multiplayer
games, when the population from which all individuals are drawn is structured -
i.e. when a given individual is only competing with a small subset of the
entire population.
  Method: To optimize the focus on multiplayer effects, a class of games were
chosen for which the payoff depends nonlinearly on the number of cooperators -
this ensures that the game cannot be represented as a sum of pair-wise
interactions, and increases the likelihood of observing behaviour different
from that seen in two-player games. The chosen class of games are named
&quot;threshold games&quot;, and are defined by a threshold, $M &gt; 0$, which describes the
minimal number of cooperators in a given match required for all the
participants to receive a benefit. The model was studied primarily through
numerical simulations of large populations of individuals, each with
interaction neighbourhoods described by various classes of networks.
  Results: When comparing the level of cooperation in a structured population
to the mean-field model, we find that most types of structure lead to a
decrease in cooperation. This is both interesting and novel, simply due to the
generality and breadth of relevance of the model - it is likely that any model
with similar payoff structure exhibits related behaviour.
  More importantly, we find that the details of the behaviour depends to a
large extent on the size of the immediate neighbourhoods of the individuals, as
dictated by the network structure. In effect, the players behave as if they are
part of a much smaller, fully mixed, population, which we suggest an expression
for.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01988</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonocore</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laenen</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnea</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melville</keyname><forenames>Stacey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vernazza</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Next-to-leading power threshold logarithms: a status report</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the Proceedings of the 12th International Symposium
  on Radiative Corrections (Radcor 2015) and LoopFest XIV, UCLA, 15-19 June,
  2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is ample evidence, dating as far back as Low's theorem, that the
universality of soft emissions extends beyond leading power in the soft energy.
This universality can, in principle, be exploited to generalise the formalism
of threshold resummations beyond leading power in the threshold variable. In
the past years, several phenomenological approaches have been partially
successful in performing such a resummation. Here, we briefly review some
recent developments which pave the way to a solution of this problem, at least
for electroweak annihilation processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01998</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Ying-Mao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xing-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yan-Ling</forenames></author></authors><title>Protecting entanglement from correlated amplitude damping channel using
  weak measurement and quantum measurement reversal</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, accepted by Quantum Information Processing</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the quantum technique of weak measurement, we propose a scheme to
protect the entanglement from correlated amplitude damping decoherence. In
contrast to the results of memoryless amplitude damping channel, we show that
the memory effects play a significant role in the suppression of entanglement
sudden death and protection of entanglement under severe decoherence. Moreover,
we find that the initial entanglement could be drastically amplified by the
combination of weak measurement and quantum measurement reversal even under the
correlated amplitude damping channel. The underlying mechanism can be
attributed to the probabilistic nature of weak measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02000</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Lyubimkov</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaminsky</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metlov</keyname><forenames>V. G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlenko</keyname><forenames>Ya. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poklad</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rachkovskaya</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Cool Giant HD 77361 - A Super Li-Rich Star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, 2015, Vol. 41, No. 12, pp. 809-823</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773715120075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Super Li-rich stars form a very small and enigmatic group whose existence
cannot be explained in terms of the standard stellar evolution theory. The goal
of our study is to check the reality of this group of cool giants based on an
independent technique. We have carried out such a check using the K giant HD
77361 (HR 3597), which has previously been assigned to this rare type, as an
example. We have redetermined the effective temperature Teff and surface
gravity log g for this star. We have applied two different methods, photometric
and spectroscopic, to estimate Teff (the accuracy of the Li-abundance
determination depends significantly on this parameter). The value of log g has
been found from the highly accurate parallax of this nearby star. To apply the
photometric method of determining Teff, we have performed UBV observations of
the star, which yielded V = 6.18 +/- 0.03, B - V = 1.13 +/- 0.01, and U - B =
1.18+/-0.05. The following parameters of the star have been found: effective
temperature Teff = 4370+/- 100 K, surface gravity log g = 2.30 +/- 0.10, iron
abundance log e(Fe) = 7.49 +/- 0.14, microturbulence Vt = 1.1 +/- 0.2 km/s,
rotational velocity V sin i = 4.5 km/s, and mass M = 1.3 +/- 0.2 Msun. The
lithium abundance has been determined from a non-LTE analysis of three Li I
lines: the resonance line at 6707.8 ?A and the subordinate lines at 6103.6 and
8126.4 ?A (the latter in a blend with a CN molecular line). We have found a
high lithium abundance, log e(Li) = 3.75 +/- 0.11, which exceeds considerably
the initial abundance log e(Li) = 3.2 +/- 0.1 for young stars in the solar
neighborhood. Thus, we have confirmed that the K giant HD 77361 actually
belongs to the type of super Li-rich stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02013</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Jaques</keyname><forenames>Ygor M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunetto</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galvao</keyname><forenames>Douglas S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanodroplets Impacting on Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unique and remarkable properties of graphene can be exploited as the
basis to a wide range of applications. However, in spite of years of
investigations there are some important graphene properties that are not still
fully understood, as for example, its wettability. There are controversial
reported results whether graphene is really hydrophobic or hydrophilic. In
order to address this problem we have carried out classical molecular dynamics
simulations of water nanodroplets shot against graphene surface. Our results
show that the contact angle values between the nanodroplets and graphene
surfaces depend on the initial droplet velocity value and these angles can
change from 86 degrees (hydrophobic) to 35 degrees (hydrophilic). Our
preliminary results indicate that the graphene wettability can be dependent on
spreading liquid dynamics and which can explain some of the apparent
inconsistencies reported in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02021</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>De Micheli</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viano</keyname><forenames>Giovanni Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Holomorphic extensions associated with series expansions</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>38 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>30B10, 30B40, 42A32, 81T28</msc-class><journal-ref>Forum Mathematicum 24 (2012), 1269-1316</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/form.2011.104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the holomorphic extension associated with power series, i.e., the
analytic continuation from the unit disk to the cut-plane $\mathbb{C} \setminus
[1,+\infty)$. Analogous results are obtained also in the study of trigonometric
series: we establish conditions on the series coefficients which are sufficient
to guarantee the series to have a KMS analytic structure. In the case of power
series we show the connection between the unique (Carlsonian) interpolation of
the coefficients of the series and the Laplace transform of a probability
distribution. Finally, we outline a procedure which allows us to obtain a
numerical approximation of the jump function across the cut starting from a
finite number of power series coefficients. By using the same methodology, the
thermal Green functions at real time can be numerically approximated from the
knowledge of a finite number of noisy Fourier coefficients in the expansion of
the thermal Green functions along the imaginary axis of the complex time plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02044</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Riggs</keyname><forenames>A J Eldorado</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasdin</keyname><forenames>N. Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groff</keyname><forenames>Tyler D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recursive Starlight and Bias Estimation for High-Contrast Imaging with
  an Extended Kalman Filter</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>30 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Astronomical Telescopes, Instruments, and Systems.
  2(1), 011017 (Feb 05, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.2.1.011017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For imaging faint exoplanets and disks, a coronagraph-equipped observatory
needs focal plane wavefront correction to recover high contrast. The most
efficient correction methods iteratively estimate the stellar electric field
and suppress it with active optics. The estimation requires several images from
the science camera per iteration. To maximize the science yield, it is
desirable both to have fast wavefront correction and to utilize all the
correction images for science target detection. Exoplanets and disks are
incoherent with their stars, so a nonlinear estimator is required to estimate
both the incoherent intensity and the stellar electric field. Such techniques
assume a high level of stability found only on space-based observatories and
possibly ground-based telescopes with extreme adaptive optics. In this paper,
we implement a nonlinear estimator, the iterated extended Kalman filter (IEKF),
to enable fast wavefront correction and a recursive, nearly-optimal estimate of
the incoherent light. In Princeton's High Contrast Imaging Laboratory we
demonstrate that the IEKF allows wavefront correction at least as fast as with
a Kalman filter and provides the most accurate detection of a faint companion.
The nonlinear IEKF formalism allows us to pursue other strategies such as
parameter estimation to improve wavefront correction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02048</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Lelito</keyname><forenames>Aleksandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>Oleg I.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Gibbons--Tsarev equation: symmetries, invariant solutions, and
  applications</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><msc-class>Primary 54C40, 14E20, Secondary 46E25, 20C20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present the full classification of the symmetry-invariant
solutions for the Gibbons--Tsarev equation. Then we use these solutions to
construct explicit expressions for reductions of Benney's moments equations, to
get solutions of Pavlov's equation, and to find integrable reductions of the
Ferapontov--Huard--Zhang system, which describes implicit two-phase solutions
of the dKP equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02056</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Iftikhar</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jezouin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthore</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gennser</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parmentier</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavanna</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierre</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-channel Kondo effect and renormalization flow with macroscopic
  quantum charge states</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>Letter (5 pages, 4 figures) and Methods (10 pages, 6 figures)</comments><journal-ref>Nature 526, 233 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature15384</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many-body correlations and macroscopic quantum behaviors are fascinating
condensed matter problems. A powerful test-bed for the many-body concepts and
methods is the Kondo model which entails the coupling of a quantum impurity to
a continuum of states. It is central in highly correlated systems and can be
explored with tunable nanostructures. Although Kondo physics is usually
associated with the hybridization of itinerant electrons with microscopic
magnetic moments, theory predicts that it can arise whenever degenerate quantum
states are coupled to a continuum. Here we demonstrate the previously elusive
`charge' Kondo effect in a hybrid metal-semiconductor implementation of a
single-electron transistor, with a quantum pseudospin-1/2 constituted by two
degenerate macroscopic charge states of a metallic island. In contrast to other
Kondo nanostructures, each conduction channel connecting the island to an
electrode constitutes a distinct and fully tunable Kondo channel, thereby
providing an unprecedented access to the two-channel Kondo effect and a clear
path to multi-channel Kondo physics. Using a weakly coupled probe, we reveal
the renormalization flow, as temperature is reduced, of two Kondo channels
competing to screen the charge pseudospin. This provides a direct view of how
the predicted quantum phase transition develops across the symmetric quantum
critical point. Detuning the pseudospin away from degeneracy, we demonstrate,
on a fully characterized device, quantitative agreement with the predictions
for the finite-temperature crossover from quantum criticality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02077</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Makropoulou</keyname><forenames>Mersini</forenames></author></authors><title>Cancer and electromagnetic radiation therapy: Quo Vadis?</title><categories>physics.med-ph q-bio.TO</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In oncology, treating cancer with a beam of photons is a well established
therapeutic technique, developed over 100 years, and today over 50% of cancer
patients will undergo traditional X-ray radiotherapy. However, ionizing
radiation therapy is not the only option, as the high-energy photons delivering
their cell-killing radiation energy into cancerous tumor can lead to
significant damage to healthy tissues surrounding the tumor, located throughout
the beam's path. Therefore, in nowadays, advances in ionizing radiation therapy
are competitive to non-ionizing ones, as for example the laser light based
therapy, resulting in a synergism that has revolutionized medicine. The use of
non-invasive or minimally invasive (e.g. through flexible endoscopes)
therapeutic procedures in the management of patients represents a very
interesting treatment option. Moreover, as the major breakthrough in cancer
management is the individualized patient treatment, new biophotonic techniques,
e.g. photo-activated drug carriers, help the improvement of treatment efficacy
and/or normal tissue toxicity. Additionally, recent studies support that laser
technology progresses could revolutionize cancer proton therapy, by reducing
the cost of the needed installations. The aim of this review is to present some
laser-based future objectives for cancer radiation therapy, aiming to address
the relevant advances in the ionizing and non-ionizing radiation therapy, i.e.
protons and heavy ions therapy, as well as photodynamic targeted and molecular
therapies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02078</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Goncalves</keyname><forenames>Cayo Emilio Monteiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galvao</keyname><forenames>Breno Rodrigues Lamaghere</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braga</keyname><forenames>Joao Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate multireference study of Si3 electronic manifold</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since it has been shown that the silicon trimer has a highly multi-reference
character, accurate multi-reference configuration interaction calculations are
performed to elucidate its electronic manifold. Emphasis is given to the long
range part of the potential, aiming to understand the atom-diatom collisions
dynamical aspects, to describe conical intersections and important saddle
points along the reactive path. Potential energy surface main features analysis
are performed for benchmarking, and highly accurate values for structures,
vibrational constants and energy gaps are reported, as well as the unpublished
spin-orbit coupling magnitude. The results predict that inter-system crossings
will play an important role in dynamical simulations, specially in triplet
state quenching, making the problem of constructing a precise potential energy
surface more complicated and multi-layer dependent. The ground state is
predicted to be the singlet one, but since the singlet-triplet gap is rather
small (2.448 kJ/mol) both of them are expected to be populated at room
temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02079</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mychelkin</keyname><forenames>Eduard G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makukov</keyname><forenames>Maxim A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tachyonic approach to neutrino dark matter</title><categories>physics.gen-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>Reported at 14th Marcel Grossmann Meeting (MG14), Rome, July 12-18,
  2015. Submitted to conference proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply a new approach based on three relativistic groups (bradyon, tachyon
and instanton) forming the `Lorentz groupoid' which allows, in particular, to
consider tachyons without introducing imaginary masses and negative energies
(related, as known, to violation of causality and unitarity). This leads to
effectively scalar conglomerate composed of tachyonic neutrino and antineutrino
spinor wave functions as a viable model for stationary dark matter. We also
briefly discuss a relevant early non-stationary high-energy stage of the
universe evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02083</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferralis</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bryndzia</keyname><forenames>L. Taras</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossman</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Genome-inspired molecular identification in organic matter via Raman
  spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rapid, non-destructive characterization of molecular level chemistry for
organic matter (OM) is experimentally challenging. Raman spectroscopy is one of
the most widely used techniques for non-destructive chemical characterization,
although it currently does not provide detailed identification of molecular
components in OM, due to the combination of diffraction-limited spatial
resolution and poor applicability of peak-fitting algorithms. Here, we develop
a genome-inspired collective molecular structure fingerprinting approach, which
utilizes ab initio calculations and data mining techniques to extract molecular
level chemistry from the Raman spectra of OM. We illustrate the power of such
an approach by identifying representative molecular fingerprints in OM, for
which the molecular chemistry is to date inaccessible using non-destructive
characterization techniques. Chemical properties such as aromatic cluster size
distribution and H/C ratio can now be quantified directly using the identified
molecular fingerprints. Our approach will enable non-destructive identification
of chemical signatures with their correlation to the preservation of
biosignatures in OM, accurate detection and quantification of environmental
contamination, as well as objective assessment of OM with respect to their
chemical contents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02117</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Adluru</keyname><forenames>Nagesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Destiche</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tromp</keyname><forenames>Do P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidson</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Andrew L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluating consistency of deterministic streamline tractography in
  non-linearly warped DTI data</title><categories>physics.med-ph q-bio.QM</categories><comments>32 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tractography is typically performed for each subject using the diffusion
tensor imaging (DTI) data in its native subject space rather than in some space
common to the entire study cohort. Despite performing tractography on a
population average in a normalized space, the latter is considered less
favorably at the \emph{individual} subject level because it requires spatial
transformations of DTI data that involve non-linear warping and reorientation
of the tensors. Although the commonly used reorientation strategies such as
finite strain and preservation of principle direction are expected to result in
adequate accuracy for voxel based analyses of DTI measures such as fractional
anisotropy (FA), mean diffusivity (MD), the reorientations are not always exact
except in the case of rigid transformations. Small imperfections in
reorientation at individual voxel level accumulate and could potentially affect
the tractography results adversely. This study aims to evaluate and compare
deterministic white matter fiber tracking in non-linearly warped DTI against
that in native DTI. The data present promising evidence that tractography in
non-linear warped DTI data could indeed be a viable and valid option for
various statistical analysis of DTI data in a spatially normalized space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02131</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Pansart</keyname><forenames>Jean Pierre</forenames><affiliation>IRFU</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Clifford algebra gauge invariant Lagrangian for gravity. Part 2 :
  compatibility with General Relativity tests</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gauge fields associated to the Dirac matrix algebra used with the standard
quadratic gauge field Lagrangian lead to an extended gravitational Lagrangian
which includes the Einstein-Hilbert one, plus quadratic, cosmological constant
and torsion terms. This note looks at three cases : the static central
symmetric field, the isotropic expanding universe, and the asymptotic field of
a rotating body, and show that, in weak gravitational fields, there is no
contradiction with General Relativity results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02143</id><created>2015-12-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>R. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulations of substructures in relativistic jets</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 20 figures</comments><msc-class>83-04, 83-08, 83C10, 83C57, 83C55, 76W05, 65Z05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a set of simulations of relativistic jets from accretion disk
initial setup with a new code in Fortran 90 to get numerical solutions of a
system of General Relativistic Magnetohydrodynamics (GRMHD) partial
differential equations in a fixed Black Hole (BH) spacetime which is able to
show substructures formations inside the jet as well as a lobe formation on the
disk. For this, a central scheme of finite volume method without dimensional
split and no Riemann solvers (a Nessyahu-Tadmor method) was implemented. Thus,
we were able to obtain stable numerical solutions with spurious oscillations
under control and no excessive numerical dissipation. We setup a magnetized
accretion disk uncharged plasma surrounding a central Schwarzschild BH immersed
in a magnetosphere which evolve to the ejection of matter in the form of jet
with its substructures over a distance of almost twenty times the BH radius.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ph/9603254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ph/9603254</id><created>1996-03-08</created><updated>1998-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>CINVESTAV-IPN Unidad Merida</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huerta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>CINVESTAV-IPN Unidad Merida</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Colon</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>CINVESTAV-IPN Unidad Merida</affiliation></author></authors><title>Scalar Sea Contributions to Spin 1/2 Baryon Structure and Magnetic
  Moments</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Final version</comments><doi>10.1063/1.49755</doi><abstract>  We treat the baryon as a composite system made out of a &quot;core&quot; of three
quarks (as in the standard quark model) surrounded by a &quot;sea&quot; (of gluons and
$q\bar{q}$-pairs) which is specified by its total quantum numbers like flavor,
spin and color. Specifically, we assume the sea to be a flavor octet with spin
0 but no color. The general wavefunction for spin 1/2 baryons with such a sea
component is given and an application to the magnetic moments is considered.
Numerical analysis shows that the scalar sea can provide a good fit to the
magnetic moment data using experimental errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
