<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:38:14Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-02-06" from="2016-02-05" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0810.4948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0810.4948</id><created>2008-10-27</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belenkiy</keyname><forenames>Ari</forenames><affiliation>Department of Statistics, Simon Fraser University, Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Echague</keyname><forenames>Eduardo Vila</forenames><affiliation>IBM-Chile, Santiago, CHILE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Groping Toward Linear Regression Analysis: Newton's Analysis of
  Hipparchus' Equinox Observations</title><categories>physics.hist-ph astro-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Observatory, 2016 February, Vol. 136, No. 1250, pp. 1-22</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In February 1700, Isaac Newton needed a precise tropical year to design a new
universal calendar that would supersede the Gregorian one. However,
17th-Century astronomers were uncertain of the long-term variation in the
inclination of the Earth's axis and were suspicious of Ptolemy's equinox
observations. As a result, they produced a wide range of tropical years. Facing
this problem, Newton attempted to compute the length of the year on his own,
using the ancient equinox observations reported by a famous Greek astronomer
Hipparchus of Rhodes, ten in number. Though Newton had a very thin sample of
data, he obtained a tropical year only a few seconds longer than the correct
length. The reason lies in Newton's application of a technique similar to
modern regression analysis. Newton wrote down the first of the two so-called
'normal equations' known from the ordinary least-squares (OLS) method. In that
procedure, Newton seems to have been the first to employ the mean (average)
value of the data set, while the other leading astronomers of the era (Tycho
Brahe, Galileo, and Kepler) used the median. Fifty years after Newton, in 1750,
Newton's method was rediscovered and enhanced by Tobias Mayer. Remarkably, the
same regression method served with distinction in the late 1920s when the
founding fathers of modern cosmology, Georges Lemaitre (1927), Edwin Hubble
(1929), and Willem de Sitter (1930), employed it to derive the Hubble constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1202.2194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1202.2194</id><created>2012-02-10</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mills</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient statistical classification of satellite measurements</title><categories>physics.ao-ph stat.ML</categories><comments>Corrected formatting errors, corrected equation in appendix</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Remote Sensing, 2011, 32(21): 6109-6132</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/01431161.2010.507795</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supervised statistical classification is a vital tool for satellite image
processing. It is useful not only when a discrete result, such as feature
extraction or surface type, is required, but also for continuum retrievals by
dividing the quantity of interest into discrete ranges. Because of the high
resolution of modern satellite instruments and because of the requirement for
real-time processing, any algorithm has to be fast to be useful. Here we
describe an algorithm based on kernel estimation called Adaptive Gaussian
Filtering that incorporates several innovations to produce superior efficiency
as compared to three other popular methods: k-nearest-neighbour (KNN), Learning
Vector Quantization (LVQ) and Support Vector Machines (SVM). This efficiency is
gained with no compromises: accuracy is maintained, while estimates of the
conditional probabilities are returned. These are useful not only to gauge the
accuracy of an estimate in the absence of its true value, but also to
re-calibrate a retrieved image and as a proxy for a discretized continuum
variable. The algorithm is demonstrated and compared with the other three on a
pair of synthetic test classes and to map the waterways of the Netherlands.
Software may be found at: http://libagf.sourceforge.net.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.0097</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.0097</id><created>2012-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Lloyd-Williams</keyname><forenames>J H</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic Monte Carlo simulations inspired by epitaxial graphene growth</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 85, 161402(R) (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.85.161402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene, a flat monolayer of carbon atoms packed tightly into a two
dimensional hexagonal lattice, has unusual electronic properties which have
many promising nanoelectronic applications. Recent Low Energy Electron
Microscopy (LEEM) experiments show that the step edge velocity of epitaxially
grown 2D graphene islands on Ru(0001) varies with the fifth power of the
supersaturation of carbon adatoms. This suggests that graphene islands grow by
the addition of clusters of five atoms rather than by the usual mechanism of
single adatom attachment.
  We have carried out Kinetic Monte Carlo (KMC) simulations in order to further
investigate the general scenario of epitaxial growth by the attachment of
mobile clusters of atoms. We did not seek to directly replicate the Gr/Ru(0001)
system but instead considered a model involving mobile tetramers of atoms on a
square lattice. Our results show that the energy barrier for tetramer break up
and the number of tetramers that must collide in order to nucleate an immobile
island are the important parameters for determining whether, as in the
Gr/Ru(0001) system, the adatom density at the onset of island nucleation is an
increasing function of temperature. A relatively large energy barrier for
adatom attachment to islands is required in order for our model to produce an
equilibrium adatom density that is a large fraction of the nucleation density.
A large energy barrier for tetramer attachment to islands is also needed for
the island density to dramatically decrease with increasing temperature. We
show that islands grow with a velocity that varies with the fourth power of the
supersaturation of adatoms when tetramer attachment is the dominant process for
island growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.5085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.5085</id><created>2013-01-22</created><updated>2014-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Jingyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shaomin</forenames></author></authors><title>A Precise Calculation of Delayed Coincidence Selection Efficiency and
  Accidental Coincidence Rate</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C 39, 056201 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/39/5/056201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model is proposed to address issues on the precise background evaluation
due to the complex data structure defined by the delayed coincidence method,
which is widely used in reactor electron-antineutrino oscillation experiments.
In this model, the effects from the muon veto, uncorrelated random background,
coincident signal and background are all studied with the analytical solutions,
simplifying the estimation of the systematic uncertainties of signal efficiency
and accidental background rate determined by the unstable single rate. The
result of calculation is validated numerically with a number of simulation
studies and is also applied and validated in the recent Daya Bay
hydrogen-capture based oscillation measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1302.1513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1302.1513</id><created>2013-02-06</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dinu</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact final state integrals for strong field QED</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.87.052101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper introduces the exact, analytic integration of all final state
variables for the process of nonlinear Compton scattering in an intense plane
wave laser pulse, improving upon a previously slow and challenging numerical
approach. Computationally simple and insightful formulae are derived for the
total scattering probability and mean energy-momentum of the emitted radiation.
The general form of the effective mass appears explicitely. We consider several
limiting cases, and present a quantum correction to Larmor's formula. Numerical
results are plotted and analysed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.3278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.3278</id><created>2013-03-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Nuclear Vibrations on the Energetics of Polythiophene:
  Quantized Energy Molecular Dynamics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 fgures</comments><journal-ref>Aust. J. Chem., 66(9), 1021-1028 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1071/CH13112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effects of nuclear dynamics on the energetics of polythiophene relevant for
the performance of organic solar cells are studied for the first time. Nuclear
motions change the expectation values of frontier orbital energies and the band
gap by about 0.1 eV vs. values at the equilibrium geometry, which is expected
to have a significant effect on light absorption, charge separation, and donor
regeneration. A new molecular dynamics (MD) algorithm, which accounts for the
quantum nature of vibrations, is introduced. It reproduces effects of
temperature and deuteration which are lost in the standard MD. Inclusion of
quantized vibrations leads to a broadening of the band gap and of energy levels
by about 20% at 300K, while having little effect on their expectation values
(which change by up to 0.03 eV). Increase in temperature from 300K to 400K and
deuteration cause an additional broadening of the spectrum by about 26% and
21%, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.2487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.2487</id><created>2013-05-11</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eckhardt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teschl</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author></authors><title>A coupling problem for entire functions and its application to the
  long-time asymptotics of integrable wave equations</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><msc-class>37K40, 35Q35 (Primary) 30D20, 37K20 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Nonlinearity 29, 1036--1046 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0951-7715/29/3/1036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel technique for analyzing the long-time asymptotics of
integrable wave equations in the case when the underlying isospectral problem
has purely discrete spectrum. To this end, we introduce a natural coupling
problem for entire functions, which serves as a replacement for the usual
Riemann-Hilbert problem, which does not apply in these cases. As a prototypical
example, we investigate the long-time asymptotics of the dispersionless
Camassa-Holm equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.4433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.4433</id><created>2013-09-17</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Castellanos-Gomez</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>Herre S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>Gary A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Folded MoS2 layers with reduced interlayer coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 figures + 8 supp. info. figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Research 2014, 7(4): 572-578</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12274-014-0425-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) structures generated by folding single-
and bilayer MoS2 flakes. We find that this modified layer stacking leads to a
decrease in the interlayer coupling and an enhancement of the photoluminescence
emission yield. We additionally find that folded single-layer MoS2 structures
show a contribution to photoluminescence spectra of both neutral and charged
excitons, which is a characteristic feature of single-layer MoS2 that has not
been observed in multilayer MoS2. The results presented here open the door to
fabrication of multilayered MoS2 samples with high optical absorption while
maintaining the advantageous enhanced photoluminescence emission of
single-layer MoS2 by controllably twisting the MoS2 layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.4633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.4633</id><created>2013-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Rohr</keyname><forenames>Rudolf P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naisbit</keyname><forenames>Russel E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazza</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bersier</keyname><forenames>Louix-F&#xe9;lix</forenames></author></authors><title>Matching-centrality decomposition and the forecasting of new links in
  networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI q-bio.PE</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences (2016),
  283:20152702</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspb.2015.2702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Networks play a prominent role in the study of complex systems of interacting
entities in biology, sociology, and economics. Despite this diversity, we
demonstrate here that a statistical model decomposing networks into matching
and centrality components provides a comprehensive and unifying quantification
of their architecture. First we show, for a diverse set of networks, that this
decomposition provides an extremely tight fit to observed networks.
Consequently, the model allows very accurate prediction of missing links in
partially known networks. Second, when node characteristics are known, we show
how the matching-centrality decomposition can be related to this external
information. Consequently, it offers a simple and versatile tool to explore how
node characteristics explain network architecture. Finally, we demonstrate the
efficiency and flexibility of the model to forecast the links that a novel node
would create if it were to join an existing network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.4523</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.4523</id><created>2014-05-18</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klypin</keyname><forenames>Anatoly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karachentsev</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makarov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasonova</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author></authors><title>Abundance of Field Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures. Published in MNRAS: 2015, v454, p1798</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new measurements of the abundance of galaxies with a given
circular velocity in the Local Volume: a region centered on the Milky Way
Galaxy and extending to distance 10Mpc. The sample of 750 mostly dwarf galaxies
provides a unique opportunity to study the abundance and properties of galaxies
down to absolute magnitudes MB= -10, and virial masses Mvir= 1e9Msun. We find
that the standard LCDM model gives remarkably accurate estimates for the
velocity function of galaxies with circular velocities V&gt;60kms and
corresponding virial masses Mvir&gt; 3e10Msun, but it badly fails by
over-predicting 5 times the abundance of large dwarfs with velocities V=
30-50kms. The Warm Dark Matter models cannot explain the data either,
regardless of mass of the WDM particle. Just as in previous observational
studies, we find a shallow asymptotic slope dN/dlog V = V**alpha, alpha =-1 of
the velocity function, which is inconsistent with the standard LCDM model that
predicts the slope alpha =-3. Though reminiscent to the known overabundance of
satellites problem, the overabundance of field galaxies is a much more
difficult problem. For the LCDM model to survive, in the 10Mpc radius of the
Milky Way there should be 1000 dark galaxies with virial mass Mvir= 1e10Msun,
extremely low surface brightness and no detectable HI gas. So far none of this
type of galaxies have been discovered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.0297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.0297</id><created>2014-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Brasch</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qun-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schiller</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kippenberg</keyname><forenames>Tobias J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation Hardness of High-Q Silicon Nitride Microresonators for Space
  Compatible Integrated Optics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>V. Brasch, Q.-F. Chen, S. Schiller, T. J. Kippenberg, Opt.
  Express. 22, 30786 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.22.030786</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</license><abstract>  Integrated optics has distinct advantages for applications in space because
it integrates many elements onto a monolithic, robust chip. As the development
of different building blocks for integrated optics advances, it is of interest
to answer the important question of their resistance with respect to ionizing
radiation. Here we investigate effects of proton radiation on high-Q silicon
nitride microresonators formed by a waveguide ring. We show that the
irradiation with high-energy protons has no lasting effect on the linear
optical losses of the microresonators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.0545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.0545</id><created>2014-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Legrain</keyname><forenames>Fleur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Aluminum doping improves the energetics of lithium, sodium, and
  magnesium storage in silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Power Sources, 274, 65-70 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.10.037</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  While Si is an effective insertion type anode for Li-ion batteries,
crystalline Si has been shown to be unsuitable for Na and Mg storage due, in
particular, to insufficient binding strength. It has recently been reported
that Si nanowires could be synthesized with high-concentration (several atomic
%) and dispersed Al doping. Here we show based on density functional theory
calculations that Al doping significantly improves the energetics for Na and Mg
insertion, specifically, making it thermodynamically favored versus vacuum
reference states. For high Al concentrations, the energy of Mg in Al-doped Si
approaches the cohesive energy of Mg. However, the migration barriers for the
diffusion of Li (0.57-0.70 eV), Na (1.07-1.19 eV) and Mg (0.97-1.18 eV) in
Al-doped Si are found to remain about as high as in pure Si, likely preventing
effective electrochemical sodiation and magnesiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7358</id><created>2014-09-25</created><authors><author><keyname>McClean</keyname><forenames>Jarrod R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Al&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Compact wavefunctions from compressed imaginary time evolution</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>RSC Adv., 2015, 5, 102277</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5RA23047K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simulation of quantum systems promises to deliver physical and chemical
predictions for the frontiers of technology. Unfortunately, the exact
representation of these systems is plagued by the exponential growth of
dimension with the number of particles, or colloquially, the curse of
dimensionality. The success of approximation methods has hinged on the relative
simplicity of physical systems with respect to the exponentially complex worst
case. Exploiting this relative simplicity has required detailed knowledge of
the physical system under study. In this work, we introduce a general and
efficient black box method for many-body quantum systems that utilizes
technology from compressed sensing to find the most compact wavefunction
possible without detailed knowledge of the system. It is a Multicomponent
Adaptive Greedy Iterative Compression (MAGIC) scheme. No knowledge is assumed
in the structure of the problem other than correct particle statistics. This
method can be applied to many quantum systems such as spins, qubits,
oscillators, or electronic systems. As an application, we use this technique to
compute ground state electronic wavefunctions of hydrogen fluoride and recover
98% of the basis set correlation energy or equivalently 99.996% of the total
energy with $50$ configurations out of a possible $10^7$. Building from this
compactness, we introduce the idea of nuclear union configuration interaction
for improving the description of reaction coordinates and use it to study the
dissociation of hydrogen fluoride and the helium dimer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7601</id><created>2014-09-26</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanazawa</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author></authors><title>Calabi-Yau threefolds of type K (I): Classification</title><categories>math.AG hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, comments welcome</comments><msc-class>14J32, 14J28, 14F45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Any Calabi-Yau threefold X with infinite fundamental group admits an \'etale
Galois covering either by an abelian threefold or by the product of a K3
surface and an elliptic curve. We call X of type A in the former case and of
type K in the latter case. In this paper, we provide the full classification of
Calabi-Yau threefolds of type K, based on Oguiso and Sakurai's work. Together
with a refinement of Oguiso and Sakurai's result on Calabi-Yau threefolds of
type A, we finally complete the classification of Calabi-Yau threefolds with
infinite fundamental group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.6370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.6370</id><created>2014-10-23</created><updated>2014-10-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jiahao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Xizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Honghua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Yongguan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Chaohong</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative Quantum Metrology with Spin Cat States</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 2015; 5: 17894</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep17894</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The maximally entangled states are excellent candidates for achieving
Heisenberg-limited measurements in ideal quantum metrology, however, they are
fragile against dissipation such as particle losses and their achievable
precisions may become even worse than the standard quantum limit (SQL). Here we
present a robust high-precision measurement scheme via spin cat states (a kind
of non-Gaussian entangled states in superposition of two spin coherent states)
in the presence of particle losses. The input spin cat states are of excellent
robustness against particle losses and their achievable precisions may still
beat the SQL. For realistic measurements based upon our scheme, comparing with
the population measurement, the parity measurement is more suitable for
yielding higher precisions. In phase measurement with realistic dissipative
systems of bosons, our scheme provides a robust and realizable way to achieve
high-precision measurements beyond the SQL.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.7811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.7811</id><created>2014-10-28</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Erdmenger</keyname><forenames>Johanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flory</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newrzella</keyname><forenames>Max-Niklas</forenames></author></authors><title>Bending branes for DCFT in two dimensions</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc</categories><comments>35 pages + appendices, 12 figures, v2: added references and a
  paragraph on negative tension solutions, v3: updated references</comments><report-no>MPP-2014-372</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1501 (2015) 058</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2015)058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a holographic dual model for defect conformal field theories
(DCFT) in which we include the backreaction of the defect on the dual geometry.
In particular, we consider a dual gravity system in which a two-dimensional
hypersurface with matter fields, the brane, is embedded into a
three-dimensional asymptotically Anti-de Sitter spacetime. Motivated by recent
proposals for holographic duals of boundary conformal field theories (BCFT), we
assume the geometry of the brane to be determined by Israel junction
conditions. We show that these conditions are intimately related to the energy
conditions for the brane matter fields, and explain how these energy conditions
constrain the possible geometries. This has implications for the holographic
entanglement entropy in particular. Moreover, we give exact analytical
solutions for the case where the matter content of the brane is a perfect
fluid, which in a particular case corresponds to a free massless scalar field.
Finally, we describe how our results may be particularly useful for extending a
recent proposal for a holographic Kondo model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1622</id><created>2014-11-06</created><updated>2015-08-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bieri</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messio</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernu</keyname><forenames>Bernard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lhuillier</keyname><forenames>Claire</forenames></author></authors><title>Gapless chiral spin liquid in a kagome Heisenberg model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5+6 pages, 7 figs; refs added, typos corrected; discussion and refs
  updated, minor corrections; replaced w. published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 060407(R) (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.060407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experiments on the Heisenberg S=1/2 quantum spin liquid
candidate material kapellasite, we classify all possible chiral (time-reversal
symmetry breaking) spin liquids with fermionic spinons on the kagome lattice.
We obtain the phase diagram for the physically relevant extended Heisenberg
model, comparing the energies of a wide range of microscopic variational wave
functions. We propose that, at low temperature, kapellasite exhibits a gapless
chiral spin liquid phase with spinon Fermi surfaces. This two-dimensional state
inherits many properties of the nearby one-dimensional phase of decoupled
anti-ferromagnetic spin chains, but also shows some remarkable differences. We
discuss the spin structure factors and other physical properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4558</id><created>2014-11-17</created><updated>2015-04-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoudian</keyname><forenames>Samiyeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Shao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobrosavljevi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum criticality at the Anderson transition: a TMT perspective</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B. 92, 144202 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.144202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a complete analytical and numerical solution of the Typical Medium
Theory (TMT) for the Anderson metal-insulator transition. In this theory, we
self-consistently calculate the typical amplitude of the electron wave-We
present a complete analytical and numerical solution of the Typical Medium
Theory (TMT) for the Anderson metal-insulator transition. This approach
self-consistently calculates the typical amplitude of the electronic
wave-functions, thus representing the conceptually simplest order-parameter
theory for the Anderson transition. We identify all possible universality
classes for the critical behavior, which can be found within such a mean-field
approach. This provides insights into how interaction-induced renormalizations
of the disorder potential may produce qualitative modifications of the critical
behavior. We also formulate a simplified description of the leading critical
behavior, thus obtaining an effective Landau theory for Anderson localization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4007</id><created>2014-12-12</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruschi</keyname><forenames>David Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>On the weight of entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures. Updated to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 54, 182-186 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.01.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a scenario where quantum correlations affect the gravitational
field. We show that quantum correlations between particles occupying different
positions have an effect on the gravitational field. We find that the small
perturbations induced by the entanglement depend on the amount of entanglement
and vanish for vanishing quantum correlations. Our results suggest that there
is a form of entanglement that has a weight, since it affects the gravitational
field. This conclusion may lead towards a new understanding of the role of
quantum correlations within the overlap of relativistic and quantum theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.5578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.5578</id><created>2014-12-17</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ranjith</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nath</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skoulatos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasinathan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skourski</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsirlin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collinear order in a frustrated three-dimensional spin-$\frac12$
  antiferromagnet Li$_2$CuW$_2$O$_8$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>published version with supplemental material merged into the text</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 094426 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.094426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic frustration in three dimensions (3D) manifests itself in the
spin-$\frac12$ insulator Li$_2$CuW$_2$O$_8$. Density-functional band-structure
calculations reveal a peculiar spin lattice built of triangular planes with
frustrated interplane couplings. The saturation field of 29 T contrasts with
the susceptibility maximum at 8.5 K and a relatively low N\'eel temperature
$T_N\simeq 3.9$ K. Magnetic order below $T_N$ is collinear with the propagation
vector $(0,\frac12,0)$ and an ordered moment of 0.65(4) $\mu_B$ according to
neutron diffraction data. This reduced ordered moment together with the low
maximum of the magnetic specific heat ($C^{\max}/R\simeq 0.35$) pinpoint strong
magnetic frustration in 3D. Collinear magnetic order suggests that quantum
fluctuations play crucial role in this system, where a non-collinear spiral
state would be stabilized classically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.01615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.01615</id><created>2015-01-03</created><updated>2015-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>G. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhaskar</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jha</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xulu</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective gravitational mass of the Ay\'{o}n-Beato and Garc\'{\i}a
  metric</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Modern Physics Letters A</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A 30, 1550120 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732315501205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we calculate the effective gravitational mass of
Ay\'{o}n-Beato and Garc\'{\i}a regular (non-singular) static spherically
symmetric asymptotically Minkowskian metric that is a solution to Einstein's
equations coupled with a nonlinear electromagnetic field. The effective
gravitational mass is negative, zero, or positive that depends on the ratio of
magnitude of electric charge to the ADM mass and the ratio of the radial
distance to the ADM mass. As expected, at large value of radial distance, our
result gives effective gravitational mass of the Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om metric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.03560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.03560</id><created>2015-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raikh</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the inhomogeneously-broadened spin noise spectrum with ac
  drive</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 155301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.155301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the presence of random hyperfine fields, the noise spectrum, \delta
s_{\omega}^2, of a spin ensemble represents a narrow peak centered at \omega =0
and a broad &quot;wing&quot; reflecting the distribution of the hyperfine fields. In the
presence of an ac drive, the dynamics of a single spin acquires additional
harmonics at frequencies determined by both, the drive frequency and the local
field. These harmonics are reflected as additional peaks in the noise spectrum.
We study how the ensemble-averaged \delta s_{\omega}^2 evolves with the drive
amplitude, \omega_dr (in the frequency units). Our main finding is that
additional peaks in the spectrum, caused by the drive, remain sharp even when
\omega_dr is much smaller than the typical hyperfine field. The reason is that
the drive affects only the spins for which the local Larmour frequency is close
to the drive frequency. The shape of the low-frequency &quot;Rabi&quot;-peak in \delta
s_{\omega}^2 is universal with both, the position and the width, being of the
order of \omega_dr. When the drive amplitude exceeds the width of the hyperfine
field distribution, the noise spectrum transforms into a set of sharp peaks
centered at harmonics of the drive frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00350</id><created>2015-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raikh</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant magneto-tunneling between normal and ferromagnetic electrodes
  in relation to the three-terminal spin transport</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 195316 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.195316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently suggested mechanism [Y. Song and H. Dery, Phys. Rev. Lett. 113,
047205 (2014)] of the three-terminal spin transport is based on the resonant
tunneling of electrons between ferromagnetic and normal electrodes via an
impurity. The sensitivity of current to a weak external magnetic field stems
from a spin blockade, which, in turn, is enabled by strong on-site repulsion.
We demonstrate that this sensitivity exists even in the absence of repulsion
when a single-particle description applies. Within this description, we
calculate exactly the resonant-tunneling current between the electrodes. The
mechanism of magnetoresistance, completely different from the spin blocking,
has its origin in the interference of virtual tunneling amplitudes. Spin
imbalance in ferromagnetic electrode is responsible for this interference and
the resulting coupling of the Zeeman levels. This coupling also affects the
current in the correlated regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00833</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00833</id><created>2015-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Legrain</keyname><forenames>Fleur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotsis</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Amorphous carbon a promising material for sodium ion battery anodes: a
  first principles study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figues</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C 119 (2015) 13496-13501</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b03407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparative ab initio computational study of sodium and lithium
storage in amorphous (glassy) carbon (a-C) vs. graphite. Amorphous structures
are obtained by fitting stochastically generated structures to a reference
radial distribution function. Li insertion is thermodynamically favored in both
graphite and a-C. While sodium insertion is thermodynamically unfavored in
graphite, a-C possesses multiple insertion sites with binding energies stronger
than Na cohesive energy, making it usable as anode material for Na-ion
batteries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03395</id><created>2015-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Horio</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambolode</keyname><forenames>L. C. C.</forenames><suffix>II</suffix></author><author><keyname>Okazaki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ono</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumigashira</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anzai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arita</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Namatame</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ootsuki</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawada</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizokawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koike</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujimori</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppression of the antiferromagnetic pseudogap in the electron-doped
  high-temperature superconductor by &quot;protect annealing&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7:10567 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms10567</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the hole-doped cuprates, a small amount of carriers suppresses
antiferromagnetism and induces superconductivity. In the electron-doped
cuprates, on the other hand, superconductivity appears only in a narrow range
of high electron concentration ($\sim$ doped Ce content) after reduction
annealing, and strong antiferromagnetic (AFM) correlation persists in the
superconducting phase. Recently, Pr$_{1.3-x}$La$_{0.7}$Ce$_{x}$CuO$_{4}$
(PLCCO) bulk single crystals annealed by a &quot;protect annealing&quot; method showed a
high $T_c$ of $\sim$ 27 K for small Ce content down to $x \sim 0.05$. By
angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES) measurements of PLCCO
crystals, we observed a sharp quasi-particle peak on the entire Fermi surface
without signature of an AFM pseudogap unlike all the previous work, indicating
a dramatic reduction of AFM correlation length and/or of magnetic moments. The
superconducting state was found to extend over a wide electron concentration
range. The present ARPES results fundamentally change the long-standing picture
on the electronic structure in the electron-doped regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03533</id><created>2015-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yingqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Lithium and sodium storage on tetracyanoethylene (TCNE) and
  TCNE-(doped)-graphene complexes: a computational study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Mater. Chem. Phys. 156 (2015) 180-187</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.matchemphys.2015.02.045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Li and Na attachment to free tetracyanoethylene (TCNE) molecules and TCNE
adsorbed on doped graphene is studied using density functional theory. While
TCNE is adsorbed only weakly on ideal graphene, we identified a configuration
in which TCNE is chemisorbed on Al-doped graphene via molecule C atom and a
surface oxygen atom. Up to four (five) Li and Na atoms can be stored on both
free (adsorbed) TCNE with binding energies stronger than cohesive energies of
the Li and Na metals. When storing up to three atoms per molecule, it should be
possible to avoid reduction of common battery electrolytes. TCNE immobilized on
a conducting graphene-based substrate could therefore become an efficient anode
material for organic Li and Na ion batteries. Importantly, there is no
significant difference either in specific capacity (per unit mass of material
excluding Li/Na) nor in voltage between Li and Na storage, which makes this
kind of approach very promising for post-Li storage in general.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.01963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.01963</id><created>2015-03-06</created><updated>2016-01-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bacani</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamas</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fantini</keyname><forenames>M. C. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural studies of mesoporous ZrO$_{2}$-CeO$_{2}$ and
  ZrO$_{2}$-CeO$_{2}$/SiO$_{2}$ mixed oxides for catalytical applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jallcom.2016.01.213</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work the synthesis of ZrO$_{2}$-CeO$_{2}$ and
ZrO$_{2}$-CeO$_{2}$/SiO$_{2}$ were developed, based on the process to form
ordered mesoporous materials such as SBA-15 silica. The triblock copolymer
Pluronic P-123 was used as template, aiming to obtain crystalline single phase
walls and larger specific surface area, for future applications in catalysis.
SAXS and XRD results showed a relationship between ordered pores and the
material crystallization. 90% of CeO$_{2}$ leaded to single phase homogeneous
ceria-zirconia solid solution of cubic fluorite structure (Fm$\bar{3}$m). The
SiO$_{2}$ addition improved structural and textural properties as well as the
reduction behavior at lower temperatures, investigated by XANES measurements
under H$_{2}$ atmosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07324</id><created>2015-03-25</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Wei-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Travers</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>Philip St. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-ionization-threshold emission in atomic gases driven by intense
  sub-cycle pulses</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 18, 023018 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/023018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study theoretically the dipole radiation of a hydrogen atom driven by an
intense sub-cycle pulse. The time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation for the
system is solved by ab initio calculation to obtain the dipole response.
Remarkably, a narrowband emission lasting longer than the driving pulse appears
at a frequency just above the ionization threshold. An additional calculation
using the strong field approximation also recovers this emission, which
suggests that it corresponds to the oscillation of nearly-bound electrons that
behave similarly to Rydberg electrons. The predicted phenomenon is unique to
ultrashort driving pulses but not specific to any particular atomic structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03605</id><created>2015-04-14</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Landon</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yau</keyname><forenames>Horng-Tzer</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence of local statistics of Dyson Brownian motion</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>43 pages. Second draft contains improvements of the hypotheses of
  main result</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the rate of convergence of the local statistics of Dyson Brownian
motion to the GOE/GUE for short times $t=o(1)$ with deterministic initial data
V . Our main result states that if the density of states of $V$ is bounded both
above and away from $0$ down to scales $\ell \ll t$ in a small interval of size
$G \gg t$ around an energy $E_0$, then the local statistics coincide with the
GOE/GUE near the energy $E_0$ after time $t$. Our methods are partly based on
the idea of coupling two Dyson Brownian motions from [6], the parabolic
regularity result of [15], and the eigenvalue rigidity results of [21].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01211</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01211</id><created>2015-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pesin</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raikh</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin pumping from a ferromagnet into a hopping insulator: the role of
  resonant absorption of magnons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 045405 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experiments on spin pumping from a ferromagnet into
organic materials in which the charge transport is due to hopping, we study
theoretically the generation and propagation of spin current in a hopping
insulator. Unlike metals, the spin polarization at the boundary with
ferromagnet is created as a result of magnon absorption within pairs of
localized states and it spreads following the current-currying resistor network
(although the charge current is absent). We consider a classic resonant
mechanism of the ac absorption in insulators and adapt it to the absorption of
magnons. A strong enhancement of pumping efficiency is predicted when the
Zeeman splitting of the localized states in external magnetic field is equal to
the frequency of ferromagnetic resonance. Under this condition the absorption
of a magnon takes place within individual sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03156</id><created>2015-05-12</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ahlers</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barger</keyname><forenames>Vernon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author></authors><title>Galactic Neutrinos in the TeV to PeV Range</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>34 pages, 13 figures, 1 table; final version in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 013009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.013009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the contribution of Galactic sources to the flux of astrophysical
neutrinos recently observed by the IceCube Collaboration. We show that in the
simplest model of homogeneous and isotropic cosmic ray diffusion in the Milky
Way the Galactic diffuse neutrino emission consistent with $\gamma$-ray
(Fermi-LAT) and cosmic ray data (KASCADE, KASCADE-Grande and CREAM) is expected
to account for only $4\%-8\%$ of the IceCube flux above 60 TeV. Direct neutrino
emission from cosmic ray-gas ($pp$) interactions in the sources would require
an unusually large average opacity above 0.01. On the other hand, we find that
the IceCube events already probe Galactic neutrino scenarios via the
distribution of event arrival directions. Based on the latter, we show that
most Galactic scenarios can only have a limited contribution to the
astrophysical signal: diffuse Galactic emission ($\lesssim50\%$), quasi-diffuse
emission of neutrino sources ($\lesssim65\%$), extended diffuse emission from
the Fermi Bubbles ($\lesssim25\%$) or unidentified TeV $\gamma$-ray sources
($\lesssim25\%$). The arguments discussed here leave, at present, dark matter
decay unconstrained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05221</id><created>2015-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gobato</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gobato</keyname><forenames>Desire Francine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gobato</keyname><forenames>Alekssander</forenames></author></authors><title>LOT-G3: Plasma Lamp, Ozonator and CW transmitter</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>in Portuguese</comments><doi>10.5902/2179-460X19387</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LOT-G3 is designed to be a versatile equipment that perform several
simple experiments for use in helping the physics classes for high school. Easy
construction, low cost, using easily accessible materials. Its construction
involves simple practices and knowledge of electromagnetism. It has the
function of a plasma globe to demonstrate the ionization of a low pressure gas,
as well as the formation of magnetic field. Can be used as sanitizer closed
environments such as automotive vehicles in ozonator function, demonstrating
the ionization of oxygen in the atmosphere, producing ozone, essential to life
on earth. And as a sparks transmitter, low power, low frequency modulated
continuous wave in (CW), for signals in Morse code. Therefore the equipment
here called LOT-G3, has three functions: a plasma lamp, ozonator and CW
transmitter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04433</id><created>2015-06-14</created><updated>2015-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Unwin</keyname><forenames>H. Juliette T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wells</keyname><forenames>Garth N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author></authors><title>CO$_2$ dissolution in a background hydrological flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.geo-ph</categories><msc-class>76S05, 76R10, 76R50, 86A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics (2016) 789:768-784</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.752</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the long time steady-state dissolution of CO$_{2}$ in a deep
saline aqquifer in the presence of a background hydrological flow. In
steady-state, the distribution of CO$_2$ in the groundwater upstream of the
aquifer involves a balance between three competing effects: (i) the
buoyancy-driven flow of CO$_2$ saturated water; (ii) the diffusion of CO$_2$
from saturated to under-saturated water; and (iii) the advection associated
with the oncoming background flow. This leads to three limiting regimes. In the
limit of very slow diffusion, a nearly static intrusion of dense fluid may
extend a finite distance upstream, balanced by the pressure gradient associated
with the oncoming background flow. In the limit of fast diffusion relative to
the flow, a gradient zone may become established in which the along aquifer
diffusive flux balances the advection associated with the background flow.
However, if the buoyancy-driven flow speed exceeds the background hydrological
flow speed, then a third, intermediate regime may become established. In this
regime, a convective recirculation develops upstream of the anticline involving
the vertical diffusion of CO$_2$ from an upstream propagating flow of dense
CO$_2$ saturated water into the downstream propagating flow of CO$_2$
unsaturated water. For each limiting case, we find analytical solutions for the
distribution of CO$_2$ upstream of the anticline, and test our analysis with
full numerical simulations. A key result is that, although there may be very
different controls on the distribution and extent of CO$_2$ bearing water
upstream of the anticline, in each case the dissolution rate is given by the
product of the background volume flux and the difference in concentration
between the CO$_2$ saturated water and the original aquifer water upstream.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05195</id><created>2015-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jisoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Soon Gu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Je-Geun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hyeon</keyname><forenames>Taeghwan</forenames></author></authors><title>Size Dependence of Metal-Insulator Transition in Stoichiometric Fe3O4
  Nanocrystals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, Nano Letters (accepted)</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2015 (7) pp 4337 - 4342</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b00331</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetite (Fe3O4) is one of the most actively studied materials with a famous
metal-insulator transition (MIT), so-called the Verwey transition at around 123
K. Despite the recent progress in synthesis and characterization of Fe3O4
nanocrystals (NCs), it is still an open question how the Verwey transition
changes on a nanometer scale. We herein report the systematic studies on size
dependence of the Verwey transition of stoichiometric Fe3O4 NCs. We have
successfully synthesized stoichiometric and uniform-sized Fe3O4 NCs with sizes
ranging from 5 to 100 nm. These stoichiometric Fe3O4 NCs show the Verwey
transition when they are characterized by conductance, magnetization, cryo-XRD,
and heat capacity measurements. The Verwey transition is weakly size-dependent
and becomes suppressed in NCs smaller than 20 nm before disappearing completely
for less than 6 nm, which is a clear, yet highly interesting indication of a
size effect of this well-known phenomena. Our current work will shed new light
on this ages-old problem of Verwey transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06395</id><created>2015-06-21</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Danila</keyname><forenames>Bogdan</forenames></author></authors><title>Comprehensive spectral approach for community structure analysis on
  complex networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cs.SI</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures, final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 022301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.022301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple but efficient spectral approach for analyzing the community
structure of complex networks is introduced. It works the same way for all
types of networks, by spectrally splitting the adjacency matrix into a
&quot;unipartite&quot; and a &quot;multipartite&quot; component. These two matrices reveal the
structure of the network from different perspectives and can be analyzed at
different levels of detail. Their entries, or the entries of their lower-rank
approximations, provide measures of the affinity or antagonism between the
nodes that highlight the communities and the &quot;gateway&quot; links that connect them
together. An algorithm is then proposed to achieve the automatic assignment of
the nodes to communities based on the information provided by either matrix.
This algorithm naturally generates overlapping communities but can also be
tuned to eliminate the overlaps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07223</id><created>2015-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kalashnikov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paterova</keyname><forenames>Anna V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulik</keyname><forenames>Sergei P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivitsky</keyname><forenames>Leonid A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Infrared Spectroscopy with Visible Light</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>submitted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 10, 98-101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2015.252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spectral measurements in the infrared (IR) optical range provide unique
fingerprints of materials which are useful for material analysis, environmental
sensing, and health diagnostics. Current IR spectroscopy techniques require the
use of optical equipment suited for operation in the IR range, which faces
challenges of inferior performance and high cost. Here we develop a
spectroscopy technique, which allows spectral measurements in the IR range
using visible spectral range components. The technique is based on nonlinear
interference of infrared and visible photons, produced via Spontaneous
Parametric Down Conversion (SPDC). The intensity interference pattern for a
visible photon depends on the phase of an IR photon, which travels through the
media. This allows determining properties of the media in the IR range from the
measurements of visible photons. The technique can substitute and/or complement
conventional IR spectroscopy techniques, as it uses well-developed optical
components for the visible range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02855</id><created>2015-07-10</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schlederer</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigl</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining ALP-photon coupling using galaxy clusters</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures; version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 01 (2016) 038</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study photon-ALP conversion by resonance effects in the magnetized plasma
of galaxy clusters and compare the predicted distortion of the cosmic microwave
background spectrum in the direction of such objects to measurements of the
thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect. Using galaxy cluster models based on current
knowledge, we obtain upper limits on the photon-ALP coupling constant $g$ of
$\lesssim \mathcal{O}(10^{-11}$ GeV$^{-1}$). The constraints apply to the mass
range of $2\cdot 10^{-14}$ eV $ \lesssim m_\text{ALP} \lesssim 3\cdot 10^{-12}$
eV in which resonant photon-ALP conversions can occur. These limits are
slightly stronger than current limits, and furthermore provide an independent
constraint. We find that a next generation PRISM-like experiment would allow
limits down to $g \approx \mathcal{O} (10^{-14}$ GeV$^{-1})$, two orders of
magnitude stronger than the currently strongest limits in this mass range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04625</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2015-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mattheakis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitsios</keyname><forenames>I. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsironis</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzortzakis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rogue events in complex linear and nonlinear photonic media</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Chaos, Solitons &amp; Fractals Volume 84, March 2016, Pages 73-80</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chaos.2016.01.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ocean rogue waves (RW) -huge solitary waves- have for long triggered the
interest of scientists. RWs emerge in a complex environment and it is still
dubious the importance of linear versus nonlinear processes. Recent works have
demonstrated that RWs appear in various other physical systems such as
microwaves, nonlinear crystals, cold atoms, etc. In this work we investigate
optical wave propagation in strongly scattering random lattices embedded in the
bulk of transparent glasses. In the linear regime we observe the appearance of
RWs that depend solely on the scattering properties of the medium.
Interestingly, the addition of nonlinearity does not modify the RW statistics,
while as the nonlinearities are increased multiple-filamentation and intensity
clamping destroy the RW statistics. Numerical simulations agree nicely with the
experimental findings and altogether prove that optical rogue waves are
generated through the linear strong scattering in such complex environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05269</id><created>2015-07-19</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Li-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Mo-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>$\mathbb{Z}_3$ Parafermionic Chain Emerging From Yang-Baxter Equation</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Main text: 12 pages; Supplementary: 4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct the 1D $\mathbb{Z}_3$ parafermionic model based on the solution
of Yang-Baxter equation and express the model by three types of fermions. It is
shown that the $\mathbb{Z}_3$ parafermionic chain possesses both triple
degenerate ground states and non-trivial topological winding number. Hence, the
$\mathbb{Z}_3$ parafermionic model is a direct generalization of 1D
$\mathbb{Z}_2$ Kitaev model. Both the $\mathbb{Z}_2$ and $\mathbb{Z}_3$ model
can be obtained from Yang-Baxter equation. On the other hand, to show the
algebra of parafermionic tripling intuitively, we define a new 3-body
Hamiltonian $\hat{H}_{123}$ based on Yang-Baxter equation. Different from the
Majorana doubling, the $\hat{H}_{123}$ holds triple degeneracy at each of
energy levels. The triple degeneracy is protected by two symmetry operators of
the system, $\omega$-parity $P$($\omega=e^{{\textrm{i}\frac{2\pi}{3}}}$) and
emergent parafermionic operator $\Gamma$, which are the generalizations of
parity $P_{M}$ and emergent Majorana operator in Lee-Wilczek model,
respectively. Both the $\mathbb{Z}_3$ parafermionic model and $\hat{H}_{123}$
can be viewed as SU(3) models in color space. In comparison with the Majorana
models for SU(2), it turns out that the SU(3) models are truly the
generalization of Majorana models resultant from Yang-Baxter equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06402</id><created>2015-07-23</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lochan</keyname><forenames>Kinjalk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extracting information about the initial state from the black hole
  radiation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>version to appear in Phys.Rev.Letts; selected as Editor's Suggestion</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 051301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.051301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The crux of the black hole information paradox is related to the fact that
the complete information about the initial state of a quantum field in a
collapsing spacetime is not available to future asymptotic observers, belying
the expectations from a unitary quantum theory. We study the imprints of the
initial quantum state contained in a specific class of distortions of the black
hole radiation and identify the classes of in-states which can be
partially/fully reconstructed from the information contained within. Even for
the general in-state, we can uncover some specific information. These results
suggest that a \textit{classical} collapse scenario ignores this richness of
information in the resulting spectrum and a consistent quantum treatment of the
entire collapse process might allow us to retrieve much more information from
the spectrum of the final radiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06764</id><created>2015-07-24</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Awasthi</keyname><forenames>Shalini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapil</keyname><forenames>Venkat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Nisanth N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sampling Free Energy Surfaces as Slices by Combining Umbrella Sampling
  and Metadynamics</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metadynamics (MTD) is a very powerful technique to sample high-dimensional
free energy landscapes, and due to its self-guiding property, the method has
been successful in studying complex reactions and conformational changes. MTD
sampling is based on filling the free energy basins by biasing potentials and
thus for cases with flat, broad and unbound free energy wells, the
computational time to sample them becomes very large. To alleviate this
problem, we combine the standard Umbrella Sampling (US) technique with MTD to
sample orthogonal collective variables (CVs) in a simultaneous way. Within this
scheme, we construct the equilibrium distribution of CVs from biased
distributions obtained from independent MTD simulations with umbrella
potentials. Reweighting is carried out by a procedure that combines US
reweighting and Tiwary-Parrinello MTD reweighting within the Weighted Histogram
Analysis Method (WHAM). The approach is ideal for a controlled sampling of a CV
in a MTD simulation, making it computationally efficient in sampling flat,
broad and unbound free energy surfaces. This technique also allows for a
distributed sampling of a high-dimensional free energy surface, further
increasing the computational efficiency in sampling. We demonstrate the
application of this technique in sampling high-dimensional surface for various
chemical reactions using ab initio and QM/MM hybrid molecular dynamics
simulations. Further, in order to carry out MTD bias reweighting for computing
forward reaction barriers in ab initio or QM/MM simulations, we propose a
computationally affordable approach that does not require recrossing
trajectories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08591</id><created>2015-07-30</created><updated>2015-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Kerwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Jeng-Da</forenames></author></authors><title>Van der Waals interactions in rare-gas dimers: The role of interparticle
  interactions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.atm-clus physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 18, 3011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5CP06317E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the potential energy curves of rare-gas dimers with various
ranges and strengths of interparticle interactions (nuclear-electron,
electron-electron, and nuclear-nuclear interactions). Our investigation is
based on the highly accurate coupled-cluster theory associated with those
interparticle interactions. For comparison, the performance of the
corresponding Hartree-Fock theory, second-order Moller-Plesset perturbation
theory, and density functional theory is also investigated. Our results reveal
that when the interparticle interactions retain the long-range Coulomb tails,
the nature of van der Waals interactions in the rare-gas dimers remains
similar. By contrast, when the interparticle interactions are sufficiently
short-range, the conventional van der Waals interactions in the rare-gas dimers
completely disappear, yielding purely repulsive potential energy curves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08824</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shirayama</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadowaki</keyname><forenames>Hideyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyadera</keyname><forenames>Tetsuhiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugita</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamakoshi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiseki</keyname><forenames>Takemasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murata</keyname><forenames>Daisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Takurou N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujimoto</keyname><forenames>Shohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chikamatsu</keyname><forenames>Masayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical transitions in hybrid perovskite solar cells: Ellipsometry,
  density functional theory, and quantum efficiency analyses for CH3NH3PbI3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>45 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Applied 5, 014012 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.5.014012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report artifact-free CH3NH3PbI3 optical constants extracted from
ultra-smooth perovskite layers without air exposure and assign all the optical
transitions in the visible/ultraviolet region unambiguously based on density
functional theory (DFT) analysis that assumes a simple pseudo-cubic crystal
structure. From the self-consistent spectroscopic ellipsometry analysis of the
ultra-smooth CH3NH3PbI3 layers, we find that the absorption coefficients of
CH3NH3PbI3 (alpha = 3.8 x 10^4 cm-1 at 2.0 eV) are comparable to those of
CuInGaSe2 and CdTe, and high alpha values reported in earlier studies are
overestimated seriously by extensive surface roughness of CH3NH3PbI3 layers.
The polarization-dependent DFT calculations show that CH3NH3+ interacts
strongly with the PbI3- cage, modifying the CH3NH3PbI3 dielectric function in
the visible region rather significantly. When the effect of CH3NH3+ on the
optical transition is eliminated in the DFT calculation, CH3NH3PbI3 dielectric
function deduced from DFT shows excellent agreement with the experimental
result. As a result, distinct optical transitions observed at E0 (Eg) = 1.61
eV, E1 = 2.53 eV, and E2 = 3.24 eV in CH3NH3PbI3 are attributed to the direct
semiconductor-type transitions at the R, M, and X points in the pseudo-cubic
Brillouin zone, respectively. We further perform the quantum efficiency (QE)
analysis for a standard hybrid-perovskite solar cell incorporating a mesoporous
TiO2 layer and demonstrate that the QE spectrum can be reproduced almost
perfectly when the revised CH3NH3PbI3 optical constants are employed.
Depth-resolved QE simulations confirm that Jsc is limited by the material's
longer wavelength response and indicate the importance of optical confinement
and long carrier diffusion lengths in hybrid perovskite solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02718</id><created>2015-08-11</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harland-Lang</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoze</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryskin</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exclusive physics at the LHC with SuperChic 2</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, 7 figures. Version accepted for publication in EPJC</comments><report-no>IPPP/15/34, DCPT/15/68</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:9</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3832-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a range of physics results for central exclusive production
processes at the LHC, using the new SuperChic 2 Monte Carlo event generator.
This includes significant theoretical improvements and updates, most
importantly a fully differential treatment of the soft survival factor, as well
as a greater number of generated processes. We provide an overview of the
latest theoretical framework, and consider in detail a selection of final
states, namely exclusive 2 and 3 jets, photoproduced vector mesons, two-photon
initiated muon and $W$ boson pairs and heavy $\chi_{c,b}$ quarkonia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01638</id><created>2015-09-04</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dudley</keyname><forenames>Harry J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goenka</keyname><forenames>Abhishek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orellana</keyname><forenames>Cesar J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martonosi</keyname><forenames>Susan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-year optimization of malaria intervention: a mathematical model</title><categories>q-bio.PE math.OC physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 9 figures, 6 tables. Under review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Malaria is a mosquito-borne, lethal disease that affects millions and kills
hundreds of thousands of people each year. In this paper, we develop a model
for allocating malaria interventions across geographic regions and time,
subject to budget constraints, with the aim of minimizing the number of
person-days of malaria infection. The model considers a range of several
conditions: climatic characteristics, treatment efficacy, distribution costs,
and treatment coverage. We couple an expanded susceptible-infected-recovered
(SIR) compartment model for the disease dynamics with an integer linear
programming (ILP) model for selecting the disease interventions. Our model
produces an intervention plan for all regions, identifying which combination of
interventions, with which level of coverage, to use in each region and year in
a five-year planning horizon. Simulations using the model yield high-level,
qualitative insights on optimal intervention policies: The optimal policy is
different when considering a five-year time horizon than when considering only
a single year, due to the effects that interventions have on the disease
transmission dynamics. The vaccine intervention is rarely selected, except if
its assumed cost is significantly lower than that predicted in the literature.
Increasing the available budget causes the number of person-days of malaria
infection to decrease linearly up to a point, after which the benefit of
increased budget starts to taper. The optimal policy is highly dependent on
assumptions about mosquito density, selecting different interventions for wet
climates with high density than for dry climates with low density, and the
interventions are found to be less effective at controlling malaria in the wet
climates when attainable intervention coverage is 60% or lower. However, when
intervention coverage of 80% is attainable, then malaria prevalence drops
quickly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02933</id><created>2015-09-09</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shapourian</keyname><forenames>Hassan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Taylor L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagrams of disordered Weyl semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>More explanation added to Sec. II, Fig. 7 included as an explicit
  example of phase boundaries of the AHI phase</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 075108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.075108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weyl semimetals are gapless quasi-topological materials with a set of
isolated nodal points forming their Fermi surface. They manifest their
quasi-topological character in a series of topological electromagnetic
responses including the anomalous Hall effect. Here we study the effect of
disorder on Weyl semimetals while monitoring both their nodal/semi-metallic and
topological properties through computations of the localization length and the
Hall conductivity. We examine three different lattice tight-binding models
which realize the Weyl semimetal in part of their phase diagram and look for
universal features that are common to all of the models, and interesting
distinguishing features of each model. We present detailed phase diagrams of
these models for large system sizes and we find that weak disorder preserves
the nodal points up to the diffusive limit, but does affect the Hall
conductivity. We show that the trend of the Hall conductivity is consistent
with an effective picture in which disorder causes the Weyl nodes move within
the Brillouin zone along a specific direction that depends deterministically on
the properties of the model and the neighboring phases to the Weyl semimetal
phase. We also uncover an unusual (non-quantized) anomalous Hall insulator
phase which can only exist in the presence of disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04279</id><created>2015-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>McClean</keyname><forenames>Jarrod R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babbush</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Al&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>The theory of variational hybrid quantum-classical algorithms</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 023023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/023023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many quantum algorithms have daunting resource requirements when compared to
what is available today. To address this discrepancy, a quantum-classical
hybrid optimization scheme known as &quot;the quantum variational eigensolver&quot; was
developed with the philosophy that even minimal quantum resources could be made
useful when used in conjunction with classical routines. In this work we extend
the general theory of this algorithm and suggest algorithmic improvements for
practical implementations. Specifically, we develop a variational adiabatic
ansatz and explore unitary coupled cluster where we establish a connection from
second order unitary coupled cluster to universal gate sets through relaxation
of exponential splitting. We introduce the concept of quantum variational error
suppression that allows some errors to be suppressed naturally in this
algorithm on a pre-threshold quantum device. Additionally, we analyze
truncation and correlated sampling in Hamiltonian averaging as ways to reduce
the cost of this procedure. Finally, we show how the use of modern derivative
free optimization techniques can offer dramatic computational savings of up to
three orders of magnitude over previously used optimization techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05223</id><created>2015-09-17</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xf6;yh&#xf6;nen</keyname><forenames>Kim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weststr&#xf6;m</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ojanen</keyname><forenames>Teemu</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological superconductivity in ferromagnetic atom chains beyond the
  deep-impurity regime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 014517 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.014517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent developments in the search for topological superconductivity have
brought lattices of magnetic adatoms on a superconductor into intense focus. In
this work we will study ferromagnetic chains of adatoms on superconducting
surfaces with Rashba spin-orbit coupling. Generalising the deep-impurity
approach employed extensively in previous works to arbitrary subgap energies,
we formulate the theory of the subgap spectrum as a nonlinear matrix eigenvalue
problem. We obtain an essentially analytical description of the subgap
spectrum, allowing an efficient study of the topological properties. Employing
a flat-band Hamiltonian sharing the topological properties of the chain, we
evaluate the $\mathbb{Z}$-valued winding number and discover five distinct
topological phases. Our results also confirm that the topological band
formation does not require the decoupled Shiba energies to be fine-tuned to the
gap centre. We also study the properties of Majorana bound states in the
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05841</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Budhi</keyname><forenames>Romy H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashiwase</keyname><forenames>Shoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suematsu</keyname><forenames>Daijiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation due to a non-minimal coupling of singlet scalars in the
  radiative seesaw model</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>28 pages, 6 figures, typos fixed, reference added, additional comment</comments><report-no>KANAZAWA-15-14</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 013022 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.013022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radiative neutrino mass model with inert doublet dark matter is a
promising model for the present experimental issues which cannot be explained
within the standard model. We study an extension of this model focusing on
cosmological features brought about from the scalar sector. Inflation due to
singlet scalars with hierarchical non-minimal couplings with the Ricci scalar
may give a favorable solution for both neutrino masses and baryon number
asymmetry in the Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06666</id><created>2015-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Azad</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kort-Kamp</keyname><forenames>W. J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sykora</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weisse-Bernstein</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luk</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalvit</keyname><forenames>D. A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. -T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Metasurface Broadband Solar Absorber</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 20347 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep20347</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a broadband, polarization independent, omnidirectional
absorber based on a metallic metasurface architecture, which accomplishes
greater than 90% absorptance in the visible and near-infrared range of the
solar spectrum, and exhibits low emissivity at mid- and far-infrared
wavelengths. The complex unit cell of the metasurface solar absorber consists
of eight pairs of gold nano-resonators that are separated from a gold ground
plane by a thin silicon dioxide spacer. Our experimental measurements reveal
high-performance absorption over a wide range of incidence angles for both s-
and p-polarizations. We also investigate numerically the frequency-dependent
field and current distributions to elucidate how the absorption occurs within
the metasurface structure. Furthermore, we discuss the potential use of our
metasurface absorber design in solar thermophotovoltaics by exploiting
refractory plasmonic materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08987</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draine</keyname><forenames>Bruce T.</forenames></author></authors><title>X-Ray Absorption and Scattering by Interstellar Grains</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>32 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 817 139 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/817/2/139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interstellar abundance determinations from fits to X-ray absorption edges
often rely on the incorrect assumption that scattering is insignificant and can
be ignored. We show instead that scattering contributes significantly to the
attenuation of X-rays for realistic dust grain size distributions and
substantially modifies the spectrum near absorption edges of elements present
in grains. The dust attenuation modules used in major X-ray spectral fitting
programs do not take this into account. We show that the consequences of
neglecting scattering on the determination of interstellar elemental abundances
are modest; however, scattering (along with uncertainties in the grain size
distribution) must be taken into account when near-edge extinction fine
structure is used to infer dust mineralogy. We advertise the benefits and
accuracy of anomalous diffraction theory for both X-ray halo analysis and near
edge absorption studies. An open source Fortran suite, General Geometry
Anomalous Diffraction Theory (GGADT), is presented that calculates X-ray
absorption, scattering, and differential scattering cross sections for grains
of arbitrary geometry and composition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.09010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.09010</id><created>2015-09-30</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lochan</keyname><forenames>Kinjalk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sumanta</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete quantum spectrum of black holes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Matches the published version</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B (2016), pp. 37-42</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.01.060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum genesis of Hawking radiation is a long-standing puzzle in black
hole physics. Semi-classically one can argue that the spectrum of radiation
emitted by a black hole look very much sparse unlike what is expected from a
thermal object. It was demonstrated through a simple quantum model that a
quantum black hole will retain a discrete profile, at least in the weak energy
regime. However, it was suggested that this discreteness might be an artifact
of the simplicity of eigen-spectrum of the model considered. Different quantum
theories can, in principle, give rise to different complicated spectra and make
the radiation from black hole dense enough in transition lines, to make them
look continuous in profile. We show that such a hope from a geometry-quantized
black hole is not realized as long as large enough black holes are dubbed with
a classical mass area relation in any gravity theory ranging from GR,
Lanczos-Lovelock to f(R) gravity. We show that the smallest frequency of
emission from black hole in any quantum description, is bounded from below, to
be of the order of its inverse mass. That leaves the emission with only two
possibilities. It can either be non-thermal, or it can be thermal only with the
temperature being much larger than 1/M.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00381</id><created>2015-10-01</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Kerwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Jeng-Da</forenames></author></authors><title>SCAN-based hybrid and double-hybrid density functionals from models
  without fitted parameters</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.atm-clus physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 6 figures, 1 table, supplementary material not included</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 044114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4940734</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By incorporating the nonempirical SCAN semilocal density functional [Sun,
Ruzsinszky, and Perdew, Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 036402 (2015)] in the underlying
expression of four existing hybrid and double-hybrid models, we propose one
hybrid (SCAN0) and three double-hybrid (SCAN0-DH, SCAN-QIDH, and SCAN0-2)
density functionals, which are free from any fitted parameters. The SCAN-based
double-hybrid functionals consistently outperform their parent SCAN semilocal
functional for self-interaction problems and noncovalent interactions. In
particular, SCAN0-2, which includes about 79% of Hartree-Fock exchange and 50%
of second-order Moller-Plesset correlation, is shown to be reliably accurate
for a very diverse range of applications, such as thermochemistry, kinetics,
noncovalent interactions, and self-interaction problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01535</id><created>2015-10-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Alberello</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chabchoub</keyname><forenames>Amin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramstad</keyname><forenames>Odin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babanin</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toffoli</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Gaussian properties of second-order wave orbital velocity</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.coastaleng.2016.01.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A stochastic second-order wave model is applied to assess the statistical
properties of wave orbital velocity in random sea states below the water
surface. Directional spreading effects as well as the dependency of the water
depth are investigated by means of a Monte-Carlo approach. Unlike for the
surface elevation, sub-harmonics dominate the second-order contribution to
orbital velocity. We show that a notable set-down occurs for the most energetic
and steepest groups. This engenders a negative skewness in the temporal
evolution of the orbital velocity. A substantial deviation of the upper and
lower tails of the probability density function from the Gaussian distribution
is noticed, velocities are faster below the wave trough and slower below the
wave crest when compared with linear theory predictions. Second-order
nonlinearity effects strengthen with reducing the water depth, while weaken
with the broadening of the wave spectrum. The results are confirmed by
laboratory data. Corresponding experiments have been conducted in a large wave
basin taking into account the directionality of the wave field. As shown,
laboratory data are in very good agreement with the numerical prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01813</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01813</id><created>2015-10-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Legrain</keyname><forenames>Fleur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malyi</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>Clas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of alpha- and beta- tin for lithium, sodium, and magnesium
  storage: an ab initio study including phonon contributions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143 (2015) 204701</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4936284</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparative ab initio study of Li, Na, and Mg storage in tin,
including phononic effects and phase competition between alpha and beta Sn. Mg
doping at low concentration is found to stabilize the beta phase. On the
contrary, Li and Na doping is shown to reverse the stability of the phases at
room temperature: Li/Na-doped alpha-Sn is more stable than Li/Na-doped beta-Sn
up to a temperature of around 380/400 K. This may rationalize the formation of
alpha-Sn upon lithiation and delithiation of beta-Sn anodes reported in
experimental studies. The changes in phase stability with Li/Na/Mg doping are
directly related to the intercalation energies of Li/Na/Mg in one phase versus
the other: at 300 K, Li/Na is easier intercalated in alpha-Sn (-0.37/-0.08 eV)
than in beta-Sn (0.06/0.49 eV), while Mg intercalation energy is, although
positive (i.e. unfavored intercalation), lower in beta-Sn (0.53 eV) than in
alpha-Sn (0.66 eV). The temperature effect is found to affect significantly the
intercalation energy, by up to 0.13 eV at 300 K. Analysis of diffusion barriers
shows that Li, Na, and Mg diffusion in beta-Sn is anisotropic with migration
barriers along the (001) direction (respectively 0.01, 0.22, and 0.07 eV)
significantly lower than those in alpha-Sn (respectively 0.20, 0.52, and 0.40
eV).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02854</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ainsaar</keyname><forenames>Siim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kree</keyname><forenames>Mihkel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalda</keyname><forenames>Jaan</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent mixing: matching real flows to Kraichnan flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Majority of theoretical results regarding turbulent mixing are based on the
model of ideal flows with zero correlation time. We discuss the reasons why
such results may fail for real flows and develop a scheme which makes it
possible to match real flows to ideal flows. In particular we introduce the
concept of mixing dimension of flows which can take fractional values. For real
incompressible flows, the mixing dimension exceeds the topological dimension;
this leads to a local inhomogeneity of mixing --- a phenomenon which is not
observed for ideal flows and has profound implications, for instance impacting
the rate of bimolecular reactions in turbulent flows. Finally, we build a model
of compressible flows which reproduces the anomalous Lyapunov exponent values
observed for time-correlated flows by Boffetta et al (2004), and provide a
qualitative explanation of this phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03020</id><created>2015-10-11</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>Mir Vahid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Askari</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author></authors><title>Ruderman-Kittel-Kasuya-Yosida interaction in Weyl semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 224435 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.224435</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically demonstrate the Ruderman-Kittel-Kasuya-Yosida interaction
between magnetic impurities that is mediated by the Weyl fermions embedded
inside a three-dimensional Weyl semimetal (WSM). The WSM is characterized by a
pair of Weyl points separated in the momentum space. Using the Green's function
method and a two-band model, we show that four terms contribute to the magnetic
impurity interaction in the WSM phase: the Heisenberg, Dzyaloshinsky-Moriya,
spin-frustrated and Ising terms. Except the last term which is vanishingly
small in the plane perpendicular to the line connecting two Weyl points, all
the other interaction terms are finite. Furthermore, the magnetic spins of the
Dzyaloshinsky-Moriya and spin-frustrated terms lie in the plane perpendicular
to the line connecting two Weyl points, but in this plane, the magnetic spins
of the Ising term have no components. For each contribution, an analytical
expression is obtained, falling off with a spatial dependence as $R^{-5}$ at
Weyl points and showing beating behavior that depends on the direction between
two magnetic impurities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04936</id><created>2015-10-16</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The invariant polarisation-tensor field for deuterons in storage rings
  and the Bloch equation for the polarisation-tensor density</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>27 pages. Further examples and some extra detail</comments><report-no>DESY 15-181</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I extend and update earlier work, summarised in [1], whereby the invariant
polarisation-tensor field (ITF) for deuterons in storage rings was introduced
to complement the invariant spin field (ISF). Taken together, the ITF and the
ISF provide a definition of the equilibrium spin density-matrix field which, in
turn, offers a clean framework for describing equilibrium spin-1 ensembles in
storage rings. I show how to construct the ITF by stroboscopic averaging, I
give examples, I discuss adiabatic invariance and I introduce a formalism for
describing the effect of noise and damping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06992</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>Dermot G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaillant</keyname><forenames>Christophe L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frye</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morita</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutson</keyname><forenames>Jeremy M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum chaos in ultracold collisions between Yb($^1$S$_0$) and
  Yb($^3$P$_2$)</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.CD</categories><comments>5 Pages, 3 figures. Data available at doi:10.15128/ns0646000</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 022703 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.022703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate and analyze Feshbach resonance spectra for ultracold
Yb($^1$S$_0$) + Yb($^3$P$_2$) collisions as a function of an interatomic
potential scaling factor $\lambda$ and external magnetic field. We show that,
at zero field, the resonances are distributed randomly in $\lambda$, but that
signatures of quantum chaos emerge as a field is applied. The random zero-field
distribution arises from superposition of structured spectra associated with
individual total angular momenta. In addition, we show that the resonances in
magnetic field in the experimentally accessible range 400 to 2000~G are
chaotically distributed, with strong level repulsion that is characteristic of
quantum chaos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08295</id><created>2015-10-28</created><updated>2015-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Segerer</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;ttgermann</keyname><forenames>P. J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alberola</keyname><forenames>A. Piera</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zahler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xe4;dler</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>A versatile method to generate multiple types of micropatterns</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, and 2 pages supplementary information (3
  supplemental figures)</comments><journal-ref>Biointerphases 11, 011005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1116/1.4940703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Micropatterning techniques have become an important tool for the study of
cell behavior in controlled microenvironments. As a consequence, several
approaches for the creation of micropatterns have been developed in recent
years. However, the diversity of substrates, coatings and complex patterns used
in cell science is so great that no single existing technique is capable of
fabricating designs suitable for all experimental conditions. Hence, there is a
need for patterning protocols that are flexible with regard to the materials
used and compatible with different patterning strategies to create more
elaborate setups. In this work, we present a versatile approach to
micropatterning. The protocol is based on plasma treatment, protein coating,
and a PLL-PEG backfill step, and produces homogeneous patterns on a variety of
substrates. Protein density within the patterns can be controlled, and density
gradients of surface-bound protein can be formed. Moreover, by combining the
method with microcontact printing, it is possible to generate patterns composed
of three different components within one iteration of the protocol. The
technique is simple to implement and should enable cell science labs to create
a broad range of complex and highly specialized microenvironments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00490</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Griesshammer</keyname><forenames>Harald W.</forenames><affiliation>George Washington U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Assessing Theory Uncertainties in EFT Power Countings from Residual
  Cutoff Dependence</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages LaTeX2e (pdflatex) including 5 figures as .pdf files using
  PoS.cls. Presented at the 8th International Workshop on Chiral Dynamics,
  CD2015, 29 June - 3 July 2015, Pisa, Italy; accepted for publication in the
  proceedings: PoS(CD15)104. Revision: substantial expansion with
  clarifications and addition of comments, minor corrections; conclusions
  unchanged</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I summarise a method to quantitatively assess the consistency of
power-counting proposals in Effective Field Theories which are non-perturbative
at leading order. It uses the fact that the Renormalisation Group evolution of
an observable predicts the functional form of its residual cutoff dependence on
the EFT breakdown scale, low-momentum scales, and the order of the calculation.
Passing this test is a necessary but not sufficient consistency criterion for a
suggested power counting whose exact nature is disputed. For example, in ChiEFT
with more than one nucleon, a lack of universally accepted analytic solutions
obfuscates the relation between convergence pattern and numerical results, and
led to proposals which predict different numbers of Low Energy Coefficients at
the same chiral order. The method may provide an independent check whether an
observable is renormalised at a given order, and of both the breakdown scale
and the momentum-dependent order-by-order convergence pattern of an EFT.
Conversely, it may help identify LECs which produce renormalised observables at
a given order. I also discuss its underlying assumptions and relation to the RG
Equation; useful choices for observables and cutoffs; the momentum window in
which the test provides best signals; its dependence on the values and forms of
cutoffs as well as on the EFT parameters; the impact of fitting Low Energy
Coefficients to data in different or the same channel; caveats and limitations.
Since the test is designed to minimise the use of data, it allows one to
quantitatively falsify if the EFT has been renormalised consistently, rather
than quantifying how an EFT compares to experiment. Its application in
particular to the 3P0 and 3P2-3F2 partial waves of NN scattering in ChiEFT may
elucidate persistent power-counting issues. Details and a better bibliography
can be found in an upcoming publication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02239</id><created>2015-11-06</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garaldi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moscardini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Zoomed high-resolution simulations of Multi-coupled Dark Energy: cored
  galaxy density profiles at high redshift</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>25 pages, 9 figures; added references and fixed typos, as published
  in Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)050</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform for the first time high-resolution zoom-in re-simulations of
individual halos in the context of the Multi-coupled Dark Energy (McDE)
scenario, which is characterised by the existence of two distinct dark matter
particle species with opposite couplings to a Dark Energy scalar field. We
compare the structural properties of the simulated halos to the standard
Lambda-CDM results. The zoomed-in initial conditions are set up using a
specifically designed code called ZInCo that we publicly release along with the
present paper. Our numerical results allow to investigate in detail and with
unprecedented resolution the halo segregation process that characterises McDE
cosmologies from its very early stages. In particular, we find that in contrast
to what could be inferred from previous numerical analysis at lower resolution,
the segregation process is already in place at redshifts as high as z ~ 7. Most
remarkably, we find that the subsequent evolution of the segregation leads to
the formation of cored total matter density profiles with a core size that
progressively increases in time. The shape of the cored profiles can be
accurately predicted as the superposition of two NFW profiles with an
increasing offset, thereby confirming the interpretation of the simulations
results in terms of the segregation of the two dark matter components of the
halo as a consequence of their different coupling to the Dark Energy field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02741</id><created>2015-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>MacCormick</keyname><forenames>Calum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergamini</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mansell</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cable</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modi</keyname><forenames>Kavan</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersensitive measurement using single-atom control of an atomic
  ensemble</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 023805 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.023805</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the operation of a novel sensor based on atom interferometry,
which can achieve supra-classical sensitivity by exploiting quantum
correlations in mixed states of many qubits. The interferometer is based on
quantum gates which use coherently-controlled Rydberg interactions between a
single atom (which acts as a control qubit) and an atomic ensemble (which
provides register qubits). In principle, our scheme can achieve precision
scaling with the size of the ensemble - which can extend to large numbers of
atoms - while using only single-qubit operations on the control and bulk
operations on the ensemble. We investigate realistic implementation of the
interferometer, and our main aim is to develop a new approach to quantum
metrology that can achieve quantum-enhanced measurement precision by exploiting
coherent operations on large impure quantum states. We propose an experiment to
demonstrate the enhanced sensitivity of the protocol, and to investigate a
transition from classical to supra-classical sensitivity which occurs when
using highly-mixed probe states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03666</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Erdmenger</keyname><forenames>Johanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flory</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoyos</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newrzella</keyname><forenames>Max-Niklas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jackson M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy in a Holographic Kondo Model</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc</categories><comments>26 pages + appendices, 10 figures, v2: This is the pre-peer reviewed
  version of the following article: Fortsch.Phys. 64 (2016) 109-130, which has
  been published in final form at
  http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/prop.201500099/abstract</comments><report-no>MPP-2015-248, FPAUO-15/15</report-no><journal-ref>Fortsch.Phys. 64 (2016) 109-130</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201500099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate entanglement and impurity entropies in a recent holographic
model of a magnetic impurity interacting with a strongly coupled system. There
is an RG flow to an IR fixed point where the impurity is screened, leading to a
decrease in impurity degrees of freedom. This information loss corresponds to a
volume decrease in our dual gravity model, which consists of a codimension one
hypersurface embedded in a BTZ black hole background in three dimensions. There
are matter fields defined on this hypersurface which are dual to Kondo field
theory operators. In the large N limit, the formation of the Kondo cloud
corresponds to the condensation of a scalar field. The entropy is calculated
according to the Ryu-Takayanagi prescription. This requires to determine the
backreaction of the hypersurface on the BTZ geometry, which is achieved by
solving the Israel junction conditions. We find that the larger the scalar
condensate gets, the more the volume of constant time slices in the bulk is
reduced, shortening the bulk geodesics and reducing the impurity entropy. This
provides a new non-trivial example of an RG flow satisfying the g-theorem.
Moreover, we find explicit expressions for the impurity entropy which are in
agreement with previous field theory results for free electrons. This
demonstrates the universality of perturbing about an IR fixed point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04181</id><created>2015-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sim</keyname><forenames>Hasung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Joosung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>Jaehong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>Manh Duc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Je-Geun</forenames></author></authors><title>Hexagonal RMnO$_3$: a model system for 2D triangular lattice
  antiferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>46 pages, 14 figures, submitted to Acta Crystallographica B as a
  feature article</comments><journal-ref>Acta Cryst. (2016). B72, 3-19</journal-ref><doi>10.1107/S2052520615022106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The hexagonal RMnO$_3$ (h-RMnO$_3$) are multiferroic materials, which exhibit
the coexistence of a magnetic order and ferroelectricity. Their distinction is
in their geometry that both results in an unusual mechanism to break inversion
symmetry, and also produces a 2D triangular lattice of Mn spins, which is
subject to geometrical magnetic frustration due to the antiferromagnetic
interactions between nearest neighbour Mn ions. This unique combination makes
the h-RMnO$_3$ a model system to test ideas of spin-lattice coupling,
particularly when the both the improper ferroelectricity and the Mn
trimerisation that appears to determine the symmetry of the magnetic structure
arise from the same structure distortion. In this review, we demonstrate how
the use of both neutron and X-ray diffraction and inelastic neutron scattering
techniques have been essential to paint this comprehensive and coherent picture
of the h-RMnO$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05308</id><created>2015-11-17</created><updated>2016-01-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Information, fidelity, and reversibility in general quantum measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. A93 (2016) 022104</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.022104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the amounts of information, fidelity, and reversibility obtained
by arbitrary quantum measurements on completely unknown states. These
quantities are expressed as functions of the singular values of a measurement
operator corresponding to the obtained outcome. As an example, we consider a
class of quantum measurements with highly degenerate singular values to discuss
tradeoffs among information, fidelity, and reversibility. The tradeoffs are at
the level of a single outcome, in the sense that the quantities pertain to each
single outcome rather than the average over all possible outcomes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05381</id><created>2015-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kordts</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Hairun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brasch</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kippenberg</keyname><forenames>Tobias J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher order mode suppression in high-Q anomalous dispersion SiN
  microresonators for temporal dissipative Kerr soliton formation</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 41, Issue 3, pp. 452-455 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.000452</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-Q silicon nitride (SiN) microresonators enable optical Kerr frequency
comb generation on a photonic chip and have recently been shown to support
fully coherent combs based on temporal dissipative Kerr soliton formation. For
bright soliton formation it is necessary to operate SiN waveguides in the
multimode regime so as to produce anomalous group velocity dispersion. This can
lead to local disturbances of the dispersion due to avoided crossings caused by
coupling between different mode families, and therefore prevent the soliton
formation. Here we demonstrate that a single mode &quot;filtering&quot; section inside
high-Q resonators enables to efficiently suppress avoided crossings, while
preserving high quality factors (Q~10^6). We demonstrate the approach by single
soliton formation in SiN resonators with filtering section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05873</id><created>2015-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez-Castillo</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaltenborn</keyname><forenames>M. A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excluded volume effects in the hybrid star EoS</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 668 (2016) 012035</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/668/1/012035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this contribution, we outline a new 2-phase description of the
quark-nuclear matter hybrid equation of state that takes into account effects
of phase space occupation (excluded volume) in both, the hadronic and the quark
matter phases. For the nuclear matter phase, the reduction of the available
volume at increasing density leads to a stiffening, while for the quark matter
phase a reduction of the effective string tension in the confining density
functional is obtained. The deconfinement phase transition in the resulting
hybrid equation of state is sensitive to both excluded volume effects. As an
application, we consider matter under compact star constraints of electric
neutrality and $\beta$-equilibrium. We obtain mass-radius relations for hybrid
stars that fulfill the $2M_\odot$ constraint and exhibit the high-mass twin
phenomenon. Both features depend sensitively on the excluded volume.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05880</id><created>2015-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ayriyan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez-Castillo</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigorian</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mass-radius constraints for the neutron star EoS - Bayesian analysis</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 668 (2016) 012038</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/668/1/012038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest a new Bayesian analysis (BA) using disjunct M-R constraints for
extracting probability measures for cold, dense matter equations of state
(EoS). One of the key issues of such an analysis is the question of a
deconfinement transition in compact stars and whether it proceeds as a
crossover or rather as a first order transition. We show by postulating results
of not yet existing radius measurements for the known pulsars with a mass of
$2M_\odot$ that a radius gap of about 3 km would clearly select an EoS with a
strong first order phase transition as the most probably one. This would
support the existence of a critical endpoint in the QCD phase diagram under
scrutiny in present and upcoming heavy-ion collision experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06764</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Zhong-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitev</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Hongxi</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin asymmetries for vector boson production in polarized p+p collisions</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures, published version in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 014036 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.014036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the cross section for vector boson ($W^{\pm}/Z^0/\gamma^*$)
production in polarized nucleon-nucleon collisions for low transverse momentum
of the observed vector boson. For the case where one measures the transverse
momentum and azimuthal angle of the vector bosons, we present the cross
sections and the associated spin asymmetries in terms of transverse momentum
dependent parton distribution functions (TMDs) at tree level within the TMD
factorization formalism. To assess the feasibility of experimental
measurements, we estimate the spin asymmetries for $W^{\pm}/Z^0$ boson
production in polarized proton-proton collisions at the Relativistic Heavy Ion
Collider (RHIC) by using current knowledge of the relevant TMDs. We find that
some of these asymmetries can be sizable if the suppression effect from TMD
evolution is not too strong. The $W$ program at RHIC can, thus, test and
constrain spin theory by providing unique information on the universality
properties of TMDs, TMD evolution, and the nucleon structure. For example, the
single transverse spin asymmetries could be used to probe the well-known Sivers
function $f_{1T}^{\perp q}$, as well as the transversal helicity distribution
$g_{1T}^{q}$ via the parity-violating nature of $W$ production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08362</id><created>2015-11-26</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Venkatesh</keyname><forenames>B. Prasanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Dell</keyname><forenames>D. H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldwin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>An optomechanical elevator: Transport of a Bloch oscillating
  Bose-Einstein condensate up and down an optical lattice by cavity sideband
  amplification and cooling</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Atoms, 4(1), 2 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/atoms4010002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the optomechanics of an atomic Bose-Einstein condensate
interacting with the optical lattice inside a laser-pumped optical cavity and
subject to a uniform bias force such as gravity. An atomic wave packet in a
tilted lattice undergoes Bloch oscillations; in a cavity the backaction of the
atoms on the light leads to a time-dependent modulation of the intracavity
lattice at the Bloch frequency. When the Bloch frequency is on the order of the
cavity damping rate we find transport of the atoms either up or down the
lattice. The transport dynamics can be interpreted as a manifestation of
dynamical backaction-induced sideband damping/amplification of the
optomechanical Bloch oscillator. Depending on the sign of the pump-cavity
detuning, atoms are transported either with or against the bias force
accompanied by an up- or down-conversion of the frequency of the pump laser
light. We also evaluate the prospects for using the optomechanical Bloch
oscillator to make continuous measurements of forces by reading out the Bloch
frequency. In this context we establish the significant result that the optical
spring effect is absent and the Bloch frequency is not modified by the
backaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02218</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2016-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Celis</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Wan-Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lust</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Stringy explanation of $b \to s \ell^+ \ell^-$ anomalies</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures</comments><report-no>LMU-ASC 72/15, MPP-2015-275</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 02 (2016) 007</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the recent anomalies in $b \to s \ell^+ \ell^-$ transitions
observed by the LHCb collaboration can be accommodated within string motivated
models with a low mass $Z^{\prime}$ gauge boson. Such $Z^{\prime}$ gauge boson
can be obtained in compactifications with a low string scale. We consider a
class of intersecting D-brane models, in which different families of quarks and
leptons are simultaneously realized at different D-brane intersections. The
explanation of $b \to s \ell^+ \ell^-$ anomalies via a stringy $Z^{\prime}$
sets important restrictions on these viable D-brane constructions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02761</id><created>2015-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Yichen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>Chia Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeng</keyname><forenames>Yi Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joannopoulos</keyname><forenames>John D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soljacic</keyname><forenames>Marin</forenames></author></authors><title>Broadband Angular Selectivity of Light at the Nanoscale: Progress,
  Applications and Outlook</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>14 page, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Rev. 3, 011103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4941257</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Humankind has long endeavored to control the propagation direction of light.
Since time immemorial, shades, lenses and mirrors have been used to control the
flow of light. In modern society, with the rapid development of nanotechnology,
the control of light is moving toward devices at micrometer and even nanometer
scales. At such scales, traditional devices based on geometrical optics reach
their fundamental direction limits and cease to work. Nano photonics, on the
other hand, has attracted wide attention from researchers, especially in the
last decade, due to its ability to manipulate light at the nanoscale. This
review focuses on the nano photonics systems that aim to select light based on
its propagation direction. In the first half of this review, we survey the
literature and the current state of the art focused on enabling optical
broadband angular selectivity. The mechanisms we review can be classified into
three main categories: (i) microscale geometrical optics, (ii) multilayer
birefringent materials and (iii) Brewster modes in plasmonic systems, photonic
crystals and metamaterials. In the second half, we present two categories of
potential applications for broadband angularly selective systems. The first
category aims at enhancing the efficiency of solar energy harvesting, through
photovoltaic process or solar thermal process. The second category aims at
enhancing light extracting efficiency and detection sensitivity. Finally, we
discuss the most prominent challenges in broadband angular selectivity and some
prospects on how to solve these challenges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07317</id><created>2015-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Phase diagram and time-of-flight absorption pictures of
  ultracold Bose system in a square optical superlattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL 113 (2016), 16004</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/113/16004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, by the use of the generalized effective potential theory,
with the help of process-chain approach under the framework of Kato formulation
of perturbation expansion, we calculate out the quantum phase diagram up to
8-th order for an ultracold Bose system in a square optical superlattice. Base
on these perturbative data, with the help of the linear fit extrapolation
technique, more accurate results are gotten, which are in excellent agreement
with recent Monte-Carlo numerical results. Moreover, by employing the
generalized re-summed Green's function method and cumulant expansion, the
momentum distribution function of the system is also calculated analytically
and the time-of-flight absorption pictures of the system are plotted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07648</id><created>2015-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Arkhipov</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arkhipov</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babushkin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-induced transparency mode-locking, and area theorem</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optics Letters, V.41(4), pp.737-740 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.000737</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-induced transparency mode-locking (or coherent mode-locking, CML) which
is based on intracavity self-induced transparency soliton dynamics, allows
potentially to achieve nearly single cycle intracavity pulse durations, much
below the phase relaxation time $T_2$ in a laser, which, despite of great
promise, has not yet been realized experimentally. We develop a diagram
technique which allows to predict the main features of CML regimes in a generic
two-section laser. We show that CML can arise directly at the first laser
threshold if the phase relaxation time is large enough. Furthermore, CML
regimes can be unconditionally stable. We also predict the existence of
``super-CML regimes``, with a pulse coupled to several Rabi oscillations in the
nonlinear medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01554</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Ruben Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brion</keyname><forenames>Etienne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosshans</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermalization in a 1D Rydberg gas: validity of the microcanonical
  ensemble hypothesis</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>v2: Add comparison with Bettelli et al.'s Monte-Carlo simulation
  (App. A) + typo correction</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We question the microcanonical hypothesis, often made to account for the
thermalization of complex closed quantum systems, on the specific example of a
chain of two-level atoms optically driven by a resonant laser beam and strongly
interacting via Rydberg-Rydberg dipole-dipole interactions. Along its
(necessarily unitary) evolution, this system is indeed expected to thermalize,
i.e. observables, such as the number of excitations, stop oscillating and reach
equilibrium-like expectation values. The latter are often calculated through
assuming the system can be effectively described by a thermal-like
microcanonical state. Here, we compare the distribution of excitations in the
chain calculated either according to the microcanonical assumption or through
direct exact numerical simulation. This allows us to show the limitations of
the thermal equilibrium hypothesis and precise its applicability conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02823</id><created>2016-01-12</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silveirinha</keyname><forenames>Mario G.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\mathbb{Z}_{2}$ Topological Index for Continuous Photonic Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>published in PHYSICAL REVIEW B 93, 075110 (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 075110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.075110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electronic topological insulators are one of the breakthroughs of the 21st
century condensed matter physics. So far, the search for a light counterpart of
an electronic topological insulator has remained elusive. This is due to the
fundamentally different natures of light and matter and the different spins of
photons and electrons. Here, it is shown that the theory of electronic
topological insulators has a genuine analogue in the context of light wave
propagation in time-reversal invariant continuous materials. We introduce a
Gauge invariant $Z_2$ index that depends on the global properties of the
photonic band structure and is robust to any continuous weak variation of the
material parameters that preserves the time-reversal invariance. A nontrivial
$Z_2$ index has two possible causes: (i) the lack of smoothness of the
pseudo-Hamiltonian in the ${\bf{k}} \to \infty$ limit, and (ii) the
entanglement between positive and negative frequency eigenmode branches. In
particular, it is proven that electric-type plasmas and magnetic-type plasmas
are topologically inequivalent for a fixed wave polarization. We propose a
bulk-edge correspondence that links the number of edge modes with the
topological invariants of two continuous bulk materials, and present detailed
numerical examples that illustrate the application of the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03558</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Monney</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matt</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesot</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strocov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipscombe</keyname><forenames>O. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayden</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A resonant inelastic x-ray scattering study of the spin and charge
  excitations in the overdoped superconductor La1.77Sr0.23CuO4</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures; accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 075103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.075103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS) study of spin and
charge excitations in overdoped La1.77Sr0.23CuO4 along two high-symmetry
directions. The line shape of these excitations is analyzed and they are shown
to be highly overdamped. Their spectral weight and damping are found to be
strongly momentum dependent. Qualitative agreement between these observations
and a calculated RPA susceptibility is obtained for this overdoped compound,
implying that a significant contribution to the RIXS signal stems from a
continuum of charge excitations. Furthermore, this suggests that the
spin-excitations in the overdoped regime can be captured qualitatively by an
itinerant picture. Our calculations also predict a new low-energy spin
excitation branch to exist along the nodal direction near the zone center. With
the energy resolution of the present experiment, this branch is not resolvable
but we show that next generation of high-resolution spectrometers will be able
to test this prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04246</id><created>2016-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Gao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Guo-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Xin-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact parameter dependence of pion ratio in probing the nuclear
  symmetry energy using heavy-ion collisions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in Adv. in High Energy
  Phys</comments><journal-ref>Adv. in High Energy Phys. 2016, 9317873 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The impact parameter dependence of \rpi ratio is examined in heavy-ion
collisions at 400MeV/nucleon within a transport model. It is shown that the
sensitivity of \rpi ratio on symmetry energy shows a transition from central to
peripheral collisions, i.e., the stiffer symmetry energy leads to a larger \rpi
ratio in peripheral collisions while the softer symmetry energy always leads
this ratio to be larger in central collisions. After checking the kinematic
energy distribution of \rpi ratio, we found this transition of sensitivity of
\rpi ratio to symmetry energy is mainly from less energetic pions, i.e., the
softer symmetry energy gets the less energetic pions to form a smaller \rpi
ratio in peripheral collisions while these pions generate a larger \rpi ratio
in central collisions. Undoubtedly, the softer symmetry energy can also lead
more energetic pions to form a larger \rpi ratio in peripheral collisions.
Nevertheless, considering that most of pions are insufficient energetic at this
beam energy, we therefore suggest the \rpi ratio as a probe of the high-density
symmetry energy effective only in central at most to midcentral collisions,
thereby avoiding the possible information of low-density symmetry energy
carried in \rpi ratio from peripheral collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04854</id><created>2016-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Musiolik</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teiser</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jankowski</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurm</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Collisions of CO$_2$ Ice Grains in Planet Formation</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/818/1/16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In protoplanetary disks, CO$_2$ is solid ice beyond its snow line at $\sim 10
\rm AU$. Due to its high abundance, it contributes heavily to the collisional
evolution in this region of the disk. For the first time, we carried out
laboratory collision experiments with CO$_2$ ice particles and a CO$_2$-covered
wall at a temperature of 80 K. Collision velocities varied between 0 - 2.5 m/s.
Particle sizes were on the order of $\sim$ 100 $\mu$m. We find a threshold
velocity between the sticking and the bouncing regime at 0.04 m/s. Particles
with greater velocities but below 1 m/s bounce off the wall. For yet greater
velocities, fragmentation occurs. We give analytical models for the
coefficients of restitution and fragmentation strength consistent with the
experimental data. Set in context, our data show that CO$_2$ ice and silicate
dust resemble each other in the collisional behavior. Compared to water ice the
sticking velocity is an order of magnitude smaller. One immediate consequence
as example is that water ice particles mantled by CO$_2$ ice lose any &quot;sticking
advantage.&quot; In this case, preferential planetesimal growth attributed to the
sticking properties of water ice will be limited to the region between the
H$_2$O ice line and the CO$_2$ ice line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00428</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vos</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames><affiliation>ATLAS and CMS collaborations</affiliation></author></authors><title>Top-quark mass measurements at the LHC: alternative methods</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Alternative top quark mass determinations can provide inputs to the world
average with orthogonal systematic uncertainties and may help to refine the
interpretation of the standard method. Among a number of recent results I focus
on the extractions by ATLAS and CMS of the top quark pole mass from the top
quark pair and tt + 1 jet production cross-section, which have now reached a
precision of 1%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00507</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Modelling of Disordered Magnetic Systems: La2-xSrxCoO4</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic properties of La2-xSrxCoO4 have been modelled using McPhase for
different doping levels x. Footprints of different interactions, such as local
single ion anisotropy and variations in the exchange interactions have been
identified in the profile of the diffuse elastic neutron scattering cross
section. The role of quantum fluctuations in the formation of the hourglass
spectrum is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01463</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Elaeva</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiryaeva</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zhukov M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactions between discontinuities for binary mixture separation
  problem and hodograph method</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.NA physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures</comments><msc-class>35Lxx, 35L67, 35L40, 35L45, 35L50, 35L65</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Cauchy problem for first-order PDE with the initial data which have a
piecewise discontinuities localized in different spatial points is completely
solved. The interactions between discontinuities arising after breakup of
initial discontinuities are studied with the help of the hodograph method. The
solution is constructed in analytical implicit form. To recovery the explicit
form of solution we propose the transformation of the PDEs into some ODEs on
the level lines (isochrones) of implicit solution. In particular, this method
allows us to solve the Goursat problem with initial data on characteristics.
The paper describes a specific problem for zone electrophoresis (method of the
mixture separation). However, the method proposed allows to solve any system of
two first-order quasilinear PDEs for which the second order linear PDE, arising
after the hodograph transformation, has the Riemann-Green function in explicit
form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01471</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Comin</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutarto</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>E. H. da Silva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauviere</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonn</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawatzky</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damascelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Response to comment on &quot;Broken translational and rotational symmetry via
  charge stripe order in underdoped YBa2Cu3O6+y&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Response to original comment: B.V. Fine, Science 351, 235 (2016)
  (arxiv version at http://arxiv.org/abs/1602.00888)</comments><journal-ref>Science 351, 235 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aac4778</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fine questions our interpretation of unidirectional-stripes over
bidirectional-checkerboard, and illustrates his criticism by simulating a
momentum space structure consistent with our data and corresponding to a
checkerboard-looking real space density. Here we use a local
rotational-symmetry analysis to demonstrate that the simulated image is in
actuality composed of locally unidirectional modulations of the charge density,
consistent with our original conclusions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01480</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Nord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Refregier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamper</keyname><forenames>La.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamper</keyname><forenames>Lu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hambrecht</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forero-Romero</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serrano</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coles</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicola</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busha</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saunders</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jouvel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wechsler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>SPOKES: an End-to-End Simulation Facility for Spectroscopic Cosmological
  Surveys</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>24 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-009-AE</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of dark matter, dark energy and large-scale gravity pose some of
the most pressing questions in cosmology today. These fundamental questions
require highly precise measurements, and a number of wide-field spectroscopic
survey instruments are being designed to meet this requirement. A key component
in these experiments is the development of a simulation tool to forecast
science performance, define requirement flow-downs, optimize implementation,
demonstrate feasibility, and prepare for exploitation. We present SPOKES
(SPectrOscopic KEn Simulation), an end-to-end simulation facility for
spectroscopic cosmological surveys designed to address this challenge. SPOKES
is based on an integrated infrastructure, modular function organization,
coherent data handling and fast data access. These key features allow
reproducibility of pipeline runs, enable ease of use and provide flexibility to
update functions within the pipeline. The cyclic nature of the pipeline offers
the possibility to make the science output an efficient measure for design
optimization and feasibility testing. We present the architecture, first
science, and computational performance results of the simulation pipeline. The
framework is general, but for the benchmark tests, we use the Dark Energy
Spectrometer (DESpec), one of the early concepts for the upcoming project, the
Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI). We discuss how the SPOKES
framework enables a rigorous process to optimize and exploit spectroscopic
survey experiments in order to derive high-precision cosmological measurements
optimally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01498</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mansour</keyname><forenames>Zeinab S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational methods for fractional $q$-Sturm--Liouville Problems</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>39A13, 26A33, 49R05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we formulate a regular $q$-fractional Sturm--Liouville problem
(qFSLP) which includes the left-sided Riemann--Liouville and the right-sided
Caputo $q$-fractional derivatives of the same order $\alpha$, $\alpha\in
(0,1)$. We introduce the essential $q$-fractional variational analysis needed
in proving the existence of a countable set of real eigenvalues and associated
orthogonal eigenfunctions for the regular qFSLP when $\alpha&gt;1/2$ associated
with the boundary condition $y(0)=y(a)=0$. A criteria for the first eigenvalue
is proved. Examples are included. These results are a generalization of the
integer regular $q$-Sturm--Liouville problem introduced by Annaby and Mansour
in [1].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01536</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe1;sztor</keyname><forenames>Gabriella</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent ATLAS results and preparations for Run 2</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Presented on the XXII International Workshop High Energy Physics and
  Quantum Field Theory (QFTHEP2015), Samara, Russia, 24 Jun - 1 Jul 2015</comments><report-no>ATL-PHYS-PROC-2016-020</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CERN LHC delivered 25/fb of proton-proton collision data in 2011-2012 at
sqrt{s} = 7 - 8 TeV centre-of-mass energy to the ATLAS detector. These Run 1
data were used to discover the Higgs boson and measure its properties as well
as to perform numerous other tests of the Standard Model via precision
measurements and searches for New Physics. In preparation for the Run 2 data
taking at sqrt{s} = 13 TeV, the collaboration embarked on an upgrade program
during the long LHC machine shutdown in 2013-2015. The early 2015 data set was
then used to promptly recommission the apparatus allowing the first physics
results to appear already in the summer of 2015. After briefly reviewing the
upgrade and the improved performance of the detector, this paper concentrates
on the final Run~1 results on Higgs, W and Z boson, electroweak multi-boson and
top quark production as well as on searches for supersymmetry and other new
phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01544</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Jbara</keyname><forenames>Ahmed S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abood</keyname><forenames>H. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Khursan</keyname><forenames>Amin H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of doping and In-composition on gain of long wavelength
  III-nitride QDs</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures and 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optics, December 2012, Volume 41, Issue 4, pp 214-223</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12596-012-0085-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we calculate material gain for long wavelength III-nitride InN
and AlInN quantum dot (QD) structures. Strain and QD inhomogeneity are included
in the calculations. The study covers (800-2300 nm) wavelength range which is
important in optical communications. While p-doping is shown to be efficient to
increasing gain, changing QD size (especially QD radius) is more efficient to
vary wavelength. The results predicted that n-doped QD structures are promises
for broad band laser applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01545</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ashikhmin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ching-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brun</keyname><forenames>Todd</forenames></author></authors><title>Correction of Data and Syndrome Errors by Stabilizer Codes</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT quant-ph</categories><comments>2 figures. This is a short version of our full paper (in preparation)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Performing active quantum error correction to protect fragile quantum states
highly depends on the correctness of error information--error syndromes. To
obtain reliable error syndromes using imperfect physical circuits, we propose
the idea of quantum data-syndrome (DS) codes that are capable of correcting
both data qubits and syndrome bits errors. We study fundamental properties of
quantum DS codes and provide several CSS-type code constructions of quantum DS
codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01546</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Al-Khursan</keyname><forenames>Amin H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jbara</keyname><forenames>Ahmed S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abood</keyname><forenames>H. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Four-wave mixing in long wavelength III-nitride QD-SOAs</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures and 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Optik - International Journal for Light and Electron Optics,
  October 2013, Volume 124, Issue 19, Pages 4072 - 4079</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijleo.2012.12.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Four wave mixing analysis is stated for quantum dot semiconductor optical
amplifiers (QD SOAs) using the propagation equations (including nonlinear
propagation contribution) coupled with the QD rate equations under the
saturation assumption. Long wavelength III-nitride InN and AlInN QD SOAs are
simulated. Asymmetric behavior due to linewidth enhancement factor is assigned.
P-doping increases efficiency. Lossless efficiency for InAlN QDs for longer
radii is obtained. Carrier heating is shown to have a considerable effect and a
detuning dependence is expected at most cases. InN QD SOAs shown to have higher
efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01552</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Gang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>yanping</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>jianning</keyname><forenames>Fu</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Curve Solutions of an Eclipsing Binary OGLE-GD-ECL-04451 with a
  Dramatic Change in Amplitude</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present light curve solutions of the W UMa-type eclipsing binary
OGLE-GD-ECL-04451, observed by both the \emph{Optical Gravitational Lensing
Ex-periment} (\emph{OGLE}) program in 2006 and the \emph{Antarctica Survey
Telescope} (\emph{AST3-1}) in 2012 at Dome A. We analyzed this binary system
with the Wilson-Devinney(W-D) method 2013 version and derived the mass ratio
$q=2.91 \pm 0.07$, the inclination $i=76.86^\circ \pm 0.23^\circ$, and the
light variattion amplitud was $0^m.51$ based on the \emph{OGLE} data. From the
\emph{AST3-1}'s data, we find that the amplitude dropped to $0^m.44$(2012) and
the difference of magnitudes of the two light maxima is $0^m.03$. A hot spot
was then added on the surface of the secondary to demonstrate the amplitude
change and O'Conell effect of the binary system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01554</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Noguchi</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamazaki</keyname><forenames>Rekishu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ataka</keyname><forenames>Manabu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tabuchi</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Toyofumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usami</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Yasunobu</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong coupling in multimode quantum electromechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cavity electro-(opto-)mechanics allows us to access not only single isolated
but also multiple mechanical modes in a massive object. Here we develop a
multi-mode electromechanical system in which a several membrane vibrational
modes are coupled to a three-dimensional loop-gap superconducting microwave
cavity. The tight confinement of the electric field across a
mechanically-compliant narrow-gap capacitor brings the system into the quantum
strong coupling regime under a red-sideband pump field. We demonstrate strong
coupling between two mechanical modes, which is induced by two-tone parametric
drives and mediated by a virtual photon in the cavity. The tunable
inter-mechanical-mode coupling can be used to generate entanglement between the
mechanical modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01556</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yuelei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic anisotropy of the single-crystalline ferromagnetic insulator
  Cr2Ge2Te6</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Japanese Journal of Applied Physics 55, 033001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/JJAP.55.033001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cr2Ge2Te6 (CGT), a layered ferromagnetic insulator, has attracted a great
deal of interest recently owing to its potential for integration with Dirac
materials to realize the quantum anomalous Hall effect (QAHE) and to develop
novel spintronics devices. Here, we study the uniaxial magnetic anisotropy
energy of single-crystalline CGT and determine that the magnetic easy axis is
directed along the c-axis in its ferromagnetic phase. In addition, CGT is an
insulator below the Curie temperature. These properties make CGT a potentially
promising candidate substrate for integration with topological insulators for
the realization of the high-temperature QAHE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01583</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirkamali</keyname><forenames>Ashrafalsadat S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muminov</keyname><forenames>Khikmat Kh.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of the Efficiency of CdS/CdTe Tandem Multi-Junction Solar
  Cells</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study CdS/CdTe solar cells by means of AMPS-1D software.
First we study the effect of thickness of semiconductor layers on the output
parameters of the CdS/CdTe solar cell, such as density of short-circuit
current, open circuit voltage, fill factor and efficiency. Numerical simulation
shows that the highest efficiency of single-junction CdS/CdTe solar cell equal
to 18.3% is achieved when the CdTe layer thickness is 1000 nm and a CdS layer
is 60 nm. Then, in order to obtain the maximal value of the efficiency, new
tandem multi-junction structure consisting of layers of two solar cells
connected with each other back to back are designed and engineered taking into
account the results obtained for the single-junction solar cells. Numerical
simulations show that its highest efficiency in 31.8% can be obtained when the
thickness of CdS p-layer is equal to 50 nm, and the thickness of the CdS
n-layer is equal to 200 nm, while thicknesses of the CdTe n-layer and CdTe
p-layer are kept fixed and equal to 3000 nm and 1000 nm, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01604</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kimmoun</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Branger</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kharif</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onorato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelleher</keyname><forenames>E. J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kibler</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akhmediev</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chabchoub</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation Instability and Phase-Shifted Fermi-Pasta-Ulam Recurrence</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Instabilities are common phenomena frequently observed in nature, sometimes
leading to unexpected catastrophes and disasters in seemingly normal
conditions. The simplest form of instability in a distributed system is its
response to a harmonic modulation. Such instability has special names in
various branches of physics and is generally known as modulation instability
(MI). The MI is tightly related to Fermi-Pasta-Ulam (FPU) recurrence since
breather solutions of the nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation (NLSE) are known to
accurately describe growth and decay of modulationally unstable waves in
conservative systems. Here, we report theoretical, numerical and experimental
evidence of the effect of dissipation on FPU cycles in a super wave tank,
namely their shift in a determined order. In showing that ideal NLSE breather
solutions can describe such dissipative nonlinear dynamics, our results may
impact the interpretation of a wide range of new physics scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01605</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ritacco</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adam</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adane</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andr&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beelen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beno&#xee;t</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bideaud</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billot</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourrion</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catalano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coiffard</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Comis</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xe9;sert</keyname><forenames>F. -X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doyle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goupy</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leclercq</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mac&#xed;as-P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maury</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monfardini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pajot</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascale</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perotto</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisano</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponthieu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebolo-Iglesias</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rev&#xe9;ret</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruppin</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sievers</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triqueneaux</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zylka</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>NIKA 2: next-generation continuum/polarized camera at the IRAM 30 m
  telescope and its prototype</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, proceeding for the conference: Extragalactic
  radio surveys 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NIKA 2 (New Instrument of Kids Array) is a next generation continuum and
polarized instrument successfully installed in October 2015 at the IRAM 30 m
telescope on Pico-Veleta (Granada, Spain). NIKA 2 is a high resolution
dual-band camera, operating with frequency multiplexed LEKIDs (Lumped Element
Kinetic Inductance Detectors) cooled at 100 mK. Dual color images are obtained
thanks to the simultaneous readout of a 1020 pixels array at 2 mm and 1140 x 2
pixels arrays at 1.15 mm with a final resolution of 18 and 12 arcsec
respectively, and 6.5 arcmin of Field of View (FoV). The two arrays at 1.15 mm
allow us to measure the linear polarization of the incoming light. This will
place NIKA 2 as an instrument of choice to study the role of magnetic fields in
the star formation process. The NIKA experiment, a prototype for NIKA 2 with a
reduced number of detectors (about 400 LEKIDs) and FoV (1.8 arcmin), has been
successfully operated at the IRAM 30 telescope in several open observational
campaigns. The performance of the NIKA 2 polarization setup has been
successfully validated with the NIKA prototype.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01611</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>R. Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Setny</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzubiella</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Solvent fluctuations induce non-Markovian kinetics in hydrophobic
  pocket-ligand binding</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the impact of water fluctuations on the key-lock association
kinetics of a hydrophobic ligand (key) binding to a hydrophobic pocket (lock)
by means of a minimalistic stochastic model system. It describes the collective
hydration behavior of the pocket by bimodal fluctuations of a water-pocket
interface that dynamically couples to the diffusive motion of the approaching
ligand via the hydrophobic interaction. This leads to a set of overdamped
Langevin equations in 2D-coordinate-space, that is Markovian in each dimension.
Numerical simulations demonstrate locally increased friction of the ligand,
decelerated binding kinetics, and local non-Markovian (memory) effects in the
ligand's reaction coordinate as found previously in explicit-water molecular
dynamics studies of model hydrophobic pocket-ligand binding [1,2]. Our
minimalistic model elucidates the origin of effectively enhanced friction in
the process that can be traced back to long-time decays in the
force-autocorrelation function induced by the effective, spatially fluctuating
pocket-ligand interaction. Furthermore, we construct a generalized 1D-Langevin
description including a spatially local memory function that enables further
interpretation and a semi-analytical quantification of the results of the
coupled 2D-system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01639</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01639</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Burzur&#xed;</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Island</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Torres</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fursina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Campo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roubeau</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teat</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aliaga-Alcalde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>H. S. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sequential electron transport and vibrational excitations in an organic
  molecule coupled to few-kayer graphene electrodes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1021/acsnano.5b07382</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene electrodes are promising candidates to improve reproducibility and
stability in molecular electronics through new electrode-molecule anchoring
strategies. Here we report sequential electron transport in few-layer graphene
transistors containing individual curcuminoid-based molecules anchored to the
electrodes via pi-pi orbital bonding. We show the coexistence of inelastic
co-tunneling excitations with single-electron transport physics owing to an
intermediate molecule-electrode coupling; we argue that an intermediate
electron-phonon coupling is the origin of these vibrational-assisted
excitations. These experimental observations are complemented with density
functional theory calculations to model electron transport and the interaction
between electrons and vibrational modes of the curcuminoid molecule. We find
that the calculated vibrational modes of the molecule are in agreement with the
experimentally observed excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01643</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kamann</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husser</keyname><forenames>Tim-Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brinchmann</keyname><forenames>Jarle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emsellem</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weilbacher</keyname><forenames>Peter M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wisotzki</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendt</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krajnovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Davor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>Martin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bacon</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dreizler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>MUSE crowded field 3D spectroscopy of over 12,000 stars in the globular
  cluster NGC 6397 - II. Probing the internal dynamics and the presence of a
  central black hole</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201527065</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed analysis of the kinematics of the Galactic globular
cluster NGC 6397 based on more than ~18,000 spectra obtained with the novel
integral field spectrograph MUSE. While NGC 6397 is often considered a core
collapse cluster, our analysis suggests a flattening of the surface brightness
profile at the smallest radii. Although it is among the nearest globular
clusters, the low velocity dispersion of NGC 6397 of &lt;5km/s imposes heavy
demands on the quality of the kinematical data. We show that despite its
limited spectral resolution, MUSE reaches an accuracy of 1km/s in the analysis
of stellar spectra. We find slight evidence for a rotational component in the
cluster and the velocity dispersion profile that we obtain shows a mild central
cusp. To investigate the nature of this feature, we calculate spherical Jeans
models and compare these models to our kinematical data. This comparison shows
that if a constant mass-to-light ratio is assumed, the addition of an
intermediate-mass black hole with a mass of 600M_sun brings the model
predictions into agreement with our data, and therefore could be at the origin
of the velocity dispersion profile. We further investigate cases with varying
mass-to-light ratios and find that a compact dark stellar component can also
explain our observations. However, such a component would closely resemble the
black hole from the constant mass-to-light ratio models as this component must
be confined to the central ~5arcsec of the cluster and must have a similar
mass. Independent constraints on the distribution of stellar remnants in the
cluster or kinematic measurements at the highest possible spatial resolution
should be able to distinguish the two alternatives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01647</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Cimrak</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jancigova</keyname><forenames>Iveta</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-uniform force allocation for area preservation in spring network
  models</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1002/cnm.2757</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In modelling of elastic objects in a flow such as red blood cells, white
blood cells, or tumour cells, several elastic moduli are involved. One of them
is the area conservation modulus. In this paper, we focus on spring network
models and we introduce a new way of modeling the area preservation modulus. We
take into account the current shape of the individual triangles and find the
proportional allocation of area conservation forces, which would for individual
triangles preserve their shapes. The analysis shows that this approach tends to
regularize the triangulation. We demonstrate this effect on individual
triangles as well as on the complete triangulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01653</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kolasi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sellier</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szafran</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit coupling measurement by the scanning gate microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a procedure for extraction of the Fermi surface for a
two-dimensional electron gas with a strong Rashba spin-orbit coupling from
conductance microscopy. Due to the interplay between the effective spin-orbit
magnetic field and the external one within the plane of confinement, the
backscattering induced by a charged tip of an atomic force microscope located
above the sample, leads to the spin precession, and thus to the spin mixing of
the incident and reflected modes. This mixing leads to a characteristic
angle-dependent beating pattern visible in the conductance maps. We show that
the structure of the Fermi level, bearing signatures of the spin-orbit
coupling, can be extracted from the Fourier transform of the interference
fringes in the conductance maps as a function of the magnetic field direction.
We propose a simple analytical model which can be used to fit the experimental
data in order to obtain the spin-orbit coupling constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01662</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Wid</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breitenstein</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkin</keyname><forenames>S. S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of the unidirectional spin heat conveyer effect in a 200nm
  thin Yttrium Iron Garnet film</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the unidirectional spin wave heat conveyer effect in
sub-micron thick yttrium iron garnet (YIG) films using lock-in thermography
(LIT). Although the effect is small in thin layers this technique allows us to
observe asymmetric heat transport by magnons which leads to asymmetric
temperature profiles differing by several mK on both sides of the exciting
antenna, respectively. Comparison of Damon-Eshbach and backward volume modes
shows that the unidirectional heat flow is indeed due to non-reciprocal
spin-waves. Because of the finite linewidth, small asymmetries can still be
observed when only the uniform mode of ferromagnetic resonance is excited. The
latter is of extreme importance for example when measuring the inverse
spin-Hall effect because the temperature differences can result in
thermovoltages at the contacts. Because of the non-reciprocity these
thermovoltages reverse their sign with a reversal of the magnetic field which
is typically deemed the signature of the inverse spin-Hall voltage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01663</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ponomarev</keyname><forenames>Evgeniy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Lezama</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ubrig</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morpurgo</keyname><forenames>Alberto F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ambipolar Light-Emitting Transistors on Chemical Vapor Deposited
  Monolayer MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2015, 15 (12), pp.8289-8294</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b03885</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We realize and investigate ionic liquid gated field-effect transistors (FETs)
on large-area MoS2 monolayers grown by chemical vapor deposition (CVD). Under
electron accumulation, the performance of these devices is comparable to that
of FETs based on exfoliated flakes. FETs on CVD-grown material, however,
exhibit clear ambipolar transport, which for MoS2 monolayers had not been
reported previously. We exploit this property to estimate the bandgap {\Delta}
of monolayer MoS2 directly from the device transfer curves and find {\Delta}
$\approx$ 2.4-2.7 eV. In the ambipolar injection regime, we observe
electroluminescence due to exciton recombination in MoS2, originating from the
region close to the hole-injecting contact. Both the observed transport
properties and the behavior of the electroluminescence can be consistently
understood as due to the presence of defect states at an energy of 250-300 meV
above the top of the valence band, acting as deep traps for holes. Our results
are of technological relevance, as they show that devices with useful
optoelectronic functionality can be realized on large-area MoS2 monolayers
produced by controllable and scalable techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01664</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Bugiolacchi</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bamford</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tar</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thacker</keyname><forenames>Neil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>Ian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joy</keyname><forenames>Katherine H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grindrod</keyname><forenames>Peter M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lintott</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>The Moon Zoo citizen science project: Preliminary results for the Apollo
  17 landing site</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Icarus</comments><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.01.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Moon Zoo is a citizen science project that utilises internet crowd-sourcing
techniques. Moon Zoo users are asked to review high spatial resolution images
from the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Camera (LROC), onboard NASAs LRO
spacecraft, and perform characterisation such as measuring impact crater sizes
and identify morphological features of interest. The tasks are designed to
address issues in lunar science and to aid future exploration of the Moon. We
have tested various methodologies and parameters therein to interrogate and
reduce the Moon Zoo crater location and size dataset against a validated expert
survey. We chose the Apollo 17 region as a test area since it offers a broad
range of cratered terrains, including secondary-rich areas, older maria, and
uplands. The assessment involved parallel testing in three key areas: (1)
filtering of data to remove problematic mark-ups; (2) clustering methods of
multiple notations per crater; and (3) derivation of alternative crater
degradation indices, based on the statistical variability of multiple notations
and the smoothness of local image structures. We compared different
combinations of methods and parameters and assessed correlations between
resulting crater summaries and the expert census.
  We derived the optimal data reduction steps and settings of the existing Moon
Zoo crater data to agree with the expert census. Further, the regolith depth
and crater degradation states derived from the data are also found to be in
broad agreement with other estimates for the Apollo 17 region. Our study
supports the validity of this citizen science project but also recommends
improvements in key elements of the data acquisition planning and production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01670</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maljuk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efremov</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataeva</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gass</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blum</keyname><forenames>C. G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steckel</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruner</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritschel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolter</keyname><forenames>A. U. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geck</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hess</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koepernik</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>J. van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurmehl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chner</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ba2YIrO6: A cubic double perovskite material with Ir5+ ions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 014434 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.014434</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Materials with a 5d4 electronic configuration are generally considered to
have a nonmagnetic ground state (J=0). Interestingly, Sr2YIrO6 (Ir5+ having 5d4
electronic configuration) was recently reported to exhibit long-range magnetic
order at low temperature and the distorted IrO6 octahedra were discussed to
cause the magnetism in this material. Hence, a comparison of structurally
distorted Sr2YIrO6 with cubic Ba2YIrO6 may shed light on the source of
magnetism in such Ir5+ materials with 5d4 configuration. Besides, Ir5+
materials having 5d4 are also interesting in the context of recently predicted
excitonic types of magnetism. Here we report a single-crystal-based analysis of
the structural, magnetic, and thermodynamic properties of Ba2YIrO6. We observe
that in Ba2YIrO6 for temperatures down to 0.4 K, long-range magnetic order is
absent but at the same time correlated magnetic moments are present. We show
that these moments are absent in fully relativistic ab initio band-structure
calculations; hence, their origin is presently unclear.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01680</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Zhaoli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon Boltzmann equation-based discrete unified gas kinetic scheme for
  multiscale heat transfer</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical prediction of multiscale heat transfer is a challenging problem due
to the wide range of time and length scales involved. In this work a discrete
unified gas kinetic scheme (DUGKS) is developed for heat transfer in materials
with different acoustic thickness based on the phonon Boltzmann equation. With
discrete phonon direction, the Boltzmann equation is discretized with a
second-order finite-volume formulation, in which the time-step is fully
determined by the Courant-Friedrichs-Lewy (CFL) condition. The scheme has the
asymptotic preserving (AP) properties for both diffusive and ballistic regimes,
and can present accurate solutions in the whole transition regime as well. The
DUGKS is a self-adaptive multiscale method for the capturing of local transport
process. Numerical tests for both heat transfers with different Knudsen numbers
are presented to validate the current method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01683</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobzar</keyname><forenames>Oleh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sushchov</keyname><forenames>Olexandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hnatyk</keyname><forenames>Bohdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchenko</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr</forenames></author></authors><title>The Influence of Magnetic Fields on UHECR Propagation from Virgo A</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>In Proceedings of the 34th International Cosmic Ray Conference
  (ICRC2015), The Hague, The Netherlands</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Active galactic nuclei (AGN) are considered as one of the most appropriate
sources of cosmic rays with energy exceeding $\sim 10^{18}$ eV. Virgo A (M87 or
NGC 4486) is the second closest to the Milky Way active galaxy. According to
existing estimations it can be a prominent source of ultra high energy cosmic
rays (UHECR). However not many events have been registered in the sky region
near Virgo A, possibly due to magnetic field influence. In the present work we
check UHECR events from the recent sets of data (AUGER, Telescope Array etc.)
for possibility of their origination in this AGN. We carried out the simulation
of UHECR motion from Virgo A taking into account their deflections in galactic
(GMF) as well as extragalactic (EGMF) magnetic fields according to the several
latest models. The maps of expected UHECR arrival directions were obtained as a
result. It has been found the following: 1) UHECR deflection caused by EGMF is
comparable with GMF one, moreover the influence of EGMF sometimes is
dominating; 2) effect of EGMF demonstrates obvious asymmetry in the final
distribution of expected UHECR arrival directions; 3) the results of
simulations depend on chosen GMF model and are still open for the discussion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01684</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Isikgor</keyname><forenames>Furkan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becer</keyname><forenames>C. Remzi</forenames></author></authors><title>Lignocellulosic biomass: a sustainable platform for the production of
  bio-based chemicals and polymers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Polym. Chem., 2015, 6, 4497-4559</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5PY00263J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The demand for petroleum dependent chemicals and materials has been
increasing despite the dwindling of their fossil resources. As the dead-end of
petroleum based industry has started to appear, today's modern society has to
implement alternative energy and valuable chemical resources immediately. Owing
to the importance of lignocellulosic biomass being the most abundant and
bio-renewable biomass on earth, this critical review provides insights into the
potential of lignocellulosic biomass as an alternative platform to fossil
resources. In this context, over 200 value-added compounds, which can be
derived from lignocellulosic biomass by various treatment methods, are
presented with their references. Lignocellulosic biomass based polymers and
their commercial importance are also reported mainly in the frame of these
compounds. This review article aims to draw the map of lignocellulosic biomass
derived chemicals and their synthetic polymers, and to reveal the scope of this
map in today's modern chemical and polymer industry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01689</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Marais</keyname><forenames>Adriana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinayskiy</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petruccione</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Grondelle</keyname><forenames>Rienk</forenames></author></authors><title>A quantum protective mechanism in photosynthesis</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 6 figure</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 5, Article number: 8720 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep08720</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the emergence of oxygenic photosynthesis, living systems have developed
protective mechanisms against reactive oxygen species. During charge separation
in photosynthetic reaction centres, triplet states can react with molecular
oxygen generating destructive singlet oxygen. The triplet product yield in
bacteria is observed to be reduced by weak magnetic fields. Reaction centres
from plants' photosystem II share many features with bacterial reaction
centres, including a high-spin iron whose function has remained obscure. To
explain observations that the magnetic field effect is reduced by the iron, we
propose that its fast-relaxing spin plays a protective role in photosynthesis
by generating an effective magnetic field. We consider a simple model of the
system, derive an analytical expression for the effective magnetic field and
analyse the resulting triplet yield reduction. The protective mechanism is
robust for realistic parameter ranges, constituting a clear example of a
quantum effect playing a macroscopic role vital for life.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01692</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Z. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>G. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Astrophysical Reaction Rate for the
  $^{12}\textrm{C}(\alpha,\gamma)^{16}\textrm{O}$ Reaction</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters 817, L5 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/817/1/L5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new astrophysical reaction rate for $^{12}$C($\alpha,\gamma$)$^{16}$O has
been evaluated on the basis of a global R-matrix fitting to the available
experimental data. The reaction rates of $^{12}$C($\alpha,\gamma$)$^{16}$O for
stellar temperatures between 0.04 $\leq$ $T_9$ $\leq$ 10 are provided in a
tabular form and by an analytical fitting expression. At $T_9$ = 0.2, the
reaction rate is (7.83 $\pm$ 0.35)$\times10^{15}$ $\rm{cm^3 mol^{-1} s^{-1}}$,
where stellar helium burning occurs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01694</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Sinitsyna</keyname><forenames>Vera G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinitsyna</keyname><forenames>Vera Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Very Hight Energy Observationa of Shell-Type Supernova Remnants with
  SHALON Mirror Cherenkov Telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in Bulletin of the Lebedev Physics Institute, 2015, vol.
  42, issue 6, pp. 169-175</comments><journal-ref>Bulletin of the Lebedev Physics Institute, 2015, vol. 42, issue 6,
  pp. 169-175</journal-ref><doi>10.3103/S1068335615060032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The investigation of VHE gamma-ray sources by any methods, including mirror
Cherenkov telescopes, touches on the problem of the cosmic ray origin and,
accordingly, the role of the Galaxy in their generation. The SHALON
observations have yielded the results on Galactic shell-type supernova remnants
(SNR) on different evolution stages. Among them are: SNRs Tycho's SNR, Cas A,
IC 443, $\gamma$Cygni SNR and classical nova GK Per (Nova 1901). For each of
SNRs the observation results are presented with spectral energy distribution by
SHALON in comparison with other experiment data and images by SHALON. The
collected experimental data have confirmed the prediction of the theory about
the hadronic generation mechanism of very high energy 800 GeV - 100 TeV
$\gamma$-rays in Tycho's SNR, Cas A and IC443.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01709</id><created>2016-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rahemi</keyname><forenames>Reza</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature dependence of slow positron reemission from metals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intensity of positron reemission from a metal is related to its work
function. This property is dependent on temperature and can be modified with
temperature control. In this article a simple model is proposed to explain and
predict the variation of the positron work function with temperature. The
dependence of slow positron yield of metals on temperature is predicted based
on this model and the critical temperatures at which the slow positron yield is
maximum is calculated. The proposed model is consistent with experimental
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01713</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ol&#xe1;h</keyname><forenames>Katalin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappaport</keyname><forenames>Saul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joss</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of binary and multiple systems among rapidly rotating K and M
  dwarf stars from Kepler data</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Living Together: Planets, Host Stars and Binaries, ASP Conference
  Series, 2015, Vol. 496., p.83</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From an examination of ~18,000 Kepler light curves of K- and M-stars we find
some 500 which exhibit rotational periods of less than 2 days. Among such
stars, approximately 50 show two or more incommensurate periodicities. We
discuss the tools that allow us to differentiate between rotational modulation
and other types of light variations, e.g., due to pulsations or binary
modulations. We find that these multiple periodicities are independent of each
other and likely belong to different, but physically bound, stars. This
scenario was checked directly by UKIRT and adaptive optics imaging,
time-resolved Fourier transforms, and pixel-level analysis of the data. Our
result is potentially important for discovering young multiple stellar systems
among rapidly rotating K- and M-dwarfs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01715</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Eynard</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belliard</keyname><forenames>Rapha&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchal</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author></authors><title>Loop equations from differential systems</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To any differential system $d\Psi=\Phi\Psi$ where $\Psi$ belongs to a Lie
group (a fiber of a principal bundle) and $\Phi$ is a Lie algebra $\mathfrak g$
valued 1-form on a Riemann surface $\Sigma$, is associated an infinite sequence
of &quot;correlators&quot; $W_n$ that are symmetric $n$-forms on $\Sigma^n$. The goal of
this article is to prove that these correlators always satisfy &quot;loop
equations&quot;, the same equations satisfied by correlation functions in random
matrix models, or the same equations as Virasoro or W-algebra constraints in
CFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01719</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Schulze</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donko</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derzsi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korolov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuengel</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of ambipolar electric fields on the electron heating in
  capacitive RF plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the electron heating dynamics in electropositive argon and
helium capacitively coupled RF discharges driven at 13.56 MHz by Particle in
Cell simulations and by an analytical model. The model allows to calculate the
electric field outside the electrode sheaths, space and time resolved within
the RF period. Electrons are found to be heated by strong ambipolar electric
fields outside the sheath during the phase of sheath expansion in addition to
classical sheath expansion heating. By tracing individual electrons we also
show that ionization is primarily caused by electrons that collide with the
expanding sheath edge multiple times during one phase of sheath expansion due
to backscattering towards the sheath by collisions. A synergistic combination
of these different heating events during one phase of sheath expansion is
required to accelerate an electron to energies above the threshold for
ionization. The ambipolar electric field outside the sheath is found to be time
modulated due to a time modulation of the electron mean energy caused by the
presence of sheath expansion heating only during one half of the RF period at a
given electrode. This time modulation results in more electron heating than
cooling inside the region of high electric field outside the sheath on time
average. If an electric field reversal is present during sheath collapse, this
time modulation and, thus, the asymmetry between the phases of sheath expansion
and collapse will be enhanced. We propose that the ambipolar electron heating
should be included in models describing electron heating in capacitive RF
plasmas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01726</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucantonio</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teresi</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeSimone</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum theory of swelling material surfaces with applications to
  thermo-responsive gel membranes and surface mass transport</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jmps.2016.02.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Soft membranes are commonly employed in shape-morphing applications, where
the material is programmed to achieve a target shape upon activation by an
external trigger, and as coating layers that alter the surface characteristics
of bulk materials, such as the properties of spreading and absorption of
liquids. In particular, polymer gel membranes experience swelling or shrinking
when their solvent content change, and the non-homogeneous swelling field may
be exploited to control their shape. Here, we develop a theory of swelling
material surfaces to model polymer gel membranes and demonstrate its features
by numerically studying applications in the contexts of biomedicine,
micro-motility, and coating technology. We also specialize the theory to
thermo-responsive gels, which are made of polymers that change their affinity
with a solvent when temperature varies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01748</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Currie</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanbicki</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kioseoglou</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonker</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical control of charged exciton states in tungsten disulfide</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 Figures, 32 references</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 106, 201907 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4921472</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method is presented for optically preparing WS2 monolayers to luminesce
from only the charged exciton (trion) state--completely suppressing the neutral
exciton. When isolating the trion state, we observed changes in the Raman A1g
intensity and an enhanced feature on the low energy side of the E12g peak.
Photoluminescence and optical reflectivity measurements confirm the existence
of the prepared trion state. This technique also prepares intermediate regimes
with controlled luminescence amplitudes of the neutral and charged exciton.
This effect is reversible by exposing the sample to air, indicating the change
is mitigated by surface interactions with the ambient environment. This method
provides a tool to modify optical emission energy and to isolate physical
processes in this and other two-dimensional materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01752</id><created>2016-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bord&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Christian J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reforming the international system of units: On our way to redefine the
  base units solely from fundamental constants and beyond</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our purpose is to offer a logical analysis of the system of units and to
explore possible paths towards a consistent and unified system with an original
perspective. The path taken here builds on the fact that, thanks to optical or
matter-wave interferometry, any measurement can be reduced to a dimensionless
phase measurement and we follow this simple guiding line. We finally show how
one could progress even further on the path of a synthetic framework for
fundamental metrology based upon pure geometry in five dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01757</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Baade</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martayan</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivinius</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author></authors><title>Be Stars as Seen Through Telescopes in Survey Mode (I)</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>To appear in conference proceedings &quot;Bright Emissaries: Be Stars as
  Messengers of Star-Disk Physics&quot;, eds. A. Sigut and C. Jones (11 Aug 2014 -
  13 Aug 2014, London, Ontario, Canada)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In spite of the almost all-encompassing variability of Be stars, surveys play
a steadily increasing role in complementing the insights gained from
single-star studies. The definition of classical Be stars as recently augmented
by \cite{Rivinius2013} enables unambiguous identification of Be stars in a much
increased range of observations. Results of targeted surveys are briefly
reviewed for the effects of metallicity, binarity, and evolution. It still
remains to be seen whether Be stars are safe benchmarks for the calibration of
evolutionary models with rapid rotation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01771</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Alagic</keyname><forenames>Gorjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fefferman</keyname><forenames>Bill</forenames></author></authors><title>On Quantum Obfuscation</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Encryption of data is fundamental to secure communication in the modern
world. Beyond encryption of data lies obfuscation, i.e., encryption of
functionality. It is well-known that the most powerful means of obfuscating
classical programs, so-called ``black-box obfuscation',' is provably impossible
[Barak et al '12]. However, several recent results have yielded candidate
schemes that satisfy a definition weaker than black-box, and yet still have
numerous applications.
  In this work, we initialize the rigorous study of obfuscating programs via
quantum-mechanical means. We define notions of quantum obfuscation which
encompass several natural variants. The input to the obfuscator can describe
classical or quantum functionality, and the output can be a circuit description
or a quantum state. The obfuscator can also satisfy one of a number of
obfuscation conditions: black-box, information-theoretic black-box,
indistinguishability, and best possible; the last two conditions come in three
variants: perfect, statistical, and computational. We discuss many
applications, including CPA-secure quantum encryption, quantum
fully-homomorphic encryption, and public-key quantum money.
  We then prove several impossibility results, extending a number of
foundational papers on classical obfuscation to the quantum setting. We prove
that quantum black-box obfuscation is impossible in a setting where adversaries
can possess more than one output of the obfuscator. In particular, generic
transformation of quantum circuits into black-box-obfuscated quantum circuits
is impossible. We also show that statistical indistinguishability obfuscation
is impossible, up to an unlikely complexity-theoretic collapse. Our proofs
involve a new tool: chosen-ciphertext-secure encryption of quantum data, which
was recently shown to be possible assuming quantum-secure one-way functions
exist [Alagic et al '16].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01775</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikuta</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takesue</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced violation of the Collins-Gisin-Linden-Massar-Popescu inequality
  with optimized time-bin-entangled ququarts</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 022307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.022307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-dimensional quantum entanglement is drawing attention because it enables
us to perform quantum information tasks that are robust against noises. To test
the nonlocality of entangled qudits, the Collins-Gisin-Linden-Massar-Popescu
(CGLMP) inequality has been proposed and demonstrated using qudits based on
orbital angular momentum, time-energy uncertainty, and frequency bins. Here, we
report the generation and observation of time-bin entangled ququarts. We
implemented a measurement for the CGLMP inequality test using cascaded delay
Mach-Zehnder interferometers fabricated by using planar lightwave circuit
technology, with which we achieved a precise and stable measurement for
time-bin-entangled ququarts. In addition, we generated an optimized entangled
state by modulating the pump pulse intensities, with which we can observe the
theoretical maximum violation for the CGLMP inequality test. As a result, we
successfully observed a Bell-type parameter $S_4 = 2.774 \pm 0.025$ violating
the CGLMP inequality for the maximally entangled state and an enhanced
Bell-type parameter $S_4 = 2.913 \pm 0.023$ for the optimized entangled state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01778</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Pulwicki</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of Plant Growth; A Theory Based on Riemannian Geometry</title><categories>q-bio.TO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>PhD thesis, 188 pages. Accepted December 2015 at University of
  Calgary, Canada</comments><msc-class>53Z05 (Primary), 92C80, 35Q92, 35R01, 74L15 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, a new model for macroscopic plant tissue growth based on
dynamical Riemannian geometry is presented. We treat 1D and 2D tissues as
continuous, deformable, growing geometries for sizes larger than 1mm. The
dynamics of the growing tissue are described by a set of coupled tensor
equations in non-Euclidean (curved) space. These coupled equations represent a
novel feedback mechanism between growth and curvature dynamics.
  For 1D growth, numerical simulations are compared to two measures of root
growth. First, modular growth along the simulated root shows an elongation zone
common to many species of plant roots. Second, the relative elemental growth
rate (REGR) calculated in silico exhibits temporal dynamics recently
characterized in high-resolution root growth studies but which thus far lack a
biological hypothesis to explain them. Namely, the REGR can evolve from a
single peak localized near the root tip to a double-peak structure. In our
model, this is a direct consequence of considering growth as both a geometric
reaction-diffusion process and expansion due to a distributed source of new
materials.
  In 2D, we study a circularly symmetric growing disk with emergent negative
curvatures. These results are compared against thin disk experiments, which are
a proxy model for plant leaves. These results also apply to the curvature
evolution and the inhomogeneous growth pattern of the Acetabularia cap. Lastly,
we extend the model to anisotropic disks and predict the growth dynamics for a
2D curved surface which develops an elongated shape with localized ruffling.
  Our model also provides several measures of the dynamics of tissue growth.
These include the time evolution of the metric and velocity field, which are
dynamical variables in the model, as well as expansion, shear and rotation
which are deformation tensors characterizing the growth of the tissue.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01781</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Janoschek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Los Alamos National Laboratory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lander</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames><affiliation>European Commission, Joint Research Centre, Institute for Transuranium Elements, Karlsruhe, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lawrence</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames><affiliation>Los Alamos National Laboratory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames><affiliation>Los Alamos National Laboratory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lumsden</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames><affiliation>Quantum Condensed Matter Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Abernathy</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames><affiliation>Quantum Condensed Matter Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames><affiliation>Los Alamos National Laboratory</affiliation></author></authors><title>Comments on 'Phonon and magnetic structure in {\delta}-plutonium from
  density-functional theory' by P. S\&quot;oderlind et al</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In their recent paper [S\&quot;oderlind, P. et al., Sci. Rep. 5, 15958 (2015)],
S\&quot;oderlind et al. discuss two subjects from a theoretical point of view: the
phonon spectra and the possible magnetic structure of {\delta}-plutonium (Pu).
Here, we comment on the second subject. S\&quot;oderlind et al. compare the Pu
magnetic form factor F(Q) calculated via density functional theory (DFT) with
measurements of F(Q) by neutron spectroscopy [Janoschek, M. et al., Sci. Adv.
1, e1500188 (2015)]. In particular, this comparison does not consider a number
of experimental facts established in the neutron spectroscopy study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01790</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Chuang</keyname><forenames>Hsun-Jen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chamlagain</keyname><forenames>Bhim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koehler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perera</keyname><forenames>Meeghage Madusanka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jiaqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandrus</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomanek</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zhixian</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-Resistance 2D/2D Ohmic Contacts: A Universal Approach to
  High-Performance WSe2, MoS2, and MoSe2 Transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 4 figures, Nano Lett. Accepted</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b05066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new strategy for fabricating 2D/2D low-resistance ohmic contacts
for a variety of transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) using van der Waals
assembly of substitutionally doped TMDs as drain/source contacts and TMDs with
no intentional doping as channel materials. We demonstrate that few-layer WSe2
field-effect transistors (FETs) with 2D/2D contacts exhibit low contact
resistances of ~ 0.3 k ohm.um, high on/off ratios up to &gt; 109, and high drive
currents exceeding 320 uA um-1. These favorable characteristics are combined
with a two-terminal field-effect hole mobility ~ 2x102 cm2 V-1 s-1 at room
temperature, which increases to &gt;2x103 cm2 V-1 s-1 at cryogenic temperatures.
We observe a similar performance also in MoS2 and MoSe2 FETs with 2D/2D drain
and source contacts. The 2D/2D low-resistance ohmic contacts presented here
represent a new device paradigm that overcomes a significant bottleneck in the
performance of TMDs and a wide variety of other 2D materials as the channel
materials in post-silicon electronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01800</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Howard</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the flaring emission at the Galactic Centre</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures, Galactic Center Workshop (19 - 23 October 2009 :
  Shanghai, China), The Galactic Center: a Window to the Nuclear Environment of
  Disk Galaxies. Proceedings of a workshop held at Shanghai, China Oct. 19-23,
  2009. Ed. M. R. Morris, Q. D. Wang, F. Yuan. Astronomical Society of the
  Pacific, 2011, p.378</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The massive black hole at the Galactic Centre is known to be variable in
radio, millimeter, near-IR and X-rays. We investigate the physical processes
responsible for the variable observed emissions from the compact radio source
Sgr A*. We study the evolution of the variable emission region and present
light curves and time-resolved spectra of emissions from the accretion disk,
close to the event horizon, near the marginally stable orbit of a Kerr black
hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01809</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Roudbari</keyname><forenames>Mahnaz Shokrpour</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Brummelen</keyname><forenames>E. Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verhoosel</keyname><forenames>Clemens V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Multiscale Diffuse-Interface Model for Two-Phase Flow in Porous Media</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we consider a multiscale phase-field model for
capillarity-driven flows in porous media. The presented model constitutes a
reduction of the conventional Navier-Stokes-Cahn-Hilliard phase-field model,
valid in situations where interest is restricted to dynamical and equilibrium
behavior in an aggregated sense, rather than a precise description of
microscale flow phenomena. The model is based on averaging of the equation of
motion, thereby yielding a significant reduction in the complexity of the
underlying Navier-Stokes-Cahn-Hilliard equations, while retaining its
macroscopic dynamical and equilibrium properties. Numerical results are
presented for the representative 2-dimensional capillary-rise problem
pertaining to two closely spaced vertical plates with both identical and
disparate wetting properties. Comparison with analytical solutions for these
test cases corroborates the accuracy of the presented multiscale model. In
addition, we present results for a capillary-rise problem with a non-trivial
geometry corresponding to a porous medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01810</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01810</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Alert</keyname><forenames>Ricard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casademunt</keyname><forenames>Jaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tierno</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Landscape-Inversion Phase Transition in Dipolar Colloids: Tuning the
  Structure and Dynamics of 2D Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 198301 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.198301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the 2D crystalline phases of paramagnetic colloidal particles with
dipolar interactions and constrained on a periodic substrate. Combining theory,
simulation, and experiments we demonstrate a new scenario of first-order phase
transitions that occurs via a complete inversion of the energy landscape,
featuring non-conventional properties that allow for: (i) tuning of crystal
symmetry; (ii) control of dynamical properties of different crystalline orders
via tuning of their relative stability with an external magnetic field; (iii)
an equivalent but independent control of the same dynamic properties via
temporal modulations of that field; and (iv) non-standard phase-ordering
kinetics involving spontaneous formation of transient metastable domains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01811</id><created>2016-01-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>Raina J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Jon W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contescu</keyname><forenames>Cristian I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear spin correlations and collective excitations in supercritical
  H$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Submitted 12-21-2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nuclear spins are known to experience spontaneous long-range correlations
only below 2.5 mili-Kelvin in superfluid $^3$He. Here we present the first
evidence of nuclear spin coupling in molecular hydrogen (H$_2$) at 74-92 Kelvin
using neutron scattering, showing a fundamental change in nature from the
incoherent scattering universally expected from hydrogen, which reflects single
particle properties of uncorrelated nuclear spins, to coherent, with a peak
materializing on the elastic line, indicating H$_2$-H$_2$ nuclear spin
correlations. In this novel phase, the dynamic response of the system also
changes nature, and collective excitations with an effective mass of nine H$_2$
are observed with inelastic scattering at momentum transfers up to 37
\AA$^{-1}$, corresponding to length scales smaller than the H-H bond, where
previous experiments have always found single atom excitations. This novel
behavior has only been observed from H$_2$ within the subnanometer sized
graphitic pores of a carbon material, marking the first demonstration that a
confined materials environment can be used to control nuclear spin
correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0411047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-02-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0411047</id><created>2004-11-03</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>ChiYi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Fundamental Modification of Standard Cosmological Metric</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper a novel physical picture of space-time is introduced by means
of making a further distinction on the absolute background of space-time and
the relative length or duration of base units of space-time. Just based on the
existence of the absolute background for space, an explicit dynamical equation
which satisfies a moderately general principle of relativity is logically
derived under the nonrelativistic framework of classical mechanics. The nature
of the inertial force is firstly revealed as the real forces acting on the
reference object. Therefore, Einstein's equivalence principle should be
abandoned and only the numerical equality between the inertial mass and
gravitational mass can be retained. Consequently, the candidate for the
standard clock should be changed and an adjusted physical picture for how to
convert the gravitational force into a geometric effect on space-time is
thereby presented. As for cosmology, it should be emphasized that the observer
at the present time on the earth, instead of the comoving observer, is the only
true observer. The coordinate time &quot;t&quot; in the cosmological metric is just
introduced as the reading number of the observational clock, whose running rate
is duplicated from the clock equipped by the observer at the present time on
the earth. With this new physical picture of space-time, an extra factor $b(t)$
must be introduced into the cosmological metric to describe the gravitational
time dilation effect since the comoving local intrinsic clock will run in a
faster and faster rate with the expanding of the universe. In this way, we may
obtain a positive value of $\rho+3p$ and avoid the introduction of dark energy
in the current universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
