<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T00:03:56Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-20" from="2017-01-20" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0911.5231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0911.5231</id><created>2009-11-27</created><updated>2011-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tosin</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial/boundary-value problems of tumor growth within a host tissue</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP q-bio.TO</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures</comments><msc-class>35B45, 35Q92, 92B05</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Biol., 66(1):163-202 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00285-012-0505-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper concerns multiphase models of tumor growth in interaction with a
surrounding tissue, taking into account also the interplay with diffusible
nutrients feeding the cells. Models specialize in nonlinear systems of possibly
degenerate parabolic equations, which include phenomenological terms related to
specific cell functions. The paper discusses general modeling guidelines for
such terms, as well as for initial and boundary conditions, aiming at both
biological consistency and mathematical robustness of the resulting problems.
Particularly, it addresses some qualitative properties such as a priori
nonnegativity, boundedness, and uniqueness of the solutions. Existence of the
solutions is studied in the one-dimensional time-independent case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.4614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.4614</id><created>2010-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dokuchaev</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eroshenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Horizons as They Are Looked from a Moving Frame</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures, preprint submitted to Theoretical Physics</comments><journal-ref>Theoretical Physics 1, 18 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.22606/tp.2016.11005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the cosmological horizons in the expanding universe from the
point of view of observer moving with respect to CMB frame. The deformation
(non-sphericity) of cosmological horizons is demonstrated. Some principle
consequences are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.6044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.6044</id><created>2012-10-22</created><updated>2013-03-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ching Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Multistable binary decision making on networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.SI stat.AP</categories><comments>v3: mostly published version; v2: fixed minor textual errors; 21
  pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E87 (2013) 032806</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.87.032806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple model for a binary decision making process on a graph,
motivated by modeling social decision making with cooperative individuals. The
model is similar to a random field Ising model or fiber bundle model, but with
key differences on heterogeneous networks. For many types of disorder and
interactions between the nodes, we predict discontinuous phase transitions with
mean field theory which are largely independent of network structure. We show
how these phase transitions can also be understood by studying microscopic
avalanches, and describe how network structure enhances fluctuations in the
distribution of avalanches. We suggest theoretically the existence of a
&quot;glassy&quot; spectrum of equilibria associated with a typical phase, even on
infinite graphs, so long as the first moment of the degree distribution is
finite. This behavior implies that the model is robust against noise below a
certain scale, and also that phase transitions can switch from discontinuous to
continuous on networks with too few edges. Numerical simulations suggest that
our theory is accurate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.3735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.3735</id><created>2014-01-15</created><updated>2014-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Losada</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortin</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castagnino</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portesi</keyname><forenames>Mariela</forenames></author></authors><title>A semiclassical condition for chaos based on Pesin theorem</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Theoretical Physics, 54, 7 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-014-2437-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A semiclassical method to determine if the classical limit of a quantum
system is chaotic or not, based on Pesin theorem, is presented. The method is
applied to a phenomenological Gamow--type model and it is concluded that its
classical limit is chaotic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.2813</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.2813</id><created>2014-04-10</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banisch</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>Nata&#x161;a Djurdjevac</forenames></author></authors><title>Cycle flow based module detection in directed recurrence networks</title><categories>physics.data-an cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><msc-class>60J20, 94C15</msc-class><journal-ref>EPL (Europhysics Letters), Volume 108, Number 6 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/108/68008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new cycle flow based method for finding fuzzy partitions of
weighted directed networks coming from time series data. We show that this
method overcomes essential problems of most existing clustering approaches,
which tend to ignore important directional information by considering only
one-step, one-directional node connections. Our method introduces a novel
measure of communication between nodes using multi-step, bidirectional
transitions encoded by a cycle decomposition of the probability flow. Symmetric
properties of this measure enable us to construct an undirected graph that
captures information flow of the original graph seen by the data and apply
clustering methods designed for undirected graphs. Finally, we demonstrate our
algorithm by analyzing earthquake time series data, which naturally induce
(time-)directed networks. This article has been published originally in EPL,
DOI: 10.1209/0295-5075/108/68008. This version differs from the published
version by minor formatting details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2351</id><created>2014-09-08</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frasca</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solutions for classical Yang-Mills fields</title><categories>math-ph hep-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages. No figure. This paper has been superseded by
  arxiv:1509.05292 appeared on EPJ Plus</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a set of exact solutions of the classical Yang-Mills equations.
They have the property to satisfy a massive dispersion relation and hold in all
gauges. These solutions can be used to describe the vacuum of the quantum
Yang-Mills theory and so, they provide a general framework to build a quantum
field theory. The components of the field become separated on a generic gauge
but are all equal just in the Lorenz (Landau) gauge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1861</id><created>2014-11-07</created><updated>2016-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rajpoot</keyname><forenames>Subhash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vacaru</keyname><forenames>Sergiu I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonholonomic Jet Deformations and Exact Solutions for Modified Ricci
  Soliton and Einstein Equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages with table of content, latex 2e, 11 pt, v3 accepted to
  IJGMMP. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1312.4844</comments><msc-class>58A20, 53C05, 53C43, 83C15, 83D05</msc-class><journal-ref>IJGMMP 14 (2017) 1750032</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887817500323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $\mathbf{g}$ be a pseudo--Riemanian metric of arbitrary signature on a
manifold $\mathbf{V}$ with conventional $n+n$ dimensional splitting, $\ n\geq
2,$ determined by a nonholonomic (non--integrable) distribution $\mathcal{N}$
defining a generalized (nonlinear) connection and associated nonholonomic frame
structures. We shall work with a correspondingly adapted linear metric
compatible connection $\hat{\mathbf{D}}$ and its nonzero torsion
$\hat{\mathcal{T}}$, both completely determined by $\mathbf{g}$. Our first goal
is to prove that there are certain generalized frame and/or jet transforms and
prolongations with $(\mathbf{g},\mathbf{V})\rightarrow
(\hat{\mathbf{g}},\hat{\mathbf{V}})$ into explicit classes of solutions of some
generalized Einstein equations $\hat{\mathbf{R}}\mathit{ic}=\Lambda
\hat{\mathbf{g}}$, $\Lambda =const$, encoding various types of nonholonomic)
Ricci soliton configurations and/or jet variables and symmetries. The second
goal is to solve additional constraint equations for zero torsion,
$\hat{\mathcal{T}}=0$, on generalized solutions constructed in explicit forms
with jet variables and extract Levi-Civita configurations. This allows us to
find generic off-diagonal exact solutions depending on all space time
coordinates on $\mathbf{V}$ via generating and integration functions and
various classes of constant jet parameters and associated symmetries. We shall
study (third goal) how such generalized metrics and connections can be related
by so-called &quot;half-conformal&quot; and/ or jet deformations of certain sub-classes
of solutions with one, or two, Killing symmetries. Finally, there are
considered some examples when exact solutions are constructed as nonholonomic
jet prolongations of the Kerr metrics, with possible Ricci soliton
deformations, and characterized by nonholonomic jet structures and generalized
connections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04035</id><created>2015-06-12</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Man Leong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messenger</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hendry</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>Ik Siong</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximising the detection probability of kilonovae associated with
  gravitational wave observations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><report-no>LIGO-P1500085</report-no><journal-ref>ApJ, 834, 84 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/1/84</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Estimates of the source sky location for gravitational wave signals are
likely span areas ranging up to hundreds of square degrees or more, making it
very challenging for most telescopes to search for counterpart signals in the
electromagnetic spectrum. To boost the chance of successfully observing such
counterparts, we have developed an algorithm which optimizes the number of
observing fields and their corresponding time allocations by maximizing the
detection probability. As a proof-of-concept demonstration, we optimize
follow-up observations targeting kilonovae using telescopes including CTIO-Dark
Energy Camera, Subaru-HyperSuprimeCam, Pan-STARRS and Palomar Transient
Factory. We consider three simulated gravitational wave events with 90%
credible error regions spanning areas from ~30 deg^2 to ~300 deg^2. Assuming a
source at 200 Mpc, we demonstrate that to obtain a maximum detection
probability, there is an optimized number of fields for any particular event
that a telescope should observe. To inform future telescope design studies, we
present the maximum detection probability and corresponding number of observing
fields for a combination of limiting magnitudes and fields-of-view over a range
of parameters. We show that for large gravitational wave error regions,
telescope sensitivity rather than field-of-view, is the dominating factor in
maximizing the detection probability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05537</id><created>2015-06-17</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Qirong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinacci</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maji</keyname><forenames>Moupiya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuexing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springel</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernquist</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>Baryonic impact on the dark matter distribution in Milky Way-size
  galaxies and their satellites</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>22 pages, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw374</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the impact of baryons on the distribution of dark matter in a Milky
Way-size halo by comparing a high-resolution, moving-mesh cosmological
simulation with its dark matter-only counterpart. We identify three main
processes related to baryons -- adiabatic contraction, tidal disruption and
reionization -- which jointly shape the dark matter distribution in both the
main halo and its subhalos. The relative effect of each baryonic process
depends strongly on the subhalo mass. For massive subhalos with maximum
circular velocity $v_{\rm max} &gt; 35 km/s$, adiabatic contraction increases the
dark matter concentration, making these halos less susceptible to tidal
disruption. For low-mass subhalos with $v_{\rm max} &lt; 20 km/s$, reionization
effectively reduces their mass on average by $\approx$ 30% and $v_{\rm max}$ by
$\approx$ 20%. For intermediate subhalos with $20 km/s &lt; v_{\rm max} &lt; 35
km/s$, which share a similar mass range as the classical dwarf spheroidals,
strong tidal truncation induced by the main galaxy reduces their $v_{\rm max}$.
Moreover, the stellar disk of the main galaxy effectively depletes subhalos
near the central region. As a combined result of reionization and increased
tidal disruption, the total number of low-mass subhalos in the hydrodynamic
simulation is nearly halved compared to that of the $\textit{N-}$body
simulation. We do not find dark matter cores in dwarf galaxies, unlike previous
studies that employed bursty feedback-driven outflows. The substantial impact
of baryons on the abundance and internal structure of subhalos suggests that
galaxy formation and evolution models based on $\textit{N}$-body simulations
should include these physical processes as major components.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05462</id><created>2015-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Meschke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemppinen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pekola</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate Coulomb Blockade Thermometry up to 60 Kelvin</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A 374, 20150052 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsta.2015.0052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate experimentally a precise realization of Coulomb Blockade
Thermometry (CBT) working at temperatures up to 60 K. Advances in nano
fabrication methods using electron beam lithography allow us to fabricate a
uniform arrays of sufficiently small tunnel junctions to guarantee an overall
temperature reading uncertainty of about 1\%
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00850</id><created>2015-08-04</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cerqueti</keyname><forenames>Roy</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Santis</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic Ising model with flipping sets of spins and fast decreasing
  temperature</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures, Accepted for publication in &quot;Annales de
  l'Institut Henri Poincar\'e, Probabilit\'es et Statistiques&quot;</comments><msc-class>60K35, 82B44</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper deals with the stochastic Ising model with a temperature shrinking
to zero as time goes to infinity. A generalization of the Glauber dynamics is
considered, on the basis of the existence of simultaneous flips of some spins.
Such dynamics act on a wide class of graphs which are periodic and embedded in
$\mathbb{R}^d$. The interactions between couples of spins are assumed to be
quenched i.i.d. random variables following a Bernoulli distribution with
support $\{-1,+1\}$. The specific problem here analyzed concerns the assessment
of how often (finitely or infinitely many times, almost surely) a given spin
flips. Adopting the classification proposed in \cite{GNS}, we present
conditions in order to have models of type $\mathcal{F}$ (any spin flips
finitely many times), $\mathcal{I}$ (any spin flips infinitely many times) and
$\mathcal{M}$ (a mixed case). Several examples are provided in all dimensions
and for different cases of graphs. The most part of the obtained results holds
true for the case of zero-temperature and some of them for the cubic lattice
$\mathbb{L}_d=(\mathbb{Z}^d, \mathbb{E}_d)$ as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04532</id><created>2015-08-19</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Man'ko</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markovich</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Breakdown of separability due to confinement, submitted to Report on
  mathematical physics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This submission has been replaced since the name change and the
  significant additions in the text</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple system of two particles in a bidimensional configurational space $S$
is studied. The possibility of breaking in $S$ the time independent
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation of the system into two separated one-dimensional
one-body Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equations is assumed. In this paper, we focus on how
the latter property is countered by imposing such boundary conditions as
confinement in a limited region of $S$ and/or restrictions on the joint
coordinate probability density stemming from the sign-invariance condition of
the relative coordinate (an impenetrability condition). Our investigation
demonstrates the reducibility of the problem under scrutiny into that of a
single particle living in a limited domain of its bidimensional configurational
space. These general ideas are illustrated introducing the coordinates $X_c$
and $x$ of the center of mass of two particles and of the associated relative
motion, respectively. The effects of the confinement and the impenetrability
are then analyzed by studying with the help of an appropriate Green's function
and the time evolution of the covariance of $X_c$ and $x$. Moreover, to
calculate the state of the single particle constrained within a square, a
rhombus, a triangle and a rectangle the Green's function expression in terms of
Jacobi $\theta_3$-function is applied. All the results are illustrated by
examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04986</id><created>2015-10-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pechal</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurpiers</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdumalikov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichler</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mlynek</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shnirman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gefen</keyname><forenames>Yuval</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallraff</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filipp</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of geometric dephasing using a superconducting qubit</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 6, 8757 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms9757</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum system interacting with its environment is subject to dephasing
which ultimately destroys the information it holds. Using a superconducting
qubit, we experimentally show that this dephasing has both dynamic and
geometric origins. It is found that geometric dephasing, which is present even
in the adiabatic limit and when no geometric phase is acquired, can either
reduce or restore coherence depending on the orientation of the path the qubit
traces out in its projective Hilbert space. It accompanies the evolution of any
system in Hilbert space subjected to noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08318</id><created>2015-10-28</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thyagarajan</keyname><forenames>Nithyanandan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beardsley</keyname><forenames>Adam P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowman</keyname><forenames>Judd D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Miguel F.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Generic and Efficient E-field Parallel Imaging Correlator for
  Next-Generation Radio Telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Accepted in MNRAS, 17 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern radio telescopes are favouring densely packed array layouts with large
numbers of antennas ($N_\textrm{A}\gtrsim 1000$). Since the complexity of
traditional correlators scales as $\mathcal{O}(N_\textrm{A}^2)$, there will be
a steep cost for realizing the full imaging potential of these powerful
instruments. Through our generic and efficient E-field Parallel Imaging
Correlator (EPIC), we present the first software demonstration of a generalized
direct imaging algorithm, namely, the Modular Optimal Frequency Fourier (MOFF)
imager. Not only does it bring down the cost for dense layouts to
$\mathcal{O}(N_\textrm{A}\log_2 N_\textrm{A})$ but can also image from
irregular layouts and heterogeneous arrays of antennas. EPIC is highly modular,
parallelizable, implemented in object-oriented Python, and publicly available.
We have verified the images produced to be equivalent to those from traditional
techniques to within a precision set by gridding coarseness. We have also
validated our implementation on data observed with the Long Wavelength Array
(LWA1). We provide a detailed framework for imaging with heterogeneous arrays
and show that EPIC robustly estimates the input sky model for such arrays.
Antenna layouts with dense filling factors consisting of a large number of
antennas such as LWA, the Square Kilometre Array, Hydrogen Epoch of
Reionization Array, and Canadian Hydrogen Intensity Mapping Experiment will
gain significant computational advantage by deploying an optimized version of
EPIC. The algorithm is a strong candidate for instruments targeting transient
searches of Fast Radio Bursts (FRB) as well as planetary and exoplanetary
phenomena due to the availability of high-speed calibrated time-domain images
and low output bandwidth relative to visibility-based systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05090</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-12-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>B&#xe9;ny</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;dric</forenames></author></authors><title>Inferring effective field observables from a discrete model</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 013013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/19/1/013013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A spin system on a lattice can usually be modelled at large scales by an
effective quantum field theory. A key mathematical result relating the two
descriptions is the quantum central limit theorem, which shows that certain
spin observables satisfy an algebra of bosonic fields under certain conditions.
Here, we show that these particular observables and conditions are the relevant
ones for an observer with certain limited abilities to resolve spatial
locations as well as spin values. This is shown by computing the asymptotic
behaviour of a quantum Fisher information metric as function of the resolution
parameters. The relevant observables characterise the state perturbations whose
distinguishability does not decay too fast as a function of spatial or spin
resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00671</id><created>2015-12-02</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yibin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonperturbative emergence of Dirac fermion in strongly correlated
  composite fermions of fractional quantum Hall effects</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 table, 1 figure, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035123 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classic composite fermion field theory (Ref. 1) builds up an excellent
framework to uniformly study important physical objects and globally explain
anomalous experimental phenomena in fractional quantum Hall physics while there
are also inherent weaknesses. We present a nonperturbative emergent Dirac
fermion theory from this strongly correlated composite fermion field theory,
which overcomes these serious long-standing shortcomings. The particle-hole
symmetry of Dirac equation resolves this particle-hole symmetry enigma in the
composite fermion field theory. With the help of presented numerical data, we
show that for main Jain's sequences of fractional quantum Hall effects, this
emergent Dirac fermion theory is most likely nonperturbatively stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01430</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Praloy</forenames><affiliation>Indian Statistical Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Subir</forenames><affiliation>Indian Statistical Institute</affiliation></author></authors><title>Noncommutative Geometry and Fluid Dynamics</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures, change of title, new references added, no
  change in results and conclusions; minor changes and references added, to
  appear in EPJC; erratum included (page 19), change in Dirac algebra leads to
  significant changes in some of the conclusions</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4488-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper we have developed a Non-Commutative (NC) generalization
of perfect fluid model from first principles, in a Hamiltonian framework. The
noncommutativity is introduced at the Lagrangian (particle) coordinate space
brackets and the induced NC fluid bracket algebra for the Eulerian (fluid)
field variables is derived. Together with a Hamiltonian this NC algebra
generates the generalized fluid dynamics that satisfies exact local
conservation laws for mass and energy thereby maintaining mass and energy
conservation. However, nontrivial NC correction terms appear in charge and
energy fluxes. Other non-relativistic spacetime symmetries of the NC fluid are
also discussed in detail. This constitutes the study of kinematics and dynamics
of NC fluid.
  In the second part we construct an extension of Friedmann-Robertson-Walker
(FRW) cosmological model based on the NC fluid dynamics presented here. We
outline the way in which NC effects generate cosmological perturbations
bringing in anisotropy and inhomogeneity in the model. We also derive a NC
extended Friedmann equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05263</id><created>2016-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Dumur</keyname><forenames>&#xc9;tienne</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;ng</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feofanov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei&#xdf;l</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krupko</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roch</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naud</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;cile</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guichard</keyname><forenames>Wiebke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buisson</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author></authors><title>Unexpectedly allowed transition in two inductively coupled transmons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Applied Superconductivity, 26, 1-4 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TASC.2016.2515020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present experimental results in which the unexpected zero-two transition
of a circuit composed of two inductively coupled transmons is observed. This
transition shows an unusual magnetic flux dependence with a clear disappearance
at zero magnetic flux. In a transmon qubit the symmetry of the wave functions
prevents this transition to occur due to selection rule. In our circuit the
Josephson effect introduces strong couplings between the two normal modes of
the artificial atom. This leads to a coherent superposition of states from the
two modes enabling such transitions to occur.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06559</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutreix</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser-induced topological transitions in phosphorene with inversion
  symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Includes Supplemental Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 241404(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.241404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent ab initio calculations and experiments reported
insulating-semimetallic phase transitions in multilayer phosphorene under a
perpendicular dc field, pressure or doping, as a possible route to realize
topological phases. In this work, we show that even a monolayer phosphorene may
undergo Lifshitz transitions toward semimetallic and topological insulating
phases, provided it is rapidly driven by in-plane time-periodic laser fields.
Based on a four-orbital tight-binding description, we give an
inversion-symmetry-based prescription in order to apprehend the topology of the
photon-renormalized band structure, up to the second order in the
high-frequency limit. Apart from the initial band insulating behavior, two
additional phases are thus identified. A semimetallic phase with massless Dirac
electrons may be induced by linear polarized fields, whereas elliptic polarized
fields are likely to drive the material into an anomalous quantum Hall phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01093</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barkeshli</keyname><forenames>Maissam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freedman</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Modular transformations through sequences of topological charge
  projections</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages. v2: Added appendix describing protocol for realizing the
  pi/8 phase gate in the Ising x Ising* state with gapped boundaries and
  topological charge measurements. v3: updated author affiliation</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 165108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.165108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ground state subspace of a topological phase of matter forms a
representation of the mapping class group of the space on which the state is
defined. We show that elements of the mapping class group of a surface of genus
$g$ can be obtained through a sequence of topological charge projections along
at least three mutually intersecting non-contractible cycles. We demonstrate
this both through the algebraic theory of anyons and also through an analysis
of the topology of the space-time manifold. We combine this result with two
observations: (i) that surfaces of genus $g$ can be effectively simulated in
planar geometries by using bilayer, or doubled, versions of the topological
phase of interest, and inducing the appropriate types of gapped boundaries; and
(ii) that the required topological charge projections can be implemented as
adiabatic unitary transformations by locally tuning microscopic parameters of
the system, such as the energy gap. These observations suggest a possible path
towards effectively implementing modular transformations in physical systems.
In particular, they also show how the $\text{Ising} \otimes
\overline{\text{Ising}}$ state, in the presence of disconnected gapped
boundaries, can support universal topological quantum computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02742</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Castano-Yepes</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez-Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the photoacoustic signal during the porous silicon formation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 121, 025103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973940</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within this work, the kinetics of the growing stage of porous silicon (PS)
during the etching process was studied using the photoacoustic technique. A
p-type Si with low resistivity was used as a substrate. An extension of
Rosencwaig and Gersho model is proposed in order to analyze the temporary
changes that take place in the amplitude of the photoacoustic signal during the
PS growth. The solution of the heat equation takes into account the modulated
laser beam, the changes in the reflectance of the PS-backing heterostructure,
the electrochemical reaction, and the Joule effect as thermal sources. The
model includes the time-dependence of the sample thickness during the
electrochemical etching of PS. The changes in the reflectance are identified as
the laser reflections in the internal layers of the system. The reflectance is
modeled by an additional sinusoidal-monochromatic light source and its
modulated frequency is related to the velocity of the PS growth. The chemical
reaction and the DC components of the heat sources are taken as an average
value from the experimental data. The theoretical results are in agreement with
the experimental data and hence provided a method to determine variables of the
PS growth, such as the etching velocity and the thickness of the porous layer
during the growing process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09210</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Correggi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacomelli</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Superconductivity in Presence of Corners</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.supr-con math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, pdfLaTex, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Math. Phys. 29 (2017), 1750005 (24 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0129055X17500052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an extreme type-II superconducting wire with non-smooth cross
section, i.e., with one or more corners at the boundary, in the framework of
the Ginzburg-Landau theory. We prove the existence of an interval of values of
the applied field, where superconductivity is spread uniformly along the
boundary of the sample. More precisely the energy is not affected to leading
order by the presence of corners and the modulus of the Ginzburg-Landau
minimizer is approximately constant along the transversal direction. The
critical fields delimiting this surface superconductivity regime coincide with
the ones in absence of boundary singularities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02905</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Politano</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slotman</keyname><forenames>Guus J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rold&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiarello</keyname><forenames>Gennaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campi</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>Mikhail I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Shengjun</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of moir\'e superlattice reconstruction in the electronic
  excitation spectrum of graphene-metal heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Supplemental materials available at
  http://www.theorphys.science.ru.nl/people/yuan/</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4.2 (2017): 021001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa53ba</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the electronic excitation spectrum in periodically rippled
graphene on Ru(0001) and flat, commensurate graphene on Ni(111) by means of
high-resolution electron energy loss spectroscopy and a combination of density
functional theory and tight-binding approaches. We show that the periodic
moir\'e superlattice originated by the lattice mismatch in graphene/Ru(0001)
induces the emergence of an extra mode, which is not present in
graphene/Ni(111). Contrary to the ordinary intra-band plasmon of doped
graphene, the extra mode is robust in charge-neutral graphene/metal contacts,
having its origin in electron-hole inter-band transitions between van Hove
singularities that emerge in the reconstructed band structure, due to the
moir\'e pattern superlattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07509</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Emmons</keyname><forenames>Samuel B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Daekyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platter</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author></authors><title>The Operator Product Expansion Beyond Leading Order for Two-Component
  Fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figure, 4 tables, Eqs.(13), (15), and (59) are corrected
  with an additional term called C', published version</comments><report-no>LA-UR-15-29631</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043615 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043615</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a homogeneous, balanced gas of strongly interacting fermions in
two spin states interacting through a large scattering length. Finite range
corrections are needed for a quantitative description of data which experiments
and numerical simulations have provided. We use a perturbative field
theoretical framework and a tool called the Operator Product Expansion (OPE),
which together allow for the expression of finite range corrections to the
universal relations and momentum distribution. Using the OPE, we derive the
$1/k^6$ part of the momentum tail, which is related to the sum of the
derivative of the energy with respect to the finite range and the averaged
kinetic energy of opposite spin pairs. By comparing the $1/k^4$ term and the
$1/k^6$ correction in the momentum distribution to provided Quantum Monte Carlo
(QMC) data, we show that including the $1/k^6$ part offers marked improvements.
Our field theoretical approach allows for a clear understanding of the role of
the scattering length and finite effective range in the universal relations and
the momentum distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07815</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khlebnikov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay of near-critical currents in superconducting nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures; v2: minor changes, published in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064517 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider decay of supercurrent via phase slips in a discrete
one-dimensional superconductor (a chain of nodes connected by superconducting
links), aiming to explain the experimentally observed power-3/2 scaling of the
activation barrier in nanowires at currents close to the critical. We find
that, in this discrete model, the power-3/2 scaling holds for both long and
short wires even in the presence of bulk superconducting leads, despite the
suppression of thermal fluctuations at the ends. We also consider decay via
tunneling (quantum phase slips), which becomes important at low temperatures.
We find numerically the relevant Euclidean solutions (periodic instantons) and
determine the scaling of the tunneling exponent near the critical current. The
scaling law is power-5/4, different from that of the thermal activation
exponent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04401</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-11-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Samyobrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>S. Dutta</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent perfect absorption mediated enhancement of transverse spin in a
  gap plasmon guide</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Appl. Phys. (2016) 76: 30001</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjap/2016160330</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a symmetric gap plasmon guide (a folded Kretschmann
configuration) supporting both symmeric and antisymmetric coupled surface
plasmons. We calculate the transverse spin under illumination from both the
sides like in coherent perfect absorption (CPA), whereby all the incident light
can be absorbed to excite one of the modes of the structure. Significant
enhancement in the transverse spin is shown to be possible when the CPA dip and
the mode excitation are at the same frequency. The enhancement results from
CPA-mediated total transfer of the incident light to either of the coupled
modes and the associated large local fields. The transverse spin is localized
in the structure since in the ambient dielectric there are only incident plane
waves lacking any structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06063</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Azreg-A&#xef;nou</keyname><forenames>Mustapha</forenames></author></authors><title>Cyclic and heteroclinic flows near general static spherically symmetric
  black holes: Semi-cyclic flows -- Addendum and corrigendum</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, New title</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 36</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4613-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new accretion solutions of a polytropic perfect fluid onto an
f(R)-gravity de Sitter-like black hole. We consider two f(R)-gravity models and
obtain finite-period cyclic flows oscillating between the event and
cosmological horizons as well as semi-cyclic critical flows executing a two-way
motion from and back to the same horizon. Besides the generalizations and new
solutions presented in this work, a corrigendum to Eur. Phys. J. C (2016)
76:280 is provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08277</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazquez-Mozo</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Galileon Radiation from a Spherical Collapsing Shell</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.SR gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 figures. v3: minor changes, reference added. It matches
  the version published in Journal of High Energy Physics</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1701 (2017) 070</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galileon radiation in the collapse of a thin spherical shell of matter is
analyzed. In the framework of a cubic Galileon theory, we compute the field
profile produced at large distances by a short collapse, finding that the
radiated field has two peaks traveling ahead of light fronts. The total energy
radiated during the collapse follows a power law scaling with the shell's
physical width and results from two competing effects: a Vainshtein suppression
of the emission and an enhancement due to the thinness of the shell.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01663</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Golam Mortuza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardar</keyname><forenames>Gopal</forenames></author></authors><title>Transient response from Unruh-DeWitt detector along Rindler trajectory
  in polymer quantization</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure, revtex4; v2 new reference added, few typos fixed;
  a constant term which was missed earlier incorporated; results unchanged</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If an Unruh-DeWitt detector operates for an infinite proper time along the
trajectory of a uniformly accelerated observer in Fock space then induced
transition rate of the detector is proportional to Planck distribution. For a
realistic detector which operates only for a finite period, the instantaneous
transition rate contains both transient and non-transient terms. In particular,
the non-transient term contains a residue evaluated at the pole of the
two-point function. We show here by considering a massless scalar field that
unlike in Fock quantization, the short-distance two-point function contains no
pole in polymer quantization, the quantization techniques used in loop quantum
gravity. Consequently, corresponding transition rate of the Unruh-DeWitt
detector contains only transient terms. Thus, the result presented here
provides an alternative evidence for absence of Unruh effect in polymer
quantization which was shown earlier by the authors using methods of Bogoliubov
transformation and Kubo-Martin-Schwinger condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01984</id><created>2016-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Murray</keyname><forenames>Callum R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorshkov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Many-body decoherence dynamics and optimised operation of a
  single-photon switch</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 092001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/9/092001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a theoretical framework to characterize the decoherence dynamics
due to multi-photon scattering in an all-optical switch based on Rydberg atom
induced nonlinearities. By incorporating the knowledge of this decoherence
process into optimal photon storage and retrieval strategies, we establish
optimised switching protocols for experimentally relevant conditions, and
evaluate the corresponding limits in the achievable fidelities. Based on these
results we work out a simplified description that reproduces recent experiments
[arXiv:1511.09445] and provides a new interpretation in terms of many-body
decoherence involving multiple incident photons and multiple gate excitations
forming the switch. Aside from offering insights into the operational capacity
of realistic photon switching capabilities, our work provides a complete
description of spin wave decoherence in a Rydberg quantum optics setting, and
has immediate relevance to a number of further applications employing photon
storage in Rydberg media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02442</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author></authors><title>The Tau of Galaxy Clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, Accepted to JCAP, typos corrected</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent emergence of detections of the kinetic Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (kSZ)
effect through cross-correlation techniques is encouraging for the prospects of
future cosmic microwave background (CMB) experiments. Extracting information on
the large-scale velocity fields and constraining cosmological parameters from
such kSZ measurements requires an understanding of the optical depth to CMB
photons through halos. Using cosmological hydrodynamic simulations we find that
there exists a low-scatter relation between the optical depth and thermal
Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (tSZ) signal of halos within a physical aperture. We propose
that such a relation can be used to break the degeneracy between optical depth
and line-of-sight velocity in kSZ measurements. The limiting factors in our
proposal are systematic uncertainties associated with the sub-grid physics
models in the simulations, which we calculate to be less than 10 percent. We
discuss future observational measurements that could potentially be used to
mitigate the systematic uncertainties in this scaling relation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04099</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kolevatov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological bounces and Lorentzian wormholes in Galileon theories with
  an extra scalar field</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages. Journal version, minor corrections</comments><report-no>INR-TH-2016-024</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123516 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study whether it is possible to design a &quot;classical&quot; spatially flat
bouncing cosmology or a static, spherically symmetric asymptotically flat
Lorentzian wormhole in cubic Galileon theories interacting with an extra scalar
field. We show that bouncing models are always plagued with gradient
instabilities, while there are always ghosts in wormhole backgrounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04272</id><created>2016-07-13</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wongwathanarat</keyname><forenames>Annop</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimm-Strele</keyname><forenames>Hannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames></author></authors><title>APSARA: A multi-dimensional unsplit fourth-order explicit Eulerian
  hydrodynamics code for arbitrary curvilinear grids</title><categories>physics.comp-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures, 8 tables; accepted by Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 595, A41 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new fourth-order, finite-volume hydrodynamics code named Apsara.
The code employs a high-order, finite-volume method for mapped coordinates with
extensions for nonlinear hyperbolic conservation laws. Apsara can handle
arbitrary structured curvilinear meshes in three spatial dimensions. The code
has successfully passed several hydrodynamic test problems, including the
advection of a Gaussian density profile and a nonlinear vortex and the
propagation of linear acoustic waves. For these test problems, Apsara produces
fourth-order accurate results in case of smooth grid mappings. The order of
accuracy is reduced to first-order when using the nonsmooth circular grid
mapping. When applying the high-order method to simulations of low-Mach number
flows, for example, the Gresho vortex and the Taylor-Green vortex, we discover
that Apsara delivers superior results to codes based on the dimensionally
split, piecewise parabolic method (PPM) widely used in astrophysics. Hence,
Apsara is a suitable tool for simulating highly subsonic flows in astrophysics.
In the first astrophysical application, we perform implicit large eddy
simulations (ILES) of anisotropic turbulence in the context of core collapse
supernova (CCSN) and obtain results similar to those previously reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05705</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokozaki</keyname><forenames>Norimi</forenames></author></authors><title>Splitting Mass Spectra and Muon g-2 in Higgs-Anomaly Mediation</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures; discussion added; Table 1 extended</comments><report-no>TU-1030</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B762 (2016) 72-79</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.09.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scenario where only the Higgs multiplets have direct couplings
to a supersymmetry (SUSY) breaking sector. The standard model matter multiplets
as well as the gauge multiples are sequestered from the SUSY breaking sector;
therefore, their masses arise via anomaly mediation at the high energy scale
with a gravitino mass of $\sim$100 TeV. Due to renormalization group running
effects from the Higgs soft masses, the masses of the third generation
sfermions become O(10) TeV at the low energy scale, while the first and second
generation sfermion masses are O(0.1-1) TeV, avoiding the tachyonic slepton
problem and flavor changing neutral current problem. With the splitting mass
spectrum, the muon g-2 anomaly is explained consistently with the observed
Higgs boson mass of 125 GeV. Moreover, the third generation Yukawa couplings
are expected to be unified in some regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07275</id><created>2016-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Waitz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lower</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schober</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keiling</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitzer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertens</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viefhaus</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klumpp</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt-B&#xf6;cking</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>L. Ph. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyabe</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rescigno</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCurdy</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;ffler</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jahnke</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xf6;rner</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-particle interference of electron pairs on a molecular level</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.atm-clus quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 083002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.083002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the photo-doubleionization of $H_2$ molecules with 400 eV
photons. We find that the emitted electrons do not show any sign of two-center
interference fringes in their angular emission distributions if considered
separately. In contrast, the quasi-particle consisting of both electrons (i.e.
the &quot;dielectron&quot;) does. The work highlights the fact that non-local effects are
embedded everywhere in nature where many-particle processes are involved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07424</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2016-11-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gruszecki</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mailyan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorobets</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krawczyk</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Goos-Hanchen shift of a spin-wave beam transmitted through anisotropic
  interface between two ferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 014421 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.014421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main object of investigation in magnonics, spin waves (SWs) are promising
information carriers. Presently the most commonly studied are plane wave-like
SWs and SWs propagating in confined structures, such as waveguides. Here we
consider a Gaussian SW beam obliquely incident on an ultra-narrow interface
between two identical ferromagnetic materials. We use an analytical model and
micromagnetic simulations for an in-depth analysis of the influence of the
interface properties, in particular the magnetic anisotropy, on the
transmission of the SW beam. We derive analytical formulas for the reflectance,
transmittance, phase shift and Goos-Hanchen (GH) shift for beams reflected and
refracted by an interface between two semi-infinite ferromagnetic media; the
results for the refracted beam are the first to be reported to date. The GH
shifts in SW beam reflection and transmission are confirmed by micromagnetic
simulations in the thin-film geometry. We demonstrate the dependence of the
characteristic properties on the magnetic anisotropy at the interface, the
angle of incidence and the frequency of the SWs. We also propose a method for
the excitation of high-quality SW beams in micromagnetic simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08575</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cantillano</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales-Inostroza</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Real</keyname><forenames>Basti&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas-Rojas</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delgado</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szameit</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vicencio</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of dipolar transport in one-dimensional photonic lattices</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally study the transport prop- erties of dipolar and fundamental
modes on one di- mensional (1D) coupled waveguide arrays. By carefully
modulating a wide optical beam, we are able to effec- tively excite dipolar or
fundamental modes to study discrete diffraction (single-site excitation) and
gaussian beam propagation (multi-site excitation plus a phase gradient). We
observe that dipolar modes experience a larger spreading area due to an
effective larger coupling constant, which is found to be more than two times
larger than the one for fundamental modes. Addition- ally, we study the effect
of non-diagonal disorder and find that while fundamental modes are already
trapped on a weakly disorder array, dipoles are still able to prop- agate
across the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03858</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2017-01-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Melo</keyname><forenames>J. P. B. C</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsushima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>In-Medium Pion Valence Distributions in a Light-Front Model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>16 pages. 10 eps figures, typos corrected. Version to appear Physics
  Letters B</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 766 (2017) 125</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pion valence distributions in nuclear medium and vacuum are studied in a
light-front constituent quark model. The in-medium input for studying the pion
properties is calculated by the quark-meson coupling model. We find that the
in-medium pion valence distribution, as well as the in-medium pion valence wave
function, are substantially modified at normal nuclear matter density, due to
the reduction in the pion decay constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08372</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Honda</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oikawa</keyname><forenames>Akane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion decay constants at special points in type II string theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 2 figures; v2 published version</comments><report-no>WU-HEP-16-15</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the mechanism to disentangle the decay constant of closed string
axion from the string scale in the framework of type II string theory on
Calabi-Yau manifold. We find that the quantum and geometrical corrections in
the prepotential that arise at some special points in the moduli space widen
the window of axion decay constant. In particular, around the small complex
structure points, the axion decay constant becomes significantly lower than the
string scale. We also discuss the moduli stabilization leading to the
phenomenologically attractive low-scale axion decay constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08467</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Bongjae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Peitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franchini</keyname><forenames>Cesare</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties of bilayer Sr$_3$Ir$_2$O$_7$: role of epitaxial
  strain and oxygen vacancies</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024406 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using {\it ab initio} methods, we investigate the modification of the
magnetic properties of the $m=2$ member of the strontium iridates
Ruddlesden-Popper series Sr$_{m+1}$Ir$_{m}$O$_{3m+1}$, bilayer
Sr$_3$Ir$_2$O$_7$, induced by epitaxial strain and oxygen vacancies. Unlike the
single layer compound Sr$_2$IrO$_4$, which exhibits a robust in-plane magnetic
order, the energy difference between in-plane and out-of-plane magnetic
orderings in Sr$_3$Ir$_2$O$_7$ is much smaller and it is expected that small
external perturbations could induce magnetic transitions. Our results indicate
that epitaxial strain yields a spin-flop transition, that is driven by the
crossover between the intralayer $J_1$ and interlayer $J_2$ magnetic exchange
interactions upon compressive strain. While $J_1$ is essentially insensitive to
strain effects, the strength of $J_2$ changes by one order of magnitude for
tensile strains $\geq$ 3~\%. In addition, our study clarifies that the unusual
in-plane magnetic response observed in Sr$_3$Ir$_2$O$_7$ upon the application
of an external magnetic field originates from the canting of the local magnetic
moments due to oxygen vacancies, which tilt the octahedral networks - thereby
allowing for noncollinear spin configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00015</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>Nicole Yunger</forenames></author></authors><title>Jarzynski-like equality for the out-of-time-ordered correlator</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><comments>Published version. Minor typos corrected, reference added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012120 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The out-of-time-ordered correlator (OTOC) diagnoses quantum chaos and the
scrambling of quantum information via the spread of entanglement. The OTOC
encodes forward and reverse evolutions and has deep connections with the flow
of time. So do fluctuation relations such as Jarzynski's Equality, derived in
nonequilibrium statistical mechanics. I unite these two powerful, seemingly
disparate tools by deriving a Jarzynski-like equality for the OTOC. The
equality's left-hand side equals the OTOC. The right-hand side suggests a
protocol for measuring the OTOC indirectly. The protocol is
platform-nonspecific and can be performed with weak measurement or with
interference. Time evolution need not be reversed in any interference trial.
The equality opens holography, condensed matter, and quantum information to new
insights from fluctuation relations and vice versa.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00768</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qinsheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cai-Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Shaofeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xuefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Junchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Da-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast Broadband Photodetectors based on Three-dimensional Dirac
  Semimetal Cd3As2</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The efforts to pursue photo detection with extreme performance in terms of
ultrafast response time, broad detection wavelength range, and high sensitivity
have never been exhausted as driven by its wide range of optoelectronic and
photonic applications such as optical communications, interconnects, imaging
and remote sensing1. 2D Dirac semimetal graphene has shown excellent potential
toward high performance photodetector with high operation speed, broadband
response and efficient carrier multiplications benefiting from its linear
dispersion band structure with high carrier mobility and zero bandgap2-4. As
the three dimensional analogues of graphene, Dirac semimetal Cd3As2 processes
all advantages of graphene as a photosensitive material but potentially has
stronger interaction with light as bulk material and thus enhanced
responsivity5,6, which promises great potential in improving the performance of
photodetector in various aspects . In this work, we report the realization of
an ultrafast broadband photodetector based on Cd3As2. The prototype
metal-Cd3As2-metal photodetector exhibits a responsivity of 5.9 mA/W with
response time of about 6.9 ps without any special device optimization.
Broadband responses from 0.8 eV to 2.34 eV are measured with potential
detection range extendable to far infrared and terahertz. Systematical studies
indicate that the photo-thermoelectric effect plays important roles in
photocurrent generation, similar to that in graphene. Our results suggest this
emerging class of exotic quantum materials can be harnessed for photo detection
with high sensitivity and high speed (~145 GHz) in challenging
middle/far-infrared and THz range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03304</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monteiro</keyname><forenames>A. M. R. V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groenendijk</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manca</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulazimoglu</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanter</keyname><forenames>Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandersypen</keyname><forenames>L. M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caviglia</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Side gate tunable Josephson junctions at the LaAlO$_3$/SrTiO$_3$
  interface</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b03820</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novel physical phenomena arising at the interface of complex oxide
heterostructures offer exciting opportunities for the development of future
electronic devices. Using the prototypical LaAlO$_3$/SrTiO$_3$ interface as a
model system, we employ a single-step lithographic process to realize gate
tunable Josephson junctions through a combination of lateral confinement and
local side gating. The action of the side gates is found to be comparable to
that of a local back gate, constituting a robust and efficient way to control
the properties of the interface at the nanoscale. We demonstrate that the side
gates enable reliable tuning of both the normal-state resistance and the
critical (Josephson) current of the constrictions. The conductance and
Josephson current show mesoscopic fluctuations as a function of the applied
side gate voltage, and the analysis of their amplitude enables the extraction
of the phase coherence and thermal lengths. Finally, we realize a
superconducting quantum interference device in which the critical currents of
each of the constriction-type Josephson junctions can be controlled
independently via the side gates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03539</id><created>2016-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinograd</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayaffre</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xe4;mer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horvati&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reyes</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhns</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonn</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julien</keyname><forenames>M. -H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of electronic bound states in charge-ordered
  YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 017001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.017001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observing how electronic states in solids react to a local symmetry breaking
provides insight into their microscopic nature. A striking example is the
formation of bound states when quasiparticles are scattered off defects. This
is known to occur, under specific circumstances, in some metals and
superconductors but not, in general, in the charge-density-wave (CDW) state.
Here, we report the unforeseen observation of bound states when a magnetic
field quenches superconductivity and induces long-range CDW order in
YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_y$. Bound states indeed produce an inhomogeneous pattern of the
local density of states $N(E_F)$ that leads to a skewed distribution of Knight
shifts which is detected here through an asymmetric profile of $^{17}$O NMR
lines. We argue that the effect arises most likely from scattering off defects
in the CDW state, which provides a novel case of disorder-induced bound states
in a condensed-matter system and an insightful window into charge ordering in
the cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08974</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Madakavil</keyname><forenames>Abhimanyu S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Ilki</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat Engines running upon a Non-Ideal Fluid Model with Higher
  Efficiencies than upon the Ideal Gas Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in International Journal of Thermodynamics
  (IJoT)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider both Otto and Diesel heat engine cycles running upon the working
substances modeled by the van der Waals fluid as a simple non-ideal gas model.
We extensively perform the efficiency study in these model engines. Then we
find that this &quot;real&quot; engine model can go beyond its ideal-gas counterpart in
efficiency, whereas as well-known, the maximum Carnot efficiency is the same
for both ideal and non-ideal gas engines. In fact, the higher the density of
non-ideality is, the higher efficiency tends to be found, especially in the
low-temperature regime, but with more shrinkage in the range of physically
allowed compression ratio, determined by the Carnot upper bound, namely, the
Second Law of thermodynamics. Our findings imply that in addition to the engine
architectures and bath temperatures, the properties of working substances
should also be taken into consideration in the performance study of heat
engines, the theoretical model aspects of which have not sufficiently been
discussed so far. It is straightforward that our methodology may also apply for
other non-ideal fluid models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00337</id><created>2016-10-02</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreissl</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Aidan T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rempfer</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botin</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holm</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palberg</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Graaf</keyname><forenames>Joost</forenames></author></authors><title>Microfluidic Pumping by Micromolar Salt Concentrations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures, 1 table</comments><doi>10.1039/C6SM02240E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An ion-exchange-resin-based microfluidic pump is introduced that utilizes
trace amounts of ions to generate fluid flows. We show experimentally that our
pump operates in almost deionized water for periods exceeding 24h and induces
fluid flows of um/s over hundreds of um. This flow displays a far-field,
power-law decay which is characteristic of two-dimensional (2D) flow when the
system is strongly confined and of three-dimensional (3D) flow when it is not.
Using theory and numerical calculations we demonstrate that our observations
are consistent with electroosmotic pumping driven by umol/L ion concentrations
in the sample cell that serve as 'fuel' to the pump. Our study thus reveals
that trace amounts of charge carriers can produce surprisingly strong fluid
flows; an insight that should benefit the design of a new class of microfluidic
pumps that operate at very low fuel concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03049</id><created>2016-10-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Semiz</keyname><forenames>&#x130;brahim</forenames></author></authors><title>OV or TOV ?</title><categories>physics.hist-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Studies in History and Philosophy of
  Modern Physics</comments><journal-ref>Stud.Hist.Philos.Mod.Phys. 56 (2016) 13-16</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.shpsb.2016.10.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The well-known equation for hydrostatic equilibrium in a static spherically
symmetric spacetime supported by an isotropic perfect fluid is referred to as
the Oppenheimer-Volkoff (OV) equation or the Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff (TOV)
equation in various General Relativity textbooks or research papers. We
scrutinize the relevant original publications to argue that the former is the
more appropriate terminology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03410</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gartner</keyname><forenames>Luka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lerner</keyname><forenames>Edan</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear modes disentangle glassy and Goldstone modes in structural
  glasses</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures, resubmission to SciPost</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 1, 016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.1.2.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One outstanding problem in the physics of glassy solids is understanding the
statistics and properties of the low-energy excitations that stem from the
disorder that characterizes these systems' microstructure. In this work we
introduce a family of algebraic equations whose solutions represent collective
displacement directions (modes) in the multi-dimensional configuration space of
a structural glass. We explain why solutions of the algebraic equations, coined
nonlinear glassy modes, are quasi-localized low-energy excitations. We present
an iterative method to solve the algebraic equations, and use it to study the
energetic and structural properties of a selected subset of their solutions
constructed by starting from a normal mode analysis of the potential energy of
a model glass. Our key result is that the structure and energies associated
with harmonic glassy vibrational modes and their nonlinear counterparts
converge in the limit of very low frequencies. As nonlinear modes never suffer
hybridizations, our result implies that the presented theoretical framework
constitutes a robust alternative definition of `soft glassy modes' in the
thermodynamic limit, in which Goldstone modes overwhelm and destroy the
identity of low-frequency harmonic glassy modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03657</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crippa</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurand</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotekar-Patil</keyname><forenames>Dharmraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corna</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohuslavskyi</keyname><forenames>Heorhii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orlov</keyname><forenames>Alexei O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fay</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavi&#xe9;ville</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barraud</keyname><forenames>Silvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinet</keyname><forenames>Maud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanquer</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Franceschi</keyname><forenames>Silvano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jehl</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author></authors><title>Level spectrum and charge relaxation in a silicon double quantum dot
  probed by dual-gate reflectometry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04354</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on dual-gate reflectometry in a metal-oxide-semiconductor
double-gate silicon transistor operating at low temperature as a double quantum
dot device. The reflectometry setup consists of two radio-frequency resonators
respectively connected to the two gate electrodes. By simultaneously measuring
their dispersive response, we obtain the complete charge stability diagram of
the device. Charge transitions between the two quantum dots and between each
quantum dot and either the source or the drain contact are detected through
phase shifts in the reflected radio-frequency signals. At finite bias,
reflectometry allows probing charge transitions to excited quantum-dot states
thereby enabling direct access to the energy level spectra of the quantum dots.
Interestingly, we find that in the presence of charge transport across the two
dots the reflectometry signatures of interdot transitions display a dip-peak
structure containing quantitative information on the charge relaxation rates in
the double quantum dot.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04132</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ollikainen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;tt&#xf6;nen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Counter-diabatic vortex pump in spinor Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013615 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013615</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological phase imprinting is a well-established technique for
deterministic vortex creation in spinor Bose-Einstein condensates of alkali
metal atoms. It was recently shown that counter-diabatic quantum control may
accelerate vortex creation in comparison to the standard adiabatic protocol and
suppress the atom loss due to nonadiabatic transitions. Here we apply this
technique, assisted by an optical plug, for vortex pumping to theoretically
show that sequential phase imprinting up to 20 cycles generates a vortex with a
very large winding number. Our method significantly increases the fidelity of
the pump for rapid pumping compared to the case without the counter-diabatic
control, leading to the highest angular momentum per particle reported to date
for the vortex pump. Our studies are based on numerical integration of the
three-dimensional multi-component Gross-Pitaevskii equation which conveniently
yields the density profiles, phase profiles, angular momentum, and other
physically important quantities of the spin-1 system. Our results motivate the
experimental realization of the vortex pump and studies of the rich physics it
involves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05241</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kornich</keyname><forenames>Viktoriia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedder</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Thomas L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit coupling in quasi-one-dimensional Wigner crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045413 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of Rashba spin-orbit coupling (SOC) on the charge and
spin degrees of freedom of a quasi-one-dimensional (quasi-1D) Wigner crystal.
As electrons in a quasi-1D Wigner crystal can move in the transverse direction,
SOC cannot be gauged away in contrast to the pure 1D case. We show that for
weak SOC, a partial gap in the spectrum opens at certain ratios between density
of electrons and the inverse Rashba length. We present how the low-energy
branch of charge degrees of freedom deviates due to SOC from its usual linear
dependence at small wave vectors. In the case of strong SOC, we show that spin
sector of a Wigner crystal cannot be described by an isotropic
antiferromagnetic Heisenberg Hamiltonian any more, and that instead the ground
state of neighboring electrons is mostly a triplet state. We present a new spin
sector Hamiltonian and discuss the spectrum of Wigner crystal in this limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07960</id><created>2016-10-25</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barato</keyname><forenames>Andre C</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seifert</keyname><forenames>Udo</forenames></author></authors><title>Cost and Precision of Brownian Clocks</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 041053 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.041053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Brownian clocks are biomolecular networks that can count time. A paradigmatic
example are proteins that go through a cycle thus regulating some oscillatory
behaviour in a living system. Typically, such a cycle requires free energy
often provided by ATP hydrolysis. We investigate the relation between the
precision of such a clock and its thermodynamic costs. For clocks driven by a
constant thermodynamic force, a given precision requires a minimal cost that
diverges as the uncertainty of the clock vanishes. In marked contrast, we show
that a clock driven by a periodic variation of an external protocol can achieve
arbitrary precision at arbitrarily low cost. This result constitutes a
fundamental difference between processes driven by a fixed thermodynamic force
and those driven periodically. As a main technical tool, we map a periodically
driven system with a deterministic protocol to one subject to an external
protocol that changes in stochastic time intervals, which simplifies
calculations significantly. In the non-equilibrium steady state of the
resulting bipartite Markov process, the uncertainty of the clock can be deduced
from the calculable dispersion of a corresponding current.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08354</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Malmi-Kakkada</keyname><forenames>Abdul N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valls</keyname><forenames>Oriol T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Chandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dislocation Mobility and Anomalous Shear Modulus Effect in $^4$He
  Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 figures. To appear in JLTP</comments><journal-ref>J Low Temp Phys, 186, 259-274 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-016-1689-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the dislocation glide mobility in solid $^4$He within a model
that assumes the existence of a superfluid field associated with dislocation
lines. Prompted by the results of this mobility calculation, we study within
this model the role that such a superfluid field may play in the motion of the
dislocation line when a stress is applied to the crystal. To do this, we relate
the damping of dislocation motion, calculated in the presence of the assumed
superfluid field, to the shear modulus of the crystal. As the temperature
increases, we find that a sharp drop in the shear modulus will occur at the
temperature where the superfluid field disappears. We compare the drop in shear
modulus of the crystal arising from the temperature dependence of the damping
contribution due to the superfluid field, to the experimental observation of
the same phenomena in solid $^4$He and find quantitative agreement. Our results
indicate that such a superfluid field plays an important role in dislocation
pinning in a clean solid $^4$He at low temperatures and in this regime may
provide an alternative source for the unusual elastic phenomena observed in
solid $^4$He.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02498</id><created>2016-11-08</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hubig</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCulloch</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schollw&#xf6;ck</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generic Construction of Efficient Matrix Product Operators</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035129 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Matrix Product Operators (MPOs) are at the heart of the second-generation
Density Matrix Renormalisation Group (DMRG) algorithm formulated in Matrix
Product State language. We first summarise the widely known facts on MPO
arithmetic and representations of single-site operators. Second, we introduce
three compression methods (Rescaled SVD, Deparallelisation and Delinearisation)
for MPOs and show that it is possible to construct efficient representations of
arbitrary operators using MPO arithmetic and compression. As examples, we
construct powers of a short-ranged spin-chain Hamiltonian, a complicated
Hamiltonian of a two-dimensional system and, as proof of principle, the
long-range four-body Hamiltonian from quantum chemistry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04337</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Gao-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xin-Zhang</keyname></author></authors><title>Quantization of Yang-Mills Theories without the Gribov Ambiguity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B, 766, 231 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A gauge condition is presented here to quantize non-Abelian gauge theory on
the manifold $R\otimes S^{1}\otimes S^{1}\otimes S^{1}$, which is free from the
Gribov ambiguity. Perturbative calculations in the new gauge behave like the
axial gauge in ultraviolet region, while infrared behaviours of the
perturbative series are quite nontrivial. The new gauge condition, which reads
$n\cdot\partial n\cdot A=0$, may not satisfy the requirement that
$A^{\mu}(\infty)=0$ in conventional perturbative calculations. However, such
contradiction is not harmful for gauge theories constructed on the manifold
$R\otimes S^{1}\otimes S^{1}\otimes S^{1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05032</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>Ezequiel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faroughy</keyname><forenames>Darius A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamenik</keyname><forenames>Jernej F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szynkman</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Four Tops for LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>31 pages, 12 figures. v2: references added, minor typos corrected.
  Published in Nucl. Phys. B</comments><report-no>ICAS 025/16</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.11.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We design a search strategy for the Standard Model $t\bar t t \bar t$
production at the LHC in the same-sign dilepton and trilepton channels. We
study different signal features and, given the small expected number of signal
events, we scrutinize in detail all reducible and irreducible backgrounds. Our
analysis shows that by imposing a set of basic jet and lepton selection
criteria, the SM $pp \to t\bar t t \bar t$ process could be evidenced in the
near future, within Run-II, when combining both multi-lepton search channels.
We argue that this search strategy should also be used as a guideline to test
New Physics coupling predominantly to top-quarks. In particular, we show that a
non-resonant New Physics enhancement in the four-top final state would be
detectable through this search strategy. We study two {\it top-philic}
simplified models of this kind, a neutral scalar boson and a $Z^\prime$, and
present current and future exclusion limits on their mass and couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07147</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Shuguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xiangming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Huili</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Daming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pei</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Guangming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Nu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Chaosong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Le</forenames></author></authors><title>A beam monitor using silicon pixel sensors for hadron therapy</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.med-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nuclear Inst. and Methods in Physics Research, A 849C (2017) pp.
  20-24</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.12.050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the design and test results of a beam monitor developed for online
monitoring in hadron therapy. The beam monitor uses eight silicon pixel
sensors, \textit{Topmetal-${II}^-$}, as the anode array.
\textit{Topmetal-${II}^-$} is a charge sensor designed in a CMOS 0.35 $\mu$m
technology. Each \textit{Topmetal-${II}^-$} sensor has $72\times72$ pixels and
the pixel size is $83\times83$ $\mu$m$^2$. In our design, the beam passes
through the beam monitor without hitting the electrodes, making the beam
monitor especially suitable for monitoring heavy ion beams. This design also
reduces radiation damage to the beam monitor itself. The beam monitor is tested
with a carbon ion beam at the Heavy Ion Research Facility in Lanzhou (HIRFL).
Results indicate that the beam monitor can measure position, incidence angle
and intensity of the beam with a position resolution better than 20 $\mu$m,
angular resolution about 0.5$^\circ$ and intensity statistical accuracy better
than 2$\%$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08950</id><created>2016-11-27</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fierens</keyname><forenames>P. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonetti</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosz</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>A geometrical view of scalar modulation instability</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1605.01761</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel approach to the analysis of a full model of scalar
modulation instability (MI) by means of a simple geometrical description in the
power vs. frequency plane. This formulation allows to relate the shape of the
MI gain to any arbitrary dispersion profile of the medium. As a result, we
derive a straightforward explanation of the non-trivial dependence of the
cutoff power on high-order dispersion and obtain explicitly the power that
maximizes the gain. Our approach puts forth a powerful tool to synthesize a
desired MI gain with the potential application to a vast number of
parametric-amplification and supercontinuum-generation devices whose
functioning relies upon modulation instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10149</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jaffa</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitworth</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lomax</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\mathcal{Q}^{+}$: Characterising the structure of young star clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many young star clusters appear to be fractal, i.e. they appear to be
concentrated in a nested hierarchy of clusters within clusters. We present a
new algorithm for statistically analysing the distribution of stars to quantify
the level of sub-structure. We suggest that, even at the simplest level, the
internal structure of a fractal cluster requires the specification of three
parameters. (i) The 3D fractal dimension, $\mathcal{D}$, measures the extent to
which the clusters on one level of the nested hierarchy fill the volume of
their parent cluster. (ii) The number of levels, $\mathcal{L}$, reflects the
finite ratio between the linear size of the large root-cluster at the top of
the hierarchy, and the smallest leaf-clusters at the bottom of the hierarchy.
(iii) The volume-density scaling exponent, $\mathcal{C}=-\textrm{d}\ln[\delta
n]/\textrm{d}\ln[L]$ measures the factor by which the excess density, $\delta
n$, in a structure of scale $L$, exceeds that of the background formed by
larger structures; it is similar, but not exactly equivalent, to the exponent
in Larson's scaling relation between density and size for molecular clouds. We
describe an algorithm which can be used to constrain the values of $({\cal
D},{\cal L},{\cal C})$ and apply this method to artificial and observed
clusters. We show that this algorithm is able to reliably describe the three
dimensional structure of an artificial star cluster from the two dimensional
projection, and quantify the varied structures observed in real and simulated
clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00778</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Not Normal: the uncertainties of scientific measurements</title><categories>stat.AP physics.data-an</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures. Auxiliary Excel file
  (UncertaintyDataDescription.xls) lists sources of data</comments><journal-ref>Royal Society Open Science, 4, 160600 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsos.160600</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Judging the significance and reproducibility of quantitative research
requires a good understanding of relevant uncertainties, but it is often
unclear how well these have been evaluated and what they imply. Reported
scientific uncertainties were studied by analysing 41000 measurements of 3200
quantities from medicine, nuclear and particle physics, and interlaboratory
comparisons ranging from chemistry to toxicology. Outliers are common, with
5{\sigma} disagreements up to five orders of magnitude more frequent than
naively expected. Uncertainty-normalized differences between multiple
measurements of the same quantity are consistent with heavy-tailed Student-t
distributions that are often almost Cauchy, far from a Gaussian Normal bell
curve. Medical research uncertainties are generally as well evaluated as those
in physics, but physics uncertainty improves more rapidly, making feasible
simple significance criteria such as the 5{\sigma} discovery convention in
particle physics. Contributions to measurement uncertainty from mistakes and
unknown problems are not completely unpredictable. Such errors appear to have
power-law distributions consistent with how designed complex systems fail, and
how unknown systematic errors are constrained by researchers. This better
understanding may help improve analysis and meta-analysis of data, and help
scientists and the public have more realistic expectations of what scientific
results imply.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01443</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Jiajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marfatia</keyname><forenames>Danny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whisnant</keyname><forenames>Kerry</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonstandard neutrino interactions at DUNE, T2HK and T2HKK</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>38 pages, 19 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1701:071 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the matter effect caused by nonstandard neutrino interactions (NSI)
in the next generation long-baseline neutrino experiments, DUNE, T2HK and
T2HKK. If multiple NSI parameters are nonzero, the potential of these
experiments to detect CP violation, determine the mass hierarchy and constrain
NSI is severely impaired by degeneracies between the NSI parameters and by the
generalized mass hierarchy degeneracy. In particular, a cancellation between
leading order terms in the appearance channels when $\epsilon_{e\tau} =
\cot\theta_{23} \epsilon_{e\mu}$, strongly affects the sensitivities to these
two NSI parameters at T2HK and T2HKK. We also study the dependence of the
sensitivities on the true CP phase $\delta$ and the true mass hierarchy, and
find that overall DUNE has the best sensitivity to the magnitude of the NSI
parameters, while T2HKK has the best sensitivity to CP violation whether or not
there are NSI. Furthermore, for T2HKK a smaller off-axis angle for the Korean
detector is better overall. We find that due to the structure of the leading
order terms in the appearance channel probabilities, the NSI sensitivities in a
given experiment are similar for both mass hierarchies, modulo the phase change
$\delta \to \delta + 180^\circ$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03833</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03833</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lion</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panet</keyname><forenames>Isabelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerlin</keyname><forenames>Christine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bize</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delva</keyname><forenames>Pac&#xf4;me</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of a high spatial resolution geopotential model using
  atomic clock comparisons</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.comp-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Published in Journal of Geodesy (Springer)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Geodesy, pp 1-15 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00190-016-0986-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent technological advances in optical atomic clocks are opening new
perspectives for the direct determination of geopotential differences between
any two points at a centimeter-level accuracy in geoid height. However, so far
detailed quantitative estimates of the possible improvement in geoid
determination when adding such clock measurements to existing data are lacking.
We present a first step in that direction with the aim and hope of triggering
further work and efforts in this emerging field of chronometric geodesy and
geophysics. We specifically focus on evaluating the contribution of this new
kind of direct measurements in determining the geopotential at high spatial
resolution (~ 10 km). We studied two test areas, both located in France and
corresponding to a middle (Massif Central) and high (Alps) mountainous terrain.
These regions are interesting because the gravitational field strength varies
greatly from place to place at high spatial resolution due to the complex
topography. Our method consists in first generating a synthetic high resolution
geopotential map, then drawing synthetic measurement data (gravimetry and clock
data) from it, and finally reconstructing the geopotential map from that data
using least squares collocation. The quality of the reconstructed map is then
assessed by comparing it to the original one used to generate the data. We show
that adding only a few clock data points (less than 1 % of the gravimetry data)
reduces the bias significantly and improves the standard deviation by a factor
3. The effect of the data coverage and data quality on the results is
investigated, and the trade-off between the measurement noise level and the
number of data points is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04043</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takekoshi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamidani</keyname><forenames>Tetsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komugi</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohno</keyname><forenames>Kotaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tosaki</keyname><forenames>Tomoka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorai</keyname><forenames>Kazuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muller</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuno</keyname><forenames>Norikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawamura</keyname><forenames>Akiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>Toshikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Yasuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ezawa</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshima</keyname><forenames>Tai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Kimberly S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Austermann</keyname><forenames>Jason E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuo</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aretxaga</keyname><forenames>Itziar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>David H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabe</keyname><forenames>Ryohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>Grant W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yun</keyname><forenames>Min S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The 1.1 mm Continuum Survey of the Small Magellanic Cloud: Physical
  Properties and Evolution of the Dust-selected Clouds</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>26 pages, 13 figures. Appeared in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 835:55 (17pp), 2017 January 20</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/835/1/55</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first 1.1 mm continuum survey toward the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC) was
performed using the AzTEC instrument installed on the ASTE 10-m telescope. This
survey covered 4.5 deg$^2$ of the SMC with $1\sigma$ noise levels of $5-12$ mJy
beam$^{-1}$, and 44 extended objects were identified. The 1.1 mm extended
emission has good spatial correlation with $Herschel$ 160 $\mathrm{\mu m}$,
indicating that the origin of the 1.1 mm extended emission is thermal emission
from a cold dust component. We estimated physical properties using the 1.1 mm
and filtered $Herschel$ data (100, 160, 250, 350, and 500 $\mathrm{\mu m}$).
The 1.1 mm objects show dust temperatures of $17-45$ K and gas masses of
$4\times10^3-3\times10^5~M_\odot$, assuming single-temperature thermal emission
from the cold dust with an emissivity index, $\beta$, of 1.2 and a gas-to-dust
ratio of 1000. These physical properties are very similar to those of giant
molecular clouds (GMCs) in our galaxy and the Large Magellanic Cloud. The 1.1
mm objects also displayed good spatial correlation with the $Spitzer$ 24
$\mathrm{\mu m}$ and CO emission, suggesting that the 1.1 mm objects trace the
dense gas regions as sites of massive star formation. The dust temperature of
the 1.1 mm objects also demonstrated good correlation with the 24 $\mathrm{\mu
m}$ flux connected to massive star formation. This supports the hypothesis that
the heating source of the cold dust is mainly local star-formation activity in
the 1.1 mm objects. The classification of the 1.1 mm objects based on the
existence of star-formation activity reveals the differences in the dust
temperature, gas mass, and radius, which reflects the evolution sequence of
GMCs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06163</id><created>2016-12-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Bo-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yun-De</forenames></author></authors><title>Kaon-nucleon scattering to one-loop order in heavy baryon chiral
  perturbation theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 114033 (2015); erratum: Phys. Rev. D 95,019903
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.114033 10.1103/PhysRevD.95.019903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the T-matrices of kaon-nucleon ($KN$) and antikaon-nucleon
($\overline{K}N$) scattering to one-loop order in SU(3) heavy baryon chiral
perturbation theory (HB$\chi$PT). The low-energy constants (LECs) and their
combinations are then determined by fitting the phase shifts of $KN$ scattering
and the corresponding data. This leads to a good description of the phase
shifts below 200 MeV kaon laboratory momentum. We obtain the LEC uncertainties
through statistical regression analysis. We also determine the LECs through the
use of scattering lengths in order to check the consistency of the HB$\chi$PT
framework for different observables and obtain a consistent result. By using
these LECs, we predict the $\overline{K}N$ elastic scattering phase shifts and
obtain reasonable results. The scattering lengths are also predicted, which
turn out to be in good agreement with the empirical values except for the
isospin-0 $\overline{K}N$ scattering length that is strongly affected by the
$\Lambda(1405)$ resonance. As most calculations in the chiral perturbation
theory, the convergence issue is discussed in detail. Our calculations provide
a possibility to investigate the baryon-baryon interaction in HB$\chi$PT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06239</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gros</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernard</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author></authors><title>gamma-ray telescopes using conversions to electron-positron pairs: event
  generators, angular resolution and polarimetry</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Published in Astroparticle Physics (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Astroparticle Physics, Volume 88, February 2017, Pages 60-67</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2017.01.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We benchmark various available event generators in Geant4 and EGS5 in the
light of ongoing projects for high angular-resolution pair-conversion
telescopes. We compare the distributions of key kinematic variables extracted
from the geometry of the three final state particles. We validate and use as
reference an exact generator using the full 5D differential cross-section of
the conversion process. We focus in particular on the effect of the unmeasured
recoiling nucleus on the angular resolution. We show that for high resolution
trackers, the choice of the generator affects the estimated resolution of the
telescope. We also show that the current available generator are unable to
describe accurately a linearly polarised photon source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06600</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yong-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rho</keyname><forenames>Mannque</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent progress on dense nuclear matter in skyrmion approaches</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Published version. Typos are corrected</comments><journal-ref>Sci.China Phys.Mech.Astron. 60 (2017) no.3, 032001</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Skyrme model provides a novel unified approach to nuclear physics. In
this approach, single baryon, baryonic matter and medium-modified hadron
properties are treated on the same footing. Intrinsic density dependence (IDD)
reflecting the change of vacuum by compressed baryonic matter figures naturally
in the approach. In this article, we review the recent progress on accessing
dense nuclear matter by putting baryons treated as solitons, namely, skyrmions,
on crystal lattice with accents on the implications in compact stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07304</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beceanu</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlag</keyname><forenames>Wilhelm</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure formulas for wave operators</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>45 pages. A few typos have been removed</comments><msc-class>35P25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish quantitative estimates on the structure function arising in the
representation of the intertwining wave operators of a Schroedinger operator in
three dimensions. Regularity of zero energy is assumed throughout. This paper
is related to, and corrects some inaccuracies in, the first author's work
https://arxiv.org/abs/1101.0502
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00826</id><created>2016-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dutreix</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical control of electron-phonon interactions with high-frequency
  light</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work addresses the one-dimensional problem of Bloch electrons when they
are rapidly driven by a homogeneous time-periodic light and linearly coupled to
vibrational modes. Starting from a generic time-periodic electron-phonon
Hamiltonian, we derive a time-independent effective Hamiltonian that describes
the stroboscopic dynamics up to the third order in the high-frequency limit.
This yields nonequilibrium corrections to the electron-phonon coupling that are
controllable dynamically via the driving strength. This shows in particular
that local Holstein interactions in equilibrium are corrected by nonlocal
Peierls interactions out of equilibrium, as well as by phonon-assisted hopping
processes that make the dynamical Wannier-Stark localization of Bloch electrons
impossible. Subsequently, we revisit the Holstein polaron problem out of
equilibrium in terms of effective Green functions, and specify explicitly how
the binding energy and effective mass of the polaron can be controlled
dynamically. These tunable properties are reported within the weak- and
strong-coupling regimes since both can be visited within the same material when
varying the driving strength. This work provides some insight into controllable
microscopic mechanisms that may be involved during the multicycle laser
irradiations of organic molecular crystals in ultrafast pump-probe experiments,
although it should also be suitable for realizations in shaken optical lattices
of ultracold atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01442</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pezzulli</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraternali</keyname><forenames>Filippo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binney</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>The angular momentum of cosmological coronae and the inside-out growth
  of spiral galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>MNRAS, in press. 21 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive and diffuse haloes of hot gas (coronae) are important intermediaries
between cosmology and galaxy evolution, storing mass and angular momentum
acquired from the cosmic web until eventual accretion on to star-forming discs.
We introduce a method to reconstruct the rotation of a galactic corona, based
on its angular momentum distribution (AMD). This allows us to investigate in
what conditions the angular momentum acquired from tidal torques can be
transferred to star forming discs and explain observed galaxy-scale processes,
such as inside-out growth and the build-up of abundance gradients. We find that
a simple model of an isothermal corona with a temperature slightly smaller than
virial and a cosmologically motivated AMD is in good agreement with galaxy
evolution requirements, supporting hot-mode accretion as a viable driver for
the evolution of spiral galaxies in a cosmological context. We predict
moderately sub-centrifugal rotation close to the disc and slow rotation close
to the virial radius. Motivated by the observation that the Milky Way has a
relatively hot corona (T ~ 2 x 10^6 K), we also explore models with a
temperature larger than virial. To be able to drive inside-out growth, these
models must be significantly affected by feedback, either mechanical (ejection
of low angular momentum material) or thermal (heating of the central regions).
However, the agreement with galaxy evolution constraints becomes, in these
cases, only marginal, suggesting that our first and simpler model may apply to
a larger fraction of galaxy evolution history.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01640</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hamilton</keyname><forenames>K. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hart</keyname><forenames>H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pulse-shape control of two-color interference in high-order-harmonic
  generation</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on calculations of harmonic generation by neon in a mixed (800-nm +
time-delayed 400-nm) laser pulse scheme. In contrast with previous studies we
employ a short (few-cycle) 400-nm pulse, finding that this affords control of
the interference between electron trajectories contributing to the cutoff
harmonics. The inclusion of the 400-nm pulse enhances the yield and cutoff
energy, both of which exhibit a strong dependence on the time delay between the
two pulses. Using a combination of time-dependent R-matrix theory and a
classical trajectory model, we assess the mechanisms leading to these effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01792</id><created>2017-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xiucong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author></authors><title>Instantaneous GNSS attitude determination: A Monte Carlo sampling
  approach</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, Ready for publication in Acta Astronautica,2017</comments><journal-ref>Acta Astronautica, Vol. 133, pp.24-29 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actaastro.2017.01.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel instantaneous GNSS ambiguity resolution approach which makes use of
only single-frequency carrier phase measurements for ultra-short baseline
attitude determination is proposed. The Monte Carlo sampling method is employed
to obtain the probability density function of ambiguities from a
quaternion-based GNSS-attitude model and the LAMBDA method strengthened with a
screening mechanism is then utilized to fix the integer values. Experimental
results show that 100% success rate could be achieved for ultra-short
baselines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02930</id><created>2017-01-11</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luminet</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire d'Astrophysique de Marseille, Centre de Physique Th&#xe9;orique, Observatoire de Paris</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Reception of the Copernican Revolution Among Proven\c{c}al Humanists
  of the Sixteenth and Seventeenth Centuries</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>17 pages. Extended version of the article &quot;The Proven\c{c}al
  Humanists and Copernicus&quot; published in Inference vol.2 issue 4 (2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the reception of Copernican astronomy by the Proven\c{c}al
humanists of the XVIth-XVIIth centuries, beginning with Michel de Montaigne who
was the first to recognize the potential scientific and philosophical
revolution represented by heliocentrism. Then we describe how, after Kepler's
Astronomia Nova of 1609 and the first telescopic observations by Galileo, it
was in the south of France that the New Astronomy found its main promotors with
the humanists and &quot;amateurs \'eclair\'es&quot;, Nicolas-Claude Fabri de Peiresc and
Pierre Gassendi. The professional astronomer Jean-Dominique Cassini, also from
Provence, would later elevate the field to new heights in Paris.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03927</id><created>2017-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Postnikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uvarov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lokhanin</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svetovoy</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly energetic phenomena in water electrolysis</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures; Supplementary Information at
  http://www.nature.com/articles/srep39381</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 39381 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep39381</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Water electrolysis performed in microsystems with a fast change of voltage
polarity produces optically invisible nanobubbles containing H2 and O2 gases.
In this form the gases are able to the reverse reaction of water formation.
Here we report extreme phenomena observed in a millimeter-sized open system.
Under a frequency of driving pulses above 100 kHz the process is accompanied by
clicking sounds repeated every 50 ms or so. Fast video reveals that
synchronously with the click a bubble is growing between the electrodes which
reaches a size of 300 um in 50 us. Detailed dynamics of the system is monitored
by means of a vibrometer by observing a piece of silicon floating above the
electrodes. The energy of a single event is estimated as 0.3 uJ and a
significant part of this energy is transformed into mechanical work moving the
piece. The observations are explained by the combustion of hydrogen and oxygen
mixture in the initial bubble with a diameter of about 40 um. Unusual
combustion mechanism supporting spontaneous ignition at room temperature is
responsible for the process. The observed effect demonstrates a principal
possibility to build a microscopic internal combustion engine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04145</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Connelly</keyname><forenames>Erin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grammel</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraut</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serazo</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamon</keyname><forenames>Christino</forenames></author></authors><title>Universality in perfect state transfer</title><categories>quant-ph math.CO</categories><comments>16 pages. Corrected minor typos. Added citations</comments><msc-class>05C50</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A continuous-time quantum walk on a graph is a matrix-valued function
$\exp(-\mathtt{i} At)$ over the reals, where $A$ is the adjacency matrix of the
graph. Such a quantum walk has universal perfect state transfer if for all
vertices $u,v$, there is a time where the $(v,u)$ entry of the matrix
exponential has unit magnitude. We prove new characterizations of graphs with
universal perfect state transfer. This extends results of Cameron et al.
(Linear Algebra and Its Applications, 455:115-142, 2014). Also, we construct
non-circulant families of graphs with universal perfect state transfer. All
prior known constructions were circulants. Moreover, we prove that if a
circulant, whose order is prime, prime squared, or a power of two, has
universal perfect state transfer then its underlying graph must be complete.
This is nearly tight since there are universal perfect state transfer
circulants with non-prime-power order where some edges are missing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04190</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jianfa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Yingying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Cun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Runze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xintong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Zhenqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Changqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xingjiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yayu</forenames></author></authors><title>Relationship between the parent charge transfer gap and maximum
  transition temperature in cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Bulletin 61, 1826 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11434-016-1204-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the biggest puzzles concerning the cuprate high temperature
superconductors is what determines the maximum transition temperature (Tc,max),
which varies from less than 30 K to above 130 K in different compounds. Despite
this dramatic variation, a robust trend is that within each family, the
double-layer compound always has higher Tc,max than the single-layer
counterpart. Here we use scanning tunneling microscopy to investigate the
electronic structure of four cuprate parent compounds belonging to two
different families. We find that within each family, the double layer compound
has a much smaller charge transfer gap size ($\Delta_{CT}$), indicating a clear
anticorrelation between $\Delta_{CT}$ and Tc,max. These results suggest that
the charge transfer gap plays a key role in the superconducting physics of
cuprates, which shed important new light on the high Tc mechanism from doped
Mott insulator perspective.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04434</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mar&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-order corrections for the deflection of light around a massive
  object</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>24 pages, 8 figures paper to be submitted</comments><msc-class>83C10, 83C25, 83C57, 41A21</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From the Schwarzschild metric we obtain the higher-order terms (up to 20-th
order) for the deflection of light around a massive object using the
Lindstedt-Poincar\'e method to solve the equation of motion of a photon around
the stellar object. Additionally, we obtain diagonal Pad\'e approximants from
the perturbation expansion, and we show how these are a better fit for the
numerical data. Furthermore, we use these approximants in ray-tracing
algorithms to model the bending of light around the massive object.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04647</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mottram</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dishoeck</keyname><forenames>E. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kristensen</keyname><forenames>L. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jos&#xe9;-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>I. San</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herczeg</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andr</keyname><forenames>Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bontemps</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabrit</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carney</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drozdovskaya</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunham</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedele</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harsono</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xf8;rgensen</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nyves</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisini</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tafalla</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Visser</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z</keyname><forenames>U. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Outflows, infall and evolution of a sample of embedded low-mass
  protostars. The William Herschel Line Legacy (WILL) survey</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted to A&amp;A, version after language editor corrections. 47 pages,
  18 figures, 15 tables. The figures have been converted to pdf due to
  file-size considerations, which may lead to some degradation</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628682</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  [Abridged] We present spectroscopic observations in H$_{2}$O, CO and related
species with \textit{Herschel} HIFI and PACS, as well as ground-based follow-up
with the JCMT and APEX in CO, HCO$^{+}$ and isotopologues, of a sample of 49
nearby ($d&lt;$500\,pc) candidate protostars. These data are used to study the
outflow and envelope properties of these sources. We also compile their
continuum SEDs in order to constrain their physical properties. Water emission
is dominated by shocks associated with the outflow, rather than the cooler,
slower entrained outflowing gas probed by ground-based CO observations. These
shocks become less energetic as sources evolve from Class 0 to Class I. The
fraction of mass in the outflow relative to the total envelope (i.e.
$M_{\mathrm{out}}/M_{\mathrm{env}}$) remains broadly constant between Class 0
and I. The median value ($\sim$1$\%$) is consistent with a core to star
formation efficiency on the order of 50$\%$ and an outflow duty cycle on the
order of 5$\%$. Entrainment efficiency, as probed by
$F_{\mathrm{CO}}/\dot{M}_{\mathrm{acc}}$, is also invariant with source
properties and evolutionary stage. The median value (6.3\kms{}) suggests an
entrainment efficiency of between 30 and 60$\%$ if the wind is launched at
$\sim$1AU. $L$[O\,{\sc i}] is strongly correlated with $L_{\mathrm{bol}}$ but
not with $M_{\mathrm{env}}$, while low-$J$ CO is more closely correlated with
the latter than the former. This suggests that [O\,{\sc i}] traces the
present-day accretion activity while CO traces time-averaged accretion over the
dynamical timescale of the outflow. $L$[O\,{\sc i}] does not vary from Class 0
to Class I, unlike CO and H$_{2}$O. This is likely due to the ratio of atomic
to molecular gas in the wind increasing as the source evolves, balancing out
the decrease in mass accretion rate. Infall signatures are detected in
HCO$^{+}$ and H$_{2}$O in a few sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04696</id><created>2017-01-14</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Gao-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>The Continuity of the Gauge Fixing Condition $n\cdot\partial n\cdot A=0$
  for $SU(2)$ Gauge Theory</title><categories>physics.gen-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The continuity of the gauge fixing condition $n\cdot\partial n\cdot A=0$ for
$SU(2)$ gauge theory on the manifold $R\bigotimes S^{1}\bigotimes
S^{1}\bigotimes S^{1}$ is studied here, where $n^{\mu}$ stands for directional
vector along $x_{i}$-axis($i=1,2,3$). It is proved that the gauge fixing
condition is continuous given that gauge potentials are differentiable with
continuous derivatives on the manifold $R\bigotimes S^{1}\bigotimes
S^{1}\bigotimes S^{1}$ which is compact.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04983</id><created>2017-01-18</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Hua-Ding</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Dian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>An-Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Da-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological transport in Dirac electronic systems: A concise review</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B 26, 037301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/26/3/037301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Various novel physical properties have emerged in Dirac electronic systems,
especially the topological characters protected by symmetry. Current studies on
these systems have been greatly promoted by the intuitive concepts of Berry
phase and Berry curvature, which provide precise definitions of the topological
orders. In this topical review, transport properties of topological insulator
(Bi2Se3), topological Dirac semimetal (Cd3As2) and topological
insulator-graphene heterojunction are presented and discussed. Perspectives
about transport properties of two-dimensional topological nontrivial systems,
including topological edge transport, topological valley transport and
topological Weyl semimetals, are provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05183</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Montgomery</keyname><forenames>Hugh E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Jefferson Lab 12 GeV Program</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, &quot;The 26th International Nuclear Physics
  Conference&quot; (INPC2016)held in Adelaide, Australia, September 11-16, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Jefferson Lab facilities have undergone a substantial upgrade, both of
accelerator, CEBAF, and of the experimental installations. We will discuss the
progress to completion of these facilities, the status of accelerator
commissioning, and the recent first operations for physics. We will then flesh
out the anticipated exciting physics program of the next several years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05186</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Meisel</keyname><forenames>Zach</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moran</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilardy</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seymour</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couder</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Acceptance of the St. George Recoil Separator</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>Accepted to Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research A</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.01.035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Radiative alpha-capture, ($\alpha,\gamma$), reactions play a critical role in
nucleosynthesis and nuclear energy generation in a variety of astrophysical
environments. The St. George recoil separator at the University of Notre Dame's
Nuclear Science Laboratory was developed to measure ($\alpha,\gamma$) reactions
in inverse kinematics via recoil detection in order to obtain nuclear reaction
cross sections at the low energies of astrophysical interest, while avoiding
the $\gamma$-background that plagues traditional measurement techniques. Due to
the $\gamma$-ray produced by the nuclear reaction at the target location,
recoil nuclei are produced with a variety of energies and angles, all of which
must be accepted by St. George in order to accurately determine the reaction
cross section. We demonstrate the energy acceptance of the St. George recoil
separator using primary beams of helium, hydrogen, neon, and oxygen, spanning
the magnetic and electric rigidity phase space populated by recoils of
anticipated ($\alpha,\gamma$) reaction measurements. We found the performance
of St. George meets the design specifications, demonstrating its suitability
for ($\alpha,\gamma$) reaction measurements of astrophysical interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05213</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Christina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doan</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klemka</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forrey</keyname><forenames>Robert C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>B. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stancil</keyname><forenames>Phillip C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakrishnan</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inelastic cross sections and rate coefficients for collisions between CO
  and H2</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A five-dimensional coupled states (5D-CS) approximation is used to compute
cross sections and rate coefficients for CO+H2 collisions. The 5D-CS
calculations are benchmarked against accurate six-dimensional close-coupling
(6D-CC) calculations for transitions between low-lying rovibrational states.
Good agreement between the two formulations is found for collision energies
greater than 10 cm-1. The 5D-CS approximation is then used to compute two
separate databases which include highly excited states of CO that are beyond
the practical limitations of the 6D-CC method. The first database assumes an
internally frozen H2 molecule and allows rovibrational transitions for v &lt; 5
and j &lt; 30, where v and j are the vibrational and rotational quantum numbers of
the initial state of the CO molecule. The second database allows H2 rotational
transitions for initial CO states with v &lt; 5 and j &lt; 10. The two databases are
in good agreement with each other for transitions that are common to both basis
sets. Together they provide data for astrophysical models which were previously
unavailable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05220</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>St&#xe1;rek</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mi&#x10d;uda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straka</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Je&#x17e;ek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filip</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiur&#xe1;&#x161;ek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Control and enhancement of interferometric coupling between two photonic
  qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures, REVTeX4</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042321 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042321</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate and experimentally demonstrate a procedure for
conditional control and enhancement of an interferometric coupling between two
qubits encoded into states of bosonic particles. Our procedure combines local
coupling of one of the particles to an auxiliary mode and single-qubit quantum
filtering. We experimentally verify the proposed procedure using a linear
optical setup where qubits are encoded into quantum states of single photons
and coupled at a beam splitter with a fixed transmittance. With our protocol,
we implement a range of different effective transmittances, demonstrate both
enhancement and reduction of the coupling strength, and observe dependence of
two-photon bunching on the effective transmittance. To make our analysis
complete, we also theoretically investigate a more general scheme where each
particle is coupled to a separate auxiliary mode and show that this latter
scheme enables to achieve higher implementation probability. We show that our
approach can be extended also to other kinds of qubit-qubit interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05235</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tikhomirov</keyname><forenames>Victor V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative theory of channeling particle diffusion in transverse
  energy in the presence of nuclear scarrering and direct evaluation of
  dechanneling length</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A refined equation for channe;ing particle diffusion in transverse energy
taking into consideration large-angle scattering by nuclei is suggested. This
equation is reduced to the Sturm-Liouville problem allowing one to reveal both
the origin and the limitations of the dechanneling length notion. The values of
the latter is evaluated for both positively and negatively charged particles of
various energies. It is also demonstrated that the dechanneling length notion
is inapplicable for the nuclear dechanneling process of positively charged
particles, while the effective electron dechanneling length of the latter vary
more than twice converging to a constant assymptotic value at the depth
exceeding the latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05236</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ben-Av</keyname><forenames>Radel</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Chinese Magic Box</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work introduces a new concept of Chinese-Magic-Box. The general idea is
to have a box such that the sender can store information in multiple drawers.
The receiver is free to open any drawer. However, once the receiver opens the
drawer, he can retrieve the information from that drawer only, that is, the
information that was stored in the other drawers is lost. This property is
achieved by storing the information using a set of non-orthogonal quantum
states. The different drawers are realized by different orthogonal set of basis
for the measurement. Once the measurement is performed, the information in this
basis is retrieved. At the same time, due to wave function collapse the
information in the other basis is lost and cannot be retrieved. I show how to
construct a set of states for a single qubit to implement a Box with two or
three drawers. Some applications are discussed. Among them is a new
non-symmetric Quantum Key Distribution with only single direction classical
communication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05239</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Borodin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetric elliptic functions, IRF models, and dynamic exclusion
  processes</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce stochastic Interaction-Round-a-Face (IRF) models that are
related to representations of the elliptic quantum group $E_{\tau,\eta}(sl_2)$.
For stochasic IRF models in a quadrant, we evaluate averages for a broad family
of observables that can be viewed as higher analogs of $q$-moments of the
height function for the stochastic (higher spin) six vertex models.
  In a certain limit, the stochastic IRF models degenerate to (1+1)d
interacting particle systems that we call dynamic ASEP and SSEP; their jump
rates depend on local values of the height function. For the step initial
condition, we evaluate averages of observables for them as well, and use those
to investigate one-point asymptotics of the dynamic SSEP.
  The construction and proofs are based on remarkable properties (branching and
Pieri rules, Cauchy identities) of a (seemingly new) family of symmetric
elliptic functions that arise as matrix elements in an infinite volume limit of
the algebraic Bethe ansatz for $E_{\tau,\eta}(sl_2)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05240</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Burenin</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Revnivtsev</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkachenko</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorobyev</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semena</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meshcheryakov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodonov</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eselevitch</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlinsky</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sample of Cataclysmic Variables from 400d X-ray Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>published in Astronomy Letters (Pis'ma v Astronomicheskij Zhurnal)</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, Volume 42, Issue 4, pp.240-250, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773716040022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a sample of cataclysmic variables (CVs) identified among the X-ray
sources from the 400 square degree X-ray survey based on ROSAT pointing data
(400d). The procedure of the CV selection among the X-ray sources using
additional optical and infrared data from Sloan Digital Sky Survey and WISE
survey is described. The results of the optical observations of the selected
objects carried out mainly with the Russian-Turkish 1.5-m telescope (RTT-150)
and the 6-m telescope of the Special Astrophysical Observatory of the Russian
Academy of Sciences (BTA) are presented. Some observations have also been
performed with the Sayan Observatory 1.6-m AZT-33IK telescope. Currently we
selected eight CVs, four of which were found for the first time in our work.
Based on this sample, we have obtained preliminary constraints on the CV X-ray
luminosity function in the solar neighborhood in the low luminosity range, L_X
~ 10^29-10^30 erg s^-1 (0.5-2 keV). We show that the logarithmic slope of the
CV X-ray luminosity function in this luminosity range is less steep than at L_X
&gt; 10^31 erg s^-1. From our CV X-ray luminosity function estimates it follows
that few thousand CVs will be detected in theSpectrum-Roentgen-Gamma (SRG)
observatory all-sky X-ray survey at high Galactic latitudes, which will allow
to obtain much more accurate measurements of CV X-ray luminosity function in
the luminosity range L_X &lt; 10^30-10^31 erg s^-1.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05244</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Prvanovic</keyname><forenames>Slobodan</forenames></author></authors><title>Operator of Time and Generalized Schroedinger Equation</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the framework of self-adjoint operator of time in non-relativistic
quantum mechanics the equation describing change of the state of quantum system
with respect to energy is introduced. The operator of time appears to be the
generator of the change of energy while the operator of energy, that is
conjugate to the operator of time, generates time evolution in this proposal.
Two examples, one with discrete time and the other with continuous one, are
given and the generalization of Schroedinger equation is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05245</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>R. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The emission-line regions in the nucleus of NGC 1313 probed with
  GMOS-IFU: a supergiant/hypergiant candidate and a kinematically cold nucleus</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures, 1 table, published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 466, 749 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3194</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NGC 1313 is a bulgeless nearby galaxy, classified as SB(s)d. Its proximity
allows high spatial resolution observations. We performed the first detailed
analysis of the emission-line properties in the nuclear region of NGC 1313,
using an optical data cube obtained with the Gemini Multi-object Spectrograph.
We detected four main emitting areas, three of them (regions 1, 2 and 3) having
spectra typical of H II regions. Region 1 is located very close to the stellar
nucleus and shows broad spectral features characteristic of Wolf-Rayet stars.
Our analysis revealed the presence of one or two WC4-5 stars in this region,
which is compatible with results obtained by previous studies. Region 4 shows
spectral features (as a strong H$\alpha$ emission line, with a broad component)
typical of a massive emission-line star, such as a luminous blue variable, a
B[e] supergiant or a B hypergiant. The radial velocity map of the ionized gas
shows a pattern consistent with rotation. A significant drop in the values of
the gas velocity dispersion was detected very close to region 1, which suggests
that the young stars there were formed from this cold gas, possibly keeping low
values of velocity dispersion. Therefore, although detailed measurements of the
stellar kinematics were not possible (due to the weak stellar absorption
spectrum of this galaxy), we predict that NGC 1313 may also show a drop in the
values of the stellar velocity dispersion in its nuclear region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05256</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Kamburov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldwin</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shayegan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay between Quantum Well Width and Interface Roughness for
  Electron Transport Mobility in GaAs Quantum Wells</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters, Volume 109, Issue 23 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4971824</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report transport mobility measurements for clean, two-dimensional (2D)
electron systems confined to GaAs quantum wells (QWs), grown via molecular beam
epitaxy, in two families of structures, a standard, symmetrically-doped GaAs
set of QWs with Al$_{0.32}$Ga$_{0.68}$As barriers, and one with additional AlAs
cladding surrounding the QWs. Our results indicate that the mobility in narrow
QWs with no cladding is consistent with existing theoretical calculations where
interface roughness effects are softened by the penetration of the electron
wave function into the adjacent low barriers. In contrast, data from AlAs-clad
wells show a number of samples where the 2D electron mobility is severely
limited by interface roughness. These measurements across three orders of
magnitude in mobility provide a road map of reachable mobilities in the growth
of GaAs structures of different electron densities, well widths, and barrier
heights.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05266</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Averin</keyname><forenames>Dmitri V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pekola</keyname><forenames>Jukka P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reversing the Landauer's erasure: single-electron Maxwell's demon
  operating at the limit of thermodynamic efficiency</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><doi>10.1002/pssb.201600677</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to Landauer's principle, erasure of information is the only part of
a computation process that unavoidably involves energy dissipation. If done
reversibly, such an erasure generates the minimal heat of $k_BT\ln 2$ per
erased bit of information. The goal of this work is to discuss the actual
reversal of the optimal erasure which can serve as the basis for the Maxwell's
demon operating with ultimate thermodynamic efficiency as dictated by the
second law of thermodynamics. The demon extracts $k_BT\ln 2$ of heat from an
equilibrium reservoir at temperature $T$ per one bit of information obtained
about the measured system used by the demon. We have analyzed this Maxwell's
demon in the situation when it uses a general quantum system with a discrete
spectrum of energy levels as its working body. In the case of the effectively
two-level system, which has been realized experimentally based on tunneling of
individual electron in a single-electron box [J.V. Koski et al., PNAS 111,
13786 (2014)], we also studied and minimized corrections to the ideal
reversible operation of the demon. These corrections include, in particular,
the non-adiabatic terms which are described by a version of the classical
fluctuation-dissipation theorem. The overall reversibility of the Maxwell's
demon requires, beside the reversibility of the intrinsic working body
dynamics, the reversibility of the measurement and feedback processes. The
single-electron demon can, in principle, be made fully reversible by developing
a thermodynamically reversible single-electron charge detector for measurements
of the individual charge states of the single-electron box.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05271</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Shulabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smy</keyname><forenames>Tom. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>Scott A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet-Mode Solutions of Space-Time Modulated Huygens' Metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A rigorous Floquet mode analysis is proposed for a zero thickness space-time
modulated Huygens' metasurface to model and determine the strengths of the new
harmonic components of the scattered fields. The proposed method is based on
Generalized Sheet Transition Conditions (GSTCs) treating a metasurface as a
spatial discontinuity. The metasurface is described in terms of Lorentzian
electric and magnetic surface susceptibilities, $\chi_\text{ee}$ and
$\chi_\text{mm}$, respectively, and its resonant frequencies are periodically
modulated in both space and time. The unknown scattered fields are then
expressed in terms of Floquet modes, which when used with the GSTCs, lead to a
system of field matrix equations. The resulting set of linear equations are
then solved numerically to determine the total scattered fields. Using a
finite-difference time domain (FDTD) solver, the proposed method is validated
and confirmed for several examples of modulation depths ($\Delta_p$) and
frequencies ($\omega_p$). Finally, the computed steady-state scattered fields
are Fourier propagated analytically, for visualization of refracted harmonics.
The proposed method is simple and versatile and able to determine the
steady-state response of a space-time modulated Huygen's metasurface, for
arbitrary modulation frequencies and depths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05301</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jingzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiaofei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hongyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuliang</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic interior transmission eigenvalue problem for
  inhomogeneous media containing obstacles and its applications to near
  cloaking</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>25 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is concerned with the invisibility cloaking in electromagnetic
wave scattering from a new perspective. We are especially interested in
achieving the invisibility cloaking by completely regular and isotropic
mediums. Our study is based on an interior transmission eigenvalue problem. We
propose a cloaking scheme that takes a three-layer structure including a
cloaked region, a lossy layer and a cloaking shell. The target medium in the
cloaked region can be arbitrary but regular, whereas the mediums in the lossy
layer and the cloaking shell are both regular and isotropic. We establish that
there exists an infinite set of incident waves such that the cloaking device is
nearly-invisible under the corresponding wave interrogation. The set of waves
is generated from the Maxwell-Herglotz approximation of the associated interior
transmission eigenfunctions. We provide the mathematical design of the cloaking
device and sharply quantify the cloaking performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05317</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Xubo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guangcan</forenames></author></authors><title>Artificial topological models based on a one-dimensional spin-dependent
  optical lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013616 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013616</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological matter is a popular topic in both condensed matter and cold atom
research. In the past decades, a variety of models have been identified with
fascinating topological features. Some, but not all, of the models can be found
in materials. As a fully controllable system, cold atoms trapped in optical
lattices provide an ideal platform to simulate and realize these topological
models. Here we present a proposal for synthesizing topological models in cold
atoms based on a one-dimensional (1D) spin-dependent optical lattice potential.
In our system, features such as staggered tunneling, staggered Zeeman field,
nearest-neighbor interaction, beyond-near-neighbor tunneling, etc. can be
readily realized. They underlie the emergence of various topological phases.
Our proposal can be realized with current technology and hence has potential
applications in quantum simulation of topological matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05326</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smidman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuei</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hanoh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>H. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antiferromagnetism with divalent Eu in EuNi$_5$As$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024416 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have successfully synthesized single crystals of EuNi$_5$As$_3$ using a
flux method and we present a comprehensive study of the physical properties
using magnetic susceptibility, specific heat, electrical resistivity,
thermoelectric power and x-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) measurements.
EuNi$_5$As$_3$ undergoes two close antiferromagnetic transitions at respective
temperatures of $T_{N1}$ = 7.2 K and $T_{N2}$ = 6.4 K, which are associated
with the Eu$^{2+}$ moments. Both transitions are suppressed upon applying a
field and we map the temperature-field phase diagrams for fields applied
parallel and perpendicular to the easy $a$ axis. XAS measurements reveal that
the Eu is strongly divalent, with very little temperature dependence,
indicating the localized Eu$^{2+}$ nature of EuNi$_5$As$_3$, with a lack of
evidence for heavy fermion behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05336</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renzler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kranabetter</keyname><forenames>Lorenz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schw&#xe4;rzler</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parajuli</keyname><forenames>Rajendra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Echt</keyname><forenames>Olof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheier</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>On enhanced hydrogen adsorption on alkali (Cesium) doped $C_{60}$ and
  effects of the quantum nature of the H2 molecule on physisorption energies</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><doi>10.1016/j.ijhydene.2017.01.069</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrogen storage by physisorption in carbon based materials is hindered by
low adsorption energies. In the last decade doping of carbon materials with
alkali, earth alkali or other metal atoms was proposed as a means to enhance
adsorption energies, and some experiments have shown promising results. We
investigate the upper bounds of hydrogen storage capacities of $C_{60}Cs$
clusters grown in ultracold helium nanodroplets by analyzing anomalies in the
ion abundance that indicate shell closure of hydrogen adsorption shells. On
bare $C_{60}^{+}$, a commensurate phase with 32 $H_2$ molecules was identified
in previous experiments. Doping $C_{60}$ with a single cesium atom leads to an
increase in relative ion abundance for the first 10 $H_2$ molecules, and the
closure of the commensurate phase is shifted from 32 to 42 $H_2$ molecules.
Density functional theory calculations indicate that thirteen energetically
enhanced adsorption sites exist, where six of them fill the groove between Cs
and $C_{60}$ and 7 are located at the cesium atom. We emphasize the large
effect of the quantum nature of the hydrogen molecule on the adsorption
energies, i.e. the adsorption energies are decreased by around 50% for
$(H_2)C_{60}Cs$ and up to 80% for $(H_2)C_{60}$ by harmonic zero-point
corrections, which represent an upper bound to corrections for dissociation
energies ($D_e$ to $D_0$) by the vibrational ground states. Five normal modes
of libration and vibration of $H_2$ physisorbed on the substrate contribute
primarily to this large decrease in adsorption energies. A similar effect can
be found for H2 physisorbed on benzene and is expected to be found for any
other weakly $H_2$-binding substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05342</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Salman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramzan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>M. Khalid</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoherence effects on multiplayer cooperative quantum games</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Commun. in Theor. Phys. 56 228 (2011)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the behavior of cooperative multiplayer quantum games [35,36] in the
presence of decoherence using different quantum channels such as amplitude
damping, depolarizing and phase damping. It is seen that the outcomes of the
games for the two damping channels with maximum values of decoherence reduce to
same value. However, in comparison to phase damping channel, the payoffs of
cooperators are strongly damped under the influence\ amplitude damping channel
for\ the lower values of decoherence parameter. In the case of depolarizing
channel, the game is a no-payoff game irrespective of the degree of
entanglement in the initial state for the larger values of decoherence
parameter. The decoherence gets the cooperators worse off.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05348</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Vita</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>On the invariant quantities in an entropy balance and their impact on
  the stability of some physical systems</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>The paper includes 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a wide class of physical systems, diffeomorphisms in the state space leave
the amount of entropy produced per unit time inside the bulk of the system
unaffected [M. Polettini et al., 12th Joint European Thermodynamics Conference,
Brescia, Italy, July 1-5, 2013]. This invariance implies that if relaxation
towards some final ('relaxed') state occurs, then the necessary condition for
the stability of the relaxed state against slowly evolving perturbations is the
same for all the systems of this class, regardless of both detailed dynamics of
the system, amplitude of fluctuations around mean values and possible
occurrence of periodic oscillations in the relaxed state. Our discussion
invokes no Onsager symmetry, no detailed model of heat transport and
production, and no approximation of local thermodynamic equilibrium. This
necessary condition of stability is the constrained minimization of time- and
path-ensemble-averaged amount of entropy produced per unit time inside the bulk
of the system; for each system, constraints are provided by the equations of
motion. (Thermodynamic equilibrium corresponds to identically vanishing amount
of entropy produced in the bulk, and satisfies trivially this condition). Our
class of physical systems includes both macroscopic and mesoscopic systems: the
problems of stability of these systems are dual to each other. As particular
cases, we retrieve some necessary criteria for stability of relaxed states
available in the literature concerning current filaments and plasmoids in a
Dense Plasma Focus, flashing ratchets, Brownian motors and dynamo-affected,
convection-ruled shells of Sun-like rotating stars - in the latter case, for
example, we retrieve the scaling of the average magnetic field to the
reciprocal of Rossby number. Finally, we argue that the validity of the popular
&quot;maximum entropy production principle&quot; is questionable in these systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05351</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Polnikov</keyname><forenames>Vladislav</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanisms of the equilibrium-range formation in the wind-wave spectrum.
  Numerical simulation</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 fugures, 1 table, 32 references</comments><msc-class>76F55</msc-class><acm-class>G.1.0</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The issue of the equilibrium-range formation in the wind-wave spectrum is
studied by a direct numerical simulation. The evolution equation of wind-wave
spectrum is numerically solved with using an exact calculation of the
Hasselmann kinetic integral and involving various modifications of known
parametrizations for the wave-pumping mechanism due to wind and the
wave-dissipation mechanism due viscosity of the upper layer. It is shown that
the balance of the last two mechanisms is responsible for a formation of
stationary part of the wind-wave spectrum. This balance allows establishing any
prescribed form of the equilibrium part of the spectrum, if the proper
representations of input and dissipation mechanisms are chosen.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05353</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Serita</keyname><forenames>Noboru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakai</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyata</keyname><forenames>Yasumitsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maniwa</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Intertube effects on one-dimensional correlated state of metallic
  single-wall carbon nanotubes probed by 13C NMR</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035128 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035128</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic states in isolated single-wall carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs) have
been considered as an ideal realization of a Tomonaga-Luttinger liquid (TLL).
However, it remains unclear whether one-dimensional correlated states are
realized under local environmental effects such as the formation of a bundle
structure. Intertube effects originating from other adjacent SWCNTs within a
bundle may drastically alter the one-dimensional correlated state. In order to
test the validity of the TLL model in bundled SWCNTs, low-energy spin
excitation is investigated by nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR). The NMR
relaxation rate in bundled mixtures of metallic and semiconducting SWCNTs shows
a power-law temperature dependence with a theoretically predicted exponent.
This demonstrates that a TLL state with the same strength as that for effective
Coulomb interactions is realized in a bundled sample, as in isolated SWCNTs. In
bundled metallic SWCNTs, we found a power-law temperature dependence of the
relaxation rate, but the magnitude of the relaxation rate is one order of
magnitude smaller than that predicted by theory. Furthermore, we found an
almost doubled magnitude of the Luttinger parameter. These results indicate
suppressed spin excitations with reduced Coulomb interactions in bundled
metallic SWCNTs, which are attributable to intertube interactions originating
from adjacent metallic SWCNTs within a bundle. Our findings give direct
evidence that bundling reduces the effective Coulomb interactions via intertube
interactions within bundled metallic SWCNTs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05354</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hettrich</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kempf</keyname><forenames>Yann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perakis</keyname><forenames>Nikolaos</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;rski</keyname><forenames>J&#x229;drzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edl</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urb&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>Jaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xf3;sa</keyname><forenames>Melinda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gini</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Owen W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schemmer</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steenari</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jold&#x17e;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Nina</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd8;degaard</keyname><forenames>Linn-Kristine Glesnes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarria</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volwerk</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Praks</keyname><forenames>Jaan</forenames></author></authors><title>Atmospheric Drag, Occultation 'N' Ionospheric Scintillation (ADONIS)
  mission proposal</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><proxy>Kavitha {\O}stgaard</proxy><doi>10.1051/swsc/2015004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Atmospheric Drag, Occultation 'N' Ionospheric Scintillation mission
(ADONIS) studies the dynamics of the terrestrial thermosphere and ionosphere in
dependency of solar events over a full solar cycle in Low Earth Orbit (LEO).
The objectives are to investigate satellite drag with in-situ measurements and
the ionospheric electron density profiles with radio occultation and
scintillation measurements. A constellation of two satellites provides the
possibility to gain near real-time data (NRT) about ionospheric conditions over
the Arctic region where current coverage is insufficient. The mission shall
also provide global high-resolution data to improve assimilative ionospheric
models. The low-cost constellation can be launched using a single Vega rocket
and most of the instruments are already space-proven allowing for rapid
development and good reliability. From July 16 to 25, 2013, the Alpbach Summer
School 2013 was organised by the Austrian Research Promotion Agency (FFG), the
European Space Agency (ESA), the International Space Science Institute (ISSI)
and the association of Austrian space industries Austrospace in Alpbach,
Austria. During the workshop, four teams of 15 students each independently
developed four different space mission proposals on the topic of &quot;Space
Weather: Science, Missions and Systems&quot;, supported by a team of tutors. The
present work is based on the mission proposal that resulted from one of these
teams' efforts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05356</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Antinucci</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting fermions on the half-line: boundary counterterms and
  boundary corrections</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>Ph.D. Thesis, Supervisor: Alessandro Giuliani, 162 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent years witnessed an extensive development of the theory of the critical
point in two-dimensional statistical systems, which allowed to prove {\it
existence} and {\it conformal invariance} of the {\it scaling limit} for
two-dimensional Ising model and dimers in planar graphs. Unfortunately, we are
still far from a full understanding of the subject: so far, exact solutions at
the lattice level, in particular determinant structure and exact discrete
holomorphicity, play a cucial role in the rigorous control of the scaling
limit. The few results about not-integrable (interacting) systems at
criticality are still unable to deal with {\it finite domains} and {\it
boundary corrections}, which are of course crucial for getting informations
about conformal covariance. In this thesis, we address the question of adapting
constructive Renormalization Group methods to non-integrable critical systems
in $d= 1+1$ dimensions. We study a system of interacting spinless fermions on a
one-dimensional semi-infinite lattice, which can be considered as a prototype
of the Luttinger universality class with Dirichlet Boundary Conditions. We
develop a convergent renormalized expression for the thermodynamic observables
in the presence of a quadratic {\it boundary defect} counterterm, polynomially
localized at the boundary. In particular, we get explicit bounds on the
boundary corrections to the specific ground state energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05357</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Altuzarra</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vezzoli</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valente</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Weibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soci</keyname><forenames>Cesare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faccio</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couteau</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlocal control of dissipation with entangled photons</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum nonlocality, i.e. the presence of strong correlations in spatially
seperated systems which are forbidden by local realism, lies at the heart of
quantum communications and quantum computing. Here, we use
polarization-entangled photon pairs to demonstrate a nonlocal control of
absorption of light in a plasmonic structure. Through the detection of one
photon with a polarization-sensitive device, we can almost deterministically
prevent or allow absorption of a second, remotely located photon. We
demonstrate this with pairs of photons, one of which is absorbed by coupling
into a plasmon of a thin metamaterial absorber in the path of a standing wave
of an interferometer. Thus, energy dissipation of specific polarization states
on a heat-sink is remotely controlled, promising opportunities for
probabilistic quantum gating and controlling plasmon-photon conversion and
entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05359</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Haaland</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lybekk</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maes</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laundal</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tenfjord</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohma</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd8;stgaard</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reistad</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snekvik</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>North-south asymmetries in cold plasma density in the magnetotail lobes:
  Cluster observations</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><proxy>Kavitha &#xc3;&#x83;&#xc2;&#x98;stgaard</proxy><doi>10.1002/2016JA023404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present observations of cold (0-70 eV) plasma density in
the magnetotail lobes. The observations and results are based on 16 years of
Cluster observation of spacecraft potential measurements converted into local
plasma densities. Measurements from all four Cluster spacecraft have been used,
and the survey indicates a persistent asymmetry in lobe density, with
consistently higher cold plasma densities in the northern lobe. External
influences, such as daily and seasonal variations in the Earth's tilt angle,
can introduce temporary north-south asymmetries through asymmetric ionization
of the two hemispheres. Likewise, external drivers, such as the orientation of
the interplanetary magnetic field can set up additional spatial asymmetries in
outflow and lobe filling. The persistent asymmetry reported in this paper is
also influenced by these external factors but is mainly caused by differences
in magnetic field configuration in the Northern and Southern Hemisphere
ionospheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05362</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Salman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jan</keyname><forenames>Munsif</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of dipole-dipole interaction on tripartite entanglement in
  different cavities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures, 15 pages</comments><journal-ref>Int J Theor Phys 55 1515 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-015-2789-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of dipole-dipole interaction, the initial relative phase and the
coupling strength with the cavity on the dynamics of three two level atoms in
the good and the bad cavity regime are investigated. It is found that the
presence of strong dipole-dipole interaction not only ensures avoiding
entanglement sudden death but also retains entanglement for long time. The
choice of the phase in the initial state is crucial to the operational regime
of the cavity. Under specific conditions, the entanglement can be frozen in
time to its initial values through strong dipole-dipole interaction. This trait
of tripartite entanglement may prove helpful in engineering multiparticle
entanglement for the practical realization of quantum technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05364</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ovsyannikov</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Constantinian</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demidov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kislinskii</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shadrin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrzhik</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-filtering in superconducting junction with the manganite interlayer</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the electronic transport and the impact of spin-filtering in
mesa-structures made of epitaxial thin films of cuprate superconductor
YBa2Cu3Ox(YBCO) and the manganite LaMnO3 (LMO) interlayer with the Au/Nb
counterelectrode. Ferromagnetic resonance measurements of heterostructure
Au/LMO/YBCO shows ferromagnetic state at temperatures below 150 K as in the
case of reference LMO film grown on the neodymium gallate substrate. The
heights of the tunneling barrier evaluated from resistive characteristics of
mesa-structures at different thickness of interlayer showed an exponential
decrease from 30 mV down to 5 mV with the increase of manganite interlayer
thickness. Temperature dependence of the conductivity of mesa-structures could
be described taking into account the d-wave superconductivity in YBCO and a
spin filtering of the electron transport. Spin filtering is supported also by
measurements of magneto-resistance and the high sensitivity of mesa-structure
conductivity to weak magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05368</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>J&#xe4;ckle</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liebhaber</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gersmann</keyname><forenames>Clemens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mews</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xe4;ger</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christiansen</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lips</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Potential of PEDOT:PSS as a hole selective front contact for silicon
  heterojunction solar cells</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the highly conductive polymer
poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene)-poly(styrenesulfonate) (PEDOT:PSS) can
successfully be applied as a hole selective front contact in silicon
heterojunction (SHJ) solar cells. In combination with a superior electron
selective heterojunction back contact based on amorphous silicon (a-Si),
mono-crystalline n-type silicon (c-Si) solar cells reach power conversion
efficiencies up to 14.8% and high open-circuit voltages exceeding 660 mV. Since
in the PEDOT:PSS/c-Si/a-Si solar cell the inferior hybrid junction is
determining the electrical device performance we are capable of assessing the
recombination velocity v_I at the PEDOT:PSS/c-Si interface. An estimated v_I of
~ 400 m/s demonstrates, that while PEDOT:PSS shows an excellent selectivity on
n-type c-Si, the passivation quality provided by the formation of a native
oxide at the c-Si surface restricts the performance of the hybrid junction.
Furthermore, by comparing the measured external quantum efficiency with optical
simulations, we quantify the losses due to parasitic absorption of PEDOT:PSS
and reflection of the device layer stack. By pointing out ways to better
passivate the hybrid interface and to increase the photocurrent we discuss the
full potential of PEDOT:PSS as a front contact in SHJ solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05374</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yingxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Lingling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jintian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Ya</forenames></author></authors><title>Monolithic integration of a high-quality factor lithium niobate
  microresonator with a free-standing membrane waveguide using femtosecond
  laser assisted ion beam writing (FLAIBW)</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate integrating a high quality factor lithium niobate microdisk
resonator with a free-standing membrane waveguide. Our technique is based on
femtosecond laser direct writing which produces the pre-structure, followed by
focused ion beam milling which reduces the surface roughness of sidewall of the
fabricated structure to nanometer scale. Efficient light coupling between the
integrated waveguide and microdisk was achieved, and the quality factor of the
microresonator was measured as high as 1.67*10^5.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05385</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Marmugi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gori</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deans</keyname><forenames>Cameron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renzoni</keyname><forenames>Ferruccio</forenames></author></authors><title>Remote detection of rotating machinery with a portable atomic
  magnetometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures. Published version can be found here
  https://www.osapublishing.org/ao/abstract.cfm?uri=ao-56-3-743</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Opt. 56, 3 (2017) 743-749</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/AO.56.000743</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate remote detection of rotating machinery, using an atomic
magnetometer at room temperature and in an unshielded environment. The system
relies on the coupling of the AC magnetic signature of the target with the
spin-polarized, precessing atomic vapor of a radio-frequency optical atomic
magnetometer. The AC magnetic signatures of rotating equipment or electric
motors appear as sidebands in the power spectrum of the atomic sensor, which
can be tuned to avoid noisy bands that would otherwise hamper detection. A
portable apparatus is implemented and experimentally tested. Proof-of-concept
investigations are performed with test targets mimicking possible applications,
and the operational conditions for optimum detection are determined. Our
instrument provides comparable or better performance than a commercial fluxgate
and allows detection of rotating machinery behind a wall. These results
demonstrate the potential for ultrasensitive devices for remote industrial and
usage monitoring, security, and surveillance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05398</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Shephard</keyname><forenames>Jacob J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Sanliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosso</keyname><forenames>Gabriele C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michaelides</keyname><forenames>Angelos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slater</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salzmann</keyname><forenames>Christoph G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is High-density Amorphous Ice Simply a 'Derailed' State along the Ice I
  to Ice IV Pathway?</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structural nature of high-density amorphous ice (HDA), which forms
through low-temperature pressure-induced amorphization of the 'ordinary' ice I,
is heavily debated. Clarifying this question is not only important for
understanding the complex condensed states of H$_2$O but also in the wider
context of pressure-induced amorphization processes, which are encountered
across the entire materials spectrum. We first show that ammonium fluoride
(NH$_4$F), which has a similar hydrogen-bonded network to ice I, also undergoes
a pressure collapse upon compression at 77 K. However, the product material is
not amorphous but NH$_4$F II, a high-pressure phase isostructural with ice IV.
This collapse can be rationalized in terms of a highly effective mechanism. In
the case of ice I, the orientational disorder of the water molecules leads to a
deviation from this mechanism and we therefore classify HDA as a 'derailed'
state along the ice I to ice IV pathway.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05421</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>Tomohisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Yumi</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation study on impact of GEM geometry for gas gain uniformity</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 21 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gas Electron Multiplier (GEM) is one of the devices for gas amplification and
available as an amplification part of detectors for many experiments. A GEM
with a 50 $\mu m$ thick insulator is popular and widely used in many
experimental fields. However it is necessary to use several layers of them to
get sufficient gas gain because gas gain which is provided with only one 50
$\mu m$ thick GEM is only several times ten. On the other hand, a thick GEM
whose amplification area is expanded from 50 to 100 $\mu m$ to get higher gas
gain which can be sufficient even with a double stack configuration. But the
measurement of gas gain uniformity using a large area 100 $\mu m$ thick GEM
reported here observed sizable non-uniformity which reached more than 50\%. We
investigated gas gain uniformity which is derived from geometries of the GEM
using $\rm{garfield^{++}}$ and considered an optimal geometry for the 100 $\mu
m$ thick GEM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05422</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Varagnolo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>CNISM and Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia 'G. Galilei'- Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Raccanello</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>CNISM and Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia 'G. Galilei'- Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pierno</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>CNISM and Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia 'G. Galilei'- Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mistura</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>CNISM and Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia 'G. Galilei'- Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Moffa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>NEST, Istituto Nanoscienze-CNR Pisa</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Persano</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>NEST, Istituto Nanoscienze-CNR Pisa</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pisignano</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>NEST, Istituto Nanoscienze-CNR Pisa</affiliation><affiliation>Dipartimento di Matematica e Fisica 'E. De Giorgi'-Universit&#xe0; del Salento</affiliation></author></authors><title>Highly sticky surfaces made by electrospun polymer nanofibers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>RSC Advances, volume 7, pages 5836-5842 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6ra24922a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a comprehensive study of the unique adhesive properties of mats
of polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA) nanofibers produced by electrospinning. Fibers
are deposited on glass, varying the diameter and the relative orientation of
the polymer filaments (random vs aligned configuration). While no significant
variation is observed in the static contact angle (about 130{\deg}) of
deposited water drops upon changing the average fiber diameter up to the
micrometer scale, fibers are found to exhibit unequalled water adhesion. Placed
vertically, they can hold up water drops as large as 60 microL, more than twice
the values typically obtained with hairy surfaces prepared by different
methods. For aligned fibers with anisotropic wetting behavior, the maximum
volume measured in the direction perpendicular to the fibers goes up to 90
{\mu}L. This work suggests new routes to tailor the wetting behavior on
extended areas by nanofiber coatings, with possible applications in adsorbing
and catalytic surfaces, microfluidic devices, and filtration technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05423</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>Abdel Nasser</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author></authors><title>Baryon-to-pion ratios within generic (non)extensive statistics</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, 1 table, presented at ICHEP2016, Chicago-USA, 3-10
  August 2016</comments><report-no>ECTP-2016-07, WLCAPP-2016-07</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The successive stages of a high-energy collision are conjectured to end up
with chemical and thermal freezeout of the produced particles. We utilize
generic (non)extensive statistics which is believed to determine the degree of
(non)extensivity through two critical exponents due to possible phase-space
modifications. This statistical approach likely manifests various types of
correlations and fluctuations and also possible interactions among the
final-state produced particles. We study the baryon-to-pion ratios at top RHIC
and LHC energies including the so-called proton anomaly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05429</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>A&#xe7;&#x131;k</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zg&#xfc;r</forenames></author></authors><title>Twistors from Killing Spinors alias Radiation from Pair Annihilation I:
  Theoretical Considerations</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is intended to be a further step through our Killing spinor
programme started with Class. Quantum Grav. \textbf{32}, 175007 (2015), and we
will advance our programme in accordance with the road map recently given in
arXiv:1611.04424v2. In the latter reference many open problems were declared,
one of which contained the uncovered relations between specific spinors in
spacetime represented by an arrow diagram built upon them. This work deals with
one of the arrows with almost all of its details and ends up with an important
physical interpretation of this setup in terms of the quantum electrodynamical
pair annihilation process. This method will shed light on the classification of
pseudo-Riemannian manifolds admitting twistors in connection with the
classification problem related to Killing spinors. Many physical
interpretations are given during the text some of which include dynamics of
brane immersions, quantum field theoretical considerations and black hole
evaporation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05435</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kehrig</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de Astrofisica de Andalucia, IAA-CSIC</affiliation></author></authors><title>Spatially resolved properties for extremely metal-poor star-forming
  galaxies with Wolf-Rayet features and high-ionization lines</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Invited review in workshop &quot;Chemical Abundances in Gaseous Nebulae&quot;
  held at Campos do Jordao (SP,Brazil) from 2th to 5th of november 2016. To be
  published in AAA Workshop Series 12. 10 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extremely metal-poor, high-ionizing starbursts in the local Universe provide
unique laboratories for exploring in detail the physics of high-redshift
systems. Also, their ongoing star-formation and haphazard morphology make them
outstanding proxies for primordial galaxies. Using integral field spectroscopy,
we spatially resolved the ISM properties and massive stars of two first-class
low metallicity galaxies with Wolf-Rayet features and nebular HeII emission:
Mrk178 and IZw18. In this review, we summarize our main results for these two
objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05436</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bach</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hach</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppression of Decoherence of a Spin-Boson System by Time-Periodic
  Control</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a finite-dimensional quantum system coupled to the bosonic
radiation field and subject to a time-periodic control operator. Assuming the
validity of a certain dynamic decoupling condition we approximate the system's
time evolution with respect to the non-interacting dynamics. For sufficiently
small coupling constants $g$ and control periods $T$ we show that a certain
deviation of coupled and uncoupled propagator may be estimated by
$\mathcal{O}(gt \, T)$. Our approach relies on the concept of Kato stability
and general theory on non-autonomous linear evolution equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05437</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghigo</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames><affiliation>DALEMBERT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Delestre</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames><affiliation>JAD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fullana</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames><affiliation>DALEMBERT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lagr&#xe9;e</keyname><forenames>P. -Y.</forenames><affiliation>DALEMBERT</affiliation></author></authors><title>Low-Shapiro hydrostatic reconstruction technique for blood flow
  simulation in large arteries with varying geometrical and mechanical
  properties</title><categories>physics.comp-ph math.NA physics.flu-dyn physics.med-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Computational Physics, Elsevier, 331, pp.108 - 136
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.11.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this work is to construct a simple, efficient and accurate
well-balanced numerical scheme for one-dimensional (1D) blood flow in large
arteries with varying geometrical and mechanical properties. As the steady
states at rest are not relevant for blood flow, we construct two well-balanced
hydrostatic reconstruction techniques designed to preserve low-Shapiro number
steady states that may occur in large network simulations. The Shapiro number S
h = u/c is the equivalent of the Froude number for shallow water equations and
the Mach number for compressible Euler equations. The first is the low-Shapiro
hydrostatic reconstruction (HR-LS), which is a simple and efficient method,
inspired from the hydrostatic reconstruction technique (HR). The second is the
subsonic hydrostatic reconstruction (HR-S), adapted here to blood flow and
designed to exactly preserve all subcritical steady states. We systematically
compare HR, HR-LS and HR-S in a series of single artery and arterial network
numerical tests designed to evaluate their well-balanced and wave-capturing
properties. The results indicate that HR is not adapted to compute blood flow
in large arteries as it is unable to capture wave reflections and transmissions
when large variations of the arteries' geometrical and mechanical properties
are considered. On the contrary, HR-S is exactly well-balanced and is the most
accurate hydrostatic reconstruction technique. However, HR-LS is able to
compute low-Shapiro number steady states as well as wave reflections and
transmissions with satisfying accuracy and is simpler and computationally less
expensive than HR-S. We therefore recommend using HR-LS for 1D blood flow
simulations in large arterial network simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05439</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Prabhudesai</keyname><forenames>G</forenames><affiliation>IEMN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bihi</keyname><forenames>I</forenames><affiliation>IEMN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zoueshtiagh</keyname><forenames>F</forenames><affiliation>IEMN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jose</keyname><forenames>J</forenames><affiliation>IEMN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baudoin</keyname><forenames>M</forenames><affiliation>IEMN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nonspherical armoured bubble vibration</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1039/b000000x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the dynamics of cylindrical armoured bubbles excited
by mechanical vibrations. A step by step transition from cylindrical to
spherical shape is reported as the intensity of the vibration is increased,
leading to a reduction of the bubble surface and a dissemination of the excess
particles. We demonstrate through energy balance that nonspherical armoured
bubbles constitute a metastable state. The vibration instills the activation
energy necessary for the bubble to return to its least energetic stable state:
a spherical armoured bubble. At this point, particle desorption can only be
achieved through higher amplitude of excitation required to overcome capillary
retention forces. Nonspherical armoured bubbles open perspectives for tailored
localized particle dissemination with limited excitation power.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05457</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Liangdong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Jae Kyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kee</keyname><forenames>Youngwook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>Jin Keun</forenames></author></authors><title>Dipole Incompatibility Related Artifacts in Quantitative Susceptibility
  Mapping</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Artifacts in quantitative susceptibility mapping (QSM) are analyzed to
establish an optimal design criterion for QSM inversion algorithms. The
magnetic field data is decomposed into two parts, dipole compatible and
incompatible parts. The dipole compatible part generates the desired
non-streaking solution. The dipole incompatible part, including noise,
discretization error, and anisotropy sources, generates artifacts defined by a
wave propagator with the B0 field direction as the time axis. Granular noise
causes streaking and contiguous error causes both streaking and shadow
artifacts. As an example, truncation-based QSM algorithms are inherently prone
to streaking artifacts because of the deviation of the dipole kernel during
truncation. Through numerical phantom and imaging experiments, several QSM
methods, including a Bayesian regularization method and the k-space truncation
methods, were compared to show that the Bayesian approach with a structural
prior provides advantages in terms of both image quality and quantitative
measures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05465</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Catapano</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xf2;</forenames></author></authors><title>The rigorous derivation of the linear Landau equation from a particle
  system in a weak-coupling limit</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a system of N particles interacting via a short-range smooth
potential, in a intermediate regime between the weak-coupling and the
low-density. We provide a rigorous derivation of the Linear Landau equation
from this particle system. The strategy of the proof consists in showing the
asymptotic equivalence between the one-particle marginal and the solution of
the linear Boltzmann equation with vanishing mean free path.Then, following the
ideas of Landau, we prove the asympotic equivalence between the solutions of
the Boltzmann and Landau linear equation in the grazing collision limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05481</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Dogiel</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyshov</keyname><forenames>D. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erlykin</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>C. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolfendale</keyname><forenames>A. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Ray (Stochastic) Acceleration from a Background Plasma</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>A talk presented at the conference &quot;Cosmic Ray Origin - beyond the
  standard models&quot; (San-Vito, Italy, 2016), submitted to Nuclear and Particle
  Physics Proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a short review of processes of stochastic acceleration in the Galaxy.
We discuss: how to estimate correctly the number of accelerated particles, and
at which condition the stochastic mechanism is able to generate power-law
nonthermal spectra. We present an analysis of stochastic acceleration in the
Galactic halo and discuss whether this mechanism can be responsible for
production of high energy electrons there, which emit gamma-ray and microwave
emission from the giant Fermi bubbles. Lastly, we discuss whether the effects
of stochastic acceleration can explain the CR distribution in the Galactic disk
(CR gradient).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05486</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements of the top quark mass from the LHC and the Tevatron</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>presented at 9th International Workshop on the CKM Unitarity Triangle
  (5 pages)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mass of the top quark is a fundamental parameter of the standard model
and has to be determined experimentally. In these proceedings, I review recent
measurements of the top quark mass in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt s=7,~8,$ and 13
TeV recorded by the ATLAS and CMS detectors at the LHC, and in $p\bar p$
collisions at $\sqrt s=1.96$ TeV recorded by the CDF and D0 experiments at the
Tevatron. The measurements are performed in final states containing two, one,
and no charged leptons. A relative precision of down to 0.3% is attained. In
addition, recent measurements aiming to determine the top quark mass in the
well-defined pole scheme using both inclusive $t\bar t$ and $t\bar t+1~{\rm
jet}$ production are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05496</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>Frank G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radio detection of Extensive Air Showers (ECRS 2016)</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Detection of the mostly geomagnetically generated radio emission of
cosmic-ray air showers provides an alternative to air-Cherenkov and
air-fluorescence detection, since it is not limited to clear nights. Like these
established methods, the radio signal is sensitive to the calorimetric energy
and the position of the maximum of the electromagnetic shower component. This
makes antenna arrays an ideal extension for particle-detector arrays above a
threshold energy of about 100 PeV of the primary cosmic-ray particles. In the
last few years the digital radio technique for cosmic-ray air showers again
made significant progress, and there now is a consistent picture of the
emission mechanisms confirmed by several measurements. Recent results by the
antenna arrays AERA and Tunka-Rex confirm that the absolute accuracy for the
shower energy is as good as the other detection techniques. Moreover, the
sensitivity to the shower maximum of the radio signal has been confirmed in
direct comparison to air-Cherenkov measurements by Tunka-Rex. The dense antenna
array LOFAR can already compete with the established techniques in accuracy for
cosmic-ray mass-composition. In the future, a new generation of radio
experiments might drive the field: either by providing extremely large exposure
for inclined cosmic-ray or neutrino showers or, like the SKA core in Australia
with its several 10,000 antennas, by providing extremely detailed measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05502</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Collins</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames><affiliation>Regensburg U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eckert</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames><affiliation>Muenster U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Heitger</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames><affiliation>Muenster U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>Regensburg U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Soeldner</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames><affiliation>Regensburg U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Charmed pseudoscalar decay constants on three-flavour CLS ensembles with
  open boundaries</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>14 pages including figures and tables, latex2e; Proceedings of the
  34th International Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30
  July 2016, Southampton, UK</comments><report-no>MS-TP-16-36</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the masses and pseudoscalar decay constants of D and D_s mesons
employing lattice QCD with non-perturbatively O(a) improved Wilson quarks and a
tree-level Symanzik-improved gauge action. Our analysis is based on the
large-volume N_f=2+1 ensembles using open boundary conditions, generated within
the CLS effort. The status of results presented here covers two lattice
spacings, a ~ 0.0854 fm and a ~ 0.0644 fm, and pion masses varied from 420 to
200 MeV. We also report on our implementation of distance preconditioning for
the calculation of heavy quark propagators and discuss the impact of the
resulting accuracy improvements on the extraction of charmed meson masses and
decay constants. This is part of a continuing analysis by the RQCD and ALPHA
Collaborations, aiming at a stable continuum extrapolation using several
lattice spacings. To extrapolate to the physical masses, we follow both, the
(2*m_l+m_s)=const. and the m_s=const. line in parameter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05506</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Roos</keyname><forenames>Matts</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter in dwarf galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Although the cusp-core controversy for dwarf galaxies is seen as a problem, I
argue that the cored central profiles can be explained by flattened cusps
because they suffer from conflicting measurements and poor statistics and
because there is a large number of conventional processes that could have
flattened them since their creation, none of which requires new physics. Other
problems, such as &quot;too big to fail&quot;, are not discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05515</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Soltanov</keyname><forenames>Kamal N.</forenames></author></authors><title>On some nonlinear equation from theory of the flows on networks</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9p. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1612.00973</comments><msc-class>Primary 35B30, 35L65, 35R02, Secondary 34A15, 34H05, 37C60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we study the nonlinear hyperbolic equations of the type of equations
from theory of flows on networks, for which we prove the solvability theorem
under the appropriate conditions and also investigate the behaviour of the
solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05528</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Sheckelton</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plumb</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trump</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broholm</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rearrangement of Van-der-Waals Stacking and Formation of a Singlet State
  at $T = 90$ K in a Cluster Magnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables in Inorg. Chem. Front., 2017</comments><doi>10.1039/C6QI00470A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Insulating Nb$_3$Cl$_8$ is a layered chloride consisting of two-dimensional
triangular layers of $S_{eff}$ = 1/2 Nb$_3$Cl$_{13}$ clusters at room
temperature. Magnetic susceptibility measurement show a sharp, hysteretic drop
to a temperature independent value below $T = 90$ K. Specific heat measurements
show that the transition is first order, with $\Delta S \approx 5\ \mathrm{J
\cdot K^{-1} \cdot mol\ \mathit{f.u.}^{-1}}$, and a low temperature $T$-linear
contribution originating from defect spins. Neutron and X-ray diffraction show
a lowering of symmetry from trigonal $P\bar{3}m1$ to monoclinic $C2/m$
symmetry, with a change in layer stacking from -AB-AB- to
-AB$^\prime$-BC$^\prime$-CA$^\prime$- and no observed magnetic order. This
lowering of symmetry and rearrangement of successive layers evades geometric
magnetic frustration to form a singlet ground state. It is the lowest
temperature at which a change in stacking sequence is known to occur in a
Van-der-Waals solid, occurs in the absence of orbital degeneracies, and
suggests that designer 2-D heterostructures may be able to undergo similar
phase transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05548</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ulyanov</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>Oran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Oliver J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobin</keyname><forenames>Isaac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanlon</keyname><forenames>Lorraine</forenames></author><author><keyname>McBreen</keyname><forenames>Sheila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelms</keyname><forenames>Nick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shortt</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Localisation of gamma-ray interaction points in thick monolithic CeBr3
  and LaBr3:Ce scintillators</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det physics.med-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nuclear Inst. and Methods in Physics Research, A 844C (2017) pp.
  81-89</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.11.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Localisation of gamma-ray interaction points in monolithic scintillator
crystals can simplify the design and improve the performance of a future
Compton telescope for gamma-ray astronomy. In this paper we compare the
position resolution of three monolithic scintillators: a 28x28x20 mm3 (length x
breadth x thickness) LaBr3:Ce crystal, a 25x25x20 mm3 CeBr3 crystal and a
25x25x10 mm3 CeBr3 crystal. Each crystal was encapsulated and coupled to an
array of 4x4 silicon photomultipliers through an optical window. The
measurements were conducted using 81 keV and 356 keV gamma-rays from a
collimated 133Ba source. The 3D position reconstruction of interaction points
was performed using artificial neural networks trained with experimental data.
Although the position resolution was significantly better for the thinner
crystal, the 20 mm thick CeBr3 crystal showed an acceptable resolution of about
5.4 mm FWHM for the x and y coordinates, and 7.8 mm FWHM for the z-coordinate
(crystal depth) at 356 keV. These values were obtained from the full position
scans of the crystal sides. The position resolution of the LaBr3:Ce crystal was
found to be considerably worse, presumably due to the highly diffusive optical
in- terface between the crystal and the optical window of the enclosure. The
energy resolution (FWHM) measured for 662 keV gamma-rays was 4.0% for LaBr3:Ce
and 5.5% for CeBr3. The same crystals equipped with a PMT (Hamamatsu R6322-100)
gave an energy resolution of 3.0% and 4.7%, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
