<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:57:58Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-05" from="2017-01-05" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.0737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.0737</id><created>2010-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Marcos A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The quantum $H_3$ integrable system</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Intern.Journ.Mod.Phys. A 25 (2010) 5567-5594</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732311034839</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum $H_3$ integrable system is a 3D system with rational potential
related to the non-crystallographic root system $H_3$. It is shown that the
gauge-rotated $H_3$ Hamiltonian as well as one of the integrals, when written
in terms of the invariants of the Coxeter group $H_3$, is in algebraic form: it
has polynomial coefficients in front of derivatives. The Hamiltonian has
infinitely-many finite-dimensional invariant subspaces in polynomials, they
form the infinite flag with the characteristic vector $\vec \al\ =\ (1,2,3)$.
One among possible integrals is found (of the second order) as well as its
algebraic form. A hidden algebra of the $H_3$ Hamiltonian is determined. It is
an infinite-dimensional, finitely-generated algebra of differential operators
possessing finite-dimensional representations characterized by a generalized
Gauss decomposition property. A quasi-exactly-solvable integrable
generalization of the model is obtained. A discrete integrable model on the
uniform lattice in a space of $H_3$-invariants &quot;polynomially&quot;-isospectral to
the quantum $H_3$ model is defined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.2127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.2127</id><created>2010-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Marcos A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>Alexander V</forenames></author></authors><title>The quantum $H_4$ integrable system</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><journal-ref>Mod.Phys.Lett. A 26 (2010) 433-447</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X10050597</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum $H_4$ integrable system is a 4D system with rational potential
related to the non-crystallographic root system $H_4$ with 600-cell symmetry.
It is shown that the gauge-rotated $H_4$ Hamiltonian as well as one of the
integrals, when written in terms of the invariants of the Coxeter group $H_4$,
is in algebraic form: it has polynomial coefficients in front of derivatives.
Any eigenfunctions is a polynomial multiplied by ground-state function
(factorization property). Spectra corresponds to one of the anisotropic
harmonic oscillator. The Hamiltonian has infinitely-many finite-dimensional
invariant subspaces in polynomials, they form the infinite flag with the
characteristic vector $\vec \al\ =\ (1,5,8,12)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.1902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.1902</id><created>2010-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Boreskov</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vieyra</keyname><forenames>J. C. L&#xf3;pez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>M. A. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sutherland-type Trigonometric Models, Trigonometric Invariants and
  Multivariate Polynomials. III. $E_8$ case</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, 3 Tables, 3 Appendices, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Intern.Journ.Mod.Phys. A 26 (2011) 1399-1437</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X11053018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that the $E_8$ trigonometric Olshanetsky-Perelomov Hamiltonian,
when written in terms of the Fundamental Trigonometric Invariants (FTI), is in
algebraic form, i.e., has polynomial coefficients, and preserves two infinite
flags of polynomial spaces marked by the Weyl (co)-vector and $E_8$ highest
root (both in the basis of simple roots) as characteristic vectors. The
explicit form of the Hamiltonian in new variables has been obtained both by
direct calculation and by means of the orbit function technique. It is shown a
triangularity of the Hamiltonian in the bases of orbit functions and of
algebraic monomials ordered through Weyl heights. Examples of first
eigenfunctions are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1102.0955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1102.0955</id><created>2011-02-04</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harshman</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranade</keyname><forenames>Kedar S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observables can be tailored to change the entanglement of any pure state</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, no figures; title now agrees with published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.A84:012303,2011</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.84.012303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that for a finite-dimensional Hilbert space, there exist observables
that induce a tensor product structure such that the entanglement properties of
any pure state can be tailored. In particular, we provide an explicit, finite
method for constructing observables in an unstructured d-dimensional system so
that an arbitrary known pure state has any Schmidt decomposition with respect
to an induced bipartite tensor product structure. In effect, this article
demonstrates that in a finite-dimensional Hilbert space, entanglement
properties can always be shifted from the state to the observables and all pure
states are equivalent as entanglement resources in the ideal case of complete
control of observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1211.4985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1211.4985</id><created>2012-11-21</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garz&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chamorro</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reyes</keyname><forenames>F. Vega</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport properties for driven granular fluids in situations close to
  homogeneous steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 figures. Several typos and mistakes have been corrected in this new
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev . E 87, 032201 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.87.032201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transport coefficients of a granular fluid driven by a stochastic bath
with friction are obtained by solving the inelastic Enskog kinetic equation
from the Chapman-Enskog method. The heat and momentum fluxes as well as the
cooling rate are determined to first order in the deviations of the
hydrodynamic field gradients from their values in the homogeneous steady state.
Since the collisional cooling cannot be compensated locally for the heat
produced by the external driving force, the reference distribution $f^{(0)}$
(zeroth-order approximation) depends on time through its dependence on
temperature. This fact gives rise to conceptual and practical difficulties not
present in the undriven case. On the other hand, to simplify the analysis and
given that we are interested in computing transport in the first order of
deviations from the reference state, the steady-state conditions are considered
to get explicit forms for the transport coefficients and the cooling rate. A
comparison with recent molecular dynamics simulations for driven granular
fluids shows an excellent agreement for the kinematic viscosity although some
discrepancies are observed for the longitudinal viscosity and the thermal
diffusivity at large densities. Finally, a linear stability analysis of the
hydrodynamic equations with respect to the homogeneous steady state is
performed. As expected, no instabilities are found thanks to the presence of
the external bath.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.2345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.2345</id><created>2013-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escobar-Ruiz</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two charges on a plane in a magnetic field: hidden algebra, (particular)
  integrability, polynomial eigenfunctions</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.str-el math.MP nlin.SI quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A46 (2013) 295204</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/46/29/295204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum mechanics of two Coulomb charges on a plane $(e_1, m_1)$ and
$(e_2, m_2)$ subject to a constant magnetic field $B$ perpendicular to the
plane is considered. Four integrals of motion are explicitly indicated. It is
shown that for two physically-important particular cases, namely that of two
particles of equal Larmor frequencies, ${e_c} \propto
\frac{e_1}{m_1}-\frac{e_2}{m_2}=0$ (e.g. two electrons) and one of a neutral
system (e.g. the electron - positron pair, Hydrogen atom) at rest (the
center-of-mass momentum is zero) some outstanding properties occur. They are
the most visible in double polar coordinates in CMS $(R, \phi)$ and relative
$(\rho, \varphi)$ coordinate systems: (i) eigenfunctions are factorizable, all
factors except one with the explicit $\rho$-dependence are found analytically,
they have definite relative angular momentum, (ii) dynamics in $\rho$-direction
is the same for both systems, it corresponds to a funnel-type potential and it
has hidden $sl(2)$ algebra; at some discrete values of dimensionless magnetic
fields $b \leq 1$, (iii) particular integral(s) occur, (iv) the hidden $sl(2)$
algebra emerges in finite-dimensional representation, thus, the system becomes
{\it quasi-exactly-solvable} and (v) a finite number of polynomial
eigenfunctions in $\rho$ appear. Nine families of eigenfunctions are presented
explicitly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.2280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.2280</id><created>2013-12-08</created><updated>2014-02-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duplij</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldin</keyname><forenames>Gerald A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shtelen</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal inversion and Maxwell field invariants in four- and
  six-dimensional spacetimes</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, birkjour.cls, submitted for the Proceedings of the XXXIInd
  Workshop on Geometric Methods in Physics, (Bialowieza, Poland, July 2013),
  v2: minor improvements</comments><msc-class>35Q61, 78A02, 78A25, 22E70</msc-class><journal-ref>Geometric Methods in Physics, Proceedings XXXII Workshop
  (Bialowieza, 2013), Trends in Mathematics 2014 (Springer), pp. 233-242</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-06248-8_20</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conformally compactified (3+1)-dimensional Minkowski spacetime may be
identified with the projective light cone in (4+2)-dimensional spacetime. In
the latter spacetime the special conformal group acts via rotations and boosts,
and conformal inversion acts via reflection in a single coordinate.
Hexaspherical coordinates facilitate dimensional reduction of Maxwell
electromagnetic field strength tensors to (3+1) from (4 + 2) dimensions. Here
we focus on the operation of conformal inversion in different
coordinatizations, and write some useful equations. We then write a conformal
invariant and a pseudo-invariant in terms of field strengths; the
pseudo-invariant in (4+2) dimensions takes a new form. Our results advance the
study of general nonlinear conformal-invariant electrodynamics based on
nonlinear constitutive equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.6406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.6406</id><created>2014-01-24</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Warneford</keyname><forenames>Emma S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dellar</keyname><forenames>Paul J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Super- and sub-rotating equatorial jets: Newtonian cooling versus
  Rayleigh friction</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.EP physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 28 figures, generates 3.4MB PDF</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical simulations of the shallow water equations on rotating spheres
produce mixtures of robust vortices and alternating zonal jets, as seen in the
atmospheres of the gas giant planets. However, simulations that include
Rayleigh friction invariably produce a sub-rotating (retrograde) equatorial jet
for Jovian parameter regimes, whilst observations of Jupiter show a
super-rotating (prograde) equatorial jet that has persisted over several
decades. Super-rotating equatorial jets have recently been obtained in shallow
water simulations that include a Newtonian relaxation of perturbations to the
layer thickness to model radiative cooling to space, and in simulations of the
thermal shallow water equations that include a similar relaxation term in their
temperature equation. Simulations of global quasigeostrophic forms of these
different models produce equatorial jets in the same directions as the parent
models, suggesting that the mechanism responsible for setting the direction
lies within quasigeostrophic theory. We provide such a mechanism by calculating
the effective force acting on the thickness-weighted zonal mean flow due to the
decay of an equatorially trapped Rossby wave. Decay due to Newtonian cooling
creates an eastward zonal mean flow at the equator, consistent with the
formation of a super-rotating equatorial jet, while decay due to Rayleigh
friction leads to a westward zonal mean flow at the equator, consistent with
the formation of a sub-rotating equatorial jet. In both cases the meridionally
integrated zonal mean of the absolute zonal momentum is westward, consistent
with the standard result that Rossby waves carry westward pseudomomentum, but
this does not preclude the zonal mean flow being eastward on and close to the
equator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.7924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.7924</id><created>2014-03-31</created><updated>2016-04-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Liangsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaokang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yingjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Baoxue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Suyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Yixin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Shiping</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified Kedem-Katchalsky equations for osmosis through nano-pore</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>92C05</msc-class><journal-ref>Desalination.399(2016)47-52</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.desal.2016.08.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents a modified Kedem-Katchalsky equations for osmosis through
nano-pore. osmotic reflection coefficient of a solute was found to be chiefly
affected by the entrance of the pore while filtration reflection coefficient
can be affected by both the entrance and the internal structure of the pore.
Using an analytical method, we get the quantitative relationship between
osmotic reflection coefficient and the molecule size. The model is verified by
comparing the theoretical results with the reported experimental data of
aquaporin osmosis. Our work is expected to pave the way for a better
understanding of osmosis in bio-system and to give us new ideas in designing
new membranes with better performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2136</id><created>2014-06-09</created><updated>2014-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pil&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>H. Olivares</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear critical charge for two-electron ion in Lagrange mesh method</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 379 (2015) 688-690</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2014.12.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Schroedinger equation for two electrons in the field of a charged fixed
center $Z$ is solved with the Lagrange mesh method for charges close to the
critical charge $Z_{cr}$. We confirm the value of the nuclear critical charge
$Z_{cr}$ recently calculated in Estienne et al. {\em Phys. Rev. Lett. \bf 112},
173001 (2014) to 11 decimal digits using an inhomogeneous (non-uniform)
three-dimensional lattice of size $70 \times 70 \times 20$. We show that the
ground state energy for H$^-$ is accurate to 14 decimals on the lattice $50
\times 50 \times 40$ in comparison with the highly accurate result by
Nakashima-Nakatsuji, {\it J. Chem. Phys. \bf 127}, 224104 (2007).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7439</id><created>2014-09-25</created><updated>2015-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-exact-solvability of the $A_{2}/G_2$ Elliptic model: algebraic
  forms, $sl(3)/g^{(2)}$ hidden algebra, polynomial eigenfunctions</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP nlin.SI quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, the solution of G_2 elliptic model added, title changed
  (slightly) and also abstract, some references added,</comments><report-no>IHES/P/14/29</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A48 (2015) 155201</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/15/155201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The potential of the $A_2$ quantum elliptic model (3-body Calogero-Moser
elliptic model) is defined by the pairwise three-body interaction through
Weierstrass $\wp$-function and has a single coupling constant. A change of
variables has been found, which are $A_2$ elliptic invariants, such that the
potential becomes a rational function, while the flat space metric as well as
its associated vector are polynomials in two variables. It is shown that the
model possesses the hidden $sl(3)$ algebra - the Hamiltonian is an element of
the universal enveloping algebra $U_{sl(3)}$ for arbitrary coupling constant -
thus, it is equivalent to $sl(3)$-quantum Euler-Arnold top. The integral, in a
form of the third order differential operator with polynomial, is constructed
explicitly, being also an element of $U_{sl(3)}$. It is shown that there exists
a discrete sequence of the coupling constants for which a finite number of
polynomial eigenfunctions, up to a (non-singular) gauge factor occur.
  The potential of the $G_2$ quantum elliptic model (3-body Wolfes elliptic
model) is defined by the pairwise and three-body interactions through
Weierstrass $\wp$-function and has two coupling constants. A change of
variables has been found, which are $G_2$ elliptic invariants, such that the
potential becomes a rational function, while the flat space metric as well as
its associated vector are polynomials in two variables. It is shown the model
possesses the hidden $g^{(2)}$ algebra. It is shown that there exists a
discrete family of the coupling constants for which a finite number of
polynomial eigenfunctions up to a (non-singular) gauge factor occur.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.2147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.2147</id><created>2014-10-05</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abdelsamie</keyname><forenames>Maher A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>Russly b Abdul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mustafa</keyname><forenames>Shuhaimi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isa</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashim</keyname><forenames>Dzulkifly</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluation of Electric and Magnetic Fields Distribution and SAR Induced
  in 3D Models of Water Containers by Radiofrequency Radiation and Their
  Relationship to the Non-Thermal Effects of Microwaves</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>45 pages, 18 figures, 10 tables. There is an update in the
  introduction and discussion parts of this version includes explanation about
  possible Mechanism for Non-thermal Effects of Microwaves</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The research works on the biological effects of electromagnetic (EM)
radiation have increased globally. Computer simulation models were developed to
assess exposure of square, rectangular, pyramidal, and cylindrical water
containers to microwave radiation at 300, 900, and 2,400 MHz. The development
of the models included determination of EM field distribution and the resulting
specific absorption rate (SAR) in the stored water. These models employed CST
STUDIO SUITE 2014 package to solve EM field equations by applying the
finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method. The effect of frequency, packaging
shape, and polarization on SAR induced in water was determined. High electric
field and point SAR were obtained over the whole azimuth and elevation angles
range in the pyramidal container model. The highest values of SAR were induced
in water at the sharp edges of the four water container models. The order of
the effect on total SAR and maximum point SAR is cylindrical &lt; square &lt;
rectangular &lt; pyramidal model at 300, 900, and 2,400 MHz for both vertical and
horizontal polarizations. It can be concluded that the variation in the
packaging shape of the containers, polarization, irradiation geometry, and
frequency. In addition, the sharp edges of the container models significantly
affect the calculation and distribution of electric and magnetic fields and SAR
values induced in the stored water, which in turn could cause variations in the
non-thermal effects of the electromagnetic fields in the stored water.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.2113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.2113</id><created>2014-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Miller,</keyname><forenames>Willard</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Turbiner</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>(Quasi)-exact-solvability on the sphere $S^n$</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><msc-class>22E70, 16G99, 37J35, 37K10, 33C45, 17B60</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Math Physics 56 (2015) 023501</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4906909</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An Exactly-Solvable (ES) potential on the sphere $S^n$ is reviewed and the
related Quasi-Exactly-Solvable (QES) potential is found and studied. Mapping
the sphere to a simplex it is found that the metric (of constant curvature) is
in polynomial form, and both the ES and the QES potentials are rational
functions. Their hidden algebra is $gl_n$ in a finite-dimensional
representation realized by first order differential operators acting on $RP^n$.
It is shown that variables in the Schr\&quot;odinger eigenvalue equation can be
separated in spherical coordinates and a number of the integrals of the second
order exists assuring the complete integrability. The QES system is
completely-integrable for $n=2$ and non-maximally superintegrable for $n\ge 3$.
There is no separable coordinate system in which it is exactly solvable. We
point out that by taking contractions of superintegrable systems, such as
induced by Wigner-In\&quot;on\&quot;u Lie algebra contractions, we can find other QES
superintegrable systems, and we illustrate this by contracting our $S^n$ system
to a QES non-maximal superintegrable system on Euclidean space $E^n$, an
extension of the Smorodinsky-Winternitz potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6247</id><created>2014-11-23</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bloznelis</keyname><forenames>Mindaugas</forenames></author></authors><title>Degree-degree distribution in a power law random intersection graph with
  clustering</title><categories>math.PR physics.data-an</categories><msc-class>91D30, 05C80, 05C07, 91C20</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The bivariate distribution of degrees of adjacent vertices (degree-degree
distribution) is an important network characteristic defining the statistical
dependencies between degrees of adjacent vertices. We show the asymptotic
degree-degree distribution of a sparse inhomogeneous random intersection graph
and discuss its relation to the clustering and power law properties of the
graph.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7020</id><created>2014-11-25</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garbali</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nienhuis</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The dilute Temperley-Lieb O($n=1$) loop model on a semi infinite strip:
  the ground state</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages, 30 figures, Updated version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the integrable dilute Temperley-Lieb (dTL) O($n=1$) loop model on
a semi-infinite strip of finite width $L$. In the analogy with the
Temperley-Lieb (TL) O($n=1$) loop model the ground state eigenvector of the
transfer matrix is studied by means of a set of $q$-difference equations,
sometimes called the $q$KZ equations. We compute some ground state components
of the transfer matrix of the dTL model, and show that all ground state
components can be recovered for arbitrary $L$ using the $q$KZ equation and
certain recurrence relation. The computations are done for generic open
boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7160</id><created>2014-11-26</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garbali</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nienhuis</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The dilute Temperley-Lieb O($n=1$) loop model on a semi infinite strip:
  the sum rule</title><categories>math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>21 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second part of our study of the ground state eigenvector of the
transfer matrix of the dilute Temperley-Lieb loop model with the loop weight
$n=1$ on a semi infinite strip of width $L$. We focus here on the computation
of the normalization (otherwise called the sum rule) $Z_L$ of the ground state
eigenvector, which is also the partition function of the critical site
percolation model. The normalization $Z_L$ is a symmetric polynomial in the
inhomogeneities of the lattice $z_1,..,z_L$. This polynomial satisfies several
recurrence relations which we solve independently in terms of Jacobi-Trudi like
determinants. Thus we provide a few determinantal expressions for the
normalization $Z_L$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07091</id><created>2015-02-25</created><updated>2015-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xinyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Lingna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jiyao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Kuiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ruquan</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable spin-orbit coupling synthesized with a modulating gradient
  magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 18983 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep18983</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the observation of tunable spin-orbit coupling (SOC) for ultracold
$^{87}$Rb atoms in hyperfine spin-1 states. Different from most earlier
experiments where atomic SOC of pseudo-spin-1/2 are synthesized with Raman
coupling lasers, the scheme we demonstrate employs a gradient magnetic field
(GMF) with ground state atoms and is immune to atomic spontaneous emission. The
effect of the SOC is confirmed through the studies of: 1) the collective dipole
oscillation of an atomic condensate in a harmonic trap after the synthesized
SOC is abruptly turned on; and 2) the minimum energy state at a finite
adiabatically adjusted momentum when the SOC strength is slowly ramped up. The
coherence properties of the spinor condensates remain very good after
interacting with modulating GMFs, which prompts the enthusiastic claim that our
work provides a new repertoire for synthesized gauge fields aimed at quantum
simulation studies with cold atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.00237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.00237</id><created>2015-04-01</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>A. J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konik</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum quenches in two spatial dimensions using chain array matrix
  product states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures. Several typos corrected in Supplemental info</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 161111 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.161111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a method for simulating the real time evolution of extended
quantum systems in two dimensions. The method combines the benefits of
integrability and matrix product states in one dimension to avoid several
issues that hinder other applications of tensor based methods in 2D. In
particular it can be extended to infinitely long cylinders. As an example
application we present results for quantum quenches in the 2D quantum (2+1
dimensional) Ising model. In quenches that cross a phase boundary we find that
the return probability shows non-analyticities in time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01137</id><created>2015-04-05</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Qiu-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Cong-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Stronger Schr\&quot;odinger-like Uncertainty Relations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures. minor corrections</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 380, 2925 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.06.054</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Uncertainty relation is one of the fundamental building blocks of quantum
theory. Nevertheless, the traditional uncertainty relations do not fully
capture the concept of incompatible observables. Here we present a stronger
Schr\&quot;odinger-like uncertainty relation, which is stronger than the relation
recently derived by L. Maccone and A. K. Pati [Phys. Rev. Lett. 113 (2014)
260401]. Furthermore, we give an additive uncertainty relation which holds for
three incompatible observables, which is stronger than the relation newly
obtained by S. Kechrimparis and S. Weigert [Phys. Rev. A 90 (2014) 062118] and
the simple extension of the Schr\&quot;odinger uncertainty relation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00099</id><created>2015-05-01</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gerhardus</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jockers</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual Pairs of Gauged Linear Sigma Models and Derived Equivalences of
  Calabi-Yau threefolds</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>66 pages, 3 figures; v2: refs. added; v3: minor changes and
  corrections -- version published in J.Geom.Phys</comments><report-no>BONN-TH-2015-05</report-no><journal-ref>J.Geom.Phys. 114 (2017) 223-259</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.geomphys.2016.12.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the phase structure of skew symplectic sigma models,
which are a certain class of two-dimensional N = (2,2) non-Abelian gauged
linear sigma models. At low energies some of them flow to non-linear sigma
models with Calabi-Yau target spaces, which emerge from non-Abelian strong
coupling dynamics. The observed phase structure results in a non-trivial
duality proposal among skew symplectic sigma models and connects non-complete
intersection Calabi-Yau threefolds, that are non-birational among another, in a
common quantum Kahler moduli space. As a consequence we find non-trivial
identifications of spectra of topological B-branes, which from a modern
algebraic geometry perspective imply derived equivalences among Calabi-Yau
varieties. To further support our proposals, we calculate the two sphere
partition function of skew symplectic sigma models to determine geometric
invariants, which confirm the anticipated Calabi-Yau threefold phases. We show
that the two sphere partition functions of a pair of dual skew symplectic sigma
models agree in a non-trivial fashion. To carry out these calculations, we
develop a systematic approach to study higher-dimensional Mellin-Barnes type
integrals. In particular, these techniques admit the evaluation of two sphere
partition functions for gauged linear sigma models with higher rank gauge
groups, but are applicable in other contexts as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06524</id><created>2015-06-22</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tomanic</keyname><forenames>Tihomir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schackert</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wulfhekel</keyname><forenames>Wulf</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xfc;rgers</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;hneysen</keyname><forenames>Hilbert v.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-band superconductivity of bulk and surface states in Ag thin films
  on Nb</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 220503(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.220503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use epitaxial strain to shift the energy of the two-dimensional Ag(111)
surface states of Ag islands on Nb(110) substrates, allowing to spatially tune
the bottom of the surface-state band $E_{\rm SS}$ through the Fermi level
$E_{\rm F}$. Bulk and surface-state contributions to the Ag(111) local density
of states (LDOS) can be separated with scanning tunneling spectroscopy. For
thick islands ($\approx$\, 20 nm), the Ag surface states are decoupled from the
Ag bulk states via orthogonality, and the superconductive gap induced by
proximity to Nb is due to bulk states only. However, for thin islands (3-4 nm),
surface-state electrons develop superconducting correlations as identified by a
complete energy gap in the LDOS when $E_{\rm F}$ is smaller than but close to
$E_{\rm F}$. The induced superconductivity in this case is of two-band nature
and appears to occur when the surface-state wave function reaches down to the
Ag/Nb interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08963</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2015-09-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>D&#x105;browski</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chrapkiewicz</keyname><forenames>Rados&#x142;aw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wasilewski</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetically tuned, robust and efficient filtering system for spatially
  multimode quantum memory in warm atomic vapors</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Modern Optics vol. 63 (20), 2029-2038 (2016), Special
  Issue: Advances in Quantum Memory</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2015.1106016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Warm atomic vapor quantum memories are simple and robust, yet suffer from a
number of parasitic processes which produce excess noise. For operating in a
single-photon regime precise filtering of the output light is essential. Here
we report a combination of magnetically tuned absorption and Faraday filters,
both light-direction-insensitive, which stop the driving lasers and attenuate
spurious fluorescence and four-wave mixing while transmitting narrowband Stokes
and anti-Stokes photons generated in write-in and readout processes. We
characterize both filters with respect to adjustable working parameters. We
demonstrate a significant increase in the signal to noise ratio upon applying
the filters seen qualitatively in measurements of correlation between the
Raman-scattered photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05795</id><created>2015-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Jezierski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waluk</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author></authors><title>Proof of Positive Energy Theorem by spacetime foliations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><msc-class>Primary 83C40, Secondary 53C12</msc-class><journal-ref>Banach Center Publications, Vol. 110 (2016) 115-120</journal-ref><doi>10.4064/bc110-0-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we present an alternative approach, requiring only basic tools of
differential geometry. This method was conceived by Kijowski and first
presented during the IV Marcel Grossman Meeting on General Relativity in Rome
(1986). It was later published in a generalized form by J. Jezierski, J.
Kijowski in 1987 (Positivity of total energy in general relativity, Physical
Review D {\bf 36} (1987), 1041-4). We summarize these results briefly and
present a new foliation gauge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06957</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cabana</keyname><forenames>Tanguy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Touboul</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Large deviations for randomly connected neural networks: I. Spatially
  extended systems</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a series of two papers, we investigate the large deviations and asymptotic
behavior of stochastic models of brain neural networks with random interaction
coefficients. In this first paper, we take into account the spatial structure
of the brain and consider (i) the presence of interaction delays that depend on
the distance between cells and (ii) Gaussian random interaction amplitude whose
mean and variance depend on the neurons positions and scale as the inverse of
the network size. We show that the empirical measure satisfies a
large-deviation principle with good rate function reaching its minimum at a
unique spatially extended probability measure. This result implies averaged
convergence of the empirical measure and propagation of chaos. The limit is
characterized through complex non-Markovian implicit equation in which the
network interaction term is replaced by a non-local Gaussian process whose
statistics depend on the solution over the whole neural field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03030</id><created>2016-01-12</created><updated>2016-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crosson</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrow</keyname><forenames>Aram W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulated Quantum Annealing Can Be Exponentially Faster than Classical
  Simulated Annealing</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.DS math.PR</categories><comments>21 pages, revised analysis includes worldline updates and spikes with
  polynomial width</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4760</report-no><journal-ref>Proc of FOCS 2016, pp. 714-723</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/FOCS.2016.81</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simulated Quantum Annealing (SQA) is a Markov Chain Monte-Carlo algorithm
that samples the equilibrium thermal state of a Quantum Annealing (QA)
Hamiltonian. In addition to simulating quantum systems, SQA has also been
proposed as another physics-inspired classical algorithm for combinatorial
optimization, alongside classical simulated annealing. However, in many cases
it remains an open challenge to determine the performance of both QA and SQA.
One piece of evidence for the strength of QA over classical simulated annealing
comes from an example by Farhi, Goldstone and Gutmann . There a bit-symmetric
cost function with a thin, high energy barrier was designed to show an
exponential seperation between classical simulated annealing, for which thermal
fluctuations take exponential time to climb the barrier, and quantum annealing
which passes through the barrier and reaches the global minimum in poly time,
arguably by taking advantage of quantum tunneling. In this work we apply a
comparison method to rigorously show that the Markov chain underlying SQA
efficiently samples the target distribution and finds the global minimum of
this spike cost function in polynomial time. Our work provides evidence for the
growing consensus that SQA inherits at least some of the advantages of
tunneling in QA, and so QA is unlikely to achieve exponential speedups over
classical computing solely by the use of quantum tunneling. Since we analyze
only a particular model this evidence is not decisive. However, techniques
applied here---including warm starts from the adiabatic path and the use of the
quantum ground state probability distribution to understand the stationary
distribution of SQA---may be valuable for future studies of the performance of
SQA on cost functions for which QA is efficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03625</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2016-02-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Hangjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witelski</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-time Thin Film Rupture Driven by Generalized Evaporative Loss</title><categories>math-ph math.MP physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>25 pages, 17 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physd.2016.10.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rupture is a nonlinear instability resulting in a finite-time singularity as
a fluid layer approaches zero thickness at a point. We study the dynamics of
rupture in a generalized mathematical model of thin films of viscous fluids
with evaporative effects. The governing lubrication model is a fourth-order
nonlinear parabolic partial differential equation with a non-conservative loss
term due to evaporation. Several different types of finite-time singularities
are observed due to balances between evaporation and surface tension or
intermolecular forces. Non-self-similar behavior and two classes of
self-similar rupture solutions are analyzed and validated against high
resolution PDE simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04556</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Katsutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Proposal for the proper gravitational energy-momentum tensor</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>A discussion on a Schwarzschild black hole is deleted</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters A, Vol.31, No.26 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a gravitational energy-momentum tensor of the general relativity
obtained using Noethers theorem. It transforms as a tensor under general
coordinate transformations. One of the two indices of the gravitational
energy-momentum tensor labels a local Lorentz frame that satisfies the
energy-momentum conservation law. The energies for a gravitational wave and a
Friedmann-Lemaitre--Robertson--Walker universe are calculated as examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08182</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jafari</keyname><forenames>Marjan</forenames></author></authors><title>Casimir entropy and internal energy of the objects in fluctuating scalar
  and electromagnetic fields</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Casimir entropy is an important aspect of casimir effect.In this paper,we
employ the path integral method to derive the total relation for casimir
entropy and internal energy of arbitrary shaped objects in the presence of
two,three and four dimensions scalar fields and electromagnetic field.We obtain
the casimir entropy and internal energy of two nanoribbon immersed in scalar
field and two nanospheres immersed in scalar field and electromagnetic
field.The casmir entropy of two nanospheres immersed in the electromagnetic
field in small interval of temperature variations,shown a different behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06120</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rentrop</keyname><forenames>Jan Frederik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meden</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobs</keyname><forenames>Severin Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization group flow of the Luttinger-Ward functional: conserving
  approximations and application to the Anderson impurity model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>27 pages, 5 figures, 16 plots</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 195160 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.195160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the renormalization group flow of the Luttinger-Ward functional and
of its two-particle irreducible vertex functions, given a cut-off in the
two-particle interaction. We derive a conserving approximation to the flow and
relate it to the fluctuation exchange approximation as well as to
non-conserving approximations introduced in an earlier publication ctuation
exchange approximation as well as to nonconserving approximations introducen
[J. F. Rentrop, S. G. Jakobs, and V. Meden, J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48, 145002
(2015)]. We apply the different approximate flow equations to the single
impurity Anderson model in thermal equilibrium at vanishing temperature.
Numerical results for the effective mass, the spin susceptibility, the charge
susceptibility, and the linear conductance reflect the similarity of the
methods to the fluctuation exchange approximation. We find the majority of the
approximations to deviate stronger from the exact results than one-particle
irreducible functional renormalization group schemes. However, we identify a
simple static two-particle irreducible flow scheme which performs remarkably
well and produces an exponential Kondo-like scale in the renormalized level
position.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03195</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Speck</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic thermodynamics for active matter</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>EPL 114, 30006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/30006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theoretical understanding of active matter, which is driven out of
equilibrium by directed motion, is still fragmental and model oriented.
Stochastic thermodynamics, on the other hand, is a comprehensive theoretical
framework for driven systems that allows to define fluctuating work and heat.
We apply these definitions to active matter, assuming that dissipation can be
modelled by effective non-conservative forces. We show that, through the work,
conjugate extensive and intensive observables can be defined even in
non-equilibrium steady states lacking a free energy. As an illustration, we
derive the expressions for the pressure and interfacial tension of active
Brownian particles. The latter becomes negative despite the observed stable
phase separation. We discuss this apparent contradiction, highlighting the role
of fluctuations, and we offer a tentative explanation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05216</id><created>2016-03-16</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guguchia</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khasanov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shengelaya</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pomjakushina</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billinge</keyname><forenames>S. J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morenzoni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooperative coupling of static magnetism and bulk superconductivity in
  the stripe phase of La_2-xBa_xCuO_4: Pressure- and doping-dependent studies</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>17 pages and 17 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Static spin-stripe order and superconductivity were systematically studied in
La_2-xBa_xCuO_4 (0.11 - 0.17) at ambient pressure by means of magnetization and
muSR experiments. We find that all the investigated La_2-xBa_xCuO_4 samples
exhibit static spin-stripe order and that the quasi two-dimensional
superconducting (SC) transition temperature T_c1 and the static spin-stripe
order temperature T_so have very similar values throughout the phase diagram.
Moreover, the magnetic and the SC properties of the x = 0.155 (LBCO-0.155) and
x = 0.17 (LBCO-0.17) samples were studied under hydrostatic pressure. As a
remarkable result, in these bulk cuprate superconductors the three-dimensional
SC transition temperature T_c and T_so nearly coincide at all pressure
investigated (0 - 2.3 GPa). We also observed a pressure induced transition from
long-range spin stripe order to a disordered magnetic state at 1.6 GPa in
LBCO-0.155, coexisting with a SC state with substantial superfluid density. In
LBCO-0.17 a disordered magnetic state is present at all p. The present results
indicate that static magnetic order and SC pairing correlations develop in a
cooperative fashion in La_2-xBa_xCuO_4, and provide a new route of
understanding the complex interplay between static magnetism and
superconductivity in the stripe phase of cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05977</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lacroix</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silk</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moulin</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boehm</keyname><forenames>Celine</forenames></author></authors><title>Connecting the new H.E.S.S. diffuse emission at the Galactic center with
  the Fermi GeV excess: a combination of millisecond pulsars and heavy dark
  matter?</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures; matches version published in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123008 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The H.E.S.S. collaboration has reported a high-energy spherically symmetric
diffuse gamma-ray emission in the inner 50 pc of the Milky Way, up to ~ 50 TeV.
Here we propose a leptonic model which provides an alternative to the hadronic
scenario presented by the H.E.S.S. collaboration, and connects the newly
reported TeV emission to the Fermi-LAT Galactic center GeV excess. Our model
relies on a combination of inverse Compton emission from a population of
millisecond pulsars---which can account for the GeV excess---and a supermassive
black hole-induced spike of heavy (~ 60 TeV) dark matter particles annihilating
into electrons with a sub-thermal cross-section. With an up-to-date
interstellar radiation field, as well as a standard magnetic field and
diffusion set-up, our model accounts for the spectral morphology of the
detected emission. Moreover, we show that the dark matter induced emission
reproduces the spatial morphology of the H.E.S.S. signal above ~ 10 TeV, while
we obtain a slightly more extended component from pulsars at lower energies,
which could be used as a prediction for future H.E.S.S. observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02279</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Gough</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovian Quantum Feedback Networks I: Quantum Transmission Lines,
  Lossless Bounded Real Property and Limit Markovian Channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 122101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4968817</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to set out the problems of modeling quantum
communication and signal processing where the communication between systems via
a non-Markovian channel. This is a general feature of quantum transmission
lines. Our ultimate objective is to extend the networks rules that have been
developed for Markovian models. To this end we recall the Hamiltonian
description of such non-Markov models of transmission lines and their
quantization. These have occurred in the context of non-quilibrium
thermodynamics, but our interest is in the transmission lines as carriers of
information rather than heat baths. We show that there is an analytic
scattering matrix associated with these models and that stability may be
formulated in terms of the lossless bounded real property. Noting that the
input and output fields do not separately satisfy a non-self- demolition
principle, we discuss the rigorous limit in which such models appear Markov and
so amenable to standard approaches of quantum filtering and control
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02337</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bourne</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kellendonk</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rennie</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>The $K$-theoretic bulk-edge correspondence for topological insulators</title><categories>math-ph math.KT math.MP math.OA</categories><comments>Minor corrections, to appear in Annales Henri Poincar\'e</comments><doi>10.1007/s00023-016-0541-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the application of Kasparov theory to topological insulator systems
and the bulk-edge correspondence. We consider observable algebras as modelled
by crossed products, where bulk and edge systems may be linked by a short exact
sequence. We construct unbounded Kasparov modules encoding the dynamics of the
crossed product. We then link bulk and edge Kasparov modules using the Kasparov
product. Because of the anti-linear symmetries that occur in topological
insulator models, real $C^*$-algebras and $KKO$-theory must be used.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02360</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arora</keyname><forenames>Srishti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ligoure</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>Laurence</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay between viscosity and elasticity in freely expanding liquid
  sheets</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Fluids 1, 083302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.1.083302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dynamics of freely expanding liquid sheets prepared with
fluids with different rheological properties, (i) viscous fluids with a
zero-shear viscosity $\eta_0$ in the range $(1-1000) \, \mathrm{mPa.s}$ and
(ii) viscoelastic Maxwell fluids whose elastic modulus, $G_0$, characteristic
relaxation time, $\tau$, and zero-shear viscosity, $\eta_0=G_0 \tau$, can be
tuned over several orders of magnitude. The sheets are produced by impacting a
drop of fluid on a small cylindrical solid target. For viscoelastic fluids, we
show that, when $\tau$ is shorter than the typical lifetime of the sheet ($\sim
10$ ms), the dynamics of the sheet is similar to that of Newtonian viscous
liquids with equal zero-shear viscosity. In that case, for little viscous
samples ($\eta_0 &lt;\sim 30$ mPa.s), the maximal expansion of the sheet,
$d_{\rm{max}}$, is independent of $\eta_0$, whereas for more viscous samples,
$d_{\rm{max}}$ decreases as $\eta_0$ increases. We provide a simple model to
account for the dependence of the maximal expansion of the sheet with the
viscosity that is based on an energy balance between inertia, surface tension
and viscous shear dissipation on the solid target, and which accounts well for
our experimental data. By contrast, when $\tau$ is longer than the typical
lifetime of the sheet, the behavior drastically differs. The sheet expansion is
strongly enhanced as compared to that of viscous samples with comparable
zero-shear viscosity, but is heterogeneous with the occurrence of cracks,
revealing the elastic nature of the viscoelastic fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05582</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsakas</keyname><forenames>Nikolas</forenames></author></authors><title>On Decay Centrality</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish a relationship between decay centrality and two widely used and
computationally cheaper measures of centrality, namely degree and closeness. We
show that for low values of the decay parameter the nodes with maximum decay
centrality also have maximum degree, whereas for high values of the decay
parameter they also maximize closeness. For intermediate values, we provide
sufficient conditions that allow the comparison of decay centrality of
different nodes and we show via numerical simulations that in the vast majority
of networks, the nodes with maximum decay centrality are characterized by a
threshold on the decay parameter below which they belong to the set of nodes
with maximum degree and above which they belong to the set of nodes with
maximum closeness. We also propose a simple rule of thumb that ensures a nearly
optimal choice with very high probability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08887</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Athenodorou</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boucaud</keyname><forenames>Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Soto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Quintero</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafeiropoulos</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gluon Green functions free of Quantum fluctuations</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This letter reports on how the Wilson flow technique can efficaciously kill
the short-distance quantum fluctuations of 2- and 3-gluon Green functions,
removes the $\Lambda_{\rm QCD}$ scale and destroys the transition from the
confining non-perturbative to the asymptotically-free perturbative sector.
After the Wilson flow, the behavior of the Green functions with momenta can be
described in terms of the quasi-classical instanton background. The same
behavior also occurs, before the Wilson flow, at low-momenta. This last result
permits applications as, for instance, the detection of instanton
phenomenological properties or a cheap lattice calibration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00293</id><created>2016-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kirtschig</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Jeroen van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortix</keyname><forenames>Carmine</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface-state spin textures in strained bulk HgTe: strain-induced
  topological phase transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 235437 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235437</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The opening of a band gap due to compressive uniaxial strain renders bulk
HgTe a strong three-dimensional topological insulators with protected gapless
surface states at any surface. By employing a six-band k.p model, we determine
the spin textures of the topological surface states of strained HgTe using
their close relations with the mirror Chern numbers of the system and the
orbital composition of the surface states. We show that at surfaces with C2v
point group symmetry an increase in the strain magnitude triggers a topological
phase transition where the winding number of the surface state spin texture is
flipped while the four topological invariants characterizing the bulk band
structure of the material are unchanged.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02641</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gough</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Stratonovich Formulation of Quantum Feedback Network Rules</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures (The Stratonovich form of the Series Product
  added in the revision.)</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 123505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972217</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We express the rules for forming quantum feedback networks using the
Stratonovich form of quantum stochastic calculus rather than the Ito, or SLH
form. Remarkably the feedback reduction rule implies that we obtain the Schur
complement of the matrix of Stratonovich coupling operators where we short out
the internal input/output coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05040</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitroy</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Yongjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bromley</keyname><forenames>Michael W. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic calculations of quasi-one-electron atoms and ions using
  Laguerre and Slater spinors</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>2 figures, 23 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 94, 062514 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.062514</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A relativistic description of the structure of heavy alkali atoms and
alkali-like ions using S-spinors and L-spinors has been developed. The core
wavefunction is defined by a Dirac-Fock calculation using an S-spinors basis.
The S-spinor basis is then supplemented by a large set of L-spinors for the
calculation of the valence wavefunction in a frozen-core model. The numerical
stability of the L-spinor approach is demonstrated by computing the energies
and decay rates of several low-lying hydrogen eigenstates, along with the
polarizabilities of a $Z=60$ hydrogenic ion. The approach is then applied to
calculate the dynamic polarizabilities of the $5s$, $4d$ and $5p$ states of
Sr$^+$. The magic wavelengths at which the Stark shifts between different pairs
of transitions are zero are computed. Determination of the magic wavelengths
for the $5s \to 4d_{\frac32}$ and $5s \to 4d_{\frac52}$ transitions near
$417$~nm (near the wavelength for the $5s \to 5p_j$ transitions) would allow a
determination of the oscillator strength ratio for the $5s \to 5p_{\frac12}$
and $5s \to 5p_{\frac32}$ transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06204</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-12-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dubeibe</keyname><forenames>F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lora-Clavijo</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Guillermo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudo-Newtonian planar circular restricted 3-body problem</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures. Accepted for publication in Physics Letters A,
  In Press</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A, 381 (6), 563-567, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.12.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of the planar circular restricted three-body problem in
the context of a pseudo-Newtonian approximation. By using the
Fodor-Hoenselaers-Perj\'es procedure, we perform an expansion in the mass
potential of a static massive spherical source up to the first non-Newtonian
term, giving place to a gravitational potential that includes first-order
general relativistic effects. With this result, we model a system composed by
two pseudo-Newtonian primaries describing circular orbits around their common
center of mass, and a test particle orbiting the system in the equatorial
plane. The dynamics of the new system of equations is studied in terms of the
Poincar\'e section method and the Lyapunov exponents, where the introduction of
a new parameter $\epsilon$, allows us to observe the transition from the
Newtonian to the pseudo-Newtonian regime. We show that when the Jacobian
constant is fixed, a chaotic orbit in the Newtonian regime can be either
chaotic or regular in the pseudo-Newtonian approach. As a general result, we
find that most of the pseudo-Newtonian configurations are less stable than
their Newtonian equivalent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00262</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ziepke</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martens</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave propagation in spatially modulated tubes</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4962173</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate wave propagation in rotationally symmetric tubes with a
periodic spatial modulation of cross section. Using an asymptotic perturbation
analysis, the governing quasi two-dimensional reaction-diffusion equation can
be reduced into a one-dimensional reaction-diffusion-advection equation.
Assuming a weak perturbation by the advection term and using projection method,
in a second step, an equation of motion for traveling waves within such tubes
can be derived. Both methods predict properly the nonlinear dependence of the
propagation velocity on the ratio of the modulation period of the geometry to
the intrinsic width of the front, or pulse. As a main feature, we can observe
finite intervals of propagation failure of waves induced by the tube's
modulation. In addition, using the Fick-Jacobs approach for the highly
diffusive limit we show that wave velocities within tubes are governed by an
effective diffusion coefficient. Furthermore, we discuss the effects of a
single bottleneck on the period of pulse trains within tubes. We observe period
changes by integer fractions dependent on the bottleneck width and the period
of the entering pulse train.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04817</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mazelanik</keyname><forenames>Mateusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#x105;browski</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wasilewski</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation steering in the angularly multimode Raman atomic memory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 24 (19), 21995-22003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.021995</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the possibility of steering the direction of correlations between
the off-resonant Raman scattered photons from the angularly multimode atomic
memory based on warm rubidium vapors. Using acousto-optic deflectors (AOD)
driven by different modulation frequencies we experimentally change the angle
of incidence of the laser beams on the atomic ensemble. Performing correlations
measurements for various deflection angles we verify that we can choose the
anti-Stokes light propagation direction independently of the correlated Stokes
scattered light in the continuous way. As a result we can select the spatial
mode of photons retrieved from the memory, which may be important for future
development of quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06433</id><created>2016-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Tao-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Xue-Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanism of High-Order Harmonic Generation from Periodic Potentials</title><categories>physics.optics physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>optics express 25,151 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.000151</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically the Bloch electron wave-packet dynamics in periodic
potentials to simulate laser-solid interactions. We introduce a quasi-classical
model in the \emph{k} space combined with the energy band structure to
understand the high-order harmonic generation (HHG) process occurring in a
subcycle timescale. This model interprets the multiple plateau structure in HHG
spectra well and the linear dependence of cutoff energies on the amplitude of
vector potential of the laser fields. It also predicts the emission time of
HHG, which agrees well with the results by solving the time-dependent
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation (TDSE). It provides a scheme to reconstruct the energy
dispersion relations in Brillouin zone and to control the trajectories of HHG
by varying the shape of laser pulses. This model is instructive for
experimental measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00140</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ozawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carusotto</keyname><forenames>Iacopo</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthetic Dimensions with Magnetic Fields and Local Interactions in
  Photonic Lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>6+2 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 013601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.013601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss how one can realize a photonic device that combines synthetic
dimensions and synthetic magnetic fields with spatially local interactions.
Using an array of ring cavities, the angular coordinate around each cavity
spans the synthetic dimension. The synthetic magnetic field arises as the
intercavity photon hopping is associated with a change of angular momentum.
Photon-photon interactions are local in the periodic angular coordinate around
each cavity. Experimentally observable consequences of the synthetic magnetic
field and of the local interactions are pointed out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00865</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2016-07-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>Rafael M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chubukov</keyname><forenames>Andrey V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-energy microscopic models for iron-based superconductors: a review</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Review paper; 39 pages, 24 figures; comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 80, 014503 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6633/80/1/014503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of sensible microscopic models is essential to elucidate the
normal-state and superconducting properties of the iron-based superconductors.
Because these materials are mostly metallic, a good starting point is an
effective low-energy model that captures the electronic states near the Fermi
level and their interactions. However, in contrast to cuprates, iron-based
high-$T_{c}$ compounds are multi-orbital systems with Hubbard and Hund
interactions, resulting in a rather involved 10-orbital lattice model. Here we
review different minimal models that have been proposed to unveil the universal
features of these systems. We first review minimal models defined solely in the
orbital basis, which focus on a particular subspace of orbitals, or solely in
the band basis, which rely only on the geometry of the Fermi surface. The
former, while providing important qualitative insight into the role of the
orbital degrees of freedom, do not distinguish between high-energy and
low-energy sectors and, for this reason, generally do not go beyond mean-field.
The latter allow one to go beyond mean-field and investigate the interplay
between superconducting and magnetic orders as well as Ising-nematic order.
However, they cannot capture orbital-dependent features like spontaneous
orbital order. We then review recent proposals for a minimal model that
operates in the band basis but fully incorporates the orbital composition and
symmetries of the low-energy excitations. We discuss the results of the
renormalization group study of such a model, particularly of the interplay
between superconductivity, magnetism, and spontaneous orbital order, and
compare theoretical predictions with experiments on iron pnictides and
chalcogenides. We also discuss the impact of the glide-plane symmetry on the
low-energy models, highlighting the key role played by the spin-orbit coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02814</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Dewang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Jianhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Ronger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Shengnian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yizheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Jingbo</forenames></author></authors><title>Powerful and Tunable THz Emitters Based on the Fe/Pt Magnetic
  Heterostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Advanced Optical Materials 4 (12), 1944-1949</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adom.201600270</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we report our study on the THz emission in Fe/Pt magnetic
heterostructures. We have carried out a comprehensive investigation of THz
emission from Fe/Pt magnetic heterostructures, employing time-domain THz
spectroscopy. We reveal that by properly tuning the thickness of Fe or Pt
layer, THz emission can be greatly improved in this type of heterostructure. We
further demonstrate that the THz field strength emitted from a newly designed
multilayer (Pt/Fe/MgO)$_n$ with n=3 can reach a value of ~1.6 kV/cm, which is
comparable to the values from the conventional GaAs antenna with a bias of 4
kV/cm, and the nonlinear crystals, e.g., 100 micrometer GaP and 2 mm ZnTe. For
the first time, the intensity and spectrum of THz wave is demonstrated to be
tunable by the magnetic field applied on the patterned magnetic Fe/Pt
heterostructures. These findings thus promise novel approaches to fabricate
powerful and tunable THz emitters based on magnetic heterostructure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03262</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Donini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pena</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero-L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-leptonic kaon decays at large $N_c$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>Expanded discussion. Conclusions unchanged. Published version</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-39, IFT-UAM/CSIC-16-063, FTUAM-16-26</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the scaling with the number of colours, $N_c$, of the weak
amplitudes mediating kaon mixing and decay. We evaluate the amplitudes of the
two relevant current-current operators on the lattice for $N_c=3-7$. We
conclude that the subleading $1/N_c$ corrections in $\hat{B}_K$ are small, but
those in the $K \rightarrow \pi\pi$ amplitudes are large and fully
anti-correlated in the $I=0, 2$ isospin channels. We briefly comment on the
implications for the $\Delta I=1/2$ rule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03925</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hua</keyname><forenames>Wenqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuzhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiuhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Fenggang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Microfocus small-angle X-ray scattering at SSRF BL16B1</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/4/048001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Offering high-brilliance X-ray beams on micrometer length scales, the
microfocus-SAXS at SSRF BL16B1 was established with a KB mirror system for
studying small sample volumes, or probing micro-scopic morphologies. The SAXS
minimum q value was 0.1nm-1 with a flux of 1.5 * 10^10 photons/s. Two
position-resolved scanning experimental methods were combined with
microfocus-SAXS that include STXM and CT. To improve the significant smearing
effect in the horizontal direction, an effective and easy-to-use desmearing
procedure for two-dimensional SAXS pattern based on the blind deconvolution was
developed and the deblurring results demonstrated the good restoration effect
for the defocus image. Finally, a bamboo sample was selected for SAXS-CT
experiment which illustrated the performance of the microfocus-SAXS method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04640</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>Eric C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vojta</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Honeycomb-lattice Heisenberg-Kitaev model in a magnetic field: Spin
  canting, metamagnetism, and vortex crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5+9 pages, 4+8 figures; v2: discussion of quantum effects and Klein
  duality extended, references added, several minor improvements</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 277202 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.277202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Heisenberg-Kitaev model is a paradigmatic model to describe the magnetism
in honeycomb-lattice Mott insulators with strong spin-orbit coupling, such as
A$_2$IrO$_3$ (A = Na, Li) and $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$. Here we study in detail the
physics of the Heisenberg-Kitaev model in an external magnetic field. Using a
combination of Monte-Carlo simulations and spin-wave theory we map out the
classical phase diagram for different directions of the magnetic field. Broken
SU(2) spin symmetry renders the magnetization process rather complex, with
sequences of phases and metamagnetic transitions. In particular, we find
various large-unit-cell and multi-Q phases including a vortex-crystal phase for
a field in the [111] direction. We also discuss quantum corrections in the
high-field phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00175</id><created>2016-07-30</created><updated>2016-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liarte</keyname><forenames>Danilo B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posen</keyname><forenames>Sam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Transtrum</keyname><forenames>Mark K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catelani</keyname><forenames>Gianluigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liepe</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sethna</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical estimates of maximum fields in superconducting resonant
  radio frequency cavities: Stability theory, disorder, and laminates</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Supercond. Sci. Technol. 30, 033002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6668/30/3/033002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretical limits to the performance of superconductors in high magnetic
fields parallel to their surfaces are of key relevance to current and future
accelerating cavities, especially those made of new higher-Tc materials such as
Nb$_3$Sn, NbN, and MgB$_2$. Indeed, beyond the so-called superheating field
$H_{\mathcal{sh}}$, flux will spontaneously penetrate even a perfect
superconducting surface and ruin the performance. We present intuitive
arguments and simple estimates for $H_{\mathcal{sh}}$, and combine them with
our previous rigorous calculations, which we summarize. We briefly discuss
experimental measurements of the superheating field, comparing to our
estimates. We explore the effects of materials anisotropy and the danger of
disorder in nucleating vortex entry. Will we need to control surface
orientation in the layered compound MgB$_2$? Can we estimate theoretically
whether dirt and defects make these new materials fundamentally more
challenging to optimize than niobium? Finally, we discuss and analyze recent
proposals to use thin superconducting layers or laminates to enhance the
performance of superconducting cavities. Flux entering a laminate can lead to
so-called pancake vortices; we consider the physics of the dislocation motion
and potential re-annihilation or stabilization of these vortices after their
entry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00183</id><created>2016-07-30</created><updated>2016-12-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Xiaoling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Huifang</forenames></author></authors><title>High-momentum distribution with subleading $k^{-3}$ tail in the odd-wave
  interacting one-dimensional Fermi gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures; accepted version by Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063650 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063650</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the odd-wave interacting identical fermions in one-dimension with
finite effective range. We show that to fully describe the high-momentum
distribution $\rho(k)$ up to $k^{-4}$, one needs four parameters characterizing
the properties when two particles {\it contact} with each other. Two parameters
are related to the variation of energy with respect to the odd-wave scattering
length and the effective range, respectively, determining the $k^{-2}$ tail and
part of $k^{-4}$ tail in $\rho(k)$. The other two parameters are related to the
center-of-mass motion of the system, respectively determining the $k^{-3}$ tail
and the other part of $k^{-4}$ tail. We point out that the unusual $k^{-3}$
tail, which has not been discovered before in atomic systems, is an intrinsic
component to complete the general form of $\rho(k)$ and also realistically
detectable under certain experimental conditions. Various other universal
relations are also derived in terms of those contact parameters, and finally
the results are confirmed through the exact solution of a two-body problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00976</id><created>2016-08-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Tovmasyan</keyname><forenames>Murad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peotta</keyname><forenames>Sebastiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf6;rm&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>P&#xe4;ivi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Sebastian D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective theory and emergent $SU(2)$ symmetry in the flat bands of
  attractive Hubbard models</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245149 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a partially filled flat Bloch band electrons do not have a well defined
Fermi surface and hence the low-energy theory is not a Fermi liquid.
Neverethless, under the influence of an attractive interaction, a
superconductor well described by the Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) wave
function can arise. Here we study the low-energy effective Hamiltonian of a
generic Hubbard model with a flat band. We obtain an effective Hamiltonian for
the flat band physics by eliminating higher lying bands via perturbative
Schrieffer-Wolff transformation. At first order in the interaction energy we
recover the usual procedure of projecting the interaction term onto the flat
band Wannier functions. We show that the BCS wave function is the exact ground
state of the projected interaction Hamiltonian and that the compressibility is
diverging as a consequence of an emergent $SU(2)$ symmetry. This symmetry is
broken by second order interband transitions resulting in a finite
compressibility, which we illustrate for a one-dimensional ladder with two
perfectly flat bands. These results motivate a further approximation leading to
an effective ferromagnetic Heisenberg model. The gauge-invariant result for the
superfluid weight of a flat band can be obtained from the ferromagnetic
Heisenberg model only if the maximally localized Wannier functions in the
Marzari-Vanderbilt sense are used. Finally, we prove an important inequality $D
\geq \mathcal{W}^2$ between the Drude weight $D$ and the winding number
$\mathcal{W}$, which guarantees ballistic transport for topologically
nontrivial flat bands in one dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01466</id><created>2016-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Rein</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Speck</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Applicability of Effective Pair Potentials for Active Brownian Particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. E 39, 84 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epje/i2016-16084-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed a case study investigating a recently proposed scheme to
obtain an effective pair potential for active Brownian particles [Farage et
al., Phys. Rev. E 91, 042310 (2015)]. Applying this scheme to the Lennard-Jones
potential, numerical simulations of active Brownian particles are compared to
simulations of passive Brownian particles interacting by the effective pair
potential. Analyzing the static pair correlations, our results indicate a
limited range of activity parameters (speed and orientational correlation time)
for which we obtain quantitative, or even qualitative, agreement. Moreover, we
find a qualitatively different behavior for the virial pressure even for small
propulsion speeds. Combining these findings we conclude that beyond linear
response active particles exhibit genuine non-equilibrium properties that
cannot be captured by effective pair interaction alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01483</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kvasil</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesterenko</keyname><forenames>V. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Repko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinig</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinhard</keyname><forenames>P. -G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deformation-induced splitting of isoscalar E0 giant resonance: Skyrme
  random-phase-approximation analysis</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review C, v.94, n.6, 064302(1-9) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.064302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deformation-induced splitting of isoscalar giant monopole resonance
(ISGMR) is systematically analyzed in a wide range of masses covering medium,
rare-earth, actinide, and superheavy axial deformed nuclei. The study is
performed within the fully self-consistent quasiparticle
random-phase-approximation (QRPA) method based on the Skyrme functional. Two
Skyrme forces, one with a large (SV-bas) and one with a small (SkP) nuclear
incompressibility, are considered. The calculations confirm earlier results
that, due to the deformation-induced E0-E2 coupling, the isoscalar E0 resonance
attains a double-peak structure and significant energy upshift. Our results are
compared with available analytic estimations. Unlike earlier studies, we get a
smaller energy difference between the lower and upper peaks and thus a stronger
E0-E2 coupling. This in turn results in more pumping of E0 strength into the
lower peak and more pronounced splitting of ISGMR. We also discuss widths of
the peaks and their negligible correlation with deformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04130</id><created>2016-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ding</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanzadeh</keyname><forenames>Pedram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuang</keyname><forenames>Zhiming</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying the eddy-jet feedback strength of the annular mode in an
  idealized GCM and reanalysis data</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>revision submitted to the Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1175/JAS-D-16-0157.1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A linear response function (LRF) that relates the temporal tendency of zonal
mean temperature and zonal wind to their anomalies and external forcing is used
to accurately quantify the strength of the eddy-jet feedback associated with
the annular mode in an idealized GCM. Following a simple feedback model, the
results confirm the presence of a positive eddy-jet feedback in the annular
mode dynamics, with a feedback strength of 0.137 day$^{-1}$ in the idealized
GCM. Statistical methods proposed by earlier studies to quantify the feedback
strength are evaluated against results from the LRF. It is argued that the
mean-state-independent eddy forcing reduces the accuracy of these statistical
methods because of the quasi-oscillatory nature of the eddy forcing. A new
method is proposed to approximate the feedback strength as the regression
coefficient of low-pass filtered eddy forcing onto low-pass filtered annular
mode index, which converges to the value produced by the LRF when timescales
longer than 200 days are used for the low-pass filtering. Applying the new
low-pass filtering method to the reanalysis data, the feedback strength in the
Southern annular mode is found to be 0.121 day$^{-1}$, which is presented as an
improvement over previous estimates. This work also highlights the importance
of using sub-daily data in the analysis by showing the significant contribution
of medium-scale waves of periods less than 2 days to the annular mode dynamics,
which was under-appreciated in most of previous research. The present study
provides a framework to quantify the eddy-jet feedback strength in models and
reanalysis data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04531</id><created>2016-08-16</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pati</keyname><forenames>Satya Prakash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Mahdawi</keyname><forenames>Muftah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Shujun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiokawa</keyname><forenames>Yohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nozaki</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahashi</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size scaling effect on N\'eel temperature of antiferromagnetic
  Cr$_2$O$_3$-(0001) films in an exchange-coupled heterostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B, vol. 94, no. 22, p. 224417, Dec. 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.224417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The scaling of antiferromagnetic ordering temperature of corundum-type
chromia films have been investigated. N\'eel temperature $T_N$ was determined
from the effect of perpendicular exchange-bias on the magnetization of a
weakly-coupled adjacent ferromagnet. For a thick-film case, the validity of
detection is confirmed by a susceptibility measurement. Detection of $T_N$ was
possible down to 1-nm-thin chromia films. The scaling of ordering temperature
with thickness was studied using different buffering materials, and compared
with Monte-Carlo simulations. The spin-correlation length and the corresponding
critical exponent were estimated, and they were consistent between experimental
and simulation results. The spin-correlation length is an order of magnitude
less than cubic antiferromagnets. We propose that the difference is from the
change of number of exchange-coupling links in the two crystal systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06789</id><created>2016-08-24</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Torfason</keyname><forenames>Kristinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valfells</keyname><forenames>Agust</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manolescu</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Field Emission From a Prolate
  Spheroidal Tip</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas (Vol.23, Issue 12), 27 December 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972821</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High resolution molecular dynamics simulations with full Coulomb interactions
of electrons are used to investigate field emission from a prolate spheroidal
tip. The space charge limited current is several times lower than the current
calculated with the Fowler-Nordheim formula. The image-charge is taken into
account with a spherical approximation, which is good around the top of the
tip, i.e. region where the current is generated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08633</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rachel</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goethel</keyname><forenames>Ilja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arovas</keyname><forenames>Daniel P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vojta</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain-induced Landau Levels in arbitrary dimensions with an exact
  spectrum</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 + 9 pages; v4: final version including references to hyperdiamond
  lattices</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 266801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.266801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Certain non-uniform strain applied to graphene flakes has been shown to
induce pseudo-Landau levels in the single-particle spectrum, which can be
rationalized in terms of a pseudo-magnetic field for electrons near the Dirac
points. However, this Landau level structure is in general approximate and
restricted to low energies. Here we introduce a family of strained bipartite
tight-binding models in arbitrary spatial dimension d and analytically prove
that their entire spectrum consists of perfectly degenerate pseudo-Landau
levels. This construction generalizes the case of triaxial strain on graphene's
honeycomb lattice to arbitrary d; in d=3 our model corresponds to tetraxial
strain on the diamond lattice. We discuss general aspects of pseudo-Landau
levels in arbitrary d.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02533</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barash</keyname><forenames>Yu. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Proximity-induced minimum radius of superconducting thin rings closed by
  the Josephson 0 or pi junction</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024503 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconductivity is shown to be completely destroyed in thin mesoscopic or
nanoscopic rings closed by the junction with a noticeable interfacial pair
breaking and/or a Josephson coupling, if a ring's radius r is less than the
minimum radius r_min. The quantity r_min depends on the phase difference across
the junction, or on the magnetic flux that controls the phase difference in the
flux-biased ring. It also depends on the Josephson and interfacial effective
coupling constants, and in particular, on whether the ring is closed by 0 or pi
junction. The current-phase relation is substantially modified when the ring's
radius exceeds r_min for some of the phase difference values, or slightly goes
beyond its maximum. The modified critical temperature Tc, as well as the
temperature dependent supercurrent near Tc are identified here as functions of
the ring's radius and the magnetic flux.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06640</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moessner</keyname><forenames>Roderich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hooley</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Slow relaxation and sensitivity to disorder in trapped lattice fermions
  after a quench</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063643 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063643</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a system of non-interacting fermions in one dimension subject to
a single-particle potential consisting of (a) a strong optical lattice, (b) a
harmonic trap, and (c) uncorrelated on-site disorder. After a quench, in which
the center of the harmonic trap is displaced, we study the occupation function
of the fermions and the time-evolution of experimental observables.
Specifically, we present numerical and analytical results for the post-quench
occupation function of the fermions, and analyse the time-evolution of the
real-space density profile. Unsurprisingly for a non-interacting (and therefore
integrable) system, the infinite-time limit of the density profile is
non-thermal. However, due to Bragg-localization of the higher-energy
single-particle states, the approach to even this non-thermal state is
extremely slow. We quantify this statement, and show that it implies a
sensitivity to disorder parametrically stronger than that expected from
Anderson localization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08046</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pietzonka</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barato</keyname><forenames>Andre C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seifert</keyname><forenames>Udo</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal bound on the efficiency of molecular motors</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.BM</categories><comments>Invited contribution to proceedings of STATPHYS26, Lyon</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 124004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/12/124004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermodynamic uncertainty relation provides an inequality relating any
mean current, the associated dispersion and the entropy production rate for
arbitrary non-equilibrium steady states. Applying it here to a general model of
a molecular motor running against an external force or torque, we show that the
thermodynamic efficiency of such motors is universally bounded by an expression
involving only experimentally accessible quantities. For motors pulling cargo
through a viscous fluid, a universal bound for the corresponding Stokes
efficiency follows as a variant. A similar result holds if mechanical force is
used to synthesize molecules of high chemical potential. Crucially, no
knowledge of the detailed underlying mechano-chemical mechanism is required for
applying these bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08540</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Doma&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>Tadeusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17d;onda</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pokorn&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>Vladislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;rski</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jani&#x161;</keyname><forenames>V&#xe1;clav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novotn&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>Tom&#xe1;&#x161;</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson-phase-controlled interplay between correlation effects and
  electron pairing in a three-terminal nanostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures; v2: minor text corrections, nearly identical to
  the published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the subgap spectrum of the interacting single-level quantum dot
coupled between two superconducting reservoirs, forming the Josephson-type
circuit, and additionally hybridized with a metallic normal lead. This system
allows for the phase-tunable interplay between the correlation effects and the
proximity-induced electron pairing resulting in the singlet-doublet (0-$\pi$)
crossover and the phase-dependent Kondo effect. We investigate the spectral
function, induced local pairing, Josephson supercurrent, and Andreev
conductance in a wide range of system parameters by the numerically exact
Numerical Renormalization Group and Quantum Monte Carlo calculations along with
perturbative treatments in terms of the Coulomb repulsion and the hybridization
term. Our results address especially the correlation effects reflected in
dependencies of various quantities on the local Coulomb interaction strength as
well as on the coupling to the normal lead. We quantitatively establish the
phase-dependent Kondo temperature $\log T_{K}(\phi)\propto\cos^{2}(\phi/2)$ and
show that it can be read off from the half-width of the zero-bias enhancement
in the Andreev conductance in the doublet phase, which can be experimentally
measured by the tunneling spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01794</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Neronov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semikoz</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vovk</keyname><forenames>Ie.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirzoyan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic ray composition measurements and cosmic ray background free
  gamma-ray observations with Cherenkov telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123018 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Muon component of extensive air showers (EAS) initiated by cosmic ray
particles carries information on the primary particle identity. We show that
the muon content of EAS could be measured in a broad energy range from 10-100
TeV up to ultra-high-energy cosmic ray range using wide field-of-view imaging
atmospheric Cherenkov telescopes observing strongly inclined or nearly
horizontal EAS from the ground of from high altitude. Cherenkov emission from
muons in such EAS forms a distinct component (halo or tail) of the EAS image in
the telescope camera. We show that detection of the muon signal could be used
to measure composition of the cosmic ray spectrum in the energy ranges of the
knee, the ankle and of the Galactic-to-extragalactic transition. It could also
be used to veto the cosmic ray background in gamma-ray observations. This
technique provides a possibility for up to two orders of magnitude improvement
of sensitivity for gamma-ray flux in the energy band above 10 PeV, compared to
KASCADE-Grande, and an order-of-magnitude improvement of sensitivity in the
multi-EeV energy band, compared to Pierre Auger Observatory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02320</id><created>2016-10-07</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#x160;ari&#x107;</keyname><forenames>An&#x111;ela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michaels</keyname><forenames>Thomas C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaccone</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knowles</keyname><forenames>Tuomas P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Daan</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetics of spontaneous filament nucleation via oligomers: insights from
  theory and simulation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics The Journal of Chemical Physics J.
  Chem. Phys. 145, 211926 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4965040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nucleation processes are at the heart of a large number of phenomena, from
cloud formation to protein crystallization. A recently emerging area where
nucleation is highly relevant is the initiation of filamentous protein
self-assembly, a process that has broad implications from medicine to
nanotechnology. As such, spontaneous nucleation of protein fibrils has received
much attention in recent years with many theoretical and experimental studies
focussing on the underlying physical principles. In this paper we make a step
forward in this direction and explore the early time behaviour of filamentous
protein growth in the context of nucleation theory. We first provide an
overview of the thermodynamics and kinetics of spontaneous nucleation of
protein filaments in the presence of one relevant degree of freedom, namely the
cluster size. In this case, we review how key kinetic observables, such as the
reaction order of spontaneous nucleation, are directly related to the physical
size of the critical nucleus. We then focus on the increasingly prominent case
of filament nucleation that includes a conformational conversion of the
nucleating building-block as an additional slow step in the nucleation process.
Using computer simulations, we study the concentration dependence of the
nucleation rate. We find that, under these circumstances, the reaction order of
spontaneous nucleation with respect to the free monomer does no longer relate
to the overall physical size of the nucleating aggregate but rather to the
portion of the aggregate that actively participates in the conformational
conversion. Our results thus provide a novel interpretation of the common
kinetic descriptors of protein filament formation, including the reaction order
of the nucleation step or the scaling exponent of lag times, and put into
perspective current theoretical descriptions of protein aggregation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03621</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>H&#xe4;berle</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oeckinghaus</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmid-Lorch</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfender</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Felipe F&#xe1;varo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momenzadeh</keyname><forenames>Seyed Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finkler</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrachtrup</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Quantum-Assisted Magnetometer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>Accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 88, 013702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic sensing and imaging instruments are important tools in biological
and material sciences. There is an increasing demand for attaining higher
sensitivity and spatial resolution, with implementations using a single qubit
offering potential improvements in both directions. In this article we describe
a scanning magnetometer based on the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond as the
sensor. By means of a quantum-assisted readout scheme together with advances in
photon collection efficiency, our device exhibits an enhancement in signal to
noise ratio of close to an order of magnitude compared to the standard
fluorescence readout of the nitrogen-vacancy center. This is demonstrated by
comparing non-assisted and assisted methods in a $T_1$ relaxation time
measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04952</id><created>2016-10-16</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miloshevich</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lingam</keyname><forenames>Manasvi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrison</keyname><forenames>Philip J.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the structure and statistical theory of turbulence of extended
  magnetohydrodynamics</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.SR physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>32 pages, 6 figures, 1 table. Added references, corrected typos.
  Clarified introduction to sections IVa and IVb (Results unchanged)</comments><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa55eb</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent progress regarding the noncanonical Hamiltonian formulation of
extended magnetohydrodynamics (XMHD), a model with Hall drift and electron
inertia, is summarized. The advantages of the Hamiltonian approach are invoked
to study some general properties of XMHD turbulence, and to compare them
against their ideal MHD counterparts. For instance, the helicity flux transfer
rates for XMHD are computed, and Liouville's theorem for this model is also
verified. The latter is used, in conjunction with the absolute equilibrium
states, to arrive at the spectra for the invariants, and to determine the
direction of the cascades, e.g., generalizations of the well-known ideal MHD
inverse cascade of magnetic helicity. After a similar analysis is conducted for
XMHD by inspecting second order structure functions and absolute equilibrium
states, a couple of interesting results emerge. When cross helicity is taken to
be ignorable, the inverse cascade of injected magnetic helicity also occurs in
the Hall MHD range - this is shown to be consistent with previous results in
the literature. In contrast, in the inertial MHD range, viz. at scales smaller
than the electron skin depth, all spectral quantities are expected to undergo
direct cascading. The consequences and relevance of our results in space and
astrophysical plasmas are also briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08150</id><created>2016-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Lu-You</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Deng-Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Chen-Zhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarizabilities and tune-out wavelengths of the hyperfine ground states
  of $^{87,85}$Rb</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 94, 052510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.052510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The static and dynamic polarizabilities, and the tune-out wavelengths of the
ground state of Rb and the hyperfine ground states of $^{87, 85}$Rb have been
calculated by using relativistic configuration interaction plus core
polarization(RCICP) approach. It is found that the first primary tune-out
wavelengths of the $ 5s_{1/2}, F=1, 2 $ states of $ ^{87}$Rb are
790.018187(193) nm and 790.032602(193) nm severally, where the calculated
result for the $ 5s_{1/2}, F=2 $ state is in good agreement with the latest
high-precision measurement 790.032388(32) nm [Phys. Rev. A 92, 052501 (2015)].
Similarly, the first primary tune-out wavelengths of the $ 5s_{1/2}, F=2, 3 $
states of $^{85}$Rb are 790.023515(218) nm and 790.029918(218) nm respectively.
Furthermore, the tune-out wavelengths for the different magnetic sublevels $
M_{F}$ of each hyperfine level $F$ are also determined by considering the
contributions of tensor polarizabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08952</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guica</keyname><forenames>Monica</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk fields from the boundary OPE</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Added a detailed derivation of the bulk field in radial gauge, an
  appendix, references and various comments and cosmetic changes</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2016-144</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous work has established an equality between the geodesic integral of a
free bulk field in AdS and the contribution of the conformal descendants of its
dual CFT primary operator to the OPE of two other operators inserted at the
endpoints of the geodesic. Working in the context of the AdS$_3$/CFT$_2$
correspondence, we extend this relation to include the $1/N$ corrections to the
bulk field obtained by dressing it with i) a $U(1)$ current and ii) the CFT
stress tensor. In the former case, we argue that the contribution of the
Ka\v{c}-Moody descendants to the respective boundary OPE equals the geodesic
integral of a particular $U(1)$-dressed bulk field, which is framed to the
boundary via a split Wilson line. In the latter case, we compute the
gravitational $1/N$ corrections to the bulk field in various gauges, and then
write a CFT expression for a putative bulk field whose geodesic integral
captures the contribution of Virasoro descendants to the OPE of interest. We
comment on the bulk interpretation of this expression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09452</id><created>2016-10-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Tamara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkinson</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterising Dark Energy through supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Chapter prepared for publication in the &quot;Handbook of Supernovae&quot;,
  Springer, edited by Athem W. Alsabti and Paul Murdin. 14 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-20794-0_106-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type Ia supernovae are a powerful cosmological probe, that gave the first
strong evidence that the expansion of the universe is accelerating. Here we
provide an overview of how supernovae can go further to reveal information
about what is causing the acceleration, be it dark energy or some modification
to our laws of gravity. We first summarise the many different approaches used
to explain or test the acceleration, including parametric models (like the
standard model, LambdaCDM), non-parametric models, dark fluid models such as
quintessence, and extensions to standard gravity. We also show how supernova
data can be used beyond the Hubble diagram, to give information on
gravitational lensing and peculiar velocities that can be used to distinguish
between models that predict the same expansion history. Finally, we review the
methods of statistical inference that are commonly used, making a point of
separating parameter estimation from model selection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09839</id><created>2016-10-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xuanyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shengli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Haiyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>La-doping effect on spin-orbit coupled Sr2IrO4 probed by x-ray
  absorption spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1610.09817</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18(2016) 093019</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/9/093019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sr2IrO4 was predicted to be an unconventional superconductor upon carrier
doping since it highly resembles the high-temperature cuprates. Here, to
understand carrier doping effect on spin-orbit coupled Mott insulator Sr2IrO4,
the electronic structure and local structure distortion for Sr2-xLaxIrO4 system
have been investigated by x-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS). By comparing the
intensity of white-line features at the Ir L2,3 absorption edges, we observe
remarkably large branching ratios in La-doped compounds, greater than that of
the parent material Sr2IrO4, suggesting a strong spin-orbit interaction (SOI)
for Sr2IrO4-based system. Moreover, extended x-ray absorption fine structure
(EXAFS) spectra demonstrate more regular IrO6 octahedra, i.e. the weakened
crystal electric field (CEF) versus La-doping. By theoretical calculations, the
synergistic effect of regular IrO6 octahedra and electron doping is
established, which accounts for the transition from a Mott insulator to a
conductive state in Sr2-xLaxIrO4-based system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00240</id><created>2016-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Weeks</keyname><forenames>Eric R.</forenames></author></authors><title>An introduction to the colloidal glass transition</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>Review article which is more concise than Hunter &amp; Weeks, Rep. Prog.
  Phys. 2012</comments><journal-ref>ACS Macro Lett. 6, 27-34 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsmacrolett.6b00826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colloids are suspensions of small solid particles in a liquid, and exhibit
glassy behavior when the particle concentration is high. In these samples, the
particles are roughly analogous to individual molecules in a traditional glass.
This model system has been used to study the glass transition since the 1980's.
In this Viewpoint we summarize some of the intriguing behaviors of the glass
transition in colloids, and discuss open questions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00262</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magorrian</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xf3;lyomi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fal'ko</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic and optical properties of two-dimensional InSe from a
  DFT-parameterized tight-binding model</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245431 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a tight-binding (TB) model and $\mathbf{k\cdot p}$ theory for
electrons in monolayer and few-layer InSe. The model is constructed from a
basis of all $s$ and $p$ valence orbitals on both indium and selenium atoms,
with tight-binding parameters obtained from fitting to independently computed
density functional theory (DFT) band structures for mono- and bilayer InSe. For
the valence and conduction band edges of few-layer InSe, which appear to be in
the vicinity of the $\Gamma$ point, we calculate the absorption coefficient for
the principal optical transitions as a function of the number of layers, $N$.
We find a strong dependence on $N$ of the principal optical transition
energies, selection rules, and optical oscillation strengths, in agreement with
recent observations \cite{Bandurin2016}. Also, we find that the conduction band
electrons are relatively light ($m \propto 0.14-0.18 m_e$), in contrast to an
almost flat, and slightly inverted, dispersion of valence band holes near the
$\Gamma$-point, which is found for up to $N \propto 6$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00311</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Butson</keyname><forenames>Dylan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Philsang</forenames></author></authors><title>Degenerate Classical Field Theories and Boundary Theories</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA math.RT</categories><comments>38 pages, content still being updated; comments welcome!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a framework for degenerate classical field theories in the BV
formalism, which allows us to discuss many interesting examples of theories
which do not admit a Lagrangian description. Further, we study phase spaces and
boundary conditions for classical field theories on manifolds with boundary,
and from a fixed classical field theory together with a choice of boundary
condition, construct a degenerate classical field theory on the boundary. We
apply these ideas to many physically interesting examples including the
Kapustin-Witten twists of N=4 supersymmetric Yang-Mills, Chern-Simons theory,
the chiral Wess-Zumino-Witten model, chiral Toda theory, and a new 3d classical
field theory called Whittaker theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03492</id><created>2016-11-10</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-interacting Dark Matter Without Direct Detection Constraints</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures. References and a general discussion of indirect
  detection constraint added. Published version</comments><report-no>NUHEP-TH/16-06</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Dark Univ. 15 (2017) 82-89</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.dark.2016.12.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the self-interacting dark matter scenario in a simple dark sector
model where the dark matter interacts through a dark photon. Splitting a Dirac
fermion dark matter into two levels using a small Majorana mass can evade
strong direct detection constraints on the kinetic mixing between the dark and
normal photons, thus allowing the dark sector to be more visible at high
intensity and/or high energy experiments. It is pointed out that such a mass
splitting has a strong impact on the dark matter self-interaction strength. We
derive the new parameter space of a pseudo-Dirac self-interacting dark matter.
Interestingly, with increasing mass splitting, a weak scale dark matter mass
window survives that could be probed by the LHC and future colliders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04259</id><created>2016-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Setare</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adami</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Horizon Fluffs: In the Context of Generalized Minimal Massive Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1606.05260</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a metric which describes Ba$\tilde{\text{n}}$ados geometries and
show that the considered metric is a solution of generalized minimal massive
gravity (GMMG) model. We consider the Killing vector field which preserves the
form of considered metric. Using the off-shell quasi-local approach we obtain
the asymptotic conserved charges of given solution. Similar to the Einstein
gravity in the presence of negative cosmological constant, for the GMMG model
also, we show that the algebra among the asymptotic conserved charges is
isomorphic to two copies of the Virasoro algebra. Eventually, we find relation
between the algebra of the near horizon and the asymptotic conserved charges.
This relation show that the main part of the horizon fluffs proposal of
Refs.\cite{140,14} appear for generic black holes in the class of
Ba$\tilde{\text{n}}$ados geometries in the context of GMMG model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01423</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarisaman</keyname><forenames>Mustafa</forenames></author></authors><title>Unidirectional reflectionlessness and invisibility in the TE and TM
  modes of a PT-symmetric slab system</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 1 table, 24 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013806 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unidirectional invisibility of a PT-symmetric optical system is of great
interest, but challenging as well since it is infeasible to fulfill it through
wide optical frequency ranges in all angular directions. Accordingly we study
reflectionless and invisible patterns in the TE and TM modes of an optical slab
system consisting of adjacent or separated pair of balanced gain and loss
layers with a gap. We provide a comprehensive study of one of the simplest
experimentally accessible examples of a unidirectionally reflectionless and
invisible PT-symmetric optical slab system. We obtain the physically optimal
conditions for the realization of these phenomena. We derive analytic
expressions, and show that only certain gain amounts restricted to take values
between certain minimum and maximum values give rise to uni/bi-directionally
invisible configurations. The size of gap decides the measure of
reflectionlessness and invisibility parameters, especially on gain value and
incident angle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02495</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-01-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magee</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niemeyer</keyname><forenames>Kyle E</forenames></author></authors><title>An initial investigation of the performance of GPU-based swept
  time-space decomposition</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cs.DC cs.MS</categories><comments>14 pages; submitted to 2017 AIAA SciTech Forum</comments><msc-class>65M55 (Primary), 35Q35 (Secondary)</msc-class><acm-class>G.1.8; G.4; J.2</acm-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Simulations of physical phenomena are essential to the expedient design of
precision components in aerospace and other high-tech industries. These
phenomena are often described by mathematical models involving partial
differential equations (PDEs) without exact solutions. Modern design problems
require simulations with a level of resolution that is difficult to achieve in
a reasonable amount of time even in effectively parallelized solvers. Though
the scale of the problem relative to available computing power is the greatest
impediment to accelerating these applications, significant performance gains
can be achieved through careful attention to the details of memory accesses.
Parallelized PDE solvers are subject to a trade-off in memory management: store
the solution for each timestep in abundant, global memory with high access
costs or in a limited, private memory with low access costs that must be passed
between nodes. The GPU implementation of swept time-space decomposition
presented here mitigates this dilemma by using private (shared) memory,
avoiding internode communication, and overwriting unnecessary values. It shows
significant improvement in the execution time of the PDE solvers in one
dimension achieving speedups of 6-2x for large and small problem sizes
respectively compared to naive GPU versions and 7-300x compared to parallel CPU
versions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04355</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mielczarek</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-Field Correspondence</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.mes-hall gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure. A mistake related to the large spin limit has
  been corrected. General conclusions remain unchanged</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the recent article Phys.\ Lett.\ B {\bf 759} (2016) 424 a new class of
field theories called Nonlinear Field Space Theory has been proposed. In this
approach, the standard field theories are considered as linear approximations
to some more general theories characterized by nonlinear field phase spaces.
The case of spherical geometry is especially interesting due to its relation
with the spin physics. Here, we explore this possibility showing that classical
scalar field theory with such a field space can be viewed as a perturbation of
a continuous spin system. In this picture, the spin precession and the scalar
field excitations are dual descriptions of the same physics. The duality is
studied on the example of the Heisenberg model. It is shown that the Heisenberg
model coupled to a magnetic field leads to a non-relativistic scalar field
theory, characterized by quadratic dispersion relation. Finally, on the basis
of analysis of the relation between the spin phase space and the scalar field
theory we propose the \emph{Spin-Field correspondence} between the known types
of fields and the corresponding spin systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05088</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Tong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piao</keyname><forenames>Yun-Song</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the primordial universe with gravitational waves detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables; published version, a new subsection
  and many references added</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2017)010</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/01/010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spectrum of primordial gravitational waves (GWs), especially its tilt
$n_T$, carries significant information about the primordial universe. Combining
recent aLIGO and Planck2015+BK14 data, we find that the current limit is
$n_T=0.016^{+0.614}_{-0.989}$ at 95% C.L. We also estimate the impacts of
Einstein Telescope and LISA on constraining $n_T$. Moreover, based on the
effective field theory of cosmological perturbations, we make an attempt to
confront some models of early universe scenarios, which produce blue-tilted GWs
spectrum ($n_T&gt;0$), with the corresponding datasets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05208</id><created>2016-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Guoqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Su-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Guangqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Tay-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Songtian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belopolski</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alidoust</keyname><forenames>Nasser</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>Daniel S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Fengqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeng</keyname><forenames>Horng-Tay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bansil</keyname><forenames>Arun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Hsin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>M. Zahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic-scale visualization of quasiparticle interference on a type-II
  Weyl semimetal surface</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>To appear in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 266804 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.266804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We combine quasiparticle interference simulation (theory) and atomic
resolution scanning tunneling spectro-microscopy (experiment) to visualize the
interference patterns on a type-II Weyl semimetal Mo$_{x}$W$_{1-x}$Te$_2$ for
the first time. Our simulation based on first-principles band topology
theoretically reveals the surface electron scattering behavior. We identify the
topological Fermi arc states and reveal the scattering properties of the
surface states in Mo$_{0.66}$W$_{0.34}$Te$_2$. In addition, our result reveals
an experimental signature of the topology via the interconnectivity of bulk and
surface states, which is essential for understanding the unusual nature of this
material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07039</id><created>2016-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velinov</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Computation of ion production rate and short, mid and long term
  ionization effect by cosmic rays during Bastille day event</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.space-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1612.07100</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The galactic cosmic rays are the main source of ionization in the Earth
stratosphere and troposphere. The induced by primary cosmic ray particles
ionization is important in various processes related to atmospheric physics and
chemistry, specifically the minor constituents. The ion production in the
atmosphere is enhanced compared to the average following major solar energetic
particles events, specifically over the polar caps. During the solar cycle 23
we observed several strong ground level enhancements, one of the strongest
among them been the Bastille day event on 14 July 2000. In the work presented
here we apply a full Monte Carlo 3-D model in order to compute the cosmic ray
induced ionization. The model is based on atmospheric shower simulation with
the PLANETOCOSMICS code and the ion production rate is considered as a
superposition of cosmic rays with galactic and solar origin. The ion production
rate is computed as a function of the altitude above the sea level and the
short, mid and long term ionization effect relative to the average due to
galactic cosmic rays is computed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07100</id><created>2016-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mishev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velinov</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Computation of complex ion production due to cosmic rays during the
  Halloween sequence of GLEs on October-November 2003</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.space-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1612.07039</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The possible effect of solar variability, accordingly cosmic rays variation
on atmospheric physics and chemistry is highly debated over the last years.
According to several recent models the induced by cosmic rays atmospheric
ionization plays a key role in several different processes. At recent, an
apparent effect on minor constituents and aerosols over polar regions during
major solar proton events was observed. The ion production rate during ground
level enhancements is a superposition of the contribution of cosmic rays with
galactic and solar origin. The solar cycle 23 provided several strong ground
level enhancements. The period of end October - beginning of November 2003 was
characterized by a strong cosmic ray variability, namely a sequence of three
GLEs was observed. In addition, there were several Forbush decreases, which led
to a suppression of galactic cosmic ray flux. As a consequence the cosmic ray
induced ion production in the atmosphere and the corresponding ionization
effect were subject of dynamical changes. Here we compute the complex ion
production due to cosmic rays during the Halloween sequence of ground level
enhancements on October-November 2003 and we estimate the ionization effect.
The spectral and angular characteristics of the solar protons are explicitly
considered throughout the events as well their time evolution. The ionization
effect during the period is computed at several altitudes above the sea level
in a region with $R_{c}$ $\le$ 1 GV and $R_{c}$ $\le$ 2 GV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07814</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cooke</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunney</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crivelli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced anti-hydrogen ion production</title><categories>hep-ex physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, prepared for the proceedings of the WAG2015
  conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of anti-hydrogen ions in the GBAR experiment will occur via a
two step charge exchange process. In a first reaction, the anti-protons from
the ELENA ring at CERN will capture a positron from a positronium target
producing anti-hydrogen atoms. Those interacting in the same positronium target
will produce in a second step anti-hydrogen ions. This results in a dependence
for the anti-ions production rate which is roughly proportional to the
positronium density squared. We present a scheme to increase the anti-ions
production rate in the GBAR experiment by tailoring the anti-proton to the
positron pulse in order to maximise the temporal overlap of Ps and
anti-protons. Detailed simulations show that an order of magnitude could be
gained by bunching the anti-protons from ELENA. In order to avoid losses in
their capture in the Paul trap due to the energy spread introduced by the
bunching, debunching with a symmetrical inverted pulse can be applied to the
anti-hydrogen ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00792</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Christe</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krucker</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glesener</keyname><forenames>Lindsay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shih</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saint-Hilaire</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspi</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allred</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drake</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gary</keyname><forenames>Dale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gburek</keyname><forenames>Szymon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goetz</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grefenstette</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gubarev</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannah</keyname><forenames>Iain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holman</keyname><forenames>Gordon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Hugh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inglis</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>Jack</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Shinosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimchuk</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kontar</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalski</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longcope</keyname><forenames>Dana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massone</keyname><forenames>Anna-Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musset</keyname><forenames>Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piana</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramsey</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryan</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwartz</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#x119;&#x15b;licki</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turin</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warmuth</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson-Hodge</keyname><forenames>Colleen</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veronig</keyname><forenames>Astrid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilmer</keyname><forenames>Nicole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring impulsive solar magnetic energy release and particle
  acceleration with focused hard X-ray imaging spectroscopy</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Next Generation Solar Physics Mission white paper, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How impulsive magnetic energy release leads to solar eruptions and how those
eruptions are energized and evolve are vital unsolved problems in Heliophysics.
The standard model for solar eruptions summarizes our current understanding of
these events. Magnetic energy in the corona is released through drastic
restructuring of the magnetic field via reconnection. Electrons and ions are
then accelerated by poorly understood processes. Theories include contracting
loops, merging magnetic islands, stochastic acceleration, and turbulence at
shocks, among others. Although this basic model is well established, the
fundamental physics is poorly understood. HXR observations using
grazing-incidence focusing optics can now probe all of the key regions of the
standard model. These include two above-the-looptop (ALT) sources which bookend
the reconnection region and are likely the sites of particle acceleration and
direct heating. The science achievable by a direct HXR imaging instrument can
be summarized by the following science questions and objectives which are some
of the most outstanding issues in solar physics (1) How are particles
accelerated at the Sun? (1a) Where are electrons accelerated and on what time
scales? (1b) What fraction of electrons is accelerated out of the ambient
medium? (2) How does magnetic energy release on the Sun lead to flares and
eruptions? A Focusing Optics X-ray Solar Imager (FOXSI) instrument, which can
be built now using proven technology and at modest cost, would enable
revolutionary advancements in our understanding of impulsive magnetic energy
release and particle acceleration, a process which is known to occur at the Sun
but also throughout the Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00795</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Christe</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bandler</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeLuca</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspi</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golub</keyname><forenames>Leon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Randall</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allred</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brosius</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimchuk</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Solving the Coronal Heating Problem using X-ray Microcalorimeters</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Next Generation Solar Physics Mission, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Even in the absence of resolved flares, the corona is heated to several
million degrees. However, despite its importance for the structure, dynamics,
and evolution of the solar atmosphere, the origin of this heating remains
poorly understood. Several observational and theoretical considerations suggest
that the heating is driven by small, impulsive energy bursts which could be
Parker-style &quot;nanoflares&quot; (Parker 1988) that arise via reconnection within the
tangled and twisted coronal magnetic field. The classical &quot;smoking gun&quot;
(Klimchuk 2009; Cargill et al. 2013) for impulsive heating is the direct
detection of widespread hot plasma (T &gt; 6 MK) with a low emission measure. In
recent years there has been great progress in the development of Transition
Edge Sensor (TES) X-ray microcalorimeters that make them more ideal for
studying the Sun. When combined with grazing-incidence focusing optics, they
provide direct spectroscopic imaging over a broad energy band (0.5 to 10 keV)
combined with extremely impressive energy resolution in small pixels, as low as
0.7 eV (FWHM) at 1.5 keV (Lee 2015), and 1.56 eV (FWHM) at 6 keV (Smith 2012),
two orders of magnitude better than the current best traditional solid state
photon-counting spectrometers. Decisive observations of the hot plasma
associated with nanoflare models of coronal heating can be provided by new
solar microcalorimeters. These measurements will cover the most important part
of the coronal spectrum for searching for the nanoflare-related hot plasma and
will characterize how much nanoflares can heat the corona both in active
regions and the quiet Sun. Finally, microcalorimeters will enable to study all
of this as a function of time and space in each pixel simultaneously a
capability never before available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00801</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Viola</keyname><forenames>Joe</forenames></author></authors><title>The elliptic evolution of non-self-adjoint degree-2 Hamiltonians</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages, 2 figures</comments><msc-class>47D06, 47A45, 81Q12</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the relationship between the classical Hamilton flow and the quantum
Schr\&quot;odinger evolution where the Hamiltonian is a degree-2 complex-valued
polynomial. When the flow obeys a strict positivity condition equivalent to
compactness of the evolution operator, we find geometric expressions for the
$L^2$ operator norm and a singular-value decomposition of the Schr\&quot;odinger
evolution, using the Hamilton flow. The flow also gives a geometric composition
law for these operators, which correspond to a large class of integral
operators with nondegenerate Gaussian kernels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00802</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Jason S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivera</keyname><forenames>Pasqual</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaibley</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee-Wong</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Hongyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jiaqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandrus</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cobden</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Wang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author></authors><title>Interlayer Exciton Optoelectronics in a 2D Heterostructure p-n Junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Nano Letters:
  http://pubs.acs.org/doi/pdf/10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b03398</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b03398</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Semiconductor heterostructures are backbones for solid state based
optoelectronic devices. Recent advances in assembly techniques for van der
Waals heterostructures has enabled the band engineering of semiconductor
heterojunctions for atomically thin optoelectronic devices. In two-dimensional
heterostructures with type II band alignment, interlayer excitons, where
Coulomb-bound electrons and holes are confined to opposite layers, have shown
promising properties for novel excitonic devices, including a large binding
energy, micron-scale in-plane drift-diffusion, and long population and valley
polarization lifetime. Here, we demonstrate interlayer exciton optoelectronics
based on electrostatically defined lateral p-n junctions in a MoSe2-WSe2
heterobilayer. Applying a forward bias enables the first observation of
electroluminescence from interlayer excitons. At zero bias, the p-n junction
functions as a highly sensitive photodetector, where the wavelength-dependent
photocurrent measurement allows the direct observation of resonant optical
excitation of the interlayer exciton. The resulting photocurrent amplitude from
the interlayer exciton is about 200 times smaller compared to the resonant
excitation of intralayer exciton. This implies that the interlayer exciton
oscillator strength is two orders of magnitude smaller than that of the
intralayer exciton due to the spatial separation of electron and hole to
opposite layers. These results lay the foundation for exploiting the interlayer
exciton in future 2D heterostructure optoelectronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00805</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Milekhin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Lagrangian description of Borel resummation</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we will propose a physical interpretation of Borel resummation.
We will define Borel transformation on the Lagrangian level. This
transformation essentially coincides with coupling the original theory to the
non-dynamical complex dilaton field. In the perturbative sector it reproduces
standard Borel resummation. In the non-perturbative sector this transformation
reproduces Bogomolny--Zinn-Justin(BZJ) regularization. Our approach unifies the
perturbative Borel resummation and non-perturbative BZJ procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00816</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Diamond</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Prieto</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Slimmer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Watts</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Fermilab Switchyard Resonant Beam Position Monitor Electronics Upgrade
  Results</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-430-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The readout electronics for the resonant beam position monitors (BPMs) in the
Fermilab Switchyard (SY) have been upgraded, utilizing a low noise amplifier
transition board and Fermilab designed digitizer boards. The stripline BPMs are
estimated to have an average signal output of between -110 dBm and -80 dBm,
with an estimated peak output of -70 dBm. The external resonant circuit is
tuned to the SY machine frequency of 53.10348 MHz. Both the digitizer and
transition boards have variable gain in order to accommodate the large dynamic
range and irregularity of the resonant extraction spill. These BPMs will aid in
auto-tuning of the SY beamline as well as enabling operators to monitor beam
position through the spill.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00817</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ziemkiewicz</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple analytic equation for airfoil shape description</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show a simple, analytic equation describing a class of two-dimensional
shapes well suited for representation of aircraft airfoil profiles. Our goal
was to create a description characterized by a small number of parameters with
easily understandable meaning, providing a tool to alter the shape with
optimization procedures as well as manual tweaks by the designer. The generated
shapes are well suited for numerical analysis with 2D flow solving software
such as XFOIL.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00820</id><created>2017-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Zirakashvili</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogovaya</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ptuskin</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klepach</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the inverse problem for extragalactic cosmic ray nuclei with energies
  $10^{18}$ to $10^{20}$ eV</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inverse problem of cosmic ray transport of ultra-high energy cosmic rays
is considered. The analysis of Auger data on energy spectrum, energy dependence
of mean logarithm of atomic mass number and its variance allows definite
conclusions on the shape of the source spectrum in the frameworks of the
inverse problem approach. The discussion on regularization procedure for
considered ill-posed problem is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00824</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Vivoli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>PIP-II Transfer Lines Design</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-452-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The U.S. Particle Physics Project Prioritization Panel (P5) report encouraged
the realization of Fermilab's Proton Improvement Plan II (PIP-II) to support
future neutrino programs in the United States. PIP-II aims at enhancing the
capabilities of the Fermilab existing accelerator complex while simultaneously
providing a flexible platform for its future upgrades. The central part of
PIP-II project is the construction of a new 800 MeV H- Superconducting (SC)
Linac together with upgrades of the Booster and Main Injector synchrotrons. New
transfer lines will also be needed to deliver beam to the downstream
accelerators and facilities. In this paper we present the recent development of
the design of the transfer lines discussing the principles that guided their
design, the constraints and requirements imposed by the existing accelerator
complex and the following modifications implemented to comply with a better
understanding of the limitations and further requirements that emerged during
the development of the project.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00828</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>Ryan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrington</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardin</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madhusudhan</keyname><forenames>Nikku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loredo</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Challener</keyname><forenames>Ryan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foster</keyname><forenames>Andrew S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cubillos</keyname><forenames>Patricio E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blecic</keyname><forenames>Jasmina</forenames></author></authors><title>The Atmosphere and Interior Structure of HAT-P-13b from Spitzer
  Secondary Eclipses</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication by The Astrophysical Journal December 12,
  2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present {\em Spitzer} secondary-eclipse observations of the hot Jupiter
HAT-P-13 b in the 3.6 {\micron} and 4.5 {\micron} bands. HAT-P-13 b inhabits a
two-planet system with a configuration that enables constraints on the planet's
second Love number, \math{k\sb{2}}, from precise eccentricity measurements,
which in turn constrains models of the planet's interior structure. We exploit
the direct measurements of \math{e \cos \omega} from our secondary-eclipse data
and combine them with previously published radial velocity data to generate a
refined model of the planet's orbit and thus an improved estimate on the
possible interval for \math{k\sb{2}}. We report eclipse phases of \math{0.49154
\pm 0.00080} and \math{0.49711 \pm 0.00083} and corresponding \math{e \cos
\omega} estimates of \math{-0.0136 \pm 0.0013} and \math{-0.0048 \pm 0.0013}.
Under the assumptions of previous work, our estimate of \math{k\sb{2}} of 0.81
{\pm} 0.10 is consistent with the lower extremes of possible core masses found
by previous models, including models with no solid core. This anomalous result
challenges both interior models and the dynamical assumptions that enable them,
including the essential assumption of apsidal alignment. We also report eclipse
depths of 0.081\% {\pm} 0.008\% in the 3.6 {\micron} channel and 0.088 \% {\pm}
0.028 \% in the 4.5 {\micron} channel. These photometric results are
non-uniquely consistent with solar-abundance composition without any thermal
inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00829</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Asano</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garani</keyname><forenames>Raghuveer</forenames></author></authors><title>Sgoldstino search at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>34 Pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-scale supersymmetry breaking scenario in which the breaking scale is
around TeV has been discussed as a possibility to obtain a large Higgs mass and
to moderate the fine tuning problem. A characteristic feature is that the
hidden sector would be accessible at colliders in such a scenario. In this
paper, we investigate the phenomenology of sgoldstino which is the scalar
component of the goldstino superfield. We present partial widths and branching
ratios for sgoldstinos decaying to final states involving Higgs bosons and
sparticles which have not been discussed in detail so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00836</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Milli</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mawet</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mouillet</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasper</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Girard</keyname><forenames>Julien H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Adaptive optics in high-contrast imaging</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>24 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy at High Angular Resolution, Astrophysics and Space
  Science Library, Volume 439. ISBN 978-3-319-39737-5. Springer International
  Publishing Switzerland, 2016, p. 17</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-39739-9_2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of adaptive optics (AO) played a major role in modern
astronomy over the last three decades. By compensating for the atmospheric
turbulence, these systems enable to reach the diffraction limit on large
telescopes. In this review, we will focus on high contrast applications of
adaptive optics, namely, imaging the close vicinity of bright stellar objects
and revealing regions otherwise hidden within the turbulent halo of the
atmosphere to look for objects with a contrast ratio lower than 10^-4 with
respect to the central star. Such high-contrast AO-corrected observations have
led to fundamental results in our current understanding of planetary formation
and evolution as well as stellar evolution. AO systems equipped three
generations of instruments, from the first pioneering experiments in the
nineties, to the first wave of instruments on 8m-class telescopes in the years
2000, and finally to the extreme AO systems that have recently started
operations. Along with high-contrast techniques, AO enables to reveal the
circumstellar environment: massive protoplanetary disks featuring spiral arms,
gaps or other asymmetries hinting at on-going planet formation, young giant
planets shining in thermal emission, or tenuous debris disks and micron-sized
dust leftover from collisions in massive asteroid-belt analogs. After
introducing the science case and technical requirements, we will review the
architecture of standard and extreme AO systems, before presenting a few
selected science highlights obtained with recent AO instruments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00842</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Kendziora</keyname><forenames>K. R.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Angelo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baffes</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Franck</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kellett</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Use of KF Style Flanges In Low Particulate Applications</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-394-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  As SCRF particle accelerator technology advances the need for &quot;low
particulate&quot; and &quot;particle free&quot; vacuum systems becomes greater and greater. In
the course of the operation of these systems, there comes a time when various
instruments have to be temporarily attached for diagnostic purposes: RGAs, leak
detectors, and additional pumps. In an effort to make the additions of these
instruments easier and more time effective, we propose to use KF style flanges
for these types of temporary diagnostic connections. This document will
describe the tests used to compare the particles generated using the assembly
of the, widely accepted for &quot;particle free&quot; use, conflat flange to the proposed
KF style flange, and demonstrate that KF flanges produce comparable or even
less particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00863</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Embree</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fillman</keyname><forenames>Jake</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of Discrete Two-Dimensional Periodic Schr\&quot;odinger Operators
  with Small Potentials</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the spectrum of a discrete two-dimensional periodic
Schr\&quot;odinger operator on a square lattice with a sufficiently small potential
is an interval, provided the period is odd in at least one dimension. In
general, we show that the spectrum may consist of at most two intervals and
that a gap may only open at energy zero. This sharpens several results of
Kr\&quot;uger and may be thought of as a discrete version of the Bethe--Sommerfeld
conjecture. We also describe an application to the study of two-dimensional
almost-periodic operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00864</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Suhas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ziwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xiaopeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumari</keyname><forenames>Niru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davila</keyname><forenames>Noraica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strachan</keyname><forenames>John Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vine</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilcoyne</keyname><forenames>A. L. David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishi</keyname><forenames>Yoshio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>R. Stanley</forenames></author></authors><title>Conduction Channel Formation and Dissolution Due to Oxygen
  Thermophoresis/Diffusion in Hafnium Oxide Memristors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages and 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano 10, 11205 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b06275</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition metal oxide memristors, or resistive random-access memory (RRAM)
switches, are under intense development for storage-class memory because of
their favorable operating power, endurance, speed, and density. Their
commercial deployment critically depends on predictive compact models based on
understanding nanoscale physico-chemical forces, which remains elusive and
controversial owing to the difficulties in directly observing atomic motions
during resistive switching, Here, using scanning transmission synchrotron x-ray
spectromicroscopy to study in-situ switching of hafnium oxide memristors, we
directly observed the formation of a localized oxygen-deficiency-derived
conductive channel surrounded by a low-conductivity ring of excess oxygen.
Subsequent thermal annealing homogenized the segregated oxygen, resetting the
cells towards their as-grown resistance state. We show that the formation and
dissolution of the conduction channel are successfully modeled by radial
thermophoresis and Fick diffusion of oxygen atoms driven by Joule heating. This
confirmation and quantification of two opposing nanoscale radial forces that
affect bipolar memristor switching are important components for any future
physics-based compact model for the electronic switching of these devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00869</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Utsuno</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Yoshitaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-coherent character of isoscalar pairing probed with Gamow-Teller
  strength: New insight into $^{14}$C dating $\beta$ decay</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the phase coherence of isoscalar pairs from the $B({\rm
GT};0^+_1\,T\!=\!1 \to 1^+_1\,T\!=\!0)$ values in two-particle configurations
of $A=6$, 18, and 42 nuclei and two-hole configurations of $A=14$ and 38 ones.
We find that these Gamow-Teller (GT) matrix elements are always constructive
and thus enlarged under isovector- and isoscalar-pairing Hamiltonians, whereas
the observed GT strengths are strongly hindered for the two-hole
configurations, including the famous $^{14}$C dating $\beta$ decay. This
indicates that the actual isoscalar pair, unlike the isovector pair, has no
definite phase coherence, which can work against forming isoscalar-pair
condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00873</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Justin C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagredo</keyname><forenames>Francisca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>Kieron</forenames></author></authors><title>Warming Up Density Functional Theory</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density functional theory (DFT) has become the most popular approach to
electronic structure across disciplines, especially in material and chemical
sciences. Last year, at least 30,000 papers used DFT to make useful predictions
or give insight into an enormous diversity of scientific problems, ranging from
battery development to solar cell efficiency and far beyond. The success of
this field has been driven by usefully accurate approximations based on known
exact conditions and careful testing and validation. In the last decade,
applications of DFT in a new area, warm dense matter, have exploded. DFT is
revolutionizing simulations of warm dense matter including applications in
controlled fusion, planetary interiors, and other areas of high energy density
physics. Over the past decade or so, molecular dynamics calculations driven by
modern density functional theory have played a crucial role in bringing
chemical realism to these applications, often (but not always) with excellent
agreement with experiment. This chapter summarizes recent work from our group
on density functional theory at non-zero temperatures, which we call thermal
DFT. We explain the relevance of this work in the context of warm dense matter,
and the importance of quantum chemistry to this regime. We illustrate many
basic concepts on a simple model system, the asymmetric Hubbard dimer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00876</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Uskov</keyname><forenames>G. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kretov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepkin</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sbitnev</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bobreshov</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of Ultra-Wideband TEM Horn with Inhomogeneous Dielectric
  Medium</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There were proposed new formulas for the dielectric medium permittivity
distribution along spatial coordinates in the space between a linear TEM-horn's
leafs, which were obtained according to the rules of geometric optics in the
assumption of the phase center being lumped or distributed. The formulas has
been checked by FDTD simulation of an ultra-wideband signal excitation; two
cases were studied---when dielectric medium is present, and absent. For these
both cases, there was obtained voltage steady-wave ratio, as well as radiation
patterns at a set of frequencies up to 20~GHz; the results comparison was
performed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00884</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Nobukawa</keyname><forenames>Masayoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchiyama</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nobukawa</keyname><forenames>Kumiko K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamauchi</keyname><forenames>Shigeo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koyama</keyname><forenames>Katsuji</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of the Galactic Diffuse X-ray Emission: Iron K-shell Line
  Diagnostics</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures, 5 tables, published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>2016ApJ...833..268N</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/833/2/268</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports detailed K-shell line profiles of iron (Fe) and nickel
(Ni) of the Galactic Center X-ray Emission (GCXE), Galactic Bulge X-ray
Emission (GBXE), Galactic Ridge X-ray Emission (GRXE), magnetic Cataclysmic
Variables (mCVs), non-magnetic Cataclysmic Variables (non-mCVs), and coronally
Active Binaries (ABs). For the study of the origin of the GCXE, GBXE, and GRXE,
the spectral analysis is focused on equivalent widths of the Fe K$\alpha$, Fe
He$\alpha$, and Fe Ly$\alpha$ lines. The global spectrum of the GBXE is
reproduced by a combination of the mCVs, non-mCVs, and ABs spectra. On the
other hand, the GRXE spectrum shows significant data excesses at the Fe
K$\alpha$ and Fe He$\alpha$ line energies. This means that additional
components other than mCVs, non-mCVs, and ABs are required, which have
symbiotic phenomena of cold gas and very high-temperature plasma. The GCXE
spectrum shows larger excesses than those found in the GRXE spectrum at all the
K-shell lines of iron and nickel. Among them the largest ones are the Fe
K$\alpha$, Fe He$\alpha$, Fe Ly$\alpha$, and Fe Ly$\beta$ lines. Together with
the fact that the scale heights of the Fe K$\alpha$, Fe He$\alpha$, and Fe
Ly$\alpha$ lines are similar to that of the central molecular zone (CMZ), the
excess components would be related to high-energy activity in the extreme
envelopment of the CMZ.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00896</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Dirac Semimetals in Three Dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new type of three-dimensional essential Dirac semimetal with
magnetic ordering. The Dirac points are protected by the magnetic space groups
and cannot be gapped without lowering such symmetries, where the combined
antiunitary symmetry of half-translation operator and time-reversal plays an
essential role. We introduce two explicit tight-binding models for space groups
$16$ and $102$, which possesses Dirac point at time-reversal-invariant momenta
of surface Brillouin zone. In contrast to the time-reversal-invariant essential
Dirac semimetal, the magnetic space groups here can be either symmorphic or
non-symmorphic, and the magnetic DSM is symmetry tuned to the boundary between
weak topologically distinct insulating phases. Interestingly, the
symmetry-breaking perturbations could lead to an ideal Weyl semimetal phase
with only two minimal Weyl points pinned exactly at the Fermi energy for
filling $\nu\in4\mathbb{Z}+2$. By reducing the dimensionality we are able to
access the Dirac and Weyl semimetal phases in two dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00906</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miroshnichenko</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable optical bistability and tristability of nonlinear
  graphene-wrapped dielectric nanoparticles</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages and 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on full-wave scattering theory with self-consistent mean field
approximation, we study the optical multi-stability of graphene-wrapped
dielectric nanoparticles. We demonstrate that the optical bistability (OB) of
the graphene-wrapped nanoparticle exist in both near-field and far-field
spectra, and show the optical multi-stability arising from the contributions of
higher-order terms of the incident external field. Moreover, both the optical
stable region and the switching threshold values can be tuned by changing
either the Fermi level or the size of the nanoparticle. Our results promise the
graphene-wrapped dielectric nanoparticle a candidate of multi-state optical
switching, optical memories and relevant optoelectronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00907</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable optical bistability of graphene-wrapped dielectric cylinders</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, and 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study the role of nonlinear surface plasmoms on the optical
bistability of graphene-wrapped dielectric cylinders, within the framework of
both full-wave scattering theory and the quasistatic limit. Typical hysteresis
curves are observed in both near-field and far-field spectra. Moreover, we
demonstrate that introducing the full wave theory results in another bistable
behavior with a high applied electromagnetic field, suggesting a more explicit
way in analyzing the unstable behavior of the graphene-wrapped dielectric
cylinder. Furthermore, optical stable region and the switching threshold values
are proved to be tunable by changing either the size, permittivity of the
nanocylinder or the chemical potential of graphene, promising the
graphene-wrapped dielectric cylinder a candidate for all-optical switching and
nano-memories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00916</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Gabrielyan</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garibyan</keyname><forenames>Y. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazaryan</keyname><forenames>Y. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oganesyan</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oganesyan</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrosyan</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayryan</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Undulator radiation in the THz range</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The experimental device for generation of undulator radiation in terahertz
wavelength region by use of undulator on ferromagnets is created. The device is
based on a beam of a microtrone with the energy 7.5 MeV. The radiation
wavelength is 200 micron. Registered spontaneous radiation has a power of 10
microwatt at a current of a beam 2 mA in a pulse. With the optical resonator,
in a mode, the amplification of 6 percent is received, that in some times is
more than expected value. This effect is explained as a result of partial
coherence of radiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00942</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>JLQCD Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fahy</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukaya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>D meson semileptonic decays in lattice QCD with Moebius domain-wall
  quarks</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, talk presented at the 34th International
  Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016, University
  of Southampton, UK</comments><report-no>KEK-CP-350</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on our study of the D meson semileptonic decays in 2+1 flavor
lattice QCD. Gauge ensembles are generated at three lattice cutoffs up to 4.5
GeV and with pion masses as low as 300 MeV. We employ the Moebius domain-wall
fermion action for both light and charm quarks. We report our preliminary
results for the vector and scalar form factors and discuss their dependence on
the momentum transfer, quark masses and lattice spacing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00943</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>H. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mottola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholten</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preusker</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matz</keyname><forenames>K. -D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hviid</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variegation and space weathering on asteroid 21 Lutetia</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Planetary and Space Science Volume 117, November 2015, Pages
  236-245</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2015.06.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the flyby in 2010, the OSIRIS camera on-board Rosetta acquired
hundreds of high-resolution images of asteroid Lutetia's surface through a
range of narrow-band filters. While Lutetia appears very bland in the visible
wavelength range, Magrin et al. (2012) tentatively identified UV color
variations in the Baetica cluster, a group of relatively young craters close to
the north pole. As Lutetia remains a poorly understood asteroid, such color
variations may provide clues to the nature of its surface. We take the color
analysis one step further. First we orthorectify the images using a shape model
and improved camera pointing, then apply a variety of techniques (photometric
correction, principal component analysis) to the resulting color cubes. We
characterize variegation in the Baetica crater cluster at high spatial
resolution, identifying crater rays and small, fresh impact craters. We argue
that at least some of the color variation is due to space weathering, which
makes Lutetia's regolith redder and brighter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00950</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikot</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;tf&#xfc;o&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ngwueke</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Udoh</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zare</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanabadi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Klein-Gordon equation particles in exponential-type molecule potentials
  and its thermodynamic properties in D- dimensions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 14 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131:419</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16419-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we use the Nikiforv-Uvarov method to obtain the approximate
solutions of the Klein-Gordon equation with deformed five parameter exponential
type potential (DFPEP) model. We also obtain the solutions of the Schr\&quot;odinger
equation in the presence of the DFPEP in the non-relativistic limits. In
addition, we calculate in the nonrelativistic limits the thermodynamics
properties such as vibrational mean energy U, free energy F and the specific
heat capacity C . Special cases of the potential are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00957</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Fletcher</keyname><forenames>Leigh N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orton</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon-Miller</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Pater</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousis</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>P. G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacquesson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanamandra-Fisher</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Jovian Temperature and Cloud Variability during the 2009-2010 Fade of
  the South Equatorial Belt</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>22 pages, 11 figures, published in Icarus (2011)</comments><journal-ref>Icarus, Volume 213, Issue 2, June 2011, Pages 564-580</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2011.03.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mid-infrared 7-20 $\mu$m imaging of Jupiter demonstrates that the increased
albedo of Jupiter's South Equatorial Belt (SEB) during the `fade' (whitening)
event of 2009-2010 was correlated with changes to atmospheric temperature and
aerosol opacity. The opacity of the tropospheric condensation cloud deck at
pressures less than 800 mbar increased by 80% between May 2008 and July 2010,
making the SEB ($7-17^\circ$ S) as opaque in the thermal infrared as the
adjacent equatorial zone. After the cessation of discrete convective activity
within the SEB in May 2009, a cool quiescent band of high aerosol opacity (the
SEB zone at $11-15^\circ$ S) was observed separating the cloud-free northern
and southern SEB components. The cooling of the SEBZ (with peak-to-peak
contrasts of $1.0\pm0.5$ K), as well as the increased aerosol opacity at 4.8
and 8.6 $\mu$m, preceded the visible whitening of the belt by several months. A
chain of five warm, cloud-free `brown barges' (subsiding airmasses) were
observed regularly in the SEB between June 2009 and June 2010, by which time
they too had been obscured by the enhanced aerosol opacity of the SEB, although
the underlying warm circulation was still present in July 2010. The cool
temperatures and enhanced aerosol opacity of the SEBZ after July 2009 are
consistent with an upward flux of volatiles from deeper levels (e.g.,
ammonia-laden air) and enhanced condensation, obscuring the blue-absorbing
chromophore and whitening the SEB by April 2010. Revival of the dark SEB
coloration in the coming months will ultimately require sublimation of these
ices by subsidence and warming of volatile-depleted air. [Abridged]
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00961</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Daszynska-Daszkiewicz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>and BEST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Walczak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>and BEST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pamyatnykh</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames><affiliation>and BEST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jerzykiewicz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>and BEST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pigulski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>and BEST</affiliation></author></authors><title>The solitary g-mode frequencies in early B-type stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>talk at the second BRITE-Constellation Science Conference, Innsbruck,
  2016, to be published in the Proceedings of the Polish Astronomical Society,
  eds: G. Stachowski, E. Poretti, and J. Matthews</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present possible explanations of pulsations in early B-type main sequence
stars which arise purely from the excitation of gravity modes. There are three
stars with this type of oscillations detected from the BRITE light curves:
$\kappa$ Cen, a Car, $\kappa$ Vel. We show that by changing metallicity or the
opacity profile it is possible in some models to dump pressure modes keeping
gravity modes unstable. Other possible scenario involves pulsations of a lower
mass companion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00965</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Fletcher</keyname><forenames>Leigh N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orton</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giles</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>P. G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedovato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Moist Convection and the 2010-2011 Revival of Jupiter's South Equatorial
  Belt</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>30 pages, 13 figures, accepted for publication in Icarus (2017)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2017.01.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transformation of Jupiter's South Equatorial Belt (SEB) from its faded,
whitened state in 2009-2010 to its normal brown appearance is documented via
comparisons of thermal-infrared (5-20 $\mu$m) and visible-light imaging between
November 2010 and November 2011. The SEB revival consisted of convective
eruptions triggered over $\sim100$ days, potentially powered by the latent heat
released by the condensation of water. The plumes rise from the water cloud
base and ultimately diverge and cool in the stably-stratified upper
troposphere. Thermal-IR images were acquired 2 days after the SEB disturbance
was first detected by amateur observers on November 9th 2010. Subsequent images
revealed the cold, putatively anticyclonic and cloudy plume tops surrounded by
warm, cloud-free conditions at their peripheries. The majority of the plumes
erupted from a single source near $140-160^\circ$W, coincident with the remnant
cyclonic circulation of a brown barge that had formed during the fade.
Additional plumes erupted from the leading edge of the central disturbance
immediately east of the source. The tropospheric plumes excited stratospheric
thermal waves over the SEB, showing a direct connection between moist
convection and stratospheric wave activity. The subsidence of dry, unsaturated
air warmed the troposphere and removed the white aerosols. The aerosol-free air
was redistributed throughout the SEB by the zonal flow, following a
westward-moving southern branch and an eastward-moving northern branch that
revived the brown colouration over $\sim200$ days. The last stage of the
revival was the re-establishment of normal convective activity northwest of the
GRS in September 2011. Moist convection may therefore play an important role in
controlling the timescale and atmospheric variability during the SEB life
cycle. [Abridged]
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00967</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Bhuwan</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>Upendra</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Veronig</keyname><forenames>Astrid M.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. of Graz, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sajal Kumar</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shanmugaraju</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Arul Anandhar College, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Yong-Jae</forenames><affiliation>Kyung Hee Univ., South Korea</affiliation></author></authors><title>Formation and eruption of a flux rope from the sigmoid active region
  NOAA 11719 and associated M6.5 flare: A multi-wavelength study</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures, The Astrophysical Journal</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/1/42</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the formation, activation and eruption of a flux rope from the
sigmoid active region NOAA 11719 by analyzing E(UV), X-ray and radio
measurements. During the pre-eruption period of ~7 hours, the AIA 94 A images
reveal the emergence of a coronal sigmoid through the interaction between two
J-shaped bundles of loops which proceeds with multiple episodes of coronal loop
brightenings and significant variations in the magnetic flux through the
photosphere. These observations imply that repetitive magnetic reconnections
likely play a key role in the formation of the sigmoidal flux rope in the
corona and also contribute toward sustaining the temperature of the flux rope
higher than the ambient coronal structures. Notably, the formation of the
sigmoid is associated with the fast morphological evolution of an S-shaped
filament channel in the chromosphere. The sigmoid activates toward eruption
with the ascend of a large flux rope in the corona which is preceded by the
decrease of photospheric magnetic flux through the core flaring region
suggesting tether-cutting reconnection as a possible triggering mechanism. The
flux rope eruption results in a two-ribbon M6.5 flare with a prolonged rise
phase of ~21 min. The flare exhibits significant deviation from the standard
flare model in the early rise phase during which a pair of J-shaped flare
ribbons form and apparently exhibit converging motions parallel to the polarity
inversion line which is further confirmed by the motions of HXR footpoint
sources. In the later stages, the flare follows the standard flare model and
the source region undergoes a complete sigmoid-to-arcade transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00979</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Motta</keyname><forenames>Clio Bertelli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salaris</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquali</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebel</keyname><forenames>Eva K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observing the products of stellar evolution in the old open cluster M67
  with APOGEE</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 13 figures, accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent works have shown how the [C/N] ratio in stars after the first
dredge-up (FDU) can be used as an age estimator in virtue of its dependence on
stellar mass. For this purpose, precise predictions of the surface chemical
composition before and after the mixing takes place in the convective envelope
of subgiant stars are necessary. Stellar evolution models can provide us with
such predictions, although a comparision with objects of known age is needed
for calibration. Open clusters are excellent test cases, as they represent a
single stellar population for which the age can be derived through, e.g.,
isochrone fitting. In this study, we present a detailed analysis of stars
belonging to the well-known open cluster M67 observed by the APOGEE survey in
the twelfth data release of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and whose chemical
properties were derived with the ASPCAP pipeline. We find that the [C/N]
abundance of subgiant branch stars is overestimated by $\sim0.2$ dex due to an
offset in the determination of the [N/Fe] abundance. Stars on the red giant
branch and red clump are shown not to be affected by this offset. We derive
$\text{[C/N]}_{FDU}=-0.46\pm 0.03$ dex, which poses a strong constraint on
calibrations of $\text{[C/N]}_{FDU}$ as age indicator. We also do not find any
clear signature of additional chemical mixing processes that set in after the
red giant branch bump. The results obtained for M67 indicate the importance of
conducting high-resolution spectroscopic studies of open clusters of different
ages in order to establish an accurate age-dating method for field stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00989</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Krenn</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malik</keyname><forenames>Mehul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheidl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ursin</keyname><forenames>Rupert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeilinger</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum communication with photons</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>(37 pages, 19 figures)</comments><journal-ref>Optics in Our Time (pp. 455-482), Springer International
  Publishing (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-31903-2_18</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The secure communication of information plays an ever increasing role in our
society today. Classical methods of encryption inherently rely on the
difficulty of solving a problem such as finding prime factors of large numbers
and can, in principle, be cracked by a fast enough machine. The burgeoning
field of quantum communication relies on the fundamental laws of physics to
offer unconditional information security. Here we introduce the key concepts of
quantum superposition and entanglement as well as the no-cloning theorem that
form the basis of this field. Then, we review basic quantum communication
schemes with single and entangled photons and discuss recent experimental
progress in ground and space-based quantum communication. Finally, we discuss
the emerging field of high-dimensional quantum communication, which promises
increased data rates and higher levels of security than ever before. We discuss
recent experiments that use the orbital angular momentum of photons for sharing
large amounts of information in a secure fashion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00994</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Loreto</keyname><forenames>Vittorio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Servedio</keyname><forenames>Vito D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strogatz</keyname><forenames>Steven H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tria</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics on expanding spaces: modeling the emergence of novelties</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>in book &quot;Creativity and Universality in Language&quot;, 59-83 (2016);
  Springer International Publishing; isbn:978-3-319-24403-7;</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-24403-7_5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novelties are part of our daily lives. We constantly adopt new technologies,
conceive new ideas, meet new people, experiment with new situations.
Occasionally, we as individuals, in a complicated cognitive and sometimes
fortuitous process, come up with something that is not only new to us, but to
our entire society so that what is a personal novelty can turn into an
innovation at a global level. Innovations occur throughout social, biological
and technological systems and, though we perceive them as a very natural
ingredient of our human experience, little is known about the processes
determining their emergence. Still the statistical occurrence of innovations
shows striking regularities that represent a starting point to get a deeper
insight in the whole phenomenology. This paper represents a small step in that
direction, focusing on reviewing the scientific attempts to effectively model
the emergence of the new and its regularities, with an emphasis on more recent
contributions: from the plain Simon's model tracing back to the 1950s, to the
newest model of Polya's urn with triggering of one novelty by another. What
seems to be key in the successful modelling schemes proposed so far is the idea
of looking at evolution as a path in a complex space, physical, conceptual,
biological, technological, whose structure and topology get continuously
reshaped and expanded by the occurrence of the new. Mathematically it is very
interesting to look at the consequences of the interplay between the &quot;actual&quot;
and the &quot;possible&quot; and this is the aim of this short review.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01006</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Deuzeman</keyname><forenames>M J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stodolna</keyname><forenames>A S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leerssen</keyname><forenames>E E B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antoncecchi</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spook</keyname><forenames>N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleijntjens</keyname><forenames>T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Versluis</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witte</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eikema</keyname><forenames>K S E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ubachs</keyname><forenames>W</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoekstra</keyname><forenames>R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Versolato</keyname><forenames>O O</forenames></author></authors><title>Ion distribution and ablation depth measurements of a fs-ps
  laser-irradiated solid tin target</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ablation of solid tin surfaces by an 800-nanometer-wavelength laser is
studied for a pulse length range from 500 fs to 4.5 ps and a fluence range
spanning 0.9 to 22 J/cm^2. The ablation depth and volume are obtained employing
a high-numerical-aperture optical microscope, while the ion yield and energy
distributions are obtained from a set of Faraday cups set up under various
angles. We found a slight increase of the ion yield for an increasing pulse
length, while the ablation depth is slightly decreasing. The ablation volume
remained constant as a function of pulse length. The ablation depth follows a
two-region logarithmic dependence on the fluence, in agreement with the
available literature and theory. In the examined fluence range, the ion yield
angular distribution is sharply peaked along the target normal at low fluences
but rapidly broadens with increasing fluence. The total ionization fraction
increases monotonically with fluence to a 5-6% maximum, which is substantially
lower than the typical ionization fractions obtained with nanosecond-pulse
ablation. The angular distribution of the ions does not depend on the laser
pulse length within the measurement uncertainty. These results are of
particular interest for the possible utilization of fs-ps laser systems in
plasma sources of extreme ultraviolet light for nanolithography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01017</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonnet-Bidaud</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marc</forenames><affiliation>Astrophysics Department, French Alternative Energies and Atomic Energy Commission</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Diffuse Light of the Universe - On the microwave background before
  and after its discovery: open questions</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, accepted in Foundations of Physics, published online : 19
  December 2016. The final publication is available at link.springer.com</comments><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0056-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1965, the discovery of a new type of uniform radiation, located between
radiowaves and infrared light, was accidental. Known today as Cosmic Microwave
background (CMB), this diffuse radiation is commonly interpreted as a fossil
light released in an early hot and dense universe and constitutes today the
main 'pilar' of the big bang cosmology. Considerable efforts have been devoted
to derive fundamental cosmological parameters from the characteristics of this
radiation that led to a surprising universe that is shaped by at least three
major unknown components: inflation, dark matter and dark energy. This is an
important weakness of the present consensus cosmological model that justifies
raising several questions on the CMB interpretation. Can we consider its
cosmological nature as undisputable? Do other possible interpretations exist in
the context of other cosmological theories or simply as a result of other
physical mechanisms that could account for it? In an effort to questioning the
validity of scientific hypotheses and the under-determination of theories
compared to observations, we examine here the difficulties that still exist on
the interpretation of this diffuse radiation and explore other proposed tracks
to explain its origin. We discuss previous historical concepts of diffuse
radiation before and after the CMB discovery and underline the limit of our
present understanding.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01018</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Supriyo</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of particles on spinodal decomposition: A Phase field study</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Master's of Engineering thesis, Indian Institute of Science,
  Bangalore, India (2012)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this thesis, we study the interplay of phase separation and wetting in
multicomponent systems. For this purpose, we have examined the phase separation
pattern of a binary mixture (AB) in presence of stationary spherical particles
(C) which prefers one of the components of the binary (say, A). Binary AB is
composed of critical composition(50:50) and off-critical compositions(60:40,
40:60). Particle sizes of 8 units and 16 units are used in the simulations. Two
types of particle loading are used, 5\% and 10\%. We have employed a ternary
form of Cahn-Hilliard equation to incorporate immobile fillers in our system.
To elucidate the effect of wetting on phase separation we have designed three
sets of $\chi_{ij}$ and $\kappa_{ij}$ to include the effects of neutral
preference, weak preference and strong preference of the particle for one of
the binary components. If the particles are preferentially wetted by one of the
components then early stage microstructures show transient concentric alternate
layers of preferred and non-preferred phases around the particles. When
particles are neutral to binary components then such a ring pattern does not
form. At late times, neutral preference between particles and binary components
yields a continuous morphology whereas preferential wetting produces isolated
domains of non-preferred phases dispersed in a continuous matrix of preferred
phase. For off-critical compositions, if minor component wets the particle then
a bicontinuous morphology results whereas if major component wets the network a
droplet morphology is seen. When majority component wets the particle, a
possibility of double phase separation is reported. In such alloys phase
separation starts near the particle surface and propagates to the bulk at
intermediate to late times forming spherical or nearly spherical droplets of
the minor component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01022</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolotin</keyname><forenames>Yu. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanovsky</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified Planck units</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Planck units are natural physical scales of mass, length and time, built with
the help of the fundamental constants $\hbar, c, G$. The functional role of the
constants used for the construction of Planck units is different. If the first
two of them represent the limits of the action and the speed of light and
underlie quantum mechanics and special relativity, the Newton's constant $G$
&quot;only&quot; fixes the absolute value of the gravitational forces. It seems natural
to make a set of fundamental constants more consistent and more effective if
used to build Planck units only limit values. To this end, in addition to the
limit values $\hbar $ and $c$ we introduce an additional limit value - a
maximum power in nature. On the basis of these values, a modification of the
Planck unit system is proposed. The proposed modification leaves unchanged the
numerical values of Planck units, however, opens up exciting new possibilities
for interpreting the known results and for obtaining new ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01025</id><created>2016-12-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Burinskii</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>New Path to Unification of Gravity with Particle Physics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The principal new point is that ultra-high spin of the elementary particles
makes Einstein's gravity so strong, that its influence to metric is shifted
from Planck to the Compton scale! Compatibility of the Kerr-Newman (KN) gravity
with quantum theory is achieved by implementation of the supersymmetric Higgs
model without modification of the Einstein-Maxwell gravity. We consider the
nonperturbative bag-like solution to supersymmetric generalized LG field model,
which creates a flat and supersymmetric vacuum state inside the bag, forming
the Compton zone for consistent work of quantum theory. The bag is deformable,
and its shape is controlled by BPS bound, providing compatibility of the bag
boundary with external gravitational and electromagnetic (EM) field. In
particular, for the spinning KN gravity the bag takes the form of oblate disk
with a circular string placed on the disk border. Excitations of the KN EM
field create circular traveling waves. The super-bag solution is naturally
upgraded to the Wess-Zumino supersymmetric QED model, indicating a bridge from
the nonperturbative super-bag to perturbative formalism of the conventional
QED.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01027</id><created>2016-12-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>P. H. R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>R. A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Starobinsky model within the $f(R,T)$ formalism as a cosmological
  model</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we derive a cosmological model from the $f(R,T)$ theory of
gravity, for which $R$ is the Ricci scalar and $T$ is the trace of the
energy-momentum tensor. We consider $f(R,T)=f(R)+f(T)$, with $f(R)$ being the
Starobinksy model $R+\alpha R^{2}$ and $f(T)=\gamma T$, with $\alpha$ and
$\gamma$ constants. We find that from such a functional form, it is possible to
describe the cosmological scenario of a radiation-dominated universe, which has
shown to be a non-trivial feature within the $f(R,T)$ formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01045</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>Thiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gustavo</keyname><forenames>Breno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemos</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Settle</keyname><forenames>Amber</forenames></author></authors><title>An Overview of Recent Solutions to and Lower Bounds for the Firing
  Synchronization Problem</title><categories>cs.FL nlin.CG</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex systems in a wide variety of areas such as biological modeling, image
processing, and language recognition can be modeled using networks of very
simple machines called finite automata. Connecting subsystems modeled using
finite automata into a network allows for more computational power. One such
network, called a cellular automaton, consists of an n-dimensional array for n
&gt; 1 with a single finite automaton located at each point of the array. One of
the oldest problems associated with cellular automata is the firing
synchronization problem, originally proposed by John Myhill in 1957. As with
any long-standing problem, there are a large number of solutions to the firing
synchronization problem. Our goal, and the contribution of this work, is to
summarize recent solutions to the problem. We focus primarily on solutions to
the original problem, that is, the problem where the network is a
one-dimensional array and there is a single initiator located at one of the
ends. We summarize both minimal-time and non-minimal-time solutions, with an
emphasis on solutions that were published after 1998. We also focus on
solutions that minimize the number of states required by the finite automata.
In the process we also identify open problems that remain in terms of finding
minimal-state solutions to the firing synchronization problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01049</id><created>2017-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sadri</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author></authors><title>An analogy between four parametrizations of the dark energy equation of
  state onto Physical DE Models</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to scrutinize the nature of Dark Energy, many Equations of State
have been proposed. In this context we examine four popular models (the
Chevallier-Polarski-Linder (CPL) model, Jassal model, Barboza &amp; Alcaniz model
and Wetterich model) in the field of quintessence and barotropic dark energy
models, to compare with each other. We develop a theoretical method of
constructing the quintessence potential directly from the four equations of
state which describes the properties of the dark energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01050</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Tirandaz</keyname><forenames>Arash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghahramani</keyname><forenames>Farhad Taher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salari</keyname><forenames>Vahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Validity Examination of the Dissipative Quantum Model of Olfaction</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The validity of the dissipative quantum model of olfaction has not been
examined yet and therefore the model suffers from the lack of experimental
support. Here, we generalize the model and propose a numerical analysis of the
dissipative odorant-mediated inelastic electron tunneling mechanism of
olfaction, to be used as a potential examination in experiments. Our analysis
gives several predictions on the model such as efficiency of elastic and
inelastic tunneling of electrons through odorants, sensitivity thresholds in
terms of temperature and pressure, isotopic effect on sensitivity, and the
chiral recognition for discrimination between the similar and different scents.
Our predictions should yield new knowledge to design new experimental protocols
for testing the validity of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01053</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Dimova</keyname><forenames>Desislava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisov</keyname><forenames>Stoyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panchev</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nedyalkova</keyname><forenames>Miroslava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madurga</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Proykova</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author></authors><title>A model provides insight into electric field-induced rupture mechanism
  of water-in-toluene emulsion films</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>16 pages, 25 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents the first MD simulations of a model, which we have
designed for understanding the development of electro-induced instability of a
thin toluene emulsion film in contact with saline aqueous phase. This study
demonstrates the charge accumulation role in toluene film rupture when a DC
electric field is applied. The critical value of the external field at which
film ruptures, thin film charge distribution, capacitance, number densities and
film structure have been obtained in simulating the system within NVT and NPT
ensembles. A mechanism of thin film rupture driven by the electric discharge is
suggested.We show that NPT ensemble with a constant surface tension is a better
choice for further modeling of the systems that resemble more close the real
films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01054</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Golmankhaneh</keyname><forenames>Alireza K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baleanu</keyname><forenames>Dumitru</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-local Integrals and Derivatives on Fractal Sets with Applications</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we discussed the non-local derivative on the fractal Cantor
set. The scaling properties are given for both local and non-local fractal
derivatives. The local and non-local fractal differential equations are solved
and compared and related physical models are suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01063</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultracold Atomic Gases in Artificial Magnetic Fields (PhD thesis)</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>The submitted thesis is a 10-year anniversary version of the original
  thesis, being identical apart from updated journal references of publications
  based on its scientific results. Among other publications, it contributed to
  ongoing research on synthetic non-Abelian gauge fields and synthetic
  spin-orbit coupling in ultracold atomic gases. (165 pages)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A phenomenon can hardly be found that accompanied physical paradigms and
theoretical concepts in a more reflecting way than magnetism. From the
beginnings of metaphysics and the first classical approaches to magnetic poles
and streamlines of the field, it has inspired modern physics on its way to the
classical field description of electrodynamics, and further to the quantum
mechanical description of internal degrees of freedom of elementary particles.
Meanwhile, magnetic manifestations have posed and still do pose complex and
often controversially debated questions. This regards so various and utterly
distinct topics as quantum spin systems and the grand unification theory. This
may be foremost caused by the fact that all of these effects are based on
correlated structures, which are induced by the interplay of dynamics and
elementary interactions. It is strongly correlated systems that certainly
represent one of the most fascinating and universal fields of research. In
particular, low dimensional systems are in the focus of interest, as they
reveal strongly pronounced correlations of counterintuitive nature. As regards
this framework, the quantum Hall effect must be seen as one of the most
intriguing and complex problems of modern solid state physics. Even after two
decades and the same number of Nobel prizes, it still keeps researchers of
nearly all fields of physics occupied. In spite of seminal progress, its
inherent correlated order still lacks understanding on a microscopic level.
Despite this, it is obvious that the phenomenon is thoroughly fundamental of
nature. To resolve some puzzles of this nature is a key topic of this thesis.
(excerpt from abstract)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01066</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Klinke</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Hierarchical colloidal nanostructures - from fundamentals to
  applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><journal-ref>Z. Phys. Chem. 231 (2017) 1</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/zpch-2016-5004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Editorial for the Special Issue of &quot;Zeitschrift fuer Physikalische Chemie&quot; on
&quot;Hierarchical Colloidal Nanostructures&quot;
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01076</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Scarsoglio</keyname><forenames>Stefania</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iacobello</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ridolfi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex Networks Unveiling Spatial Patterns in Turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD physics.data-an</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos, 26 (13), 1650223,
  2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218127416502230</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical and experimental turbulence simulations are nowadays reaching the
size of the so-called big data, thus requiring refined investigative tools for
appropriate statistical analyses and data mining. We present a new approach
based on the complex network theory, offering a powerful framework to explore
complex systems with a huge number of interacting elements. Although interest
on complex networks has been increasing in the last years, few recent studies
have been applied to turbulence. We propose an investigation starting from a
two-point correlation for the kinetic energy of a forced isotropic field
numerically solved. Among all the metrics analyzed, the degree centrality is
the most significant, suggesting the formation of spatial patterns which
coherently move with similar vorticity over the large eddy turnover time scale.
Pattern size can be quantified through a newly-introduced parameter (i.e.,
average physical distance) and varies from small to intermediate scales. The
network analysis allows a systematic identification of different spatial
regions, providing new insights into the spatial characterization of turbulent
flows. Based on present findings, the application to highly inhomogeneous flows
seems promising and deserves additional future investigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01078</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Baffes</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Andrews</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Czajkowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Derwent</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Edelen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hanna</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hartsell</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kendziora</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Prost</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Scarpine</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shemyakin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Steimel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zuchnik</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Edelen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Colorado State U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Installation Progress At The PIP-II Injector Test At Fermilab</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>4 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-434-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  A CW-compatible, pulsed H- superconducting linac &quot;PIP-II&quot; is being planned to
upgrade Fermilab's injection complex. To validate the front-end concept, a test
accelerator (The PIP-II Injector Test, formerly known as &quot;PXIE&quot;) is under
construction. The warm part of this accelerator comprises a 10 mA DC, 30 keV H-
ion source, a 2 m-long Low Energy Beam Transport (LEBT), a 2.1 MeV Radio
Frequency Quadrupole (RFQ) capable of operation in Continuous Wave (CW) mode,
and a 10 m-long Medium Energy Beam Transport (MEBT). The paper will report on
the installation of the RFQ and the first sections of the MEBT and related
mechanical design considerations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01086</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Linkmann</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berera</keyname><forenames>Arjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstraw</keyname><forenames>Erin E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reynolds-number dependence of the dimensionless dissipation rate in
  homogeneous magnetohydrodynamic turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 013102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.013102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper examines the behavior of the dimensionless dissipation rate
$C_{\varepsilon}$ for stationary and nonstationary magnetohydrodynamic (MHD)
turbulence in presence of external forces. By combining with previous studies
for freely decaying MHD turbulence, we obtain here both the most general model
equation for $C_{\varepsilon}$ applicable to homogeneous MHD turbulence and a
comprehensive numerical study of the Reynolds number dependence of the
dimensionless total energy dissipation rate at unity magnetic Prandtl number.
We carry out a series of medium to high resolution direct numerical simulations
of mechanically forced stationary MHD turbulence in order to verify the
predictions of the model equation for the stationary case. Furthermore,
questions of nonuniversality are discussed in terms of the effect of external
forces as well as the level of cross- and magnetic helicity. The measured
values of the asymptote $C_{\varepsilon,\infty}$ lie between $0.193 \leqslant
C_{\varepsilon,\infty} \leqslant 0.268$ for free decay, where the value depends
on the initial level of cross- and magnetic helicities. In the stationary case
we measure $C_{\varepsilon,\infty} = 0.223$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01089</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;nzhuber</keyname><forenames>Franz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinlein</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiessling</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molenkamp</keyname><forenames>Laurens W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization-assisted Vector Magnetometry in Zero Bias Field with an
  Ensemble of Nitrogen-Vacancy Centers in Diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate vector magnetometry with an ensemble of nitrogen-vacancy (NV)
centers in diamond without the need for an external bias field. The anisotropy
of the electric dipole moments of the NV center reduces the ambiguity of the
optically detected magnetic resonances upon polarized visible excitation.
Further lifting of the remaining ambiguities is achieved via application of an
appropriately linearly polarized microwave field, which enables suppression of
spin-state transitions of a certain crystallographic NV orientation. This
allows for the full vector reconstruction of small (less 0.1 mT) magnetic
fields without an external bias field having to interfere with the magnetic
structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01098</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wharton</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke-Spolaor</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hessels</keyname><forenames>J. W. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bower</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cordes</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tendulkar</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassa</keyname><forenames>C. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demorest</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butler</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seymour</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abruzzo</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaspi</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keimpema</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazio</keyname><forenames>T. J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcote</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLaughlin</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paragi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ransom</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spitler</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Langevelde</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The direct localization of a fast radio burst and its host</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Nature, published online on 4 Jan 2017, DOI: 10.1038/nature20797</comments><doi>10.1038/nature20797</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fast radio bursts are astronomical radio flashes of unknown physical nature
with durations of milliseconds. Their dispersive arrival times suggest an
extragalactic origin and imply radio luminosities orders of magnitude larger
than any other kind of known short-duration radio transient. Thus far, all FRBs
have been detected with large single-dish telescopes with arcminute
localizations, and attempts to identify their counterparts (source or host
galaxy) have relied on contemporaneous variability of field sources or the
presence of peculiar field stars or galaxies. These attempts have not resulted
in an unambiguous association with a host or multi-wavelength counterpart. Here
we report the sub-arcsecond localization of FRB 121102, the only known
repeating burst source, using high-time-resolution radio interferometric
observations that directly image the bursts themselves. Our precise
localization reveals that FRB 121102 originates within 100 mas of a faint 180
uJy persistent radio source with a continuum spectrum that is consistent with
non-thermal emission, and a faint (25th magnitude) optical counterpart. The
flux density of the persistent radio source varies by tens of percent on day
timescales, and very long baseline radio interferometry yields an angular size
less than 1.7 mas. Our observations are inconsistent with the fast radio burst
having a Galactic origin or its source being located within a prominent
star-forming galaxy. Instead, the source appears to be co-located with a
low-luminosity active galactic nucleus or a previously unknown type of
extragalactic source. [Truncated] If other fast radio bursts have similarly
faint radio and optical counterparts, our findings imply that direct
sub-arcsecond localizations of FRBs may be the only way to provide reliable
associations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
