<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T00:03:50Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-19" from="2017-01-19" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.2347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.2347</id><created>2012-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Aalseth</keyname><forenames>Craig E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonicalzi</keyname><forenames>Ricco M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fast</keyname><forenames>James E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossbach</keyname><forenames>Todd W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orrell</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Overman</keyname><forenames>Cory T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandevender</keyname><forenames>Brent A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cryostat for Ultra-low-energy Threshold Germanium Spectrometers</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>Accepted to IEEE Trans. Nucl. Sci. as a peer reviewed conference
  proceedings of the Symposium on Radiation Measurements and Applications
  (SORMA West) May 14-17, 2012</comments><report-no>PNNL-SA-88541</report-no><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Nuclear Science 60(2): 1168-1174 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TNS.2012.2224669</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents progress on the development of a cryostat intended to
improve upon the low-energy threshold (below 0.5 keV) of p-type point contact
germanium gamma-ray spectrometers. Ultra-low energy thresholds are important in
the detection of low-energy nuclear recoils, an event class relevant to both
dark matter direct detection and measurement of coherent neutrino-nucleus
scattering. The cryostat design, including a thermal and electrical-field
model, is given. A prototype cryostat has been assembled and data acquired to
evaluate its vacuum and thermal performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.5200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.5200</id><created>2013-10-18</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ee</keyname><forenames>June-Haak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jungil</forenames></author></authors><title>Magic mass ratios of complete energy-momentum transfer in
  one-dimensional elastic three-body collisions</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Am. J. Phys. 83 (2), February 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4897162</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the one-dimensional scattering of two identical blocks of mass
$M$ that exchange energy and momentum via elastic collisions with an
intermediary ball of mass $m=\alpha M$. Initially, one block is incident upon
the ball with the other block at rest. For $\alpha&lt;1$, the three objects will
make multiple collisions with one another. In our analysis, we construct a
Euclidean vector $\textbf{V}_n$ whose components are proportional to the
velocities of the objects. Energy-momentum conservation then requires a
covariant recurrence relation for $\textbf{V}_n$ that transforms like a pure
rotation in three dimensions. The analytic solutions of the terminal velocities
result in a remarkable prediction for values of $\alpha$, in cases where the
initial energy and momentum of the incident block are completely transferred to
the scattered block. We call these values for $\alpha$ &quot;magic mass ratios.&quot;
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.6330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.6330</id><created>2013-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Whalen</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smidt</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rydberg</keyname><forenames>Claes-Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Jarrett L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holz</keyname><forenames>Daniel E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stiavelli</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting Ancient Supernovae at z ~ 5 - 12 with CLASH</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, submitted to ApJL</comments><report-no>LA-UR-13-27629</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supernovae are important probes of the properties of stars at high redshifts
because they can be detected at early epochs and their masses can be inferred
from their light curves. Finding the first cosmic explosions in the universe
will only be possible with the James Webb Space Telescope, the Wide-Field
Infrared Survey Telescope and the next generation of extremely large
telescopes. But strong gravitational lensing by massive clusters, like those in
the Cluster Lensing and Supernova Survey with Hubble (CLASH), could reveal such
events now by magnifying their flux by factors of 10 or more. We find that
CLASH will likely discover at least 2 - 3 core-collapse supernovae at 5 &lt; z &lt;
12 and perhaps as many as ten. Future surveys of cluster lenses similar in
scope to CLASH by the James Webb Space Telescope might find hundreds of these
events out to z ~ 15 - 17. Besides revealing the masses of early stars, these
ancient supernovae will also constrain cosmic star formation rates in the era
of first galaxy formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.3062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.3062</id><created>2014-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient fidelity control by stepwise nucleotide selection in
  polymerase elongation</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><journal-ref>Mol. Based Math. Biol. 2014, 2,141</journal-ref><doi>10.2478/mlbmb-2014-0010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polymerases select nucleotides before incorporating them for chemical
synthesis during gene replication or transcription. How the selection proceeds
stepwise efficiently to achieve sufficiently high fidelity and speed is
essential for polymerase function. We examined step-by-step selections that
have conformational transition rates tuned one at time in the polymerase
elongation cycle, with a controlled differentiation free energy at each
checkpoint. The elongation is sustained at non-equilibrium steady state with
constant free energy input and heat dissipation. It is found that error
reduction capability does not improve for selection checkpoints down the
reaction path. Hence, it is essential to select early to achieve an efficient
fidelity control. In particular, for two consecutive selections that reject the
wrong substrate back and inhibit it forward from a same kinetic state, the same
error rates are obtained at the same free energy differentiation. The initial
screening is indispensible for maintaining the elongation speed high, as the
wrong nucleotides can be removed quickly and replaced by the right nucleotides
at the entry. Overall, the elongation error rate can be repeatedly reduced
through multiple selection checkpoints. The study provides a theoretical
framework to conduct further detailed researches, and assists engineering and
redesign of related enzymes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.4709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.4709</id><created>2014-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Quijandr&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Ripoll</keyname><forenames>Juan Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zueco</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuous matrix product states for coupled fields: Application to
  Luttinger Liquids and quantum simulators</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 90, 235142 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.90.235142</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  A way of constructing continuous matrix product states (cMPS) for coupled
fields is presented here. The cMPS is a variational \emph{ansatz} for the
ground state of quantum field theories in one dimension. Our proposed scheme is
based in the physical interpretation in which the cMPS class can be produced by
means of a dissipative dynamic of a system interacting with a bath. We study
the case of coupled bosonic fields. We test the method with previous DMRG
results in coupled Lieb Liniger models. Besides, we discuss a novel application
for characterizing the Luttinger liquid theory emerging in the low energy
regime of these theories. Finally, we propose a circuit QED architecture as a
quantum simulator for coupled fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.1422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.1422</id><created>2014-12-03</created><updated>2015-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Syers</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paglione</keyname><forenames>Johnpierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Ambipolar surface state transport in non-metallic stoichiometric
  Bi$_2$Se$_3$ crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045123 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Achieving true bulk insulating behavior in Bi$_2$Se$_3$, the archetypal
topological insulator with a simplistic one-band electronic structure and
sizable band gap, has been prohibited by a well-known self-doping effect caused
by selenium vacancies, whose extra electrons shift the chemical potential into
the bulk conduction band. We report a new synthesis method for achieving
stoichiometric Bi$_2$Se$_3$ crystals that exhibit nonmetallic behavior in
electrical transport down to low temperatures. Hall effect measurements
indicate the presence of both electron- and hole-like carriers, with the latter
identified with surface state conduction and the achievement of ambipolar
transport in bulk Bi$_2$Se$_3$ crystals without gating techniques. With carrier
mobilities surpassing the highest values yet reported for topological surface
states in this material, the achievement of ambipolar transport via upward band
bending is found to provide a key method to advancing the potential of this
material for future study and applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.2301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.2301</id><created>2014-12-06</created><updated>2014-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Chaoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Lijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Jianxin</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple Cubic Carbon Phase C21-sc: A Promising Superhard Carbon Conductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Carbon, 112, 91-96,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2016.11.008</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  Traditionally, all superhard carbon phases including diamond are electric
insulators and all conductive carbon phases including graphite are mechanically
soft. Based on first-principles calculation results, we report a superhard but
conductive carbon phase C21-sc which can be obtained through increasing the sp3
bonds in the previously proposed soft and conductive phase C20-sc (Phys. Rev. B
74, 172101 2006). We also show that further increase of sp3 bonds in C21-sc
results in a superhard and insulating phase C22-sc with sp3 bonds only. With
C20-sc, C21-sc, C22-sc and graphite, the X-ray diffraction peaks from the
unidentified carbon material synthesized by compressing the mixture of
tetracyanoethylene and carbon black (Carbon, 41, 1309, 2003) can be understood.
In view of its positive stability, superhard and conductive features, and the
strong possibility of existence in previous experiments, C21-sc is a promising
multi-functional material with potential applications in extreme conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4376</id><created>2014-12-14</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Enciso</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamran</keyname><forenames>Niky</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentzian Einstein metrics with prescribed conformal infinity</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a local well-posedness theorem for the (n+1)-dimensional Einstein
equations in Lorentzian signature, with initial data $(\tilde g, K)$ whose
asymptotic geometry at infinity is similar to that anti-de Sitter (AdS) space,
and compatible boundary data $\hat g$ prescribed at the time-like conformal
boundary of space-time. More precisely, we consider an n-dimensional
asymptotically hyperbolic Riemannian manifold $(M,\tilde g)$ such that the
conformally rescaled metric $x^2 \tilde g$ (with $x$ a boundary defining
function) extends to the closure $\bar M$ of $M$ as a metric of class $C^{n-1}$
which is also polyhomogeneous of class $C^{p}$ on $\bar M$. Likewise we assume
that the conformally rescaled symmetric (0,2)-tensor $x^{2}K$ extends to the
closure as a tensor field of class $C^{n-1}$ which is polyhomogeneous of class
$C^{p-1}$. We assume that the initial data $(\tilde g, K)$ satisfy the Einstein
constraint equations and also that the boundary datum is of class $C^p$ on
$\partial M\times (-T_0,T_0)$ and satisfies a set of natural compatibility
conditions with the initial data. We then prove that there exists an integer
$r_n$, depending only on the dimension n, such that if $p \geq 2q+r_n$, with
$q$ a positive integer, then there is $T&gt;0$, depending only on the norms of the
initial and boundary data, such that the Einstein equations have a unique (up
to a diffeomorphism) solution $g$ on $(-T,T)\times M$ with the above initial
and boundary data, which is such that $x^2g$ is of class $C^{n-1}$ and
polyhomogeneous of class $C^q$. Furthermore, if $x^2\tilde g$ and $x^2K$ are
polyhomogeneous of class $C^\infty$ and $\hat g$ is in $C^\infty$, then $x^2g$
is polyhomogeneous of class $C^\infty$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.03998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.03998</id><created>2015-01-16</created><updated>2016-12-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amitai</keyname><forenames>Shahar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blumenfeld</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author></authors><title>Modifying continuous-time random walks to model finite-size particle
  diffusion in granular porous media</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Granular Matter 19: 13 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10035-016-0694-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The continuous-time random walk (CTRW) model is useful for alleviating the
computational burden of simulating diffusion in actual media. In principle,
isotropic CTRW only requires knowledge of the step-size, $P_l$, and
waiting-time, $P_t$, distributions of the random walk in the medium and it then
generates presumably equivalent walks in free space, which are much faster.
Here we test the usefulness of CTRW to modelling diffusion of finite-size
particles in porous medium generated by loose granular packs. This is done by
first simulating the diffusion process in a model porous medium of mean
coordination number, which corresponds to marginal rigidity (the loosest
possible structure), computing the resulting distributions $P_l$ and $P_t$ as
functions of the particle size, and then using these as input for a free space
CTRW. The CTRW walks are then compared to the ones simulated in the actual
media.
  In particular, we study the normal-to-anomalous transition of the diffusion
as a function of increasing particle size. We find that, given the same $P_l$
and $P_t$ for the simulation and the CTRW, the latter predicts incorrectly the
size at which the transition occurs. We show that the discrepancy is related to
the dependence of the effective connectivity of the porous media on the
diffusing particle size, which is not captured simply by these distributions.
  We propose a correcting modification to the CTRW model -- adding anisotropy
-- and show that it yields good agreement with the simulated diffusion process.
We also present a method to obtain $P_l$ and $P_t$ directly from the porous
sample, without having to simulate an actual diffusion process. This extends
the use of CTRW, with all its advantages, to modelling diffusion processes of
finite-size particles in such confined geometries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02411</id><created>2015-03-09</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>Oliver Lindblad</forenames></author></authors><title>The mode solution of the wave equation in Kasner spacetimes and redshift</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><msc-class>83C15, 34C11</msc-class><journal-ref>Math. Phys. Anal. Geom. 19 (2016), no. 4, 19:26</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11040-016-9233-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the mode solution to the Cauchy problem of the scalar wave equation
$\Box \varphi = 0$ in Kasner spacetimes. As a first result, we give the
explicit mode solution in axisymmetric Kasner spacetimes, of which flat Kasner
spacetimes are special cases. Furthermore, we give the small and large time
asymptotics of the modes in general Kasner spacetimes. Generically, the modes
in non-flat Kasner spacetimes grow logarithmically for small times, while the
modes in flat Kasner spacetimes stay bounded for small times. For large times,
however, the modes in general Kasner spacetimes oscillate with a polynomially
decreasing amplitude. This gives a notion of large time frequency of the modes,
which we use to model the wavelength of light rays in Kasner spacetimes. We
show that the redshift one obtains in this way actually coincides with the
usual cosmological redshift.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08269</id><created>2015-03-28</created><updated>2015-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Teik-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chii-Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Spin Accumulation induced Magnetocapacitance in a Single
  Electron Transistor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 5, 13704 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep13704</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interplay between spin and charge in solids is currently among the most
discussed topics in condensed matter physics. Such interplay gives rise to
magneto-electric coupling, which in the case of solids was named
magneto-electric effect, as predicted by Curie on the basis of symmetry
considerations. This effect enables the manipulation of magnetization using
electrical field or, conversely, the manipulation of electrical polarization by
magnetic field. The latter is known as the magnetocapacitance effect. Here, we
show that non-equilibrium spin accumulation can induce tunnel
magnetocapacitance through the formation of a tiny charge dipole. This dipole
can effectively give rise to an additional serial capacitance, which represents
an extra charging energy that the tunneling electrons would encounter. In the
sequential tunneling regime, this extra energy can be understood as the energy
required for a single spin to flip. A ferromagnetic single-electron-transistor
with tunable magnetic configuration is utilized to demonstrate the proposed
mechanism. It is found that the extra threshold energy is experienced only by
electrons entering the islands, bringing about asymmetry in the measured
Coulomb diamond. This asymmetry is an unambiguous evidence of spin accumulation
induced tunnel magnetocapacitance, and the measured magnetocapacitance value is
as high as 40%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03224</id><created>2015-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Chaoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>xiangyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Lijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Jianxin</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct and quasi-direct band gap silicon allotropes with remarkable
  stability</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics,18,9682,2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP00451B</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our present work, five previously proposed sp$^3$ carbon crystals were
suggested as silicon allotropes and their stabilities, electronic and optical
properties were investigated by first-principles method. We find that these
allotropes with direct or quasi-direct band gaps in range of 1.2-1.6 eV are
very suitable for applications in thin-film solar cells. They display strong
adsorption coefficients in the visible range of the sunlight in comparison with
diamond silicon. These five silicon allotropes are confirmed possessing
positive dynamical stability and remarkable themodynamical stability close to
that of diamond silicon. Especially, the direct band gap M585-silicon
possessing energy higher than diamond silicon only 25 meV per atom is expected
to be experimentally produced for thin-film solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07262</id><created>2015-06-24</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahiyan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>B. Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momennia</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transition of charged black holes in massive gravity through new
  methods</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures, change title, published version</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. (Berlin) 528, 819 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201600180</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by providing preliminary steps to understand the conception of
quantum gravity, in this paper, we study the phase structure of a semiclassical
gravitational system. We investigate the stability conditions and phase
transition of charged black holes in massive gravity via canonical and
geometrical thermodynamic approaches. We point out the effects of massive
parameter on stability conditions of these black holes and show how massive
coefficients affect the phase transition points of these black holes. We also
study the effects of boundary topology on thermodynamical behavior of the
system. In addition, we give some arguments regarding the role of higher
dimensions and highlight the effect of the electric charge in thermodynamical
behavior. Then, we extend our study to geometrical thermodynamic approach and
show that it can be a successful method for studying the black hole phase
transition. At last, by employing the relation between thermodynamical pressure
and cosmological constant, critical behavior of the system and the effects of
different parameters on critical values are investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02944</id><created>2015-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Fernandez-Lorenzo</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Ripoll</keyname><forenames>Juan Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porras</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phases of shaken quantum Ising lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 023030 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/023030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum compass model consists of a two-dimensional square spin lattice
where the orientation of the spin-spin interactions depends on the spatial
direction of the bonds. It has remarkable symmetry properties and the ground
state shows topological degeneracy. The implementation of the quantum compass
model in quantum simulation setups like ultracold atoms and trapped ions is far
from trivial, since spin interactions in those sytems typically are independent
of the spatial direction. Ising spin interactions, on the contrary, can be
induced and controlled in atomic setups with state-of-the art experimental
techniques. In this work, we show how the quantum compass model on a
rectangular lattice can be simulated by the use of the photon-assisted
tunneling induced by periodic drivings on a quantum Ising spin model. We
describe a procedure to adiabatically prepare one of the doubly-degenerate
ground states of this model by adiabatically ramping down a transverse magnetic
field, with surprising differences depending on the parity of the lattice size.
Exact diagonalizations confirm the validity of this approach for small
lattices. Specific implementations of this scheme are presented with ultracold
atoms in optical lattices in the Mott insulator regime, as well as with Rydberg
atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04041</id><created>2015-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Corona</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salgado-Garcia</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Degenerated ground-states in a class of 1D Ising-like models: a
  characterization by symbolic dynamics</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa4e5f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we study a class of one-dimensional Ising chain having a highly
degenerated set of ground-state configurations. The model consists of spin
chain having infinite-range pair interactions with a given structure. We show
that the set of ground-state configurations of such a model can be fully
characterized by means of symbolic dynamics. Particularly we found that the set
ground- state configurations defines what in symbolic dynamics is called sofic
shift space. Finally we prove that this system has a non-vanishing residual
entropy (the topological entropy of the shift space), which can be exactly
calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00108</id><created>2015-10-01</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>B. Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahiyan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamical Structure of AdS Black Holes in Massive Gravity with
  Stringy Gauge-Gravity Corrections</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 15 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33, 235007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/23/235007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by gauge/gravity group in the low energy effective theory of the
heterotic string theory and novel aspects of massive gravity in the context of
lattice physics, the minimal coupling of Gauss-Bonnet-massive gravity with
Born-Infeld electrodynamics is considered. At first, the metric function is
calculated and then the geometrical properties of the solutions are
investigated. It is found that there is an essential singularity at the origin
and the intrinsic curvature is regular elsewhere. In addition, the effects of
massive parameters are studied and black hole solutions with multi horizons are
found in this gravity. Also the conserved and thermodynamic quantities are
calculated, and it is shown that the solutions satisfy the first law of
thermodynamics. Furthermore, using heat capacity of these black holes, thermal
stability and phase transitions are investigated. The variation of different
parameters and related modifications on the (number of) phase transition are
examined. Next, the critical behavior of the Gauss-Bonnet-Born-Infeld-massive
black holes in the context of extended phase space is studied. It is shown that
how the variation of the different parameters affects the existence and absence
of phase transition. Also, it is found that for specific values of different
parameters, these black holes may enjoy the existence of new type of phase
transition which to our knowledge was not observed in black hole physics
before.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00409</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>Hideaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>Takahiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraki</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasao</keyname><forenames>Noboru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uetake</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Injection seeded tunable mid-infrared pulses by difference frequency
  mixing</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the generation of nanosecond mid-infrared pulses having
frequency tunability, a narrow linewidth, and a high pulse energy. These pulses
are obtained by frequency mixing between injection-seeded near-infrared pulses
in potassium titanyl arsenate crystals. A continuous-wave external cavity laser
diode or a Ti:sapphire ring laser is used as a tunable seeding source for the
near-infrared pulses. The typical energy of the generated mid-infrared pulses
is in the range of 0.4-1 mJ/pulse. The tuning wavelength ranges from 3142 to
4806 nm. A narrow linewidth of 1.4 GHz and good frequency reproducibility of
the mid-infrared pulses are confirmed by observing a rovibrational absorption
line of gaseous carbon monoxide at 4587 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00707</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Alejandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofman</keyname><forenames>Diego M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iqbal</keyname><forenames>Nabil</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy in Warped Conformal Field Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>37 pages + appendix, 2 figures; v2: minor changes, references added;
  v3: references added; v4: error corrected in derivation of twist operator
  dimensions, results unchanged</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed discussion of entanglement entropy in (1+1)-dimensional
Warped Conformal Field Theories (WCFTs). We implement the Rindler method to
evaluate entanglement and Renyi entropies for a single interval and along the
way we interpret our results in terms of twist field correlation functions.
Holographically a WCFT can be described in terms of Lower Spin Gravity, a
SL(2,R)xU(1) Chern-Simons theory in three dimensions. We show how to obtain the
universal field theory results for entanglement in a WCFT via holography. For
the geometrical description of the theory we introduce the concept of geodesic
and massive point particles in the warped geometry associated to Lower Spin
Gravity. In the Chern-Simons description we evaluate the appropriate Wilson
line that captures the dynamics of a massive particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08392</id><created>2015-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational Investigations on Polymerase Actions in Gene Transcription
  and Replication Combining Physical Modeling and Atomistic Simulations</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B Vol. 25, No. 1 (2016) 018706</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/25/1/018706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polymerases are protein enzymes that move along nucleic acid chains and
catalyze template-based polymerization reactions during gene transcription and
replication. The polymerases also substantially improve transcription or
replication fidelity through the non-equilibrium enzymatic cycles. We briefly
review computational efforts that have been made toward understanding
mechano-chemical coupling and fidelity control mechanisms of the polymerase
elongation. The polymerases are regarded as molecular information motors during
the elongation process. It requires a full spectrum of computational approaches
from multiple time and length scales to understand the full polymerase
functional cycle. We keep away from quantum mechanics based approaches to the
polymerase catalysis due to abundant former surveys, while address only
statistical physics modeling approach and all-atom molecular dynamics
simulation approach. We organize this review around our own modeling and
simulation practices on a single-subunit T7 RNA polymerase, and summarize
commensurate studies on structurally similar DNA polymerases. For multi-subunit
RNA polymerases that have been intensively studied in recent years, we leave
detailed discussions on the simulation achievements to other computational
chemical surveys, while only introduce very recently published representative
studies, including our own preliminary work on structure-based modeling on
yeast RNA polymerase II. In the end, we quickly go through kinetic modeling on
elongation pauses and backtracking activities. We emphasize the fluctuation and
control mechanisms of the polymerase actions, highlight the non-equilibrium
physical nature of the system, and try to bring some perspectives toward
understanding replication and transcription regulation from single molecular
details to a genome-wide scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01216</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Aaron S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gustafson</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>Craig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamai</keyname><forenames>Brittany</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Ohkyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanza</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCuller</keyname><forenames>Lee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Stephan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoughton</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomlin</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waldman</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>First measurements of high frequency cross-spectra from a pair of large
  Michelson interferometers</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-217-AE</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.Lett. 117 (2016) no.11, 111102</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.111102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements are reported of the cross-correlation of spectra of differential
position signals from the Fermilab Holometer, a pair of co-located 39 m long,
high power Michelson interferometers with flat, broadband frequency response in
the MHz range. The instrument obtains sensitivity to high frequency correlated
signals far exceeding any previous measurement in a broad frequency band
extending beyond the 3.8 MHz inverse light crossing time of the apparatus. The
dominant but uncorrelated shot noise is averaged down over $2\times 10^8$
independent spectral measurements with 381 Hz frequency resolution to obtain
$2.1\times 10^{-20} \ \mathrm{m}/\sqrt{\mathrm{Hz}}$ sensitivity to stationary
signals. For signal bandwidths $\Delta f &gt; 11$ kHz, the sensitivity to strain
$h$ or shear power spectral density of classical or exotic origin surpasses a
milestone $PSD_{\delta h} &lt; t_p$ where $t_p= 5.39\times 10^{-44}/\mathrm{Hz}$
is the Planck time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06494</id><created>2015-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Orrell</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aalseth</keyname><forenames>Craig E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnquist</keyname><forenames>Isaac J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggemeyer</keyname><forenames>Tere A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glasgow</keyname><forenames>Brian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoppe</keyname><forenames>Eric W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keillor</keyname><forenames>Martin E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morley</keyname><forenames>Shannon M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myers</keyname><forenames>Allan W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Overman</keyname><forenames>Cory T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaff</keyname><forenames>Sarah M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thommasson</keyname><forenames>Kimbrelle S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Assay methods for U-238, Th-232, and Pb-210 in lead and calibration of
  Bi-210 bremsstrahlung emission from lead</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Submitted to Journal of Radioanalytical and Nuclear Chemistry</comments><report-no>PNNL-SA-115123</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Radioanalytical and Nuclear Chemistry 309(3): 1271-1281
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10967-016-4732-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assay methods for measuring 238U, 232Th, and 210Pb concentrations in refined
lead are presented. The 238U and 232Th concentrations are determined using
isotope dilution inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ID-ICP-MS) after
anion exchange column separation of dissolved lead samples. The 210Pb
concentration is inferred through {\alpha}-spectroscopy of a daughter isotope,
210Po, after chemical precipitation separation on dissolved lead samples.
Subsequent to the 210Po {\alpha}-spectroscopy assay, a method for evaluating
210Pb concentrations in solid lead samples was developed via measurement of
bremsstrahlung radiation from \b{eta}-decay of a daughter isotope, 210Bi, by
employing a 14-crystal array of high purity germanium (HPGe) detectors. Ten
sources of refined lead were assayed. The 238U concentrations were &lt;34
microBq/kg and the 232Th concentrations ranged &lt;0.6-15 microBq/kg, as
determined by the ICP-MS assay method. The 210Pb concentrations ranged from
~0.1-75 Bq/kg, as inferred by the 210Po {\alpha}-spectroscopy assay method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06616</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barletti</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Negulescu</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author></authors><title>Hybrid classical-quantum models for charge transport in graphene with
  sharp potentials</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Withdrawn after detection of a major error in the C-E expansion</comments><msc-class>82C70 76M45 82D37</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a concise account on the derivation of hybrid quantum-classical
models for stationary electron transport in graphene, in presence of sharp
potential steps of barriers. A quantum region (an asymptotically thin strip
around the potential step or barrier) is coupled through the quantum scattering
data to a classical region, where electron transport is described in terms of
semiclassical kinetic equations. The diffusive limit of the kinetic model is
derived by means of the Chapman-Enskog method, which requires the introduction
of a boundary layer corrector and the discussion of a system of coupled Milne
problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07057</id><created>2015-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferrando</keyname><forenames>Joan Josep</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>Juan Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Null conformal Killing-Yano tensors and Birkhoff theorem</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2016) 48:40</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2036-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the space-times admitting a null conformal Killing-Yano tensor whose
divergence defines a Killing vector. We analyze the similitudes and differences
with the recently studied non null case (Gen. Relativ. Grav. (2015) {\bf 47}
1911). The results by Barnes concerning the Birkhoff theorem for the case of
null orbits are analyzed and generalized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03382</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-10-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Flavio S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nussinov</keyname><forenames>Zohar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Jeroen van den</forenames></author></authors><title>Duality of a compact topological superconductor model and the Witten
  effect</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con hep-th</categories><comments>9.1 pages, 1 figure; v3: minor changes; references added; published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 085003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.085003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a compact abelian Higgs model in 3+1 dimensions with a
topological axion term and construct its dual theories for both bulk and
boundary at strong coupling. The model may be viewed as describing a
superconductor with magnetic monopoles, which can also be interpreted as a
field theory of a topological Mott insulator. We show that this model is dual
to a non-compact topological field theory of particles and vortices. It has
exactly the same form of a model for superconducting cosmic strings with an
axion term. We consider the duality of the boundary field theory at strong
coupling and show that in this case $\theta$ is quantized as $-8\pi n/m$ where
$n$ and $m$ are the quantum numbers associated to electric and magnetic
charges. These topological states lack a non-interacting equivalent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06677</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06677</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malinowski</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nissen</keyname><forenames>P. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cywi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudner</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallahi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardner</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfra</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcus</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuemmeth</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Notch filtering the nuclear environment of a spin qubit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, including main text (5 figures) and supplementary
  information (2 figures)</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV CMT 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Nat. Nanotechnol. 12, 16-20 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nnano.2016.170</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron spins in gate-defined quantum dots provide a promising platform for
quantum computation. In particular, spin-based quantum computing in gallium
arsenide takes advantage of the high quality of semiconducting materials,
reliability in fabricating arrays of quantum dots, and accurate qubit
operations. However, the effective magnetic noise arising from the hyperfine
interaction with uncontrolled nuclear spins in the host lattice constitutes a
major source of decoherence. Low frequency nuclear noise, responsible for fast
(10 ns) inhomogeneous dephasing, can be removed by echo techniques. High
frequency nuclear noise, recently studied via echo revivals, occurs in narrow
frequency bands related to differences in Larmor precession of the three
isotopes $\mathbf{^{69}Ga}$, $\mathbf{^{71}Ga}$, and $\mathbf{^{75}As}$. Here
we show that both low and high frequency nuclear noise can be filtered by
appropriate dynamical decoupling sequences, resulting in a substantial
enhancement of spin qubit coherence times. Using nuclear notch filtering, we
demonstrate a spin coherence time ($\mathbf{T_{2}}$) of 0.87 ms, five orders of
magnitude longer than typical exchange gate times, and exceeding the longest
coherence times reported to date in Si/SiGe gate-defined quantum dots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02981</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Niiyama</keyname><forenames>Tomoaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimokawa</keyname><forenames>Tomotsugu</forenames></author></authors><title>Barrier effect of grain boundaries on the avalanche propagation of
  polycrystalline plasticity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 140102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.140102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To investigate the barrier effect of grain boundaries on the propagation of
avalanche-like plasticity at the atomic-scale, we perform three-dimensional
molecular dynamics simulations by using simplified polycrystal models including
symmetric-tilt grain boundaries. The cut-offs of stress-drop distributions
following power-law distributions decrease as the size of the crystal grains
decreases. We show that some deformation avalanches are confined by grain
boundaries; on the other hand, unignorable avalanches penetrate all the grain
boundaries included in the models. The blocking probability that one grain
boundary hinders this system-spanning avalanche is evaluated by using an
elemental probabilistic model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04214</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brzeski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlovskaia</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapitaniak</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perlikowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling multistability by discontinuous dissipative coupling</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Mechanical Sciences, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2016.12.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present an influence of discontinuous coupling on the
dynamics of multistable systems. Our model consists of two periodically forced
oscillators that can interact via soft impacts. The controlling parameters are
the distance between the oscillators and the difference in the phase of the
harmonic excitation. When the distance is large two systems do not collide and
a number of different possible solutions can be observed in both of them. When
decreasing of the distance, one can observe some transient impacts and then the
systems settle down on non-impacting attractor. It is shown that with the
properly chosen distance and difference in the phase of the harmonic
excitation, the number of possible solutions of the coupled systems can be
reduced. The proposed method is robust and applicable in many different
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01584</id><created>2016-03-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Aalseth</keyname><forenames>Craig E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collar</keyname><forenames>Juan I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colaresi</keyname><forenames>Jim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fast</keyname><forenames>James E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossbach</keyname><forenames>Todd W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orrell</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Overman</keyname><forenames>Cory T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholz</keyname><forenames>Bjorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>VanDevender</keyname><forenames>Brent A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yocum</keyname><forenames>K. Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>A Low-noise Germanium Ionization Spectrometer for Low-background Science</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Submitted to IEEE Transaction in Nuclear Science</comments><report-no>PNNL-SA-116069</report-no><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Nuclear Science 63(6): 2782-2792 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TNS.2016.2614431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent progress on the development of very low noise high purity germanium
ionization spectrometers has produced an instrument of 1.2 kg mass and
excellent noise performance. The detector was installed in a low-background
cryostat intended for use in a direct detection search for low mass, WIMP dark
matter. This Transaction reports the thermal characterization of the cryostat,
specifications of the newly prepared 1.2 kg p-type point contact germanium
detector, and the spectroscopic performance of the integrated system. The
integrated detector and low background cryostat achieved
full-width-at-half-maximum noise performance of 98 eV for an electronic pulse
generator peak and 1.9 keV for the 1332 keV Co-60 gamma ray.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07165</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yanxiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Zhifu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Bihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jincan</forenames></author></authors><title>The internal energy expression of a long-range interaction complex
  system and its statistical physical properties</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica A, 2017(473) 423</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2017.01.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Considering the interactions of two arbitrary particles, we obtain an
internal energy expression of the complex system having long-range
interactions. Based on the postulate of &quot;equal-probability principle&quot; for all
microstates, the probability distribution function of the system is derived,
and consequently, some main statistical physical properties of the system are
revealed. It is important to find that the properties of a long-range
interaction system are very closely dependent on the interaction coefficient
and particle number.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04755</id><created>2016-04-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Ravi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katukuri</keyname><forenames>Vamshi M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimoto</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Jeroen van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hozoi</keyname><forenames>Liviu</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit excitation energies, anisotropic exchange, and magnetic
  phases of honeycomb RuCl3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS 6, 37925 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep37925</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using quantum chemistry calculations we shed fresh light on the electronic
structure and magnetic properties of RuCl3, a proposed realization of the
honeycomb Kitaev spin model. It is found that the nearest-neighbor Kitaev
exchange K is weaker than in 5d5 Ir oxides but still larger than other
effective spin couplings. The electronic-structure computations also indicate a
ferromagnetic K in the halide, which is supported by a detailed analysis of the
field-dependent magnetization. From exact-diagonalization calculations for
extended Kitaev-Heisenberg Hamiltonians we additionally find that a transition
from zigzag order to a spin-liquid ground state can be induced in RuCl3 with
external magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05360</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burton</keyname><forenames>Justin C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li&#xe9;tor-Santos</keyname><forenames>Juan-Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Casimir effect between pinned particles in two-dimensional jammed
  systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM02072K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Casimir effect arises when long-ranged fluctuations are geometrically
confined between two surfaces, leading to a macroscopic force. Traditionally,
these forces have been observed in quantum systems and near critical points in
classical systems. Here we show the existence of Casimir-like forces between
two pinned particles immersed in two-dimensional systems near the jamming
transition. We observe two components to the total force: a short-ranged,
depletion force and a long-ranged, repulsive Casimir-like force. The
Casimir-like force dominates as the jamming transition is approached, and when
the pinned particles are much larger than the ambient jammed particles. We show
that this repulsive force arises due to a clustering of particles with strong
contact forces around the perimeter of the pinned particles. As the separation
between the pinned particles decreases, a region of high-pressure develops
between them, leading to a net repulsive force.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08369</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Gerrit E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huaiwu</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy repartition in the nonequilibrium steady state</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024417 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of temperature in nonequilibrium thermodynamics is an outstanding
theoretical issue. We propose an energy repartition principle that leads to a
spectral (mode-dependent) temperature in steady-state nonequilibrium systems.
The general concepts are illustrated by analytic solutions of the classical
Heisenberg spin chain connected to Langevin heat reservoirs with arbitrary
temperature profiles. Gradients of external magnetic fields are shown to
localize spin waves in a Wannier-Zeemann fashion, while magnon interactions
renormalize the spectral temperature. Our generic results are applicable to
other thermodynamic systems such as Newtonian liquids, elastic solids, and
Josephson junctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08506</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Matteo A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bina</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris</keyname><forenames>Matteo G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genoni</keyname><forenames>Marco G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tufarelli</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the diamagnetic term in light-matter interaction</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other math-ph math.MP physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures, close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Sci. Technol. 2, 01LT01 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa540a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the quantum estimation of the diamagnetic, or $A^2$, term in an
effective model of light-matter interaction featuring two coupled oscillators.
First, we calculate the quantum Fisher information of the diamagnetic parameter
in the interacting ground state. Then, we find that typical measurements on the
transverse radiation field, such as homodyne detection or photon counting,
permit to estimate the diamagnetic coupling constant with near-optimal
efficiency in a wide range of model parameters. Should the model admit a
critical point, we also find that both measurements would become asymptotically
optimal in its vicinity. Finally, we discuss binary discrimination strategies
between the two most debated hypotheses involving the diamagnetic term in
circuit QED. While we adopt a terminology appropriate to the Coulomb gauge, our
results are also relevant for the electric dipole gauge. In that case, our
calculations would describe the estimation of the so-called transverse $P^2$
term. The derived metrological benchmarks are general and relevant to any
implementation of the model, cavity and circuit QED being two relevant
examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03945</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rahimzadegan</keyname><forenames>Aso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alaee</keyname><forenames>Rasoul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez-Corbaton</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rockstuhl</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental Limits of Optical Force and Torque</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables, Supplemental Material (27 pages, 6
  figures)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical force and torque provide unprecedented control on the spatial motion
of small particles. A valid scientific question, that has many practical
implications, concerns the existence of fundamental upper bounds for the
achievable force and torque exerted by a plane wave illumination with a given
intensity. Here, while studying isotropic particles, we show that different
light-matter interaction channels contribute to the exerted force and torque;
and analytically derive upper bounds for each of the contributions. Specific
examples for particles that achieve those upper bounds are provided. We study
how and to which extent different contributions can add up to result in the
maximum optical force and torque. Our insights are important for applications
ranging from molecular sorting, particle manipulation, nanorobotics up to
ambitious projects such as laser-propelled spaceships.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00029</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00029</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-12-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Scott M.</forenames></author></authors><title>General approach to quantum channel impossibility by local operations
  and classical communication</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>To appear in Physical Review Letters. Version 2 is very close to what
  will be published, except no matlab code included here (arXiv didn't like
  mcode package). Note: semidefinite programming is no longer used in this
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 020501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.020501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a general approach to proving the impossibility of implementing a
quantum channel by local operations and classical communication (LOCC), even
with an infinite number of rounds, and find that this can often be demonstrated
by solving a set of linear equations. The method also allows one to design an
LOCC protocol to implement the channel whenever such a protocol exists in any
finite number of rounds. Perhaps surprisingly, the computational expense for
analyzing LOCC channels is not much greater than that for LOCC measurements. We
apply the method to several examples, two of which provide numerical evidence
that the set of quantum channels that are not LOCC is not closed and that there
exist channels that can be implemented by LOCC either in one round or in three
rounds that are on the boundary of the set of all LOCC channels.
  Although every LOCC protocol must implement a separable quantum channel, it
is a very difficult task to determine whether or not a given channel is
separable. Fortunately, prior knowledge that the channel is separable is not
required for application of our method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00034</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Manohar</keyname><forenames>Krithika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunton</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutz</keyname><forenames>J. Nathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Environment Identification in Flight using Sparse Approximation of Wing
  Strain</title><categories>physics.data-an q-bio.QM</categories><comments>23 pages, 12 figures. Revised version. Accepted for publication in
  Journal of Fluids and Structures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jfluidstructs.2017.01.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper addresses the problem of identifying different flow environments
from sparse data collected by wing strain sensors. Insects regularly perform
this feat using a sparse ensemble of noisy strain sensors on their wing. First,
we obtain strain data from numerical simulation of a Manduca sexta hawkmoth
wing undergoing different flow environments. Our data-driven method learns
low-dimensional strain features originating from different aerodynamic
environments using proper orthogonal decomposition (POD) modes in the frequency
domain, and leverages sparse approximation to classify a set of strain
frequency signatures using a dictionary of POD modes. This bio-inspired machine
learning architecture for dictionary learning and sparse classification permits
fewer costly physical strain sensors while being simultaneously robust to
sensor noise. A measurement selection algorithm identifies frequencies that
best discriminate the different aerodynamic environments in low-rank POD
feature space. In this manner, sparse and noisy wing strain data can be
exploited to robustly identify different aerodynamic environments encountered
in flight, providing insight into the stereotyped placement of neurons that act
as strain sensors on a Manduca sexta hawkmoth wing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01223</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hardwick</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vennin</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Koyama</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wands</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author></authors><title>Constraining Curvatonic Reheating</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages without appendices (total 39 pages), 16 figures, 2 tables,
  matches the published version in JCAP, typo in Eq.(3.3) corrected</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1608 (2016) 08, 042</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the first systematic observational constraints on reheating in
models of inflation where an additional light scalar field contributes to
primordial density perturbations and affects the expansion history during
reheating. This encompasses the original curvaton model but also covers a
larger class of scenarios. We find that, compared to the single-field case,
lower values of the energy density at the end of inflation and of the reheating
temperature are preferred when an additional scalar field is introduced. For
instance, if inflation is driven by a quartic potential, which is one of the
most favoured models when a light scalar field is added, the upper bound
$T_{\mathrm{reh}}&lt;5\times 10^{4}\,\mathrm{GeV}$ on the reheating temperature
$T_{\mathrm{reh}}$ is derived, and the implications of this value on
post-inflationary physics are discussed. The information gained about reheating
is also quantified and it is found that it remains modest in plateau inflation
(though still larger than in the single-field version of the model) but can
become substantial in quartic inflation. The role played by the vev of the
additional scalar field at the end of inflation is highlighted, and opens
interesting possibilities for exploring stochastic inflation effects that could
determine its distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04409</id><created>2016-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe4;rkim&#xe4;ki</keyname><forenames>Konsta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirvijoki</keyname><forenames>Eero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decker</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varje</keyname><forenames>Jari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurki-Suonio</keyname><forenames>Taina</forenames></author></authors><title>An advection-diffusion model for cross-field runaway electron transport
  in perturbed magnetic fields</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><doi>10.1088/0741-3335/58/12/125017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Disruption-generated runaway electrons (RE) present an outstanding issue for
ITER. The predictive computational studies of RE generation rely on
orbit-averaged computations and, as such, they lack the effects from the
magnetic field stochasticity. Since stochasiticity is naturally present in
post-disruption plasma, and externally induced stochastization offers a
prominent mechanism to mitigate RE avalanche, we present an advection-diffusion
model that can be used to couple an orbit-following code to an orbit-averaged
tool in order to capture the cross-field transport and to overcome the latter's
limitation. The transport coefficients are evaluated via a Monte Carlo method.
We show that the diffusion coefficient differs significantly from the
well-known Rechester-Rosenbluth result. We also demonstrate the importance of
including the advection: it has a two-fold role both in modelling transport
barriers created by magnetic islands and in amplifying losses in regions where
the islands are not present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05471</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rico</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabin</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ockenfels</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leder</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossert</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weitz</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Rabi model in the Brillouin zone with ultracold atoms</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013827 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013827</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum Rabi model describes the interaction between a two-level quantum
system and a single bosonic mode. We propose a method to perform a quantum
simulation of the quantum Rabi model introducing a novel implementation of the
two-level system, provided by the occupation of Bloch bands in the first
Brillouin zone by ultracold atoms in tailored optical lattices. The effective
qubit interacts with a quantum harmonic oscillator implemented in an optical
dipole trap. Our realistic proposal allows to experimentally investigate the
quantum Rabi model for extreme parameter regimes, which are not achievable with
natural light-matter interactions. Furthermore, we also identify a generalized
version of the quantum Rabi model in a periodic phase space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07581</id><created>2016-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Reddy</keyname><forenames>Tulasi Ram</forenames></author></authors><title>Probability that product of real random matrices have all eigenvalues
  real tend to 1</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Based on author's Ph.D thesis arXiv:1602.05298</comments><msc-class>60B20 (Primary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Statistics &amp; Probability Letters, Volume 124, May 2017, Pages
  30-32</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.spl.2016.12.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we consider products of real random matrices with fixed size.
Let $A_1,A_2, \dots $ be i.i.d $k \times k$ real matrices, whose entries are
independent and identically distributed from probability measure $\mu$. Let
$X_n = A_1A_2\dots A_n$. Then it is conjectured that $$\mathbb{P}(X_n \text{
has all real eigenvalues}) \rightarrow 1 \text{ as } n \rightarrow \infty.$$ We
show that the conjecture is true when $\mu$ has an atom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01015</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krieg</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strassel</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Streib</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggert</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopietz</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics and renormalized quasi-particles in the vicinity of the
  dilute Bose gas quantum critical point in two dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024414 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the functional renormalization group (FRG) to derive analytical
expressions for thermodynamic observables (density, pressure, entropy, and
compressibility) as well as for single-particle properties (wavefunction
renormalization and effective mass) of interacting bosons in two dimensions as
a function of temperature $T$ and chemical potential $\mu$. We focus on the
quantum disordered and the quantum critical regime close to the dilute Bose gas
quantum critical point. Our approach is based on a truncated vertex expansion
of the hierarchy of FRG flow equations and the decoupling of the two-body
contact interaction in the particle-particle channel using a suitable
Hubbard-Stratonovich transformation. Our analytic FRG results extend previous
analytical renormalization group calculations for thermodynamic observables at
$\mu =0$ to finite values of $\mu$. To confirm the validity of our FRG
approach, we have also performed quantum Monte Carlo simulations to obtain the
magnetization, the susceptibility, and the correlation length of the
two-dimensional spin-$1/2$ quantum $XY$ model with coupling $J$ in a regime
where its quantum critical behavior is controlled by the dilute Bose gas
quantum critical point. We find that our analytical results describe the Monte
Carlo data for $\mu \leq 0$ rather accurately up to relatively high
temperatures $T \lesssim 0.1 J$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02619</id><created>2016-07-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Genoni</keyname><forenames>Marco G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lami</keyname><forenames>Ludovico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serafini</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author></authors><title>Conditional and unconditional Gaussian quantum dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 1 figures. Close to published version, Contemporary
  Physics. Advance online publication (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Contemp. Phys. 57, 331 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00107514.2015.1125624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article focuses on the general theory of open quantum systems in the
Gaussian regime and explores a number of diverse ramifications and consequences
of the theory. We shall first introduce the Gaussian framework in its full
generality, including a classification of Gaussian (also known as
&quot;general-dyne&quot;) quantum measurements. In doing so, we will give a compact proof
for the parametrisation of the most general Gaussian completely positive map,
which we believe to be missing in the existing literature. We will then move on
to consider the linear coupling with a white noise bath, and derive the
diffusion equations that describe the evolution of Gaussian states under such
circumstances. Starting from these equations, we outline a constructive method
to derive general master equations that apply outside the Gaussian regime.
Next, we include the general-dyne monitoring of the environmental degrees of
freedom and recover the Riccati equation for the conditional evolution of
Gaussian states. Our derivation relies exclusively on the standard quantum
mechanical update of the system state, through the evaluation of Gaussian
overlaps. The parametrisation of the conditional dynamics we obtain is novel
and, at variance with existing alternatives, directly ties in to physical
detection schemes. We conclude our study with two examples of conditional
dynamics that can be dealt with conveniently through our formalism,
demonstrating how monitoring can suppress the noise in optical parametric
processes as well as stabilise systems subject to diffusive scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02827</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02827</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Korchin</keyname><forenames>Alexander Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalchuk</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay of the Higgs boson to $\tau^- \tau^+$ and non-Hermiticity of the
  Yukawa interaction</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures, revtex4; v2: one reference added, comparison
  with results of other papers included, insignificant changes in tables,
  corresponds to journal version; v3: minor typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 076003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.076003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The issue of Hermiticity of the Higgs boson interaction with fermions is
addressed. A model for non-Hermitian Yukawa interaction is proposed and
approximation of one fermion generation is considered. Symmetry properties of
the corresponding $h f \bar{f}$ Lagrangian with respect to the discrete P, C
and T transformations are analyzed, and the modified Dirac equation for the
free fermion is studied. Longitudinal polarization of the fermions in the decay
$h \to f \bar{f}$, which arises due to non-Hermiticity of the $h f \bar{f}$
interaction, is discussed. It is suggested to study effects of this
non-Hermiticity in the decay $h \to \tau^- \tau^+ \to \mu^- {\bar \nu}_\mu
\nu_\tau \, \mu^+ \nu_\mu {\bar \nu}_\tau$, for which observables (asymmetries)
are constructed which take nonzero values for a non-Hermitian $h \tau^- \tau^+$
interaction. These asymmetries are analyzed for various configurations of the
muon energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03521</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rahimzadegan</keyname><forenames>Aso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fruhnert</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alaee</keyname><forenames>Rasoul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez-Corbaton</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rockstuhl</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Force and Torque on Dipolar Dual Chiral Particles</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the one hand, electromagnetic dual particles preserve the helicity of
light upon interaction. On the other hand, chiral particles respond differently
to light of opposite helicity. These two properties on their own constitute a
source of fascination. Their combined action, however, is less explored. Here,
we study on analytical grounds the force and torque as well as the optical
cross sections of dual chiral particles in the dipolar approximation exerted by
a particular wave of well-defined helicity: A circularly polarized plane wave.
We put emphasis on particles that possess a maximally electromagnetic chiral
and hence dual response. Besides the analytical insights, we also investigate
the exerted optical force and torque on a real particle at the example of a
metallic helix that is designed to approach the maximal electromagnetic
chirality condition. Various applications in the context of optical sorting but
also nanorobotics can be foreseen considering the particles studied in this
contribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06074</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renner</keyname><forenames>Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutherland</keyname><forenames>Dave</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring Peaks and Valleys in the Diphoton Spectrum</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>v2: Added sections discussing 2016 data</comments><report-no>Cavendish-HEP-16/13, DAMTP-2016-52</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 075011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.075011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effects of resonance-continuum interference on the
diphoton spectrum in the presence of a new spin-0 or spin-2 state produced via
gluons or quarks and decaying to pairs of photons. Interference effects can
significantly influence the extraction of resonance masses and widths from the
diphoton spectrum, particularly in the case of a spin-2 resonance produced via
quarks. We illustrate these effects via a binned likelihood analysis of LHC
diphoton data at both 8 and 13 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06998</id><created>2016-07-24</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tews</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectrum of shear modes in the neutron-star crust: Estimating the
  nuclear-physics uncertainties</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures, published version</comments><report-no>INT-PUB-16-020</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 015803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.015803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I construct a model of the inner crust of neutron stars using interactions
from chiral effective field theory (EFT) in order to calculate its equation of
state (EOS), shear properties, and the spectrum of crustal shear modes. I
systematically study uncertainties associated with the nuclear physics input,
the crust composition, and neutron entrainment, and estimate their impact on
crustal shear properties and the shear-mode spectrum. I find that the
uncertainties originate mainly in two sources: The neutron-matter EOS and
neutron entrainment. I compare the spectrum of crustal shear modes to observed
frequencies of quasi-periodic oscillations in the afterglow of giant
$\gamma$-ray bursts and find that all of these frequencies could be described
within uncertainties, which are, however, at present too sizable to infer
neutron-star properties from observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07453</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Mayuri Sathyanarayana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subrahmanyan</keyname><forenames>Ravi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shankar</keyname><forenames>N Udaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chluba</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>GMOSS: All-sky model of spectral radio brightness based on physical
  components and associated radiative processes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>2017, AJ, 153, 26</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/153/1/26</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present Global MOdel for the radio Sky Spectrum (GMOSS) -- a novel,
physically motivated model of the low-frequency radio sky from 22 MHz to 23
GHz. GMOSS invokes different physical components and associated radiative
processes to describe the sky spectrum over 3072 pixels of $5^{\circ}$
resolution. The spectra are allowed to be convex, concave or of more complex
form with contributions from synchrotron emission, thermal emission and
free-free absorption included. Physical parameters that describe the model are
optimized to best fit four all-sky maps at 150 MHz, 408 MHz, 1420 MHz and 23
GHz and two maps at 22 MHz and 45 MHz generated using the Global Sky Model of
de Oliveira-Costa et al. (2008). The fractional deviation of model to data has
a median value of $6\%$ and is less than $17\%$ for $99\%$ of the pixels.
Though aimed at modeling of foregrounds for the global signal arising from the
redshifted 21-cm line of Hydrogen during Cosmic Dawn and Epoch of Reionization
(EoR) - over redshifts $150\lesssim z \lesssim 6$, GMOSS is well suited for any
application that requires simulating spectra of the low-frequency radio sky as
would be observed by the beam of any instrument. The complexity in spectral
structure that naturally arises from the underlying physics of the model
provides a useful expectation for departures from smoothness in EoR foreground
spectra and hence may guide the development of algorithms for EoR signal
detection. This aspect is further explored in a subsequent paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01283</id><created>2016-08-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Cardy</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonni</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement hamiltonians in two-dimensional conformal field theory</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><comments>30 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 123103</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/12/123103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We enumerate the cases in 2d conformal field theory where the logarithm of
the reduced density matrix (the entanglement or modular hamiltonian) may be
written as an integral over the energy-momentum tensor times a local weight.
These include known examples and new ones corresponding to the time-dependent
scenarios of a global and local quench. In these latter cases the entanglement
hamiltonian depends on the momentum density as well as the energy density. In
all cases the entanglement spectrum is that of the appropriate boundary CFT. We
emphasize the role of boundary conditions at the entangling surface and the
appearance of boundary entropies as universal O(1) terms in the entanglement
entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02233</id><created>2016-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Trieschmann</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mussenbrock</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic analysis of negative power deposition in low pressure plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology 26, 024004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6595/aa51f2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The negative power absorption in low pressure plasmas is investigated by
means of an analyical model which couples Boltzmann's equation and the
quasi-stationary Maxwell's equation. Exploiting standard Hilbert space methods
an explicit solution for both, the electric field and the distribution function
of the electrons for a bounded discharge configuration subject to an
unsymmetrical excitation has been found for the first time. The model is
applied to a low pressure inductively coupled plasma discharge. In this context
particularly the anomalous skin effect and the effect of phase mixing is
discussed. The analytical solution is compared with results from
electromagnetic full wave particle in cell simulations. Excellent agreement
between the analytical and the numerical results is found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02773</id><created>2016-08-09</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iskin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Trapped $^{173}$Yb Fermi gas across an orbital Feshbach resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages with 4 figures; to appear in PRA</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013618 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting with the two-band description of an orbital Feshbach resonance, we
study superfluid properties of a trapped $^{173}$Yb Fermi gas under the
assumptions of a local-density approximation for the trapping potential and a
mean-field approximation for the intra-band Cooper pairings. In particular, we
investigate the competition and interplay between the pair-breaking effect that
is caused by the inter-band detuning energy, and the pair-breaking and
thermal-broadening effects that are simultaneously caused by the temperature.
We predict several experimental signatures that are directly caused by this
interplay including a spatial separation of superfluid and normal phases within
the trap, and could play decisive roles in probing two-band superfluidity in
these systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04228</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2016-11-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ashtekar</keyname><forenames>Abhay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupt</keyname><forenames>Brajesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Gravity in the Sky: Interplay between fundamental theory and
  observations</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Invited article, to appear in CQG. This paper is addressed both to
  the quantum gravity and cosmology audiences. Cosmologists can focus just on
  sections I, IV.C, IV.D and V without loss of continuity. 43 pages, 13
  figures. Version 2 contains a few clarifications and new references,
  especially to compare and contrast related results in the literature</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 34, 014002 (2017), (44pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/34/1/014002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observational missions have provided us with a reliable model of the
evolution of the universe starting from the last scattering surface all the way
to future infinity. Furthermore given a specific model of inflation, using
quantum field theory on curved space-times this history can be pushed
\emph{back in time} to the epoch when space-time curvature was some $10^{62}$
times that at the horizon of a solar mass black hole! However, to extend the
history further back to the Planck regime requires input from quantum gravity.
An important aspect of this input is the choice of the background quantum
geometry and of the Heisenberg state of cosmological perturbations thereon,
motivated by Planck scale physics. This paper introduces first steps in that
direction. Specifically we propose two principles that link quantum geometry
and Heisenberg uncertainties in the Planck epoch with late time physics and
explore in detail the observational consequences of the initial conditions they
select. We find that the predicted temperature-temperature (T-T) correlations
for scalar modes are indistinguishable from standard inflation at small angular
scales even though the initial conditions are now set in the deep Planck
regime. However, \emph{there is a specific power suppression at large angular
scales}. As a result, the predicted spectrum provides a better fit to the
PLANCK mission data than standard inflation, where the initial conditions are
set in the general relativity regime. Thus, our proposal brings out a deep
interplay between the ultraviolet and the infrared. Finally, the proposal also
leads to specific predictions for power suppression at large angular scales
also for the (T-E and E-E) correlations involving electric polarization. The
PLANCK team is expected to release this data in the coming year.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06856</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>St&#xe9;phan</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Full counting statistics in the Haldane-Shastry chain</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035119 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present analytical and numerical results regarding the magnetization full
counting statistics (FCS) of a subsystem in the ground-state of the
Haldane-Shastry chain. Exact Pfaffian expressions are derived for the cumulant
generating function, as well as any observable diagonal in the spin basis. In
the limit of large systems, the scaling of the FCS is found to be in agreement
with the Luttinger liquid theory. The same techniques are also applied to
inhomogeneous deformations of the chain. This introduces a certain amount of
disorder in the system; however we show numerically that this is not sufficient
to flow to the random singlet phase, that corresponds to $XXZ$ chains with
uncorrelated bond disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06942</id><created>2016-08-24</created><updated>2016-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Brian M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broadhurst</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diego</keyname><forenames>Jose M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zitrin</keyname><forenames>Adi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coe</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>Holland C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric Corroboration of the Earliest Lensed Galaxy at z~10.8 from
  Robust Free-Form Modelling</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>23 pages, 22 figures. Accepted by ApJ on 22nd Nov 2016. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1406.2702</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/835/1/44</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A multiply-lensed galaxy, MACS0647-JD, with a probable photometric redshift
of $z\simeq 10.7^{+0.6}_{-0.4}$ is claimed to constitute one of the very
earliest known galaxies, formed well before reionization was completed.
However, spectral evidence that MACS0647-JD lies at high redshift has proven
infeasible and so here we seek an independent lensing based &quot;geometric
redshift&quot; derived from the angles between the three lensed images of
MACS0647-JD, using our free-form mass model (WSLAP+) for the lensing cluster
MACSJ0647.7+7015 (at $z=0.591$). Our lens model uses the 9 sets of multiple
images, including those of MACS0647-JD, identified by the CLASH survey towards
this cluster. We convincingly exclude the low redshift regime of $z&lt;3$, for
which convoluted critical curves are generated by our method, as the solution
bends to accommodate the wide angles of MACS0647-JD for this low redshift.
Instead, a best fit to all sets of lensed galaxy positions and redshifts
provides a geometric redshift of $z\simeq 10.8^{+0.3}_{-0.4}$ for MACS0647-JD,
strongly supporting the higher photometric redshift solution. Importantly, we
find a tight linear relation between the relative brightnesses of all 9 sets of
multiply lensed images and their relative magnifications as predicted by our
model. This agreement provides a benchmark for the quality of the lens model,
and establishes the robustness of our free-form lensing method for measuring
model-independent geometric source distances and for deriving objective central
cluster mass distributions. After correcting for its magnification the
luminosity of MACS0647-JD remains relatively high at $M_{UV}=-19.4$, which is
within a factor of a few in flux of some surprisingly luminous $z\simeq
10$--$11$ candidates discovered recently in Hubble black field surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07361</id><created>2016-08-26</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Shaofeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xuefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Caizhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast Relaxation Dynamics of Photoexcited Dirac Fermion in The Three
  Dimensional Dirac Semimetal Cadmium Arsenide</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 024303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three dimensional (3D) Dirac semimetals which can be seen as 3D analogues of
graphene have attracted enormous interests in research recently. In order to
apply these ultrahigh-mobility materials in future electronic/optoelectronic
devices, it is crucial to understand the relaxation dynamics of photoexcited
carriers and their coupling with lattice. In this work, we report ultrafast
transient reflection measurements of the photoexcited carrier dynamics in
cadmium arsenide (Cd3As2), which is one of the most stable Dirac semimetals
that have been confirmed experimentally. By using low energy probe photon of
0.3 eV, we probed the dynamics of the photoexcited carriers that are
Dirac-Fermi-like approaching the Dirac point. We systematically studied the
transient reflection on bulk and nanoplate samples that have different doping
intensities by tuning the probe wavelength, pump power and lattice temperature,
and find that the dynamical evolution of carrier distributions can be retrieved
qualitatively by using a two-temperature model. This result is very similar to
that of graphene, but the carrier cooling through the optical phonon couplings
is slower and lasts over larger electron temperature range because the optical
phonon energies in Cd3As2 are much lower than those in graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07684</id><created>2016-08-27</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Chunling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Anmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum metrology in coarsened measurement reference</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012117 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the role of coarsened measurement reference in quantum
metrology. Coarsened measurement reference comes from the coarsened reference
time and basis. When the measurement based on one common reference basis, the
disadvantage can be removed by symmetry. Due to the coarsened reference basis,
entangled states can not perform better than product states for large number of
probe particles. Given a finite uncertainty of the coarsened reference basis,
the optimal number of probe particle is obtained in estimating phase. Finally,
we prove that the maximally entangled state always achieves better precision
under the case of non-Markovian dephasing than that under the case of Markovian
dephasing. The product state is more resistant to interference of the coarsened
reference time than the entangled state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08123</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2016-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Surmach</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portnichenko</keyname><forenames>P. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Rivera</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inosov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impurity effects on spin dynamics in magnetic and superconducting iron
  pnictides and chalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Feature article for the &quot;Special Issue on Iron-Based High Temperature
  Superconductors&quot; to appear in Physica Status Solidi (b); 16 pages, 22
  figures, v4: corrected typos, optimized figures, updated references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Stat. Sol. B 254, 1600162 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssb.201600162</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we summarize the effects of magnetic and nonmagnetic impurities
on the spin dynamics in Febased superconductors and their parent compounds. The
effects of chemical substitution, vacancies, and disorder on the suppression or
stabilization of superconductivity and spin-density-wave phases are reviewed in
the context of recent neutron-spectroscopy measurements of spin excitations. We
also present new results on the structure of magnetic fluctuations in BaFe2As2
single crystals doped with Mn local moments and discuss them in relationship to
the previously reported (pi, pi) branch of checkerboard magnetic excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01769</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paula</keyname><forenames>A. L. de</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Bragan&#xe7;a</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drumond</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguiar</keyname><forenames>M. C. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spinon and bound state excitation &quot;light cones&quot; in Heisenberg XXZ Chains</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045125 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the out-of-equilibrium dynamics after a local quench that
connects two spin-1/2 XXZ chains prepared in the ground state of the
Hamiltonian in different phases, one in the ferromagnetic phase and the other
in the critical phase. We analyze the time evolution of the on-site
magnetization and bipartite entanglement entropy via adaptive time-dependent
density matrix renormalization group. In systems with short-range inter-
actions, such as the one we consider, the velocity of information transfer is
expected to be bounded, giving rise to a light-cone effect. Interestingly, our
results show that, when the anisotropy parameter of the critical chain is
sufficiently close to that of the isotropic ferromagnet, the light cone is
determined by the velocity of spin-wave bound states that propagate faster than
single-particle (&quot;spinon&quot;) excitations. Furthermore, we investigate how the
system approaches equilibrium in the inhomogeneous ground state of the
connected system, in which the ferromagnetic chain induces a nonzero
magnetization in the critical chain in the vicinity of the interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02729</id><created>2016-09-09</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pelegr&#xed;</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turpin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewenstein</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mompart</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahufinger</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single atom edge-like states via quantum interference</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013614 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013614</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate how quantum interference may lead to the appearance of robust
edge-like states of a single ultracold atom in a two-dimensional optical
ribbon. We show that these states can be engineered either within the manifold
of local ground states of the sites forming the ribbon, or of states carrying
one unit of angular momentum. In the former case, we show that the
implementation of edge-like states can be extended to other geometries, such as
tilted square lattices. In the latter case, we suggest to use the winding
number associated to the angular momentum as a synthetic dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03114</id><created>2016-09-11</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Furuya</keyname><forenames>Shunsuke C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular dependence of electron spin resonance for detecting quadrupolar
  liquid state of frustrated spin chains</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 014416 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.014416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin nematic phase is a phase of frustrated quantum magnets with a
quadrupolar order of electron spins. Since the spin nematic order is usually
masked in experimentally accessible quantities, it is important to develop a
methodology for detecting the spin nematic order experimentally. In this paper
we propose a convenient method for detecting quasi-long-range spin nematic
correlations of a quadrupolar Tomonaga-Luttinger liquid state of $S=1/2$
frustrated ferromagnetic spin chain compounds, using electron spin resonance
(ESR). We focus on linewidth of a so-called paramagnetic resonance peak in ESR
absorption spectrum. We show that a characteristic angular dependence of the
linewidth on the direction of magnetic field arises in the spin nematic phase.
Measurments of the angular dependence give a signature of the quadrupolar
Tomonaga-Luttinger liquid state. In our method we change only the direction of
the magnetic field, keeping the magnitude of the magnetic field and the
temperature. Therefore, our method is advantageous for investigating the
one-dimensional quadrupolar liquid phase that usually occupies only a narrow
region of the phase diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03144</id><created>2016-09-11</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Bao-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hao-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlating charge radius with quadrupole deformation and $B(E2)$ in
  atomic nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 014307 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.014307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A very good linear correlation is found between the four-point charge radius
relation $\delta R_{2p-2n}(Z,N)$ with that of quadrupole deformation data in
even-even nuclei. This results in a further improved charge radius relation
that holds in a precision of about 5$\times 10^{-3}$ fm. Such correlations are
also seen in global nuclear models, their precisions, however, are not enough
to be consistent with the experimental data. The new relation between charge
radii and deformation of even-even nuclei can be generalized to the reduced
electric quadrupole transition probability $B(E2)$ between the first $2^+$
state and the $0^+$ ground state, and the mean lifetime $\tau$ of the first
2$^+$ state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03702</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2016-11-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Syromyatnikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-flop transition accompanied with changing the type of magnetic
  ordering</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Magnetism and Magnetic Materials 426 (2017) 279-286</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2016.11.047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss theoretically rather rear example of spin-flop transition which is
accompanied with changing the type of magnetic ordering and which seemingly has
not been addressed yet. We demonstrate that changing the type of magnetic
ordering can manifest itself in antiferromagnetic (AF) resonance experiments as
an apparent peculiar switching of the anisotropy at the transition from the
easy-axis type to the easy-plane one. We argue that this kind of spin-flop
transition is observed recently by K.Yu. Povarov et al., Phys. Rev. B 87,
214402 (2013) in Cu(pz)$_2$(ClO$_4$)$_2$ (where pz denotes pyrazine), one of
the best realizations of spin-1/2 Heisenberg AFs on square lattice having a
very small anisotropy. We show that the magnetic ordering changes at the
spin-flop transition in this material in the direction perpendicular to AF
square planes. We examine the microscopic mechanism of such behavior in
Cu(pz)$_2$(ClO$_4$)$_2$ and find that dipolar forces and extremely small
exchange coupling between spins from neighboring planes are responsible for it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03852</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shena</keyname><forenames>Joniald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hizanidis</keyname><forenames>Johanne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovanis</keyname><forenames>Vassilios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsironis</keyname><forenames>George P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent chimeras in large semiconductor laser arrays</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Semiconductor laser arrays have been investigated experimentally and
theoretically from the viewpoint of temporal and spatial coherence for the past
forty years. In this work, we are focusing on a rather novel complex collective
behavior, namely chimera states, where synchronized clusters of emitters
coexist with unsynchronized ones. For the first time, we find such states exist
in large diode arrays based on quantum well gain media with nearest-neighbor
interactions. The crucial parameters are the evanescent coupling strength and
the relative optical frequency detuning between the emitters of the array. By
employing a recently proposed figure of merit for classifying chimera states,
we provide quantitative and qualitative evidence for the observed dynamics. The
corresponding chimeras are identified as turbulent according to the irregular
temporal behavior of the classification measure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04279</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sboychakov</keyname><forenames>A. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakhmanov</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kugel</keyname><forenames>K. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozhkov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field effects in electron systems with imperfect nesting</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 eps figures, several typos corrected, new references
  added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 014203 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.014203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the effects of an applied magnetic field on the phase diagram of a
weakly-correlated electron system with imperfect nesting. The Hamiltonian under
study describes two bands: electron and hole ones. Both bands have spherical
Fermi surfaces, whose radii are slightly mismatched due to doping. These types
of models are often used in the analysis of magnetic states in chromium and its
alloys, superconducting iron pnictides, AA-type bilayer graphene, borides, etc.
At zero magnetic field, the uniform ground state of the system turns out to be
unstable against electronic phase separation. The applied magnetic field
affects the phase diagram in several ways. In particular, the Zeeman term
stabilizes new antiferromagnetic phases. It also significantly shifts the
boundaries of inhomogeneous (phase-separated) states. At sufficiently high
fields, the Landau quantization gives rise to oscillations of the order
parameters and of the N\'eel temperature as a function of the magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04637</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2017-01-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Csernai</keyname><forenames>L. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spinnangr</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative assessment of increasing complexity</title><categories>q-bio.OT cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figure</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 473 (2017) 363</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.12.091</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the build up of complexity on the example of 1 kg matter in
different forms. We start on the simplest example of ideal gases, and then
continue with more complex chemical, biological, life and social and technical
structures. We assess the complexity of these systems quantitatively, based on
their entropy. We present a method to attribute the same entropy to known
physical systems and to complex organic molecules up to a DNA. The important
steps in this program and the basic obstacles are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06117</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2016-12-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Kan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yan-Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Triply heavy tetraquark states with the $QQ\bar{Q}\bar{q}$ configuration</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures and 9 tables. Accepted by Eur. Phys. J. A</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A 53 (2017) 5</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12199-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of the color-magnetic interaction, we systematically
investigate the mass splittings of the $QQ\bar{Q}\bar{q}$ tetraquark states and
estimated their rough masses in this work. These systems include the explicitly
exotic states $cc\bar{b}\bar{q}$ and $bb\bar{c}\bar{q}$ and the hidden exotic
states $cc\bar{c}\bar{q}$, $cb\bar{b}\bar{q}$, $bc\bar{c}\bar{q}$, and
$bb\bar{b}\bar{q}$. If a state around the estimated mass region could be
observed, its nature as a genuine tetraquark is favored. The strong decay
patterns shown here will be helpful to the experimental search for these exotic
states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07077</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Chalaev</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dery</keyname><forenames>Hanan</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppressing spin relaxation in silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>We welcome any input or suggestions for more references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Uniaxial compressive strain along the [001] direction strongly suppresses the
spin relaxation in silicon. When the strain level is large enough so that
electrons are redistributed only in the two valleys along the strain axis, the
dominant scattering mechanisms are quenched and electrons mainly experience
intra-axis scattering processes (intravalley or intervalley scattering within
valleys on the same crystal axis). We first derive the spin-flip matrix
elements due to intra-axis electron scattering off impurities, and then provide
a comprehensive model of the spin relaxation time due to all possible
interactions of conduction-band electrons with impurities and phonons. We
predict nearly three orders of magnitude improvement in the spin relaxation
time of $\sim10^{19}\text{cm}^{-3}$ antimony-doped silicon (Si:Sb) at low
temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07332</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Vanherck</keyname><forenames>Joren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulenborg</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saptsov</keyname><forenames>Roman B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Splettstoesser</keyname><forenames>Janine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegewijs</keyname><forenames>Maarten R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation of quantum dots in a magnetic field at finite bias -- charge,
  spin and heat currents</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1002/pssb.201600614</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a detailed study of the effect of finite bias and magnetic field
on the tunneling-induced decay of the state of a quantum dot by applying a
recently discovered general duality [PRB 93, 81411 (2016)]. This duality
provides deep physical insight into the decay dynamics of electronic open
quantum systems with strong Coulomb interaction. It associates the amplitudes
of decay eigenmodes of the actual system to the eigenmodes of a so-called dual
system with attractive interaction. Thereby, it predicts many surprising
features in the transient transport and its dependence on experimental control
parameters: the attractive interaction of the dual model shows up as sharp
features in the amplitudes of measurable time-dependent currents through the
actual repulsive system. In particular, for interacting quantum dots, the
time-dependent heat current exhibits a decay mode that dissipates the
interaction energy and that is tied to the fermion parity of the system. We
show that its decay amplitude has an unexpected gate-voltage dependence that is
robust up to sizable bias voltages and then bifurcates, reflecting that the
Coulomb blockade is lifted in the dual system. Furthermore, combining our
duality relation with the known Iche-duality, we derive new symmetry properties
of the decay rates as a function of magnetic field and gate voltage. Finally,
we quantify charge- and spin-mode mixing due to the magnetic field using a
single mixing parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07547</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aoyama</keyname><forenames>Shohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Kuan-Chou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Ikkoh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirashita</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todoroki</keyname><forenames>Keita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Jun-Hwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagamine</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Galaxy Simulation with Dust Formation and Destruction</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 16 figures, published on MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 466 (1): 105-121</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform smoothed particle hydrodynamics (SPH) simulations of an isolated
galaxy with a new treatment for dust formation and destruction. To this aim, we
treat dust and metal production self-consistently with star formation and
supernova feedback. For dust, we consider a simplified model of grain size
distribution by representing the entire range of grain sizes with large and
small grains. We include dust production in stellar ejecta, dust destruction by
supernova (SN) shocks, grain growth by accretion and coagulation, and grain
disruption by shattering. We find that the assumption of fixed dust-to-metal
mass ratio becomes no longer valid when the galaxy is older than 0.2 Gyr, at
which point the grain growth by accretion starts to contribute to the nonlinear
rise of dust-to-gas ratio. As expected in our previous one-zone model,
shattering triggers grain growth by accretion since it increases the total
surface area of grains. Coagulation becomes significant when the galaxy age is
greater than $\sim$ 1 Gyr: at this epoch the abundance of small grains becomes
high enough to raise the coagulation rate of small grains. We further compare
the radial profiles of dust-to-gas ratio $(\mathcal{D})$ and dust-to-metal
ratio $(\mathcal{D}/Z)$ (i.e., depletion) at various ages with observational
data. We find that our simulations broadly reproduce the radial gradients of
dust-to-gas ratio and depletion. In the early epoch ($\lesssim 0.3$ Gyr), the
radial gradient of $\mathcal{D}$ follows the metallicity gradient with
$\mathcal{D}/Z$ determined by the dust condensation efficiency in stellar
ejecta, while the $\mathcal{D}$ gradient is steeper than the $Z$ gradient at
the later epochs because of grain growth by accretion. The framework developed
in this paper is applicable to any SPH-based galaxy evolution simulations
including cosmological ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07841</id><created>2016-09-25</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shou-hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter Relic Abundance and Light Sterile Neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>JHEP 1701 (2017) 025</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we calculate the relic abundance of the dark matter particles
when they can annihilate into sterile neutrinos with the mass $\lesssim 100
\text{ GeV}$ in a simple model. Unlike the usual standard calculations, the
sterile neutrino may fall out of the thermal equilibrium with the thermal bath
before the dark matter freezes out. In such a case, if the Yukawa coupling
$y_N$ between the Higgs and the sterile neutrino is small, this process gives
rise to a larger $\Omega_{\text{DM}} h^2$ so we need a larger coupling between
the dark matter and the sterile neutrino for a correct relic abundance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08016</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Girard</keyname><forenames>Mark W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gour</keyname><forenames>Gilad</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement monotones and transformations of symmetric bipartite states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures. Updated to published version (v2). Corrected
  minor typo (v3)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012308 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The primary goal in the study of entanglement as a resource theory is to find
conditions that determine when one quantum state can or cannot be transformed
into another via local operations and classical communication. This is
typically done through entanglement monotones or conversion witnesses. Such
quantities cannot be computed for arbitrary quantum states in general, but it
is useful to consider classes of symmetric states for which closed-form
expressions can be found. In this paper, we show how to compute the convex roof
of any entanglement monotone for all Werner states. The convex roofs of the
well-known Vidal monotones are computed for all isotropic states, and we show
how this method can generalize to other entanglement measures and other types
of symmetries as well. We also present necessary and sufficient conditions that
determine when a pure bipartite state can be deterministically converted into a
Werner state or an isotropic state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09330</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>del Castillo</keyname><forenames>G. F. Torres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubalcava-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational symmetries as the existence of ignorable coordinates</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Eur. J. Phys. 38 025002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6404/aa5563</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that given a Lagrangian for a system with a finite number of
degrees of freedom, the existence of a variational symmetry is equivalent to
the existence of coordinates in the extended configuration space such that one
of the coordinates is ignorable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01928</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Buqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tufarelli</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Genuine multipartite nonlocality of permutationally invariant Gaussian
  states</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures. Close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012124 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate genuine multipartite nonlocality of pure permutationally
invariant multimode Gaussian states of continuous variable systems, as detected
by the violation of Svetlichny inequality. We identify the phase space settings
leading to the largest violation of the inequality when using displaced parity
measurements, distinguishing our results between the cases of even and odd
total number of modes. We further consider pseudospin measurements and show
that, for three-mode states with asymptotically large squeezing degree,
particular settings of these measurements allow one to approach the maximum
violation of Svetlichny inequality allowed by quantum mechanics. This indicates
that the strongest manifestation of genuine multipartite quantum nonlocality is
in principle verifiable on Gaussian states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02709</id><created>2016-10-09</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mendon&#xe7;a</keyname><forenames>J. Ricardo G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Empirical scaling of the length of the longest increasing subsequences
  of random walks</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math.PR</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 color figures, 26 references; version v2 corresponds to
  the published version</comments><msc-class>60G50, 60G51, 82C41</msc-class><acm-class>F.2.2; G.2.3; G.3</acm-class><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (8) 08LT02 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa56a3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide Monte Carlo estimates of the scaling of the length $L_{n}$ of the
longest increasing subsequences of $n$-steps random walks for several different
distributions of step lengths, short and heavy-tailed. Our simulations indicate
that, barring possible logarithmic corrections, $L_{n} \sim n^{\theta}$ with
the leading scaling exponent $0.60 \lesssim \theta \lesssim 0.69$ for the
heavy-tailed distributions of step lengths examined, with values increasing as
the distribution becomes more heavy-tailed, and $\theta \simeq 0.57$ for
distributions of finite variance, irrespective of the particular distribution.
The results are consistent with existing rigorous bounds for $\theta$, although
in a somewhat surprising manner. For random walks with step lengths of finite
variance, we conjecture that the correct asymptotic behavior of $L_{n}$ is
given by $\sqrt{n}\ln n$, and also propose the form of the subleading
asymptotics. The distribution of $L_{n}$ was found to follow a simple scaling
form with scaling functions that vary with $\theta$. Accordingly, when the step
lengths are of finite variance they seem to be universal. The nature of this
scaling remains unclear, since we lack a working model, microscopic or
hydrodynamic, for the behavior of the length of the longest increasing
subsequences of random walks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02974</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2016-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schiegg</keyname><forenames>Christian H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzierzawa</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckern</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Implementation of transmission functions for an optimized three-terminal
  quantum dot heat engine</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 085303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa5140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider two modifications of a recently proposed three-terminal quantum
dot heat engine. First, we investigate the necessity of the thermalization
assumption, namely that electrons are always thermalized by inelastic processes
when traveling across the cavity where the heat is supplied. Second, we analyze
various arrangements of tunneling-coupled quantum dots in order to implement a
transmission function that is superior to the Lorentzian transmission function
of a single quantum dot. We show that the maximum power of the heat engine can
be improved by about a factor of two, even for a small number of dots, by
choosing an optimal structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03280</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naghizadeh</keyname><forenames>Solmaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocabas</keyname><forenames>Sukru Ekin</forenames></author></authors><title>Guidelines for designing 2D and 3D plasmonic stub resonators</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 18 figures, added references, updated tables and figures,
  updated conclusion, published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 34, 207-217 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.34.000207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we compare the performance of plasmonic waveguide integrated
stub resonators based on 2D metal-dielectric-metal and 3D slot waveguide (SWG)
geometries. We show that scattering matrix theory can be extended to 3D
devices, and by employing scattering matrix theory, we provide the guidelines
for designing plasmonic 2D and 3D single-stub and double-stub resonators with a
desired spectral response at the design wavelength. We provide transmission
maps of 2D and 3D double-stub resonators versus stub lengths, and we specify
the different regions on these maps that result in a minimum, a maximum, or a
plasmonically induced transparency shape in the transmission spectrum.
Radiation loss from waveguide terminations leads to a degradation of the 3D
SWG-based resonators. We illustrate improved waveguide terminations that boost
resonator properties. We verify our results with 3D finite-difference
time-domain (FDTD) simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03308</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deur</keyname><forenames>Killian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazouin</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fromager</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact ensemble density functional theory for excited states in a model
  system: investigating the weight dependence of the correlation energy</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035120 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ensemble density functional theory (eDFT) is an exact time-independent
alternative to time-dependent DFT (TD-DFT) for the calculation of excitation
energies. Despite its formal simplicity and advantages in contrast to TD-DFT
(multiple excitations, for example, can be easily taken into account in an
ensemble), eDFT is not standard which is essentially due to the lack of
reliable approximate exchange-correlation (xc) functionals for ensembles.
Following Smith et al. [Phys. Rev. B 93, 245131 (2016)], we propose in this
work to construct an exact eDFT for the nontrivial asymmetric Hubbard dimer,
thus providing more insight into the weight dependence of the ensemble xc
energy in various correlation regimes. For that purpose, an exact analytical
expression for the weight-dependent ensemble exchange energy has been derived.
The complementary exact ensemble correlation energy has been computed by means
of Legendre--Fenchel transforms. Interesting features like discontinuities in
the ensemble xc potential in the strongly correlated limit have been
rationalized by means of a generalized adiabatic connection formalism. Finally,
functional-driven errors induced by ground-state density-functional
approximations have been studied. In the strictly symmetric case or in the
weakly correlated regime, combining ensemble exact exchange with ground-state
correlation functionals gives relatively accurate ensemble energies. However,
when approaching the equiensemble in the strongly correlated regime, this
approximation leads to highly curved ensemble energies with negative slope
which is unphysical. Using both ground-state exchange and correlation
functionals gives much better results in that case. In fact, exact ensemble
energies are almost recovered in some density domains. The analysis of
density-driven errors is left for future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03449</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sundell</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Yihao</forenames></author></authors><title>New classes of bi-axially symmetric solutions to four-dimensional
  Vasiliev higher spin gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>v3: 48 pages; minor modifications; published on JHEP with additional
  typesetting</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1701 (2017) 043</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new infinite-dimensional spaces of bi-axially symmetric
asymptotically anti-de Sitter solutions to four-dimensional Vasiliev higher
spin gravity, obtained by modifications of the Ansatz used in arXiv:1107.1217,
which gave rise to a Type-D solution space. The current Ansatz is based on
internal semigroup algebras (without identity) generated by exponentials formed
out of the bi-axial symmetry generators. After having switched on the vacuum
gauge function, the resulting generalized Weyl tensor is given by a sum of
generalized Petrov type-D tensors that are Kerr-like or 2-brane-like in the
asymptotic AdS4 region, and the twistor space connection is smooth in twistor
space over finite regions of spacetime. We provide evidence for that the
linearized twistor space connection can be brought to Vasiliev gauge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03553</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pease</keyname><forenames>Gerald E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glenn</keyname><forenames>Gregory S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long Term Sunspot Cycle Phase Coherence with Periodic Phase Disruptions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 34 figures, 7 tables. This is a v3 replacement of v2. Table
  1 and Table 7 date typos have been corrected, resulting in lowered result
  uncertainties. Other date typos on pp. 2, 3, and 5 have been corrected</comments><report-no>1610.03553v3</report-no><msc-class>70F10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1965 Paul D. Jose published his discovery that both the motion of the Sun
about the center of mass of the solar system and periods comprised of eight
Hale magnetic sunspot cycles with a mean period of ~22.37 years have a matching
periodicity of ~179 years. We have investigated the implied link between solar
barycentric torque cycles and sunspot cycles and have found that the unsigned
solar torque values from 1610 to 2057 are consistently phase and magnitude
coherent in ~179 year Jose Cycles. We are able to show that there is also a
surprisingly high degree of sunspot cycle phase coherence for times of minima
in addition to magnitude correlation of peaks between the nine Schwabe sunspot
cycles of 1878.8 to 1976.1 (SC12 through SC20) and those of 1699 to 1798.3
(SC[-5] through SC4). We further show that the remaining seven Schwabe cycles
in each ~179 year cycle are non-coherent. In addition we have analyzed the
empirical solar motion triggers of both sunspot cycle phase coherence and phase
disruption, from which we conclude that sunspot cycles SC28 through SC35 (2057
to 2143) will be phase coherent at times of minima and amplitude correlated at
maxima with SC12 through SC19 (1878.8-1964.8). The resulting predicted start
times +/- 0.9 year, 1 sigma, of future sunspot cycles SC28 to SC36 are
tabulated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09424</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ashtekar</keyname><forenames>Abhay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupt</keyname><forenames>Brajesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial conditions for cosmological perturbations</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>23 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 34, 035004 (2017) (23 pp),</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Penrose proposed that the big bang singularity should be constrained by
requiring that the Weyl curvature vanishes there. The idea behind this past
hypothesis is attractive because it constrains the initial conditions for the
universe in geometric terms and is not confined to a specific early universe
paradigm. However, the precise statement of Penrose's hypothesis is tied to
classical space-times and furthermore restricts only the gravitational degrees
of freedom. These are encapsulated only in the tensor modes of the commonly
used cosmological perturbation theory. Drawing inspiration from the underlying
idea, we propose a quantum generalization of Penrose's hypothesis using the
Planck regime in place of the big bang, and simultaneously incorporating tensor
as well as scalar modes. Initial conditions selected by this generalization
constrain the universe to be as homogeneous and isotropic in the Planck regime
\emph{as permitted by the Heisenberg uncertainty relations}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09864</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baccetti</keyname><forenames>Valentina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husain</keyname><forenames>Viqar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terno</keyname><forenames>Daniel R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The information recovery problem</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages +1 fig Published version</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 19, 17 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19010017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The issue of unitary evolution during creation and evaporation of a black
hole remains controversial. We~argue that some prominent cures are more
troubling than the disease, demonstrate that their central element---forming of
the event horizon before the evaporation begins---is not necessarily true, and
describe a fully coupled matter-gravity system which is manifestly unitary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00636</id><created>2016-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Juniper</keyname><forenames>Michael P. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>Urs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straube</keyname><forenames>Arthur V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Besseling</keyname><forenames>Rut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aarts</keyname><forenames>Dirk G. A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;wen</keyname><forenames>Hartmut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dullens</keyname><forenames>Roel P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic mode locking in a driven colloidal system: experiments and
  theory</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 013010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa53cd</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we examine the dynamics of a colloidal particle driven by a
modulated force over a sinusoidal optical potential energy landscape. Coupling
between the competing frequencies of the modulated drive and that of particle
motion over the periodic landscape leads to synchronisation of particle motion
into discrete modes. This synchronisation manifests as steps in the average
particle velocity, with mode locked steps covering a range of average driving
velocities. The amplitude and frequency dependence of the steps are considered,
and compared to results from analytic theory, Langevin Dynamics simulations,
and Dynamic Density Functional Theory. Furthermore, the critical driving
velocity is studied, and simulation used to extend the range of conditions
accessible in experiments alone. Finally, state diagrams from experiment,
simulation, and theory are used to show the extent of the dynamically locked
modes in two dimensions, as a function of both the amplitude and frequency of
the modulated drive.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03262</id><created>2016-11-10</created><updated>2016-12-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okubo</keyname><forenames>Susumu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakata</keyname><forenames>Ryohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>Hitoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Shohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei-min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimokawa</keyname><forenames>Tokuro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toru</keyname><forenames>Sakai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okuta</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>Shigeo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Hirohiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Dzyaloshinsky-Moriya interaction and the ground state in S=3/2 perfect
  kagome lattice antiferromagnet $\mathbf{KCr_3(OH)_6(SO_4)_2}$ (Cr-jarosite)
  studied by X-band and high-frequency ESR</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 024703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.024703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A single crystal S=3/2 perfect kagome lattice antiferromagnet
$\mathrm{KCr_3(OH)_6(SO_4)_2}$ (Cr-jarosite) has been studied by X-band and
high-frequency electron spin resonance (ESR). The g-values perpendicular to the
kagome plane (c-axis) and in the plane are determined to be $g_c=1.9704 \pm
0.0002$ and $g_\xi=1.9720 \pm 0.0003$, respectively, by high-frequency ESR
observed at 265 K. Antiferromagnetic resonances (AFMR) with the
antiferromagnetic gap of 120 GHz are observed at 1.9 K, which is below
$T_N$=4.5 K. The analysis of AFMR modes by the conventional molecular field
theory shows $d_p=0.27$ K and $d_z=0.07$ K, where $d_p$ and $d_z$ are in-plane
and out-of-plane components of DM d vector, respectively. From these results
and the estimated exchange interaction J=6.15 K by Okuta et al., the ground
state of Cr-jarosite is discussed in connection with the Monte Carlo
simulations result with classical Heisenberg spins on the kagome lattice by
Elhajal et al. Finally, the angular dependence of linewidth and the lineshape
observed at 296 K by X-band ESR show typical behavior of a two-dimensional
Heisenberg antiferromagnet, suggesting a good two-dimensionality of
Cr-jarosite.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03386</id><created>2016-11-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>C. H. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent progress in astrophysical plasma turbulence from solar wind
  observations</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Journal of Plasma Physics collection
  &quot;Fundamental problems of plasma astrophysics: new perspectives&quot;</comments><journal-ref>J. Plasma Phys. 82 535820602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0022377816001124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper summarises some of the recent progress that has been made in
understanding astrophysical plasma turbulence in the solar wind, from in situ
spacecraft observations. At large scales, where the turbulence is predominantly
Alfvenic, measurements of critical balance, residual energy, and 3D structure
are discussed, along with comparison to recent models of strong Alfvenic
turbulence. At these scales, a few percent of the energy is also in compressive
fluctuations, and their nature, anisotropy, and relation to the Alfvenic
component is described. In the small scale kinetic range, below the ion
gyroscale, the turbulence becomes predominantly kinetic Alfven in nature, and
measurements of the spectra, anisotropy, and intermittency of this turbulence
are discussed with respect to recent cascade models. One of the major remaining
questions is how the turbulent energy is dissipated, and some recent work on
this question, in addition to future space missions which will help to answer
it, are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03400</id><created>2016-11-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Konzen</keyname><forenames>Lance M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sefat</keyname><forenames>Athena S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice Parameters Guide Superconductivity in Iron-Arsenides</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>A review article, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter, 29 (2017), 083001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa4e03</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discovery of superconducting materials has led to their use in
technological marvels such as magnetic-field sensors in MRI machines, powerful
research magnets, short transmission cables, and high-speed trains. Despite
such applications, the uses of superconductors are not widespread because they
function much below room-temperature, hence the costly cooling. Since the
discovery of Cu- and Fe-based high-temperature superconductors (HTS), much
intense effort has tried to explain and understand the superconducting
phenomenon. While no exact explanations are given, several trends are reported
in relation to the materials basis in magnetism and spin excitations. In fact,
most HTS have antiferromagnetic undoped 'parent' materials that undergo a
superconducting transition upon small chemical substitutions in them. As it is
currently unclear which 'dopants' can favor superconductivity, this manuscript
investigates crystal structure changes upon chemical substitutions, to find
clues in lattice parameters for the superconducting occurrence. We review the
chemical substitution effects on the crystal lattice of iron-arsenide-based
crystals (2008 to present). We note that (a) HTS compounds have nearly
tetragonal structures with a-lattice parameter close to 4 A, and (b)
superconductivity can depend strongly on the c-lattice parameter changes with
chemical substitution. For example, a decrease in c-lattice parameter is
required to induce 'in-plane' superconductivity. The review of lattice
parameter trends in iron-arsenides presented here should guide synthesis of new
materials and provoke theoretical input, giving clues for HTS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04239</id><created>2016-11-13</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ying D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Huidong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Bei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luhmann</keyname><forenames>Janet G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vourlidas</keyname><forenames>Angelos</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure, Propagation and Expansion of a CME-Driven Shock in the
  Heliosphere: A Revisit of the 2012 July 23 Extreme Storm</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the structure, propagation and expansion of the shock associated
with the 2012 July 23 extreme coronal mass ejection (CME). Characteristics of
the shock determined from multi-point imaging observations are compared to in
situ measurements at different locations and a complex radio type II burst,
which according to our definition has multiple branches that may not all be
fundamental-harmonic related. The white-light shock signature can be modeled
reasonably well by a spherical structure and was expanding backward even on the
opposite side of the Sun. The expansion of the shock, which was roughly
self-similar after the first $\sim$1.5 hours from launch, largely dominated
over the translation of the shock center for the time period of interest. Our
study also suggests a bow-shock morphology around the nose at later times due
to the outward motion in combination with the expansion of the ejecta. The
shock decayed and failed to reach Mercury in the backward direction and STEREO
B and Venus in the lateral directions, as indicated by the imaging and in situ
observations. The shock in the nose direction, however, may persist to the far
outer heliosphere, with predicted impact on Dawn around 06 UT on July 25 and on
Jupiter around 23:30 UT on July 27 by an MHD model. The type II burst shows
properties generally consistent with the spatial/temporal variations of the
shock deduced from imaging and in situ observations. In particular, the
low-frequency bands agree well with the in situ measurements of a very low
density ahead of the shock at STEREO A.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04392</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nitschke</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuther</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voigt</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete exterior calculus (DEC) for the surface Navier-Stokes equation</title><categories>math.NA math.DG physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a numerical approach for the incompressible surface Navier-Stokes
equation. The approach is based on the covariant form and uses discrete
exterior calculus (DEC) in space and a semi-implicit discretization in time.
The discretization is described in detail and related to finite difference
schemes on staggered grids in flat space for which we demonstrate second order
convergence. We compare computational results with a vorticity-stream function
approach for surfaces with genus 0 and demonstrate the interplay between
topology, geometry and flow properties. Our discretization also allows to
handle harmonic vector fields, which we demonstrate on a torus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06379</id><created>2016-11-19</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jadczyk</keyname><forenames>Arkadiusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szulga</keyname><forenames>Jerzy</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz transformation from an elementary point of view</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>15A90, 15A57, 17B81, 22E70</msc-class><journal-ref>Electronic Journal of Linear Algebra, 2016, Volume 31, pp. 794-833</journal-ref><doi>10.13001/1081-3810.3302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Elementary methods are used to examine some nontrivial mathematical issues
underpinning the Lorentz transformation. Its eigen-system is characterized
through the exponential of a $G$-skew symmetric matrix, underlining its
unconnectedness at one of its extremes (the hyper-singular case). A different
yet equivalent angle is presented through Pauli coding which reveals the
connection between the hyper-singular case and the shear map.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02804</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-01-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rezaei</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of Dark-Matter Admixed Neutron Stars using the Equation of State
  from the Rotational Curves of Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 18 figures, 8 tables. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><msc-class>85</msc-class><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 835, 33 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa5273</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we employ the dark matter equations of state (DMEOSs) obtained
from the rotational curves of galaxies as well as the fermionic DMEOS with m =
1.0 GeV to study the structure of darkmatter admixed neutron stars (DMANSs).
Applying the equation of state in the Skyrme framework for the neutron matter
(NM), we calculate the mass-radius relation for different DMANSs with various
DMEOSs and central pressure of dark matter (DM) to NM ratios. Our results show
that for some DMEOSs, the mass-radius relations are in agreement with new
observations, e.g. EXO 1745-248, 4U 1608-52, and 4U 1820-30, which are
inconsistent with the normal neutron stars. We conclude that both DMEOSs and
central pressure ratios of DM to NM affect the slope of the mass-radius
relation of DMANSs. This is because of the interaction between DM and NM, which
leads to gravitationally or self-bound DMANSs. We study the radius of the NM
sphere as well as the radius of the DM halo for different DMANSs. The results
confirm that, in some cases, a NM sphere with a small radius is surrounded by a
halo of DM with a larger radius. Our calculations verify that, due to the
different degrees of DM domination in DMANSs, with a value of the visible
radius of a star two possible DMANSs with different masses can be exist. The
gravitational redshift is also calculated for DMANSs with different DMEOSs and
central pressure ratios. The results explain that the existence of DM in a
DMANS leads to higher values of gravitational redshift of the star.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02863</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schlimme</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achenbach</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aulenbacher</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baunack</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beri&#x10d;i&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosnar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dehn</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Distler</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esser</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fonvieille</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fri&#x161;&#x10d;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutheil</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kegel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohl</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolar</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreidel</keyname><forenames>H. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihovilovi&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nillius</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nuck</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pochodzalla</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoth</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sfienti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;irca</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spruck</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;tajner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tioukine</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyukin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vertical Beam Polarization at MAMI</title><categories>physics.acc-ph physics.ins-det</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.01.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the first time a vertically polarized electron beam has been used for
physics experiments at MAMI in the energy range between 180 and 855 MeV. The
beam-normal single-spin asymmetry $A_{\mathrm{n}}$, which is a direct probe of
higher-order photon exchange beyond the first Born approximation, has been
measured in the reaction $^{12}\mathrm C(\vec e,e')^{12}\mathrm C$. Vertical
polarization orientation was necessary to measure this asymmetry with the
existing experimental setup. In this paper we describe the procedure to orient
the electron polarization vector vertically, and the concept of determining
both its magnitude and orientation with the available setup. A sophisticated
method has been developed to overcome the lack of a polarimeter setup sensitive
to the vertical polarization component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03169</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ballesteros</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herranz</keyname><forenames>Francisco J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musso</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naranjo</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>The kappa-(A)dS quantum algebra in (3+1) dimensions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 766 (2017) 205-211</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum duality principle is used to obtain explicitly the Poisson
analogue of the kappa-(A)dS quantum algebra in (3+1) dimensions as the
corresponding Poisson-Lie structure on the dual solvable Lie group. The
construction is fully performed in a kinematical basis and deformed Casimir
functions are also explicitly obtained. The cosmological constant $\Lambda$ is
included as a Poisson-Lie group contraction parameter, and the limit
$\Lambda\to 0$ leads to the well-known kappa-Poincar\'e algebra in the
bicrossproduct basis. A twisted version with Drinfel'd double structure of this
kappa-(A)dS deformation is sketched.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06071</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xilei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Junguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Pin</forenames></author></authors><title>The low temperature performance of CsI(Na) crystals for WIPMs direct
  searches</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous studies showed that CsI(Na) crystals have significantly different
waveforms between alpha and gamma scintillations. In this work, the light yield
and PSD capability of CsI(Na) scintillators as a function of the temperature
down to 80 K has been studied. As temperature drops, the fast component rises
and the slow component decreases. By cooling the CsI(Na) crystals, the light
yield of high ionization events are enhanced significantly, while the light
yield of background gamma events are suppressed. At 110 K, CsI(Na) crystal
achieves the optimal balance between low threshold and good background
rejection performance. The different responses of CsI(Na) to gamma and alpha at
different temperatures are explained with self-trapped and activator
luminescence centers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06597</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Koskelo</keyname><forenames>Jaakko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fugallo</keyname><forenames>Giorgia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakala</keyname><forenames>Mikko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sottile</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cudazzo</keyname><forenames>Pierluigi</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitons in van der Waals materials: from monolayer to bulk hexagonal
  boron nitride</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted for Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035125 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a general picture of the exciton properties of layered materials
in terms of the excitations of their single-layer building blocks. To this end,
we derive a model excitonic hamiltonian by drawing an analogy with molecular
crystals, which are other prototypical van der Waals materials. We employ this
simplified model to analyse in detail the excitation spectrum of hexagonal
boron nitride (hBN) that we have obtained from the {\it ab initio} solution of
the many-body Bethe-Salpeter equation as a function of momentum. In this way we
identify the character of the lowest-energy excitons in hBN, discuss the
effects of the interlayer hopping and the electron-hole exchange interaction on
the exciton dispersion, and illustrate the relation between exciton and plasmon
excitations in layered materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07049</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sutter</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yava&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>Hasan</forenames></author></authors><title>Material properties of $\alpha$-quartz that are relevant for its
  potential use in X-ray monochromators and analyzers</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Monochromators and analyzers for X-rays of energy $&gt;$ 5 keV are
overwhelmingly made from silicon crystals, of which large specimens of high
purity and low defect density are readily available. Germanium and diamond
crystals are also occasionally used. Bragg reflection of the X-rays determines
their bandwidth, with backscattering reflections (with Bragg angles $\approx$
90$^\circ$) providing the highest energy resolution along with high photon
collection efficiency. The crystal lattices of all these materials share the
same space group $Fd\overline{3}m$, which because of its high symmetry provides
a low density of unique backscattering Bragg reflections per unit photon energy
range. This is a disadvantage for solid-state studies using resonant inelastic
X-ray scattering (RIXS) and nuclear resonant scattering (NRS), for which the
X-ray energy must be tuned to a specific electronic or nuclear transition. As a
result, crystals with lattices of lower symmetry are being considered.
$\alpha$-quartz is one of the most promising. However, data on its material
properties and fabrication techniques are widely scattered, and in the vital
matter of the atomic positions, great inconsistencies exist in the literature.
The material properties of $\alpha$-quartz that are relevant to X-ray studies
are therefore summarized and clarified here as a guide to future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07081</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>Zafar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Dhruv</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiwart</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irfan</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric partner potentials arising from nodeless half bound
  states</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, an important change regarding at least one bound
  state in one dimension</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Half Bound State (HBS) $\psi_*(x)$ can be defined as a single, conditional,
zero-energy, continuous solution of the one dimensional Schr{\&quot;o}dinger
equation for a scattering potential well $V(x)$ ($s.t ~ V(\pm \infty)=0$). The
non-normalizable and solitary HBS of a potential satisfies Neumann boundary
condition that $\psi'_*(\pm \infty)=0$ and it can have $n$ (= 0,1,2,...) number
of nodes indicating $n$ number of bound states in $V(x)$ below $E=0$. Here we
show that starting with a nodeless HBS, we can construct a (supersymmetric)
pair of finite potentials (well, double wells, well-barrier): $V_{\pm}(x)$
having no bound state and they enclose positive area on $x$-axis. On the
contrary their negative counterparts $(-cV_{\pm}(x)),c&gt;0$ do have at least one
bound state for any arbitrary positive value of $c$. Furthermore, $c
V_{\pm}(x),~ c &gt;0$ which binds positive area on x-axis in conformity with
Simon's theorem can have at least one bound state only conditionally for
instance when $c&gt;1$ or $c&gt;&gt;1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08416</id><created>2016-12-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Zielinska</keyname><forenames>Joanna A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zukauskas</keyname><forenames>Andrius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canalias</keyname><forenames>Carlota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noyan</keyname><forenames>Mehmet A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>Morgan W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fully-resonant, tunable, monolithic frequency conversion as a coherent
  UVA source</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 25, 1142-1150 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.001142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a monolithic frequency converter incorporating up to four
tuning degrees of freedom, three temperature and one strain, allowing resonance
of pump and generated wavelengths simultaneous with optimal phase-matching.
With a Rb-doped periodically-poled potassium titanyl phosphate (KTP)
implementation, we demonstrate efficient continuous-wave second harmonic
generation from 795 nm to 397 nm, with low-power efficiency of 72%/W and
high-power slope efficiency of 4.5%. The measured performance shows good
agreement with theoretical modeling of the device. We measure optical
bistability effects, and show how they can be used to improve the stability of
the output against pump frequency and amplitude variations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00395</id><created>2017-01-02</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Bochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Haitang</forenames></author></authors><title>WKB Approximation for a Deformed Schrodinger-like Equation and its
  Applications to Quasinormal Modes of Black Holes and Quantum Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>references added</comments><report-no>CTP-SCU/2017002</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we use the WKB approximation method to approximately solve a
deformed Schrodinger-like differential equation: $\left[ -\hbar^{2}
\partial_{\xi}^{2}g^{2}\left( -i\hbar\alpha\partial_{\xi}\right) -p^{2}\left(
\xi\right) \right] \psi\left( \xi\right) =0$, which are frequently dealt with
in various effective models of quantum gravity, where the parameter $\alpha$
characterizes effects of quantum gravity. For an arbitrary function $g\left(
x\right) $ satisfying several properties proposed in the paper, we find the WKB
solutions, the WKB connection formulas through a turning point, the deformed
Bohr--Sommerfeld quantization rule, and the deformed tunneling rate formula
through a potential barrier. Several examples of applying the WKB approximation
to the deformed quantum mechanics are investigated. In particular, we calculate
the bound states of the P\&quot;{o}schl-Teller potential and estimate the effects of
quantum gravity on the quasinormal modes of a Schwarzschild black hole.
Moreover, the area quantum of the black hole is considered via Bohr's
correspondence principle. Finally, the WKB solutions of the deformed
Wheeler--DeWitt equation for a closed Friedmann universe with a scalar field
are obtained, and the effects of quantum gravity on the probability of
sufficient inflation is discussed in the context of the tunneling proposal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00743</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Blinne</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron Positron Pair Production in Strong Electric Fields</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>133 pages, 42 figures. This PhD thesis draws heavily from
  arXiv:1311.1678 and arXiv:1510.02712</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work covers electron positron pair production in spatially homogeneous
electric (and magnetic) fields. Different field configurations are looked at in
order to study various phenomena including multiphoton pair production,
Sauter-Schwinger pair production and dynamically assisted pair production. The
main focus lies on pulsed, rotating fields with one main frequency component
which are called rotating Sauter pulses. The results are obtained via two
numerical methods, that rest on different theoretical approaches. A generic
method is derived from the Dirac-Heisenberg-Wigner (DHW) formalism which
entails a modified quantum kinetic equation. We call the numerical solution of
this equation the Wigner method. Other types of equations are derived from the
DHW formalism as well and numerically solved with the aim to include magnetic
fields. In the case of rotating Sauter pulses a completely different numerical
method is developed, which is based on a semiclassical approach and therefore
called the semiclassical method. A number of parameter studies are conducted to
understand pair production in rotating Sauter pulses. The Wigner method and the
semiclassical method are compared exhaustively and found to complement each
other. This makes it possible to cover the complete range of parameters of the
rotating Sauter pulse, which helps to calculate the pair production rates for
experiments involving counter-propagating circularly polarized laser light. An
interpretation of the pair production spectra is given. Due to the general
nature of the Wigner method it is possible to study more general field
configurations which include pulses with elliptic polarization, chirp or
bichromatic rotating Sauter pulses. Each of these exhibit interesting features,
including the dynamically assisted Schwinger effect in bichromatic pulses,
which could be useful in planning high-intensity laser experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01249</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Zeeuw</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author></authors><title>Reaching New Heights in Astronomy - ESO Long Term Perspectives</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 17 figures. Appears in The Messenger, December 2016. 3
  links corrected</comments><journal-ref>The Messenger, 166, 2 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A comprehensive description of ESO in the current global astronomical
context, and its plans for the next decade and beyond, are presented. This
survey covers all aspects of the Organisation, including the optical-infrared
programme at the La Silla Paranal Observatory, the submillimetre facilities
ALMA and APEX, the construction of the 39-metre European Extremely Large
Telescope and the science operation of these facilities. An extension of the
current optical/infrared/submillimetre facilities into multi-messenger
astronomy has been made with the decision to host the southern Cherenkov
Telescope Array at Paranal. The structure of the Organisation is presented and
the further development of the staff is described within the scope of the
long-range financial planning. The role of Chile is highlighted and expansion
of the number of Member States beyond the current 15 is discussed. The
strengths of the ESO model, together with challenges as well as possible new
opportunities and initiatives, are examined and a strategy for the future of
ESO is outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02491</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Viaggiu</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Axial and polar gravitational wave equations in a de Sitter expanding
  universe by Laplace transform</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>Final version published on Class. Quantum Grav</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 035018</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa5570</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the propagation in a de Sitter universe of
gravitational waves generated by perturbating some unspecified spherical
astrophysical object in the frequencies domain. We obtain the axial and polar
perturbation equations in a cosmological de Sitter universe in the usual
comoving coordinates, the coordinates we occupy in our galaxy. We write down
the relevant equations in terms of Laplace transform with respect to the
comoving time $t$ instead of the usual Fourier one that is no longer available
in a cosmological context. Both axial and polar perturbation equations are
expressed in terms of a non trivial mixture of retarded-advanced metric
coefficients with respect to the Laplace parameter $s$ (complex translation).
The axial case is studied in more detail. In particular, the axial
perturbations can be reduced to a master linear second-order differential
equation in terms of the Regge-Wheeler function $Z$ where a coupling with a
retarded $Z$ with respect to the cosmological time $t$ is present. It is shown
that a de Sitter expanding universe can change the frequency $\omega$ of a
gravitational wave as perceived by a comoving observer. The polar equations are
much more involved. Nevertheless, we show that also the polar perturbations can
be expressed in terms of four independent integrable differential equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04570</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Junjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Changqin</forenames></author></authors><title>Signature of non-Markovianity in time-resolved energy transfer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore signatures of the non-Markovianity in the time-resolved energy
transfer processes for quantum open systems. Focusing on typical systems such
as the exact solvable damped Jaynes-Cummings model and the general spin-boson
model, we establish quantitative links between the time-resolved energy current
and the symmetric logarithmic derivative quantum Fisher information (SLD-QFI)
flow, one of measures quantifying the non-Markovianity, within the framework of
non-Markovian master equations in time-local forms. From the relationships, we
find in the damped Jaynes-Cummings model that the SLD-QFI backflow from the
reservoir to the system always correlates with an energy backflow, thus we can
directly witness the non-Markovianity from the dynamics of the energy current.
In the spin-boson model, the relation is built on the rotating-wave
approximation, calibrated against exact numerical results, and proven reliable
in the weak coupling regime. We demonstrate that whether the non-Markovianity
guarantees the occurrence of an energy backflow depends on the bath spectral
function. For the Ohmic and sub-Ohmic cases, we show that no energy backflow
occurs and the energy current always flow out of the system even in the
non-Markovian regime. While in the super-Ohmic case, we observe that the
non-Markovian dynamics can induce an energy backflow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04737</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Genda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kharzeev</keyname><forenames>Dmitri E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Lifshitz transition mediated electronic transport anomaly in bulk ZrTe5</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 015005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa55a3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zirconium pentatelluride ZrTe$_5$, a fascinating topological material
platform, hosts exotic chiral fermions in its highly anisotropic
three-dimensional Dirac band and holds great promise advancing the
next-generation information technology. However, the origin underlying its
anomalous resistivity peak has been under debate for decades. Here we provide
transport evidence substantiating the anomaly to be a direct manifestation of a
Lifshitz transition in the Dirac band with an ultrahigh carrier mobility
exceeding 3$\times$10$^5$ cm$^2$ V$^{-1}$ s$^{-1}$. We demonstrate that the
Lifshitz transition is readily controllable by means of carrier doping, which
sets the anomaly peak temperature $T_p$. $T_p$ is found to scale approximately
as $n_H^{0.27}$, where the Hall carrier concentration $n_H$ is linked with the
Fermi level by $\epsilon_F$ $\propto$ $n_H^{1/3}$ in a linearly dispersed Dirac
band. This relation indicates $T_p$ monotonically increases with $\epsilon_F$,
which serves as an effective knob for fine tuning transport properties in
pentatelluride-based Dirac semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04819</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kajdic</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexandrova</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maksimovic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacombe</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazakerley</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Suprathermal electron strahl widths in the presence of narrow-band
  whistler waves in the solar wind</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>Kajdic et al., TheApJ, 833, 172, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/833/2/172</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform the first statistical study of the effects of the interaction of
suprathermal electrons with narrow-band whistler mode waves in the solar wind.
We show that this interaction does occur and that it is associated with
enhanced widths of the so called strahl component. The latter is directed along
the inter- planetary magnetic field away from the Sun. We do the study by
comparing the strahl pitch angle widths in the solar wind at 1AU in the absence
of large scale discontinuities and transient structures, such as interplanetary
shocks, interplanetary coronal mass ejections, stream interaction regions, etc.
during times when the whistler mode waves were present and when they were
absent. This is done by using the data from two Cluster instruments: STAFF data
in frequency range between ~0.1 Hz and ~200 Hz were used for determining the
wave properties and PEACE datasets at twelve central energies between ~57 eV
(equivalent to ~10 typical electron thermal energies in the solar wind, E_T )
and ~676 eV (~113 E_T ) for pitch angle measurements. Statistical analysis
shows that during the inter- vals with the whistler waves the strahl component
on average exhibits pitch angle widths between 2 and 12 degrees larger than
during the intervals when these waves are not present. The largest difference
is obtained for the electron central energy of ~344 eV (~57 E_T ).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04832</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>McClain</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Qiming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Garnet Kin-Lic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berkelbach</keyname><forenames>Timothy C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gaussian-based coupled-cluster theory for the ground state and band
  structure of solids</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of Gaussian-based ground-state and excited-state
equation-of-motion coupled-cluster theory with single and double excitations
for three-dimensional solids. We focus on diamond and silicon, which are
paradigmatic covalent semiconductors. In addition to ground-state properties
(the lattice constant, bulk modulus, and cohesive energy), we compute the
quasiparticle band structure and band gap. We sample the Brillouin zone with up
to 64 k-points using norm-conserving pseudopotentials and polarized double- and
triple-zeta basis sets, leading to canonical coupled-cluster calculations with
as many as 256 electrons in 2,176 orbitals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04834</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnsen</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>High-order schemes for the Euler equations in cylindrical/spherical
  coordinates</title><categories>math.NA math-ph math.MP physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>35L67, 35L65, 65M06</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider implementations of high-order finite difference Weighted
Essentially Non-Oscillatory (WENO) schemes for the Euler equations in
cylindrical and spherical coordinate systems with radial dependence only. The
main concern of this work lies in ensuring both high-order accuracy and
conservation. Three different spatial discretizations are assessed: one that is
shown to be high-order accurate but not conservative, one conservative but not
high-order accurate, and a new approach that is both high-order accurate and
conservative. For cylindrical and spherical coordinates, we present convergence
results for the advection equation and the Euler equations with an acoustics
problem; we then use the Sod shock tube and the Sedov point-blast problems in
cylindrical coordinates to verify our analysis and implementations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04840</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Hess</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Qingkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smalyukh</keyname><forenames>Ivan I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical patterning of magnetic domains and defects in ferromagnetic
  liquid crystal colloids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 107, 071906 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4928552</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A promising approach in designing composite materials with unusual physical
behavior combines solid nanostructures and orientationally ordered soft matter
at the mesoscale. Such composites not only inherit properties of their
constituents but also can exhibit emergent behavior, such as ferromagnetic
ordering of colloidal metal nanoparticles forming mesoscopic magnetization
domains when dispersed in a nematic liquid crystal. Here we demonstrate the
optical patterning of domain structures and topological defects in such
ferromagnetic liquid crystal colloids, which allows for altering their response
to magnetic fields. Our findings reveal the nature of the defects in this soft
matter system which is different as compared to non-polar nematics and
ferromagnets alike.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04849</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yaoran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Julian S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Taewoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senyuk</keyname><forenames>Bohdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Sailing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smalyukh</keyname><forenames>Ivan I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical manipulation of shape-morphing elastomeric liquid crystal
  microparticles doped with gold nanocrystals</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 100, 241901 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4729143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate facile optical manipulation of shape of birefringent colloidal
microparticles made from liquid crystal elastomers. Using soft lithography and
polymerization, we fabricate elastomeric microcylinders with weakly undulating
director oriented on average along their long axes. These particles are
infiltrated with gold nanospheres acting as heat transducers that allow for an
efficient localized transfer of heat from a focused infrared laser beam to a
submicrometer region within a microparticle. Photothermal control of ordering
in the liquid crystal elastomer using scanned beams allows for a robust control
of colloidal particles, enabling both reversible and irreversible changes of
shape. Possible applications include optomechanics, microfluidics, and
reconfigurable colloidal composites with shape-dependent self-assembly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04884</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Cherigui</keyname><forenames>Dounia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guella</keyname><forenames>Chahrazed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahriche</keyname><forenames>Amine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasri</keyname><forenames>Salah</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Radiative Neutrino Mass Models At The LHC Via Trilepton Events</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings of Moriond EW &amp; UT 2016 (4 pages, 4 figures)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Trilepton event represents one of the probes of the new physics at high
energy colliders. In this talk, we consider the search for processes with final
states $\ell_{\alpha}^{\pm }\ell_{\beta}^{\pm}\ell_{\gamma}^{\mp}$ +
$\slashed{E}_{T}$ where
  ${\alpha}$, ${\beta}$, ${\gamma}$= $e,\mu,\tau$, via the production of
singlet charged scalar $S^{\pm}$ which arise in a class of radiative neutrino
mass models. We discuss the opposite sign same flavor leptons signal, as well
as the background free channel in view to get a significant excess at
$\sqrt{s}$= 8 TeV and $\sqrt{s}$ = 14 TeV at the hadron collider LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04891</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Reut</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhalychev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mogilevtsev</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author></authors><title>Data-pattern tomography of entangled states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012123 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the data-pattern tomography for reconstruction of entangled states
of light. We show that for a moderate number of probe coherent states it is
possible to achieve high accuracy of representation not only for single-mode
states but also for two-mode entangled states. We analyze the stability of
these representations to the noise and demonstrate the conservation of the
purity and entanglement. Simulating the probe and signal measurements, we show
that systematic error inherent for representation of realistic signal response
with finite sets of responses from probe states still allows one to infer
reliably the signal states preserving entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04913</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04913</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kerviche</keyname><forenames>Ronan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Saikat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashok</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental limit of resolving two point sources limited by an arbitrary
  point spread function</title><categories>physics.optics cs.IT math.IT quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, submitted to ISIT 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Estimating the angular separation between two incoherently radiating
monochromatic point sources is a canonical toy problem to quantify spatial
resolution in imaging. In recent work, Tsang {\em et al.} showed, using a
Fisher Information analysis, that Rayleigh's resolution limit is just an
artifact of the conventional wisdom of intensity measurement in the image
plane. They showed that the optimal sensitivity of estimating the angle is only
a function of the total photons collected during the camera's integration time
but entirely independent of the angular separation itself no matter how small
it is, and found the information-optimal mode basis, intensity detection in
which achieves the aforesaid performance. We extend the above analysis, which
was done for a Gaussian point spread function (PSF) to a hard-aperture pupil
proving the information optimality of image-plane sinc-Bessel modes, and
generalize the result further to an arbitrary PSF. We obtain new
counterintuitive insights on energy vs. information content in spatial modes,
and extend the Fisher Information analysis to exact calculations of minimum
mean squared error, both for Gaussian and hard aperture pupils.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04927</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobakhidze</keyname><forenames>Archil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Shelley</forenames></author></authors><title>Standard Model with hidden scale invariance and light dilaton</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the minimal Standard Model as an effective low-energy description
of an unspecified fundamental theory with spontaneously broken conformal
symmetry. The effective theory exhibits classical scale invariance which
manifest itself through the dilaton field. The mass of the dilaton is generated
via the quantum scale anomaly at two-loop level and is proportional to the
techically stable hierarchy between the electroweak scale and a high energy
scale given by a dilaton vacuum expectation value. We find that a generic
prediction of this class of models is the existence of a very light dilaton
with mass between $\sim 0.01$ $\mu$eV to $\sim 100$ MeV, depending on the
hierarchy of scales. Searches for such a light scalar particle may reveal a
fundamental role of conformal invariance in nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04932</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Faria</keyname><forenames>Luiz M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A model for Faraday pilot waves over variable topography</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 2017, 811:51--66</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.750</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Couder and Fort discovered that droplets walking on a vibrating bath possess
certain features previously thought to be exclusive to quantum systems. These
millimetric droplets synchronize with their Faraday wavefield, creating a
macroscopic pilot-wave system. In this paper we exploit the fact that the waves
generated are nearly monochromatic and propose a hydrodynamic model capable of
quantitatively capturing the interaction between bouncing drops and a variable
topography. We show that our reduced model is able to reproduce some important
experiments involving the drop-topography interaction, such as non-specular
reflection and single-slit diffraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04939</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chertkov</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyak</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Ensemble of Thermostatically Controlled Loads: Statistical Physics
  Approach</title><categories>cs.SY physics.data-an physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures</comments><report-no>LA-UR-17-20283</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermostatically Controlled Loads (TCL), e.g. air-conditioners and heaters,
are by far the most wide-spread consumers of electricity. Normally the devices
are calibrated to provide the so-called bang-bang control of temperature --
changing from on to off, and vice versa, depending on temperature. Aggregation
of a large group of similar devices into a statistical ensemble is considered,
where the devices operate following the same dynamics subject to stochastic
perturbations and randomized, Poisson on/off switching policy. We analyze,
using theoretical and computational tools of statistical physics, how the
ensemble relaxes to a stationary distribution and establish relation between
the relaxation and statistics of the probability flux, associated with devices'
cycling in the mixed (discrete, switch on/off, and continuous, temperature)
phase space. This allowed us to derive and analyze spectrum of the
non-equilibrium (detailed balance broken) statistical system and uncover how
switching policy affects oscillatory trend and speed of the relaxation.
Relaxation of the ensemble is of a practical interest because it describes how
the ensemble recovers from significant perturbations, e.g. forceful temporary
switching off aimed at utilizing flexibility of the ensemble in providing
&quot;demand response&quot; services relieving consumption temporarily to balance larger
power grid. We discuss how the statistical analysis can guide further
development of the emerging demand response technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04961</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jingyuan Linda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagoudakis</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzeng</keyname><forenames>Yan-Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dory</keyname><forenames>Constantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radulaski</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelaita</keyname><forenames>Yousif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Kevin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Xun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melosh</keyname><forenames>Nicholas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vu&#x10d;kovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Jelena</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete Coherent Control of Silicon-Vacancies in Diamond Nanopillars
  Containing Single Defect Centers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Arrays of identical and individually addressable qubits lay the foundation
for the creation of scalable quantum hardware such as quantum processors and
repeaters. Silicon vacancy centers in diamond (SiV) offer excellent physical
properties such as low inhomogeneous broadening, fast photon emission, and a
large Debye-Waller factor, while the possibility for all-optical ultrafast
manipulation and techniques to extend the spin coherence times make them very
promising candidates for qubits. Here, we have developed arrays of nanopillars
containing single SiV centers with high yield, and we demonstrate ultrafast
all-optical complete coherent control of the state of a single SiV center. The
high quality of the chemical vapor deposition (CVD) grown SiV centers provides
excellent spectral stability, which allows us to coherently manipulate and
quasi-resonantly read out the state of individual SiV centers on picosecond
timescales using ultrafast optical pulses. This work opens new opportunities
towards the creation of a scalable on-chip diamond platform for quantum
information processing and scalable nanophotonics applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04962</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04962</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Miao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Shiyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Heming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Jiajian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Te</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ruifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dejun</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical studies on the impact of point defect on the structures of
  different uranium silicides</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structures, point defects and impacts of fission products for U3Si
(\b{eta}-U3Si and {\gamma}-U3Si) and USi2 ({\alpha}-USi2 and \b{eta}-USi2) are
studied by first-principles calculations. The lattice parameters of U3Si and
USi2 are calculated and the stability of different types of point defects is
predicted by their formation energies. The results show that silicon vacancies
are more prone to be produced than uranium vacancies in \b{eta}-USi2 matrix,
while uranium vacancies are the most stable defects of other three types of
crystallographic structures. The most favorable sites of fission products
(strontium, barium, cerium and neodymium) are determined in this work as well.
By calculating incorporation energies of fission products, we demonstrate that
the uranium site is the most favored for all the fissions products. Comparing
the structural changes influenced by different fission products, it is also
found that the highest volume change is caused by barium interstitials.
According to the current data, rare earth elements cerium and neodymium are
found to be more stable than alkaline earth metals strontium and barium in a
given nuclear matrix. Finally, it is also determined that in USi2 crystal
lattice fission products tend to be stabilized in uranium substitution sites,
while they are likely to form precipitates from the U3Si matrix. It is expected
that this work may provide new insight into the mechanism for structural
evolutions of silicide nuclear fuels in a reactor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04972</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Imada</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawate</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>UV/EUV High-Throughput Spectroscopic Telescope: A Next Generation Solar
  Physics Mission white paper</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5page</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the activity in the solar corona is a long-standing problem in
solar physics. Recent satellite observations, such as Hinode, Solar Dynamics
Observatory (SDO), Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph (IRIS), show the
detail characteristics of the solar atmosphere and try to reveal the energy
transfer from the photosphere to the corona through the magnetic fields and its
energy conversion by various processes. However, quantitative estimation of
energy transfer along the magnetic field is not enough. There are mainly two
reason why it is difficult to observe the energy transfer from photosphere to
corona; 1) spatial resolution gap between photosphere (a few 0.1 arcsec) and
corona (a few arcsec), 2) lack in temperature coverage. Furthermore, there is
not enough observational knowledge of the physical parameters in the energy
dissipation region. There are mainly three reason why it is difficult to
observe in the vicinity of the energy dissipation region; 1) small spatial
scale, 2) short time scale, 3) low emission. It is generally believed that the
energy dissipation occurs in the very small scale and its duration is very
short (10 second). Further, the density in the dissipation region might be very
low. Therefore, the high spatial and temporal resolution UV/EUV spectroscopic
observation with wide temperature coverage is crucial to estimate the energy
transport from photosphere to corona quantitatively and diagnose the plasma
dynamics in the vicinity of the energy dissipation region. Main Science Target
for the telescope is quantitative estimation for the energy transfer from the
photosphere to the corona, and clarification of the plasma dynamics in the
vicinity of the energy dissipation region, where is the key region for coronal
heating, solar wind acceleration, and/or solar flare, by the high spatial and
temporal resolution UV/EUV spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04980</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Deshmukh</keyname><forenames>Shivaraj D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsori</keyname><forenames>Yoav</forenames></author></authors><title>Control of chemical reactions using electric field gradients</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. (Communication) 144, 191102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4951709</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine theoretically a new idea for spatial and temporal control of
chemical reactions. When chemical reactions take place in a mixture of
solvents, an external electric field can alter the local mixture composition
thereby accelerating or decelerating the rate of reaction. The spatial
distribution of electric field strength can be non-trivial and depends on the
arrangement of the electrodes producing it. In the absence of electric field,
the mixture is homogeneous and the reaction takes place uniformly in the
reactor volume. When an electric field is applied the solvents separate and
reactants are concentrated in the same phase or separate to different phases,
depending on their relative miscibility in the solvents, and this can have a
large effect on the kinetics of the reaction. This method could provide an
alternative way to control runaway reactions and to increase the reaction rate
without using catalysts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04994</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>H. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yupeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shuang-Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zi-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bu</keyname><forenames>Qing-Cui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>JinLu</forenames></author></authors><title>A global study of Type B quasi-periodic oscillation in black hole X-ray
  binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3146</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We performed a global study on the timing and spectral properties of type-B
quasi-periodic oscillations (QPOs) in the outbursts of black hole X-ray
binaries. The sample is built based on the observations of {\it Rossi X-ray
Timing Explorer}, via searching in the literature in RXTE era for all the
identified type-B QPOs. To enlarge the sample, we also investigated some type-B
QPOs that are reported but not yet fully identified. Regarding to the time lag
and hard/soft flux ratio, we found that the sources with type-B QPOs behave in
two subgroups. In one subgroup, type-B QPO shows a hard time lag that firstly
decreases and then reverse into a soft time lag along with softening of the
energy spectrum. In the other subgroup, type-B QPOs distribute only in a small
region with hard time lag and relatively soft hardness. These findings may be
understood with a diversity of the homogeneity showing up for the hot inner
flow of different sources. We confirm the universality of a positive relation
between the type-B QPO frequency and the hard component luminosity in different
sources. We explain the results by considering that the type-B QPO photons are
produced in the inner accretion flow around the central black hole, under a
local Eddington limit. Using this relationship, we derived an mass estimation
of $9.3-27.1$ $\rm{M_{\odot}}$ for the black hole in H 1743-322.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04998</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xfc;neysu</keyname><forenames>Batu</forenames></author></authors><title>On the geometry of semiclassical limits on Dirichlet spaces</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP math.PR math.SP</categories><comments>16 pages; comments are welcome!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is a contribution to semiclassical analysis for abstract
Schr\&quot;odinger type operators on locally compact spaces: Let $X$ be a metrizable
seperable locally compact space, let $\mu$ be a Radon measure on $X$ with a
full support. Let $(t,x,y)\mapsto p(t,x,y)$ be a strictly positive pointwise
consistent $\mu$-heat kernel, and assume that the generator $H_p\geq 0$ of the
corresponding self-adjoint contraction semigroup in $L^2(X,\mu)$ induces a
regular Dirichlet form. Then, given a function $\Psi : (0,1)\to (0,\infty)$
such that the limit $\lim_{t\to 0+}p(t,x,x)\Psi (t)$ exists for all $x\in X$,
we prove that for every potential $w:X\to \mathbb{R}$ one has $$ \lim_{t \to
0+} \Psi (t)\mathrm{tr}\big(\mathrm{e}^{ -t H_p + w}\big)= \int
\mathrm{e}^{-w(x) }\lim_{t \to 0+}p(t,x,x) \Psi (t) d\mu(x)&lt;\infty $$ for the
Schr\&quot;odinger type operator $H_p + w$, provided $w$ satisfies very mild
conditions at $\infty$, that are essentially only made to guarantee that the
sum of quadratic forms $ H_p + w/t$ is self-adjoint and bounded from below for
small $t$, and to guarantee that $$
  \int \mathrm{e}^{-w(x) }\lim_{t\to 0+}p(t,x,x) \Psi (t) d\mu(x)&lt;\infty. $$
The proof is probabilistic and relies on a principle of not feeling the
boundary for $p(t,x,x)$. In particular, this result implies a new semiclassical
limit result for partition functions valid on arbitrary connected geodesically
complete Riemannian manifolds, and one also recovers a previously established
semiclassical limit result for possibly locally infinite connected weighted
graphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05012</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Kullie</keyname><forenames>Ossama</forenames></author></authors><title>How to understand the tunneling in attosecond experiment?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The measurement of the tunneling time (T-time) in today's attosecond and
strong field (low-frequency) experiments, despite its controversial discussion,
offers a fruitful opportunity to understand time measurement and the time in
quantum mechanics. In addition, as we will see in this work, a related
controversial issue is the particulate nature of the radiation. Different
models used to calculate the T-time will be discussed in this work in relation
to my model of real T-time, Phys. Rev. {\bf 92}, 052118 (2015), where an
intriguing similarity to the Bohr-Einstein photon box Gedanken experiment was
found. The tunneling process itself is still not well understood, but I am
arguing that a scattering mechanism (by the laser wave packet) offers a
possibility to understand the tunneling process in the tunneling region. This
is related to the question about the corpuscular nature of light which is
widely discussed in modern quantum optics experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05037</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milkus</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaccone</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The relation between stretched-exponential relaxation and the
  vibrational density of states in glassy disordered systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech nucl-th</categories><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 381, 446 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.12.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Amorphous solids or glasses are known to exhibit stretched-exponential decay
over broad time intervals in several of their macroscopic observables:
intermediate scattering function, dielectric relaxation modulus, time-elastic
modulus etc. This behaviour is prominent especially near the glass transition.
In this Letter we show, on the example of dielectric relaxation, that
stretched-exponential relaxation is intimately related to the peculiar lattice
dynamics of glasses. By reformulating the Lorentz model of dielectric matter in
a more general form, we express the dielectric response as a function of the
vibrational density of states (DOS) for a random assembly of spherical
particles interacting harmonically with their nearest-neighbours. Surprisingly
we find that near the glass transition for this system (which coincides with
the Maxwell rigidity transition), the dielectric relaxation is perfectly
consistent with stretched-exponential behaviour with Kohlrausch exponents $0.56
&lt; \beta &lt; 0.65$, which is the range where exponents are measured in most
experimental systems. Crucially, the root cause of stretched-exponential
relaxation can be traced back to soft modes (boson-peak) in the DOS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05046</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gargano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of DAMPE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>DAMPE space mission: first data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The DAMPE (DArk Matter Particle Explorer) satellite was launched on December
17, 2015 and started its data taking operation a few days later.
  DAMPE has a large geometric factor ($\sim~0.3\ m^2\ sr$) and provides good
tracking, calorimetric and charge measurements for electrons, gammas rays and
nuclei. This will allow precise measurement of cosmic ray spectra from tens of
$GeV$ up to about $100\ TeV$. In particular, the energy region between $1-100\
TeV$ will be explored with higher precision compared to previous experiments.
The various subdetectors allow an efficient identification of the electron
signal over the large (mainly proton-induced) background. As a result, the
all-electron spectrum will be measured with excellent resolution from few $GeV$
up to few $TeV$, thus giving the opportunity to identify possible contribution
of nearby sources. A report on the mission goals and status is presented,
together with the on-orbit detector performance and the first data coming from
space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05048</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruschel-Dutra</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espinosa</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; Miguel Rodr&#xed;guez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>Omaira Gonz&#xe1;lez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastoriza</keyname><forenames>Miriani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riffel</keyname><forenames>Rog&#xe9;rio</forenames></author></authors><title>Star formation in AGNs at the hundred parsec scale using MIR high
  resolution images</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3276</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been well established in the past decades that the central black hole
masses of galaxies correlate with dynamical properties of their harbouring
bulges. This notion begs the question of whether there are causal connections
between the AGN and its immediate vicinity in the host galaxy. In this paper we
analyse the presence of circumnuclear star formation in a sample of 15 AGN
using mid-infrared observations. The data consist of a set of 11.3{\mm} PAH
emission and reference continuum images, taken with ground based telescopes,
with sub-arcsecond resolution. By comparing our star formation estimates with
AGN accretion rates, derived from X-ray luminosities, we investigate the
validity of theoretical predictions for the AGN-starburst connection. Our main
results are: i) circumnuclear star formation is found, at distances as low as
tens of parsecs from the nucleus, in nearly half of our sample (7/15); ii) star
formation luminosities are correlated with the bolometric luminosity of the AGN
($L_{AGN}$) only for objects with $L_{AGN} \ge 10^{42}\,\,{\rm erg\,\,s^{-1}}$;
iii) low luminosity AGNs ($L_{AGN} &lt; 10^{42}\,\,{\rm erg\,\,s^{-1}}$) seem to
have starburst luminosities far greater than their bolometric luminosities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05049</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Pfn&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tegenkamp</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vattuone</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmons in one and two dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>37 pages, 17 figures, review to appear in Springer Handbook on
  Surface Science in 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasmons in low-dimensional systems respresent an important tool for coupling
energy into nanostructures and the localization of energy on the scale of only
a few nanometers. Contrary to ordinary surface plasmons of metallic bulk
materials, their dispersion goes to zero in the long wavelength limit, thus
covering a broad range of energies from terahertz to near infrared, and from
mesoscopic wavelengths down to just a few nanometers. Using specific and most
characteristic examples, we review first the properties of plasmons in
two-dimensional (2D) metallic layers from an experimental point of view. As
demonstrated, tuning of their dispersion is possible by changes of charge
carrier concentration in the partially filled 2D conduction bands, but for the
relativistic electron gas like in graphene only in the long wavelength limit.
For short wavelengths, on the other hand, the dispersion turns out to be
independent of the position of the Fermi level with respect to the Dirac point.
A linear dispersion, seen under the latter conditions in graphene, can also be
obtained in non-relativistic electron gases by coupling between 2D and 3D
electronic systems. As a well investigated example, the acoustic surface
plasmons in Shockley surface states, coupled with the bulk electronic system,
are discussed. Also the introduction of anisotropy, e.g. by regular arrays of
steps, seems to result in linearization (and to partial localization of the
plasmons normal to the steps, depending on wavelengths). In quasi-one
dimensional (1D) systems, such as arrays of gold chains on regularly stepped Si
surfaces, only the dispersion is 1D, whereas shape and slope of the dispersion
curves depend on the 2D distribution of charge within each terrace and on
coupling between wires on different terraces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05052</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Ananda</forenames></author><author><keyname>DiVincenzo</keyname><forenames>David P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Quantum Computing</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>In Topological Matter: Topological Insulators, Skyrmions and
  Majoranas, Lecture notes of the 48th IFF Spring School 2017, eds. S. Bluegel,
  Y. Mokrusov, T. Schaepers, and Y. Ando (Forschungszentrum Juelich, Key
  Technologies, Vol. 139, 2017), Sec. D7</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This set of lecture notes forms the basis of a series of lectures delivered
at the 48th IFF Spring School 2017 on Topological Matter: Topological
Insulators, Skyrmions and Majoranas at Forschungszentrum Juelich, Germany. The
first part of the lecture notes covers the basics of abelian and non-abelian
anyons and their realization in the Kitaev's honeycomb model. The second part
discusses how to perform universal quantum computation using Majorana fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05060</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Wicht</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyner</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Mercury's magnetic field in the MESSENGER era</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>40 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>in 'Planetary Geodesy and Remote Sensing', edited by Shuanggen
  Jin, pages 223-262, CRC Press, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1201/b17624-11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  MESSENGER magnetometer data show that Mercury's magnetic field is not only
exceptionally weak but also has a unique geometry. The internal field resembles
an axial dipole that is offset to the North by 20% of the planetary radius.
This implies that the axial quadrupol is particularly strong while the dipole
tilt is likely below 0.8 degree. The close proximity to the sun in combination
with the weak internal field results in a very small and highly dynamic Hermean
magnetosphere. We review the current understanding of Mercury's internal and
external magnetic field and discuss possible explanations. Classical convection
driven core dynamos have a hard time to reproduce the observations. Strong
quadrupol contributions can be promoted by different measures, but they always
go along with a large dipole tilt and generally rather small scale fields. A
stably stratified outer core region seems required to explain not only the
particular geometry but also the weakness of the Hermean magnetic field. New
interior models suggest that Mercury's core likely hosts an iron snow zone
underneath the core-mantle boundary. The positive radial sulfur gradient likely
to develop in such a zone would indeed promote stable stratification. However,
even dynamo models that include the stable layer show Mercury-like magnetic
fields only for a fraction of the total simulation time. Large scale variations
in the core-mantle boundary heat flux promise to yield more persistent results
but are not compatible with the current understanding of Mercury's lower
mantle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05111</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Spichkova</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harland</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alharthi</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author></authors><title>Online Support System for Transnational Education</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>Preprint. Paper accepted to ICEER 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The number of students who travel abroad to study or are enrolled in a
distance learning program outside their home country is growing. According to
UNESCO, such students are called internationally mobile students (IMSs) and 5
destination countries accounted for almost 50% of IMSs: United States (18%),
United Kingdom (11%), France (7%), Australia (6%), and Germany (5%).
Internationalisation of the higher education has created the so-called
borderless university, providing better opportunities for learning and
increases the human and social sustainability. In this paper, we propose an
online system to support transnational education (TNE) in Australia. This
system will consist of both an online module and quiz, and an automated
assistance module. The first part will ensure that students understand
TNE-related potential problems, such as the importance of submission deadlines,
and provide students early hints and help to avoid the TNE-related problems.
The second part will provide assistance with general issues related to studying
and living in Australia, and more specific ones tailored to a specific
institution. The ability to provide an immediate response when required will
help overcome feelings of isolation, and provide appropriate advice on matters
such as plagiarism and related issues, many of which arise from
misunderstandings due to divergent cultural backgrounds and a lack of awareness
about differences in socio-cultural environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05120</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chapman</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbative Yang-Mills Ground State in the Temporal Gauge</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, supporting derivations available from author</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Stud.: Math. Found. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40509-016-0095-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Second order corrections to the perturbative ground state wave functional and
vacuum energy of a Yang-Mills theory are calculated in the temporal gauge.
Using dimensional regularization, the concepts of renormalization and a running
coupling constant are motivated in a spatially gauge invariant way, before the
introduction of a scalar product. After definition of a scalar product, it is
shown that the renormalization constants of this approach are just those of the
Axial gauge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05140</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Antonenko</keyname><forenames>A. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charnaya</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>D. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podorozhkin</keyname><forenames>D. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uskov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bugaev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perevozchikova</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chistyakov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>J. C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchenkov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>NMR studies of the topological insulator Bi2Te3</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures,1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Te NMR studies were carried out for the bismuth telluride topological
insulator in a wide range from room temperature down to 12.5 K. The
measurements were made on a Bruker Avance 400 pulse spectrometer. The NMR
spectra were collected for the mortar and pestle powder sample and for single
crystalline stacks with orientations c parallel and perpendicular to field. The
activation energy responsible for thermal activation. The spectra for the stack
with c parallel to field showed some particular behavior below 91 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05145</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lauga</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nadal</keyname><forenames>Francois</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering instability of focused swimmers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the hallmarks of active matter is its rich nonlinear dynamics and
instabilities. Recent numerical simulations of phototactic algae showed that a
thin jet of swimmers, obtained from hydrodynamic focusing inside a Poiseuille
flow, was unstable to longitudinal perturbations with swimmers dynamically
clustering (Jibuti et al., Phys. Rev. E, 90, 2014). As a simple starting point
to understand these instabilities, we consider in this paper an initially
homogeneous one-dimensional line of aligned swimmers moving along the same
direction, and characterise its instability using both a continuum framework
and a discrete approach. In both cases, we show that hydrodynamic interactions
between the swimmers lead to instabilities in density for which we compute the
growth rate analytically. Lines of pusher-type swimmers are predicted to remain
stable while lines of pullers (such as flagellated algae) are predicted to
always be unstable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05153</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>U. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ercolani</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zannier</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ubyivovk</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhailovskii</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murata</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heun</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beltram</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Heterogeneous nucleation of catalyst-free InAs nanowires on silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 28 (2017) 065603</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa5252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the heterogeneous nucleation of catalyst-free InAs nanowires on
Si (111) substrates by chemical beam epitaxy. We show that nanowire nucleation
is enhanced by sputtering the silicon substrate with energetic particles. We
argue that particle bombardment introduces lattice defects on the silicon
surface that serve as preferential nucleation sites. The formation of these
nucleation sites can be controlled by the sputtering parameters, allowing the
control of nanowire density in a wide range. Nanowire nucleation is accompanied
by unwanted parasitic islands, but by careful choice of annealing and growth
temperature allows to strongly reduce the relative density of these islands and
to realize samples with high nanowire yield.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05163</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Treumann</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumjohann</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conductivity spectrum and dispersion relation in solar wind turbulence</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, no figures, preprint</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic turbulence in the solar wind is treated from the point of view of
electrodynamics. This can be done based on the use of Poynting's theorem
attributing all turbulent dynamics to the spectrum of turbulent conductivity.
For two directions of propagation of the turbulent fluctuations of the
electromagnetic field with respect to the mean plus external magnetic fields an
expression is constructed for the spectrum of turbulent dissipation. Use of
solar wind observations of electromagnetic power spectral densities in the
inertial subrange then allows determination of the conductivity spectrum, the
dissipative response function, in this range. It requires observations of the
complete electromagnetic spectral energy densities including electric power
spectral densities. The dissipative response function and dispersion relation
of solar wind inertial range magnetic turbulence are obtained. The dispersion
relation indicates the spatial scale decay with increasing frequency providing
independent support for the use of Taylor's hypothesis. The dissipation
function indicates an approximate shot-noise spectrum of turbulent resistivity
in the inertial range suggesting progressive structure formation in the
inertial range which hints on the presence of discrete mode turbulence and
nonlinear resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05164</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarfaraz</keyname><forenames>Wakil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madzvamuse</keyname><forenames>Anotida</forenames></author></authors><title>Classification of parameter spaces for reaction-diffusion systems on
  stationary domains</title><categories>nlin.PS math.AP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper explores the classification of parameter spaces for
reaction-diffusion systems of two chemical species on stationary domains. The
dynamics of the system are explored both in the absence and presence of
diffusion. The parameter space is fully classified in terms of the types and
stability of the uniform steady state. In the absence of diffusion the results
on the classification of parameter space are supported by simulations of the
corresponding vector-field and some trajectories around the uniform steady
state. In the presence of diffusion, the main findings are the quantitative
analysis relating the domain-size with the reaction and diffusion rates and
their corresponding influence on the dynamics of the reaction-diffusion system
when perturbed in the neighbourhood of the uniform steady state. Theoretical
predictions are supported by numerical simulations both in the presence as well
as in the absence of diffusion. Conditions on the domain size with respect to
the diffusion and reaction rates are related to the types of diffusion-driven
instabilities namely Turing, Hopf and Transcritical types of bifurcations. The
first condition is an upper bound on the area of a rectangular domain in terms
of the diffusion and reaction rates, which forbids the existence of Hopf and
Transcritical types of bifurcations, yet allowing Turing type instability to
occur. The second condition (necessary) is a lower bound on the domain size in
terms of the reaction and diffusion rates to give rise to Hopf and
Transcritical types of bifurcations as well as Turing instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05178</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Luke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galand</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kliore</keyname><forenames>Arvydas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagy</keyname><forenames>Andrew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Donoghue</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Saturn's Ionosphere</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>34 pages, 17 figures, Chapter 8 of a forthcoming multi-volume work
  entitled &quot;Saturn in the 21st Century&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This chapter summarizes our current understanding of the ionosphere of
Saturn. We give an overview of Saturn ionospheric science from the Voyager era
to the present, with a focus on the wealth of new data and discoveries enabled
by Cassini, including a massive increase in the number of electron density
altitude profiles. We discuss recent ground-based detection of the effect of
&quot;ring rain&quot; on Saturn's ionosphere, and present possible model interpretations
of the observations. Finally, we outline current model-data discrepancies and
indicate how future observations can help in advancing our understanding of the
various controlling physical and chemical processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05180</id><created>2017-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bagarello</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>$kq$-representation for pseudo-bosons, and completeness of bi-coherent
  states</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>In press in Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how the Zak $kq$-representation can be adapted to deal with
pseudo-bosons, and under which conditions. Then we use this representation to
prove completeness of a discrete set of bi-coherent states constructed by means
of pseudo-bosonic operators. The case of Riesz bi-coherent states is analyzed
in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
