<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T00:05:32Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-27" from="2017-01-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.5526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.5526</id><created>2013-05-23</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garban</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pete</keyname><forenames>G&#xe1;bor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>Oded</forenames></author></authors><title>The scaling limits of near-critical and dynamical percolation</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>72 pages, 7 figures. Slightly revised, final version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that near-critical percolation and dynamical percolation on the
triangular lattice $\eta \mathbb{T}$ have a scaling limit as the mesh $\eta \to
0$, in the &quot;quad-crossing&quot; space $\mathcal{H}$ of percolation configurations
introduced by Schramm and Smirnov. The proof essentially proceeds by
&quot;perturbing&quot; the scaling limit of the critical model, using the pivotal
measures studied in our earlier paper. Markovianity and conformal covariance of
these new limiting objects are also established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.0269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.0269</id><created>2013-09-01</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garban</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pete</keyname><forenames>G&#xe1;bor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>Oded</forenames></author></authors><title>The scaling limits of the Minimal Spanning Tree and Invasion Percolation
  in the plane</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>56 pages, 21 figures. A thoroughly revised version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the Minimal Spanning Tree and the Invasion Percolation Tree on
a version of the triangular lattice in the complex plane have unique scaling
limits, which are invariant under rotations, scalings, and, in the case of the
MST, also under translations. However, they are not expected to be conformally
invariant. We also prove some geometric properties of the limiting MST. The
topology of convergence is the space of spanning trees introduced by Aizenman,
Burchard, Newman &amp; Wilson (1999), and the proof relies on the existence and
conformal covariance of the scaling limit of the near-critical percolation
ensemble, established in our earlier works.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1694</id><created>2014-04-07</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beccaria</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Candu</keyname><forenames>Constantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaberdiel</keyname><forenames>Matthias R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The large $\mathcal{N}=4$ superconformal $\mathcal{W}_\infty$ algebra</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>37 pages; v2: reference added and typo fixed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most general large ${\cal N}=4$ superconformal ${\cal W}_{\infty}$
algebra, containing in addition to the superconformal algebra one
supermultiplet for each integer spin, is analysed in detail. It is found that
the ${\cal W}_{\infty}$ algebra is uniquely determined by the levels of the two
$\mathfrak{su}(2)$ algebras, a conclusion that holds both for the linear and
the non-linear case. We also perform various cross-checks of our analysis, and
exhibit two different types of truncations in some detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.5666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.5666</id><created>2014-04-22</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Molkaraie</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author></authors><title>An Importance Sampling Algorithm for the Ising Model with Strong
  Couplings</title><categories>stat.CO cs.IT math.IT physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Proc. 2016 Int. Zurich Seminar on Communications (IZS), Zurich,
  Switzerland, March 2-4, 2016, pp. 180-184</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of estimating the partition function of the
ferromagnetic Ising model in a consistent external magnetic field. The
estimation is done via importance sampling in the dual of the Forney factor
graph representing the model. Emphasis is on models at low temperature
(corresponding to models with strong couplings) and on models with a mixture of
strong and weak coupling parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2820</id><created>2014-09-09</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>F. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chishtie</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKeon</keyname><forenames>D. G. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effective Potential in Non-Conformal Gauge Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By using the renormalization group (RG) equation it has proved possible to
sum logarithmic corrections to quantities that arise due to quantum effects in
field theories. In particular, the effective potential V in the Standard Model
in the limit that there are no massive parameters in the classical action (the
&quot;conformal limit&quot;) has been subject to this analysis, as has the effective
potential in a scalar theory with a quartic self coupling and in massless
scalar electrodynamics. Having multiple coupling constants and/or mass
parameters in the initial action complicates this analysis, as then several
mass scales arise. We show how to address this problem by considering the
effective potential in scalar electrodynamics when the scalar field has a tree
level mass term. In addition to summing logarithmic corrections by using the RG
equation, we also consider the consequences of the condition V'(v)=0 where v is
the vacuum expectation value of the scalar. If V is expanded in powers of the
logarithms that arise, then it proves possible to show that either v is zero or
that V is independent of the scalar. (That is, either there is no spontaneous
symmetry breaking or the vacuum expectation value is not determined by
minimizing V as V is &quot;flat&quot;.)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7779</id><created>2014-11-28</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pratap</keyname><forenames>Dheeraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramakrishna</keyname><forenames>S. Anantha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollock</keyname><forenames>Justin G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iyer</keyname><forenames>Ashwin K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic Metamaterial Optical Fibers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures; Published</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express Vol. 23, Issue 7, pp. 9074-9085 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.23.009074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Internal physical structure can drastically modify the properties of
waveguides: photonic crystal fibers are able to confine light inside a hollow
air core by Bragg scattering from a periodic array of holes, while metamaterial
loaded waveguides for microwaves can support propagation at frequencies well
below cutoff. Anisotropic metamaterials assembled into cylindrically symmetric
geometries constitute light-guiding structures that support new kinds of exotic
modes. A microtube of anodized nanoporous alumina, with nanopores radially
emanating from the inner wall to the outer surface, is a manifestation of such
an anisotropic metamaterial optical fiber. The nanopores, when filled with a
plasmonic metal such as silver or gold, greatly increase the electromagnetic
anisotropy. The modal solutions in anisotropic circular waveguides can be
uncommon Bessel functions with imaginary orders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08673</id><created>2015-03-30</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Castelano</keyname><forenames>L. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fanchini</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berrada</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Open quantum system description of singlet-triplet qubits in quantum
  dots</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This version provides a description of the decoherence mechanism that
  is completely different from the published version. For a closer version see
  arXiv: 1701.03169</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 235433 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235433</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a theoretical model to describe the dissipative dynamics of
singlet-triplet (S-T_0) qubits in GaAs quantum dots. Using the concurrence
experimentally obtained as a guide, we show that each logical qubit is coupled
to its own environment because the decoherence effect can be described by
independent dephasing channels. Given the correct description of the
environment, we study the dynamics of concurrence as a function of the
temperature, the constant coupling between the system and the environment, the
preparation time, and the exchange coupling. Although the reduction of the
environment coupling constant modifies the entanglement dynamics, we
demonstrate that temperature emerges as a crucial variable and a variation of
millikelvins significantly modifies the generation of entangled states.
Furthermore, we show that the exchange coupling together with the preparation
time strongly affects the entanglement dissipative dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01035</id><created>2015-04-04</created><updated>2016-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fung</keyname><forenames>Frankie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usatyuk</keyname><forenames>Mykhaylo</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeSalvo</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chin</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable thermophoretic trapping of generic particles at low pressures</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 034102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4974489</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate levitation and three-dimensionally stable trapping of a wide
variety of particles in a vacuum chamber through the use of the thermophoretic
force in the presence of a strong temperature gradient. Typical sizes of the
trapped particles are between 10 microns and 1 mm at a pressure between 1 and
10 Torr. The trapping stability is provided by the geometry of the temperature
field, as well as the transition between the free molecule and hydrodynamic
regimes of the thermophoretic force. To quantitatively measure the
thermophoretic force, we examine the levitation heights of spherical
polyethylene spheres under various experimental conditions and determine the
temperature gradient needed to levitate the particles. A good agreement between
our experimental observations and theoretical calculations is obtained. Our
system offers a new platform to study thermophoretic phenomena and to simulate
dynamics of interacting many-body systems in a microgravity environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02981</id><created>2015-06-09</created><updated>2015-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kakodkar</keyname><forenames>Rohit R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feser</keyname><forenames>Joseph P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A framework for solving atomistic phonon-structure scattering problems
  in the frequency domain using Perfectly Matched Layer boundaries</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 118, 094301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4929780</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a numerical approach to the solution of elastic phonon scattering
problems based on a frequency domain decomposition of the atomistic equations
of motion and the use of perfectly matched layer or PML boundaries. Unlike MD
wavepacket analysis, the current approach has the ability to simulate
scattering from individual phonon modes, including wavevectors in highly
dispersive regimes. Like the Atomistic Green's Function method, the technique
reduces scattering problems to a system of linear algebraic equations via a
sparse, banded matrix. However, the use of PML boundaries enables rapid
absorption of scattered wave energies at the boundaries, and provides a simple
and inexpensive interpretation of the scattered phonon energy flux calculated
from the energy dissipation rate in the PML. The accuracy of the method is
demonstrated on connected monoatomic chains, for which an analytic solution is
known. The parameters defining the PML are found to affect the performance and
guidelines for selecting optimal parameters are given. The method is used to
study the energy transmission coefficient for connected diatomic chains over
all available wavevectors for both optical and longitudinal phonons; it is
found that when there is discontinuity between sublattices, even connected
chains of equivalent acoustic impedence have near-zero transmission coefficient
for short wavelengths. The phonon scattering cross section of an embedded
nanocylinder is calculated for a wide range of frequencies to demonstrate the
extension of the method to high dimensions. The calculations match continuum
theory for long wavelength phonons and large cylinder radii, but otherwise show
complex physics including Mie oscillations which terminate when incident phonon
frequencies exceeds the maximum available frequency in the embedded
nanocylinder, and scattering efficiencies larger than two near the Brillouin
zone edge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08393</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08393</id><created>2015-06-28</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lahoche</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oriti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization of a tensorial field theory on the homogeneous space
  SU(2)/U(1)</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>48 pages, 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the renormalization of a general field theory on the 2-sphere with
tensorial interaction and gauge invariance under the diagonal action of SU(2).
We derive the power counting for arbitrary dimension d. For the case d=4, we
prove perturbative renormalizability to all orders via multi-scale analysis,
study both the renormalised and effective perturbation series, and establish
the asymptotic freedom of the model. We also outline a general power counting
for the homogeneous space SO(D)/SO(D-1), of direct interest for quantum gravity
models in general dimensions, and point out the obstructions to the direct
generalisation of our results to these cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04921</id><created>2015-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yeung</keyname><forenames>Chi Ho</forenames></author></authors><title>Do recommender systems benefit users?</title><categories>cs.CY cs.IR cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 043401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/04/043401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recommender systems are present in many web applications to guide our
choices. They increase sales and benefit sellers, but whether they benefit
customers by providing relevant products is questionable. Here we introduce a
model to examine the benefit of recommender systems for users, and found that
recommendations from the system can be equivalent to random draws if one relies
too strongly on the system. Nevertheless, with sufficient information about
user preferences, recommendations become accurate and an abrupt transition to
this accurate regime is observed for some algorithms. On the other hand, we
found that a high accuracy evaluated by common accuracy metrics does not
necessarily correspond to a high real accuracy nor a benefit for users, which
serves as an alarm for operators and researchers of recommender systems. We
tested our model with a real dataset and observed similar behaviors. Finally, a
recommendation approach with improved accuracy is suggested. These results
imply that recommender systems can benefit users, but relying too strongly on
the system may render the system ineffective.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03837</id><created>2015-09-13</created><updated>2015-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boccato</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cenatiempo</keyname><forenames>Serena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlein</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum many-body fluctuations around nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger dynamics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>78 pages, acknowledgements added</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Henri Poincar\'e (2017) 18: 113</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-016-0513-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the many body quantum dynamics of systems of bosons interacting
through a two-body potential $N^{3\beta-1} V (N^\beta x)$, scaling with the
number of particles $N$. For $0&lt; \beta &lt; 1$, we obtain a norm-approximation of
the evolution of an appropriate class of data on the Fock space. To this end,
we need to correct the evolution of the condensate described by the
one-particle nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation by means of a fluctuation
dynamics, governed by a quadratic generator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03860</id><created>2015-10-13</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ciar&#xe1;n M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selby</keyname><forenames>John H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-order interference in extensions of quantum theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Updated in response to referee comments. 17 pages. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, Volume 47, Issue 1, pp 89--112 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0045-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum interference lies at the heart of several quantum computational
speed-ups and provides a striking example of a phenomenon with no classical
counterpart. An intriguing feature of quantum interference arises in a three
slit experiment. In this set-up, the interference pattern can be written in
terms of the two and one slit patterns obtained by blocking some of the slits.
This is in stark contrast with the standard two slit experiment, where the
interference pattern is irreducible. This was first noted by Rafael Sorkin, who
asked why quantum theory only exhibits irreducible interference in the two slit
experiment. One approach to this problem is to compare the predictions of
quantum theory to those of operationally-defined `foil' theories, in the hope
of determining whether theories exhibiting higher-order interference suffer
from pathological--or at least undesirable--features. In this paper two
proposed extensions of quantum theory are considered: the theory of Density
Cubes proposed by Dakic et al., which has been shown to exhibit irreducible
interference in the three slit set-up, and the Quartic Quantum Theory of
Zyczkowski. The theory of Density Cubes will be shown to provide an advantage
over quantum theory in a certain computational task and to posses a
well-defined mechanism which leads to the emergence of quantum theory. Despite
this, the axioms used to define Density Cubes will be shown to be insufficient
to uniquely characterise the theory. In comparison, Quartic Quantum Theory is
well-defined and we show that it exhibits irreducible interference to all
orders. This feature of the theory is argued not to be a genuine phenomenon,
but to arise from an ambiguity in the current definition of higher-order
interference. To understand why quantum theory has limited interference
therefore, a new operational definition of higher-order interference is needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03507</id><created>2015-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bochkin</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenchuk</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extension of the remotely creatable region via the local unitary
  transformation on the receiver side</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Information and Computation, Vol. 16, No. 15&amp;16 (2016)
  1349-1364</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the remote state creation via the homogeneous spin-1/2 chain and
show that the significant extension of the creatable region can be achieved
using the local unitary transformation of the so-called extended receiver (i.e.
receiver joined with the nearest node(s)). This transformation is { most}
effective in the models with all-node interactions. We consider the model with
the two-qubit sender, one-qubit receiver and two-qubit extended receiver.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01856</id><created>2015-12-06</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Mingda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Wenping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dresselhaus</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Canonical Quantization of Crystal Dislocation and Electron-Dislocation
  Scattering in an Isotropic Medium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 10 pages Supplemental materials</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 013033 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa5710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Crystal dislocations govern the plastic mechanical properties of materials
but also affect the electrical and optical properties. However, a fundamental
and quantitative quantum-mechanical theory of dislocation remains undiscovered
for decades. Here we present an exactly solvable quantum field theory of
dislocation, for both edge and screw dislocations in an isotropic medium by
introducing a new quasiparticle &quot;dislon&quot;. With this approach, the
electron-dislocation relaxation time is studied from electron self-energy which
can be reduced to classical results. Moreover, a fundamentally new type of
electron energy Friedel oscillation near dislocation core is predicted, which
can occur even with single electron at present. For the first time, the effect
of dislocations on materials' non-mechanical properties can be studied at a
full quantum field theoretical level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00121</id><created>2016-01-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>Aseema</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Mian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutt</keyname><forenames>Avik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramelow</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nussenzveig</keyname><forenames>Paulo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipson</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Interference between Transverse Spatial Waveguide Modes</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/ncomms14010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Integrated quantum optics has drastically reduced the size of table-top
optical experiments to the chip-scale, allowing for demonstrations of
large-scale quantum information processing and quantum simulation. However,
despite these advances, practical implementations of quantum photonic circuits
remain limited because they consist of large networks of waveguide
interferometers that path encode information which do not easily scale.
Increasing the dimensionality of current quantum systems using higher degrees
of freedom such as transverse spatial field distribution, polarization, time,
and frequency to encode more information per carrier will enable scalability by
simplifying quantum computational architectures, increasing security and noise
tolerance in quantum communication channels, and simulating richer quantum
phenomena. Here we demonstrate a scalable platform for photonic quantum
information processing using waveguide quantum circuit building blocks based on
the transverse spatial mode degree of freedom: mode multiplexers and mode
beamsplitters. A multimode waveguide is inherently a densely packed system of
spatial and polarization modes that can be coupled by perturbations to the
waveguide. We design a multimode waveguide consisting of three spatial modes
(per polarization) and a nanoscale grating beamsplitter to show tunable quantum
interference between pairs of photons in different transverse spatial modes. We
also cascade these structures and demonstrate NOON state interferometry within
a multimode waveguide. These devices have potential to perform transformations
on more modes and be integrated with existing architectures, providing a
scalable path to higher-dimensional Hilbert spaces and entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00453</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anninos</keyname><forenames>Dionysios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anous</keyname><forenames>Tarek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denef</keyname><forenames>Frederik</forenames></author></authors><title>Disordered Quivers and Cold Horizons</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 1 figure, v2 minor changes references added, v3 typos
  corrected and minor changes to section 4</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP-4774</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1612 (2016) 071</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2016)071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the low temperature structure of a supersymmetric quiver quantum
mechanics with randomized superpotential coefficients, treating them as
quenched disorder. These theories describe features of the low energy dynamics
of wrapped branes, which in large number backreact into extremal black holes.
We show that the low temperature theory, in the limit of a large number of
bifundamentals, exhibits a time reparametrization symmetry as well as a
specific heat linear in the temperature. Both these features resemble the
behavior of black hole horizons in the zero temperature limit. We demonstrate
similarities between the low temperature physics of the random quiver model and
a theory of large $N$ free fermions with random masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03244</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yankowitz</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>San-Jose</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>LeRoy</keyname><forenames>Brian J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure-induced commensurate stacking of graphene on boron nitride</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures and supplementary information. Updated to
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7, 13168 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13168</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combining atomically-thin van der Waals materials into heterostructures
provides a powerful path towards the creation of designer electronic devices.
The interaction strength between neighboring layers, most easily controlled
through their interlayer separation, can have significant influence on the
electronic properties of these composite materials. Here, we demonstrate
unprecedented control over interlayer interactions by locally modifying the
interlayer separation between graphene and boron nitride, which we achieve by
applying pressure with a scanning tunneling microscopy tip. For the special
case of aligned or nearly-aligned graphene on boron nitride, the graphene
lattice can stretch and compress locally to compensate for the slight lattice
mismatch between the two materials. We find that modifying the interlayer
separation directly tunes the lattice strain and induces commensurate stacking
underneath the tip. Our results motivate future studies tailoring the
electronic properties of van der Waals heterostructures by controlling the
interlayer separation of the entire device using hydrostatic pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06855</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guest</keyname><forenames>James K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Ankit</forenames></author></authors><title>3-D phononic crystals with ultra-wide band gaps</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper gradient based topology optimization (TO) is used to discover
3-D phononic structures that exhibit ultra-wide normalized all-angle all-mode
band gaps. The challenging computational task of repeated 3-D phononic
band-structure evaluations is accomplished by a combination of a fast mixed
variational eigenvalue solver and distributed Graphic Processing Unit (GPU)
parallel computations. The TO algorithm utilizes the material
distribution-based approach and a gradient-based optimizer. The design
sensitivity for the mixed variational eigenvalue problem is derived using the
adjoint method and is implemented through highly efficient vectorization
techniques. We present optimized results for two-material simple cubic (SC),
body centered cubic (BCC), and face centered cubic (FCC) crystal structures and
show that in each of these cases different initial designs converge to single
inclusion network topologies within their corresponding primitive cells. The
optimized results show that large phononic stop bands for bulk wave propagation
can be achieved at lower than close packed spherical configurations leading to
lighter unit cells. For tungsten carbide - epoxy crystals we identify all angle
all mode normalized stop bands exceeding 100%, which is larger than what is
possible with only spherical inclusions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03691</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Byung-Geel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Kook-Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Nondiffractive feature of $\gamma N\to \rho^\pm N$ with $\rho$-meson
  electromagnetic multipole moments</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B765, 221 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.10.076</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate photoproduction of charged $\rho$ off the nucleon using
$\rho(770)+\pi(140)$ Regge pole exchanges by considering the $\rho$-meson
electromagnetic multipole moments. The significance of the Ward identity at the
$\gamma\rho\rho$ vertex is emphasized for current conservation in the process.
Given $\pi$ exchange with the well-known coupling constants for $\gamma\pi\rho$
and $\pi NN$, we analyze the role of the $\rho$ exchange in the $\gamma p\to
\rho^+n$ and $\gamma n\to\rho^-p$ processes without model-dependences except
for the magnetic moment $\mu_{\rho^\pm}=\pm2.01$ and electric quadrupole moment
${\cal Q}_{\rho^\pm}=\pm0.027$ fm$^2$ taken from theoretical estimates. The
nondiffractive feature of both cross sections is reproduced with a rapid
decrease beyond the resonance region by the dominance of $\pi$ exchange over
the $\rho$\,. % Cross sections for differential and density matrix elements are
presented to compare with existing data. The parity and photon polarization
asymmetries are predicted to demonstrate the apparent roles of the $\rho$-meson
electromagnetic multipole moments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01980</id><created>2016-05-06</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>Philip B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nery</keyname><forenames>Jean Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Low temperature-semiconductor band gap thermal shifts: T^4 shifts from
  ordinary acoustic and T^2 from piezoacoustic coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures. The paper has been improved by refereeing, and
  typos have been corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035211 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At low temperature T, the experimental gap of silicon decreases as
E_g(T)=E_g(0)-AT^4. The main reason is electron-phonon renormalization. The
physics behind the T^4-power law is more complex than has been realized.
Renormalization by intraband scattering requires a careful non-adiabatic
treatment in order to correctly include acoustic phonons and avoid divergences
from piezoacoustic phonon interactions. The result is an unexpected low T term
E_g(0)+A' T^p with positive coefficient A', and power p=4 for non-piezoelectric
materials, and power p=2 for piezoelectric materials. The acoustic phonons in
piezoelectric semiconductors generate a piezoelectric field, modifying the
electron-phonon coupling. However, at higher T, when thermal acoustic phonons
of energy hbar v_s q acquire energies comparable to the electronic intermediate
state (higher than the band-edge state by hbar^2 q^2 /2m*), the low q and
higher q intraband contributions to T^p rapidly cancel, giving little thermal
effect. But there is an additional T-dependence from interband effects of
acoustic phonons. This turns out to have power law T^4 for both
non-piezoelectric and piezoelectric semiconductors. This term can have either
sign, but usually reduces the size of gaps as T increases. It arises after
cancellation of the T^2 terms that appear separately in Debye-Waller and Fan
parts of the acoustic phonon interband renormalization. The cancellation occurs
because of the acoustic sum rule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03515</id><created>2016-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Jesche</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balle</keyname><forenames>Tanita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>Kristin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geibel</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brando</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krellner</keyname><forenames>Cornelius</forenames></author></authors><title>Avoided ferromagnetic quantum critical point: Antiferromagnetic ground
  state in substituted CeFePO</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Status Solidi B 254, 1600169 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssb.201600169</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated single crystals of two substitution series
Ce(Ru$_{1-x}$Fe$_{x}$)PO and CeFe(As$_{1-y}$P$_{y}$)O in the vicinity to the
quantum critical material CeFePO by means of magnetic-susceptibility and
specific-heat measurements. We observe an antiferromagnetic ground state in the
vicinity of the quantum critical point, with pronounced metamagnetic
transitions for $H\parallel c$, which is the magnetically hard direction. Our
results verify that a ferromagnetic quantum critical point is avoided in
substituted CeFePO, because we clearly demonstrate that the ferromagnetic
ground state changes into an antiferromagnetic one, when approaching the
quantum critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07036</id><created>2016-05-23</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Fengchun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Wu</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCallum</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Sang-oh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takefuji</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jinling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lovell</keyname><forenames>Jim</forenames></author></authors><title>Progress on VLBI Ecliptic Plane Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures. IVS 2016 General Meeting Proceedings &quot;New
  Horizons with VGOS&quot;, edited by Dirk Behrend, Karen D. Baver, and Kyla L.
  Armstrong, NASA/CP-2016-219016, p351-355, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We launched the VLBI Ecliptic Plane Survey program in 2015. The goal of this
program is to find all compact sources within 7.5 degrees of the ecliptic plane
which are suitable as phase calibrators for anticipated phase referencing
observations of spacecrafts. We planned to observe a complete sample of the
sources brighter than 50 mJy at 5 GHz listed in the PMN and GB6 catalogues that
have not yet been observed with VLBI. By April 2016, eight 24-hour sessions
have been performed and processed. Among 2227 observed sources, 435 sources
were detected in three or more observations. We have also run three 8-hour
segments with VLBA for improving positions of 71 ecliptic sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09149</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Shaon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cr&#xe9;pieux</keyname><forenames>Adeline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavagna</keyname><forenames>Mireille</forenames></author></authors><title>Out-of-equilibrium Kondo Effect in a Quantum Dot: Interplay of Magnetic
  Field and Spin Accumulation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6+ pages; 3 figures; final version</comments><journal-ref>EPL 116, 57005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/57005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical study of low temperature nonequilibrium transport
through an interacting quantum dot in the presence of Zeeman magnetic field and
current injection into one of its leads. By using a self-consistent
renormalized equation of motion approach, we show that the injection of a
spin-polarized current leads to a modulation of the Zeeman splitting of the
Kondo peak in the differential conductance. We find that an appropriate amount
of spin accumulation in the lead can restore the Kondo peak by compensating the
splitting due to magnetic field. By contrast when the injected current is
spin-unpolarized, we establish that both Zeeman-split Kondo peaks are equally
shifted and the splitting remains unchanged. Our results quantitatively explain
the experimental findings reported in KOBAYASHI T. et al., Phys. Rev. Lett.
104, 036804 (2010). These features could be nicely exploited for the control
and manipulation of spin in nanoelectronic and spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01616</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baxter</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface and corner free energies of the self-dual Potts model</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures, reference 6 updated on 8 June 2016, changes to
  inversion relation method in November 2016, references added January 2017</comments><msc-class>82B20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the bulk, vertical surface, horizontal surface and corner free
energies $f_b, f_s, f'_s, f_c$ of the anisotropic self-dual $Q$-state Potts
model for $Q &gt; 4$. $f_b$ was calculated in 1973[1]. For $Q&lt;4$, $f_s, f'_s$ were
calculated in 1989[2]. Here we extend this last calculation to $Q&gt;4$ and find
agreement with the conjectures made in 2012 by Vernier and Jacobsen (VJ)[3] for
the isotropic case. All these four free energies satisfy inversion and rotation
relations. Together with some plausible analyticity assumptions, these provide
a less rigorous, but much simpler, way of determining $f_b, f_s, f'_s$. They
also imply that $f_c$ is independent of the anisotropy, being a function only
of $Q$, in which respect they resemble the order parameters of the associated
six-vertex model. Hence VJ's conjecture for $f_c$ should apply to the full
anisotropic model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03267</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-enhanced microscopy with binary-outcome photon counting</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 95, 013835 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013835</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarized light microscopy using path-entangled $N$-photon states (i.e., the
N00N states) has been demonstrated to surpass the shot-noise limit at very low
light illumination. However, the microscopy images suffer from divergence of
phase sensitivity, which inevitably reduces the image quality. Here, we show
that due to experimental imperfections, such a singularity also takes place in
the microscopy that uses twin-Fock states of light for illumination. We propose
two schemes to completely eliminate this singularity: (i) locking the phase
shift sensed by the beams at the optimal working point, by using a spatially
dependent offset phase; (ii) a combination of two binary-outcome photon
counting measurements, one with a fixed offset phase and the other without any
offset phase. Our observations remain valid for any kind of binary-outcome
measurement and may open the way for quantum-enhanced microscopy with high $N$
photon states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05186</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Otte</keyname><forenames>Adam Nepomuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Distefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Thanh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purushotham</keyname><forenames>Dhruv</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of Three High Efficiency and Blue Sensitive Silicon
  Photomultipliers</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM hep-ex</categories><comments>22 pages, 29 figures, published in Nuclear Instruments and Methods A</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.09.053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report about the optical and electrical characterization of three high
efficiency and blue sensitive Silicon photomultipliers from FBK, Hamamatsu, and
SensL. Key features of the tested devices when operated at 90% breakdown
probability are peak photon detection efficiencies between 40% and 55%,
temperature dependencies of gain and PDE that are less than 1%/$^{\circ}$C,
dark rates of $\sim$50\,kHz/mm$^{2}$ at room temperature, afterpulsing of about
2%, and direct optical crosstalk between 6% and 20%. The characteristics of all
three devices impressively demonstrate how the Silicon-photomultiplier
technology has improved over the past ten years. It is further demonstrated how
the voltage and temperature characteristics of a number of quantities can be
parameterized on the basis of physical models. The models provide a deeper
understanding of the device characteristics over a wide bias and temperature
range. They also serve as examples how producers could provide the
characteristics of their SiPMs to users. A standardized parameterization of
SiPMs would enable users to find the optimal SiPM for their application and the
operating point of SiPMs without having to perform measurements thus
significantly reducing design and development cycles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09314</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boche</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jan&#xdf;en</keyname><forenames>Gisbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaltenstadler</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement-assisted classical capacities of compound and arbitrarily
  varying quantum channels</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>Minor corrections, results unchanged, presentation updated, 21 pages,
  0 figures, accepted for publication in Quant. Inf. Proc</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider classical message transmission under entanglement assistance for
compound memoryless and arbitrarily varying quantum channels. In both cases, we
prove general coding theorems together with corresponding weak converse bounds.
In this way, we obtain single-letter characterizations of the
entanglement-assisted classical capacities for both channel models. Moreover,
we show that the entanglement-assisted classical capacity does exhibit no
strong converse property for some compound quantum channels for the average as
well as the maximal error criterion. A strong converse to the
entanglement-assisted classical capacities does hold for each arbitrarily
varying quantum channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00608</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belli</keyname><forenames>Sirio</forenames><affiliation>MPE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Newman</keyname><forenames>Andrew B.</forenames><affiliation>Carnegie</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ellis</keyname><forenames>Richard S.</forenames><affiliation>ESO and UCL and Caltech</affiliation></author></authors><title>MOSFIRE Spectroscopy of Quiescent Galaxies at 1.5 &lt; z &lt; 2.5. I -
  Evolution of Structural and Dynamical Properties</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Updated to match the published version</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 834, 18 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/1/18</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present deep near-infrared spectra for a sample of 24 quiescent galaxies
in the redshift range 1.5 &lt; z &lt; 2.5 obtained with the MOSFIRE spectrograph at
the W. M. Keck Observatory. In conjunction with a similar dataset we obtained
in the range 1 &lt; z &lt; 1.5 with the LRIS spectrograph, we analyze the kinematic
and structural properties for 80 quiescent galaxies, the largest
homogeneously-selected sample to date spanning 3 Gyr of early cosmic history.
Analysis of our Keck spectra together with measurements derived from associated
HST images reveals increasingly larger stellar velocity dispersions and smaller
sizes to redshifts beyond z~2. By classifying our sample according to Sersic
indices, we find that among disk-like systems the flatter ones show a higher
dynamical to stellar mass ratio compared to their rounder counterparts which we
interpret as evidence for a significant contribution of rotational motion. For
this subset of disk-like systems, we estimate that V/sigma, the ratio of the
circular velocity to the intrinsic velocity dispersion, is a factor of two
larger than for present-day disky quiescent galaxies. We use the velocity
dispersion measurements also to explore the redshift evolution of the dynamical
to stellar mass ratio, and to measure for the first time the physical size
growth rate of individual systems over two distinct redshift ranges, finding a
faster evolution at earlier times. We discuss the physical origin of this
time-dependent growth in size in the context of the associated reduction of the
systematic rotation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01974</id><created>2016-08-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Jaimes-Najera</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosas-Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author></authors><title>Interlace properties for the real and imaginary parts of the wave
  functions of complex-valued potentials with real spectrum</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 376 (2017) 126-144</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.10.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some general properties of the wave functions of complex-valued potentials
with real spectrum are studied. The main results are presented in a series of
lemmas, corollaries and theorems that are satisfied by the zeros of the real
and imaginary parts of the wave functions on the real line. In particular, it
is shown that such zeros interlace so that the corresponding probability
densities $\rho(x)$ are never null. We find that the profile of the imaginary
part $V_I(x)$ of a given complex-valued potential determines the number and
distribution of the maxima and minima of the related probability densities. Our
conjecture is that $V_I(x)$ must be continuous in $\mathbb R$, and that its
integral over all the real line must be equal to zero in order to get control
on the distribution of the maxima and minima of $\rho(x)$. The applicability of
these results is shown by solving the eigenvalue equation of different complex
potentials, these last being either ${\cal PT}$-symmetric or not invariant
under the ${\cal PT}$-transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03400</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>L&#xe9;vay</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szab&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Zsolt</forenames></author></authors><title>Mermin pentagrams arising from Veldkamp lines for three qubits</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>28 pages, 10 figures. Will be published in Journal of Physics A:
  Mathematical and Theoretical, Volume 50, Number 9</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa56aa</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the geometry of the space of Mermin pentagrams, objects that are
used to rule out the existence of noncontextual hidden variable theories as
alternatives to quantum theory. It is shown that this space of 12096 possible
pentagrams is organized into 1008 families, with each family containing a
&quot;double six&quot; of pentagrams. The 1008 families are connected to a special set of
Veldkamp lines in the Veldkamp space of three qubits an object well-known to
finite geometers but has only been introduced to physics recently. Due to the
transitive action of the symplectic group on this set of Veldkamp lines it is
enough to study only one &quot;canonical&quot; double six configuration of pentagrams. We
prove that the geometry of this double-six configuration is encapsulated in the
weight diagram of the 20 dimensional irreducible representation of the group
$SU(6)$. As an interesting by-product of our approach we show that Mermin
pentagrams and a class of Mermin squares labelled by three qubit Pauli
operators are inherently related. We conjecture that by studying the
representation theoretic content of other Veldkamp lines of the Veldkamp space
for $N$-qubits makes it possible to find new contextual configurations in a
systematic manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03432</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Hobbiger</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drachta</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreil</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>Helga M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenological plasmon broadening and relation to the dispersion</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Solid State Communications, 252, 54 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2017.01.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pragmatic ways of including lifetime broadening of collective modes in the
electron liquid are critically compared. Special focus lies on the impact of
the damping parameter onto the dispersion. It is quantitatively exemplified for
the two-dimensional case, for both, the charge (`sheet'-)plasmon and the
spin-density plasmon. The predicted deviations fall within the resolution
limits of advanced techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04284</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ayala</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominguez</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loewe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite Temperature QCD Sum Rules: a Review</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>Minor typos corrected. To be published in the review section of
  Advances in High Energy Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The method of QCD sum rules at finite temperature is reviewed, with emphasis
on recent results. These include predictions for the survival of charmonium and
bottonium states, at and beyond the critical temperature for de-confinement, as
later confirmed by lattice QCD simulations. Also included are determinations in
the light-quark vector and axial-vector channels, allowing to analyse the
Weinberg sum rules, and predict the dimuon spectrum in heavy ion collisions in
the region of the rho-meson. Also in this sector, the determination of the
temperature behaviour of the up-down quark mass, together with the pion decay
constant, will be described. Finally, an extension of the QCD sum rule method
to incorporate finite baryon chemical potential is reviewed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05208</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Herr</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devitt</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice Surgery Translation for Quantum Computation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>code repository: https://github.com/herr-d/LS_translation</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 1 013034 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa5709</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we outline a method for a compiler to translate any non fault
tolerant quantum circuit to the geometric representation of the lattice surgery
error-correcting code using inherent merge and split operations. Since the
efficiency of state distillation procedures has not yet been investigated in
the lattice surgery model, their translation is given as an example using the
proposed method. The resource requirements seem comparable to the defect-based
state distillation process, but modularity and eventual implementability allow
the lattice surgery model to be an interesting alternative to braiding.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08191</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zare</keyname><forenames>Moslem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rameshti</keyname><forenames>Babak Zare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghamsari</keyname><forenames>Farnood G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asgari</keyname><forenames>Reza</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric transport in monolayer phosphorene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045422 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045422</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the generalized Boltzmann theory to describe thermoelectric
transport properties of monolayer phosphorene in the presence of short- and
long-range charged impurity interactions. First, we propose a low-energy
Hamiltonian to explore the accurate electronic band structure of phosphorene in
comparison with those results obtained by density-functional simulations. We
explain the effect of the coupling between the conduction and valence bands on
the thermoelectric properties. We show that the electric conductivity of
phosphorene is highly anisotropic, while the Seebeck coefficient and figure of
merit, without being influenced via either the presence or absence of the
coupling term, are nearly isotropic. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the
conductivity for the $n$ type of doping is more influenced by the coupling term
than that of the $p$ type. Along with thermopower sign change, profound
thermoelectric effects can be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00948</id><created>2016-09-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Grebenkov</keyname><forenames>Denis S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshanin</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusive escape through a narrow opening: new insights into a classic
  problem</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures, Supplemental Materials</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 19, 2723 - 2739 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP06102H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the mean first exit time $T_{\ve}$ of a particle diffusing in a
circular or a spherical micro-domain with an impenetrable confining boundary
containing a small escape window (EW) of an angular size $\ve$. Focusing on the
effects of an energy/entropy barrier at the EW, and of the long-range
interactions (LRI) with the boundary on the diffusive search for the EW, we
develop a self-consistent approximation to derive for $T_{\ve}$ a general
expression, akin to the celebrated Collins-Kimball relation in chemical
kinetics and accounting for both rate-controlling factors in an explicit way.
Our analysis reveals that the barrier-induced contribution to $T_{\ve}$ is the
dominant one in the limit $\ve \to 0$, implying that the narrow escape problem
is not &quot;diffusion-limited&quot; but rather &quot;barrier-limited&quot;. We present the
small-$\ve$ expansion for $T_{\ve}$, in which the coefficients in front of the
leading terms are expressed via some integrals and derivatives of the LRI
potential. On example of a triangular-well potential, we show that $T_{\ve}$ is
non-monotonic with respect to the extent of the attractive LRI, being minimal
for the ones having an intermediate extent, neither too concentrated on the
boundary nor penetrating too deeply into the bulk. Our analytical predictions
are in a good agreement with the numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02683</id><created>2016-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Harukuni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyazaki</keyname><forenames>Kunimasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biroli</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author></authors><title>The Fredrickson-Andersen model with random pinning on Bethe lattices and
  its MCT transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/56004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dynamics of the randomly pinned Fredrickson-Andersen model
on the Bethe lattice. We find a line of random pinning dynamical transitions
whose dynamical critical properties are in the same universality class of the
$A_2$ and $A_3$ transitions of Mode Coupling Theory. The $A_3$ behavior appears
at the terminal point, where the relaxation becomes logarithmic and the
relaxation time diverges exponentially. We explain the critical behavior in
terms of self-induced disorder and avalanches, strengthening the relationship
discussed in recent works between glassy dynamics and Random Field Ising Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03788</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pagel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvermann</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fehske</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic Stark effect, light emission, and entanglement generation in a
  laser-driven quantum optical system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013825 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013825</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the emission spectra, the Glauber $g^{(2)}$ function, and the
entanglement of formation for a few two-level emitters coupled to a single
cavity mode and subject to an external laser-excitation. To evaluate these
quantities we couple the system to environmental degrees of freedom which leads
to dissipative dynamics. Because of the periodic time-dependence of the system
Hamiltonian, the coefficients of the (Markovian) master equation are constant
if Floquet states are used as the computational basis. Studying the emission
spectra we show that the dynamic Stark effect, i.e., the shift of spectral
lines, first appears in the second order of the laser intensity. For the
Glauber function, we find clearly distinguished parameter regimes of super- and
sub-Poissonian light emission and explain the additional features appearing for
finite laser intensity in terms of the quasienergy spectrum of the driven
emitter-cavity system. Finally, we analyze the temperature and emitter-cavity
coupling regimes where entanglement among the emitters is generated, and show
that the laser-excitation leads to a decrease of entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04979</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Husdal</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>On Effective Degrees of Freedom in the Early Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Galaxies, 4(4), 78 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/galaxies4040078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the effective degrees of freedom in the early universe, from
before the electroweak scale at a few femtoseconds after the Big Bang, until
the last positrons disappeared a few minutes later. We first look at the
established concepts of effective degrees of freedom for energy density,
pressure and entropy density, and introduce effective degrees of freedom for
number density as well. We discuss what happens with particle species as their
temperature cools down from relativistic to semi- and non-relativistic
temperatures, and then annihilates completely. This will affect the pressure as
well as the entropy per particle. We also look at the transition from a
quark-gluon plasma to a hadron gas. Using a list of known hadrons, we use a
&quot;cross-over&quot; temperature of 214 MeV where the effective degrees of freedom for
a quark-gluon plasma equals that of a hadron gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05432</id><created>2016-09-18</created><updated>2017-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Giacchini</keyname><forenames>Breno L.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the cancellation of Newtonian singularities in higher-derivative
  gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 1 figure. References added, typos corrected, some parts
  rewritten. Accepted for publication in Phys. Lett. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 766, 306-311 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently there has been a growing interest in quantum gravity theories with
more than four derivatives, including both their quantum and classical aspects.
In this work we extend the recent results concerning the non-singularity of the
modified Newtonian potential to the most relevant case in which the propagator
has complex poles. The model we consider is Einstein-Hilbert action augmented
by curvature-squared higher-derivative terms which contain polynomials on the
d'Alembert operator. We show that the classical potential of these theories is
a real quantity and it is regular at the origin disregard the (complex or real)
nature or the multiplicity of the massive poles. The expression for the
potential is explicitly derived for some interesting particular cases. Finally,
the issue of the mechanism behind the cancellation of the singularity is
discussed; specifically we argue that the regularity of the potential can hold
even if the number of massive tensor modes and scalar ones is not the same.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06263</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2017-01-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Steffen</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames><affiliation>Center for Electronic Correlations and Magnetism, EP VI, Institute of Physics, University of Augsburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fr&#xe9;sard</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames><affiliation>Normandie Universit&#xe9;, ENSICAEN, UNICAEN, CNRS, CRISMAT, Caen, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kopp</keyname><forenames>Thilo</forenames><affiliation>Center for Electronic Correlations and Magnetism, EP VI, Institute of Physics, University of Augsburg, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Capacitance and compressibility of heterostructures with strong
  electronic correlations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 035143 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong electronic correlations related to a repulsive local interaction
suppress the electronic compressibility in a single-band model, and the
capacitance of a corresponding metallic film is directly related to its
electronic compressibility. Both statements may be altered significantly when
two extensions to the system are implemented which we investigate here: (i) we
introduce an attractive nearest-neighbor interaction $V$ as antagonist to the
repulsive on-site repulsion $U$, and (ii) we consider nano-structured
multilayers (heterostructures) assembled from two-dimensional layers of these
systems. We determine the respective total compressibility $\kappa$ and
capacitance $C$ of the heterostructures within a strong coupling evaluation,
which builds on a Kotliar-Ruckenstein slave-boson technique. Whereas the
capacitance $C(n)$ for electronic densities $n$ close to half-filling is
suppressed---illustrated by a correlation induced dip in $C(n)$---it may be
appreciably enhanced close to a van Hove singularity. Moreover, we show that
the capacitance may be a non-monotonic function of $U$ close to half-filling
for both attractive and repulsive $V$. The compressibility $\kappa$ can differ
from $C$ substantially, as $\kappa$ is very sensitive to internal electrostatic
energies which in turn depend on the specific set-up of the heterostructure. In
particular, we show that a capacitor with a polar dielectric has a smaller
electronic compressibility and is more stable against phase separation than a
standard non-polar capacitor with the same capacitance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07931</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anghel</keyname><forenames>Dragos-Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>New phenomenology from an old theory--new equilibrium states in the BCS
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I analyze the low temperature limit of the BCS theory of s-wave single-band
superconductors, when the attraction band may be asymmetric with respect to the
chemical potential. I discuss equilibrium systems, taking consistently into
account the variation of the energy and of the total number of particles with
the populations of the quasiparticle energy levels. I show that the equation
for the energy gap has two solutions, one of which is stable and the other one
is metastable. When the chemical potential is the center of the attraction band
(the standard BCS assumption), the energy gap in the stable solution is
$\Delta_0$, whereas in the metastable one is $\Delta_0/3$. If the chemical
potential is not in the center of the attraction band, then a quasiparticle
imbalance appears. If the absolute value of the difference between the chemical
potential and center of the attraction band is bigger than $2\Delta_0$, then
the superconducting energy gap cannot be formed. If the number of particles is
conserved and the attraction band is asymmetric, then the stable solution is
unphysical and only metastable solutions are realized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07993</id><created>2016-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n-Luengo</keyname><forenames>Aitana Tarazaga</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;stenbauer</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winkler</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonanni</keyname><forenames>Alberta</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of processing on the stability of molybdenum oxide ultra-thin
  films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, Appendix included</comments><journal-ref>AIP Adv. 7 (2017) 015034</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4974880</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects of wet chemical processing conventionally employed in device
fabrication standards are systematically studied on molybdenum oxide (MoOx)
ultra-thin films. We have combined x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS),
angle resolved XPS and x-ray reflectivity techniques to provide deep insights
into the changes in composition, structure and electronic states upon treatment
of films with different initial stoichiometry prepared by reactive sputtering.
Our results show significant reduction effects associated with the development
of gap states in MoOx, as well as changes in the composition, density and
structure of the films, systematically correlated with the initial oxidation
state of Mo.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00553</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lagos</keyname><forenames>Macarena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Pedro G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A general theory of linear cosmological perturbations: bimetric theories</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Published version with extra comments in conclusion</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/01/047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We implement the method developed in [1] to construct the most general
parametrised action for linear cosmological perturbations of bimetric theories
of gravity. Specifically, we consider perturbations around a homogeneous and
isotropic background, and identify the complete form of the action invariant
under diffeomorphism transformations, as well as the number of free parameters
characterising this cosmological class of theories. We discuss, in detail, the
case without derivative interactions, and compare our results with those found
in massive bigravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02087</id><created>2016-10-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Frauca</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvaro Mozota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorkin</keyname><forenames>Rafael Dolnick</forenames></author></authors><title>How to Measure the Quantum Measure</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Int J Theor Phys (2017) 56: 232-258</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-016-3181-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The histories-based framework of Quantum Measure Theory assigns a generalized
probability or measure $\mu(E)$ to every (suitably regular) set $E$ of
histories. Even though $\mu(E)$ cannot in general be interpreted as the
expectation value of a selfadjoint operator (or POVM), we describe an
arrangement which makes it possible to determine $\mu(E)$ experimentally for
any desired $E$. Taking, for simplicity, the system in question to be a
particle passing through a series of Stern-Gerlach devices or beam-splitters,
we show how to couple a set of ancillas to it, and then to perform on them a
suitable unitary transformation followed by a final measurement, such that the
probability of a final outcome of &quot;yes&quot; is related to $\mu(E)$ by a known
factor of proportionality. Finally, we discuss in what sense a positive outcome
of the final measurement should count as a minimally disturbing verification
that the microscopic event $E$ actually happened.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03057</id><created>2016-10-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmelzer</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>About a &quot;nonlocal&quot; local model considered by L. Vervoort, and the
  necessity to distinguish locality from Einstein locality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Accepted by Foundations of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Found. Phys. 47(1), 113-116 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0046-3</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  L. Vervoort [arxiv:1406.0901] claims to have found a model which &quot;can violate
the Bell inequality and reproduce the quantum statistics, even if it is based
on local dynamics only&quot;. This claim is false. The proposed model contains
global elements. The physics behind the model is local, but would not allow the
explanation of violations of Bell inequalities for space-like separated events,
if superluminal causal influences are forbidden. To use it for this purpose,
one has to introduce a preferred frame where information can be send faster
than light.
  As a cause of the misunderstanding we identify the unfortunate convention to
use &quot;local&quot; as a synonym for Einstein-local, so that theories which are local
in every physically relevant sense have to be named &quot;non-local&quot;, and argue that
this convention should be abandoned.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03882</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brevik</keyname><forenames>Iver</forenames></author></authors><title>Minkowski Momentum Resulting from a Vacuum-Medium Mapping Procedure, and
  a Brief Review of Minkowski Momentum Experiments</title><categories>quant-ph physics.class-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>18 pages, no figures. Minor changes; a reference added</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 377 (2017) 10-21</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.01.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A discussion is given on the interpretation and physical importance of the
Minkowski momentum in macroscopic electrodynamics (essential for the
Abraham-Minkowski problem). We focus on the following two facets: (1) Adopting
a simple dielectric model where the refractive index $n$ is constant, we
demonstrate by means of a mapping procedure how the electromagnetic field in a
medium can be mapped into a corresponding field in vacuum. This mapping was
presented many years ago [I. Brevik and B. Lautrup, Mat. Fys. Medd. Dan. Vid.
Selsk {\bf 38}(1), 1 (1970)], but is apparently not well known. A
characteristic property of this procedure is that it shows how natural the
Minkowski energy-momentum tensor fits into the canonical formalism. Especially
the spacelike character of the electromagnetic total four-momentum for a
radiation field (implying negative electromagnetic energy in some inertial
frames), so strikingly demonstrated in the Cherenkov effect, is worth
attention. (2) Our second objective is to give a critical analysis of some
recent experiments on electromagnetic momentum. Care must here be taken in the
interpretations: it is easy to be misled and conclude that an experiment is
important for the energy-momentum problem, while what is demonstrated
experimentally is merely the action of the Abraham-Minkowski force acting in
surface layers or inhomogeneous regions. The Abraham-Minkowski force is common
for the two energy-momentum tensors and carries no information about field
momentum. As a final item, we propose an experiment that might show the
existence of the Abraham force at high frequencies. This would eventually be a
welcome optical analogue to the classic low-frequency 1975 Lahoz-Walker
experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04240</id><created>2016-10-13</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>T&#xe1;vora</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres-Herrera</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Lea F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Power-law decay exponents: a dynamical criterion for predicting
  thermalization</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From the analysis of the relaxation process of isolated lattice many-body
quantum systems quenched far from equilibrium, we deduce a criterion for
predicting when they are certain to thermalize. It is based on the algebraic
behavior $\propto t^{-\gamma}$ of the survival probability at long times. We
show that the value of the power-law exponent $\gamma$ depends on the shape and
filling of the weighted energy distribution of the initial state. Two scenarios
are explored in details: $\gamma \ge 2$ and $\gamma &lt;1$. Exponents $\gamma \ge
2$ imply that the energy distribution of the initial state is ergodically
filled and the eigenstates are uncorrelated, so thermalization is guaranteed to
happen. In this case, the power-law behavior is caused by bounds in the energy
spectrum. Decays with $\gamma &lt; 1$ emerge when the energy eigenstates are
correlated and signal lack of ergodicity. They are typical of systems
undergoing localization due to strong onsite disorder and are found also in
clean integrable systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05266</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duque</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espa&#xf1;ol</keyname><forenames>Pep</forenames></author></authors><title>Rapid convergence for simulations that project from particles onto a
  fixed mesh</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Draft article</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The advantage of particle Lagrangian methods in computational fluid dynamics
is that advection is accurately modeled. However, this complicates the
calculation of space derivatives. If a mesh is employed, it must be updated at
each time step. On the other hand, fixed mesh, Eulerian, formulations benefit
from the mesh being defined at the beginning of the simulation, but feature
non-linear advection terms. It therefore seems natural to combine the two
approaches, using a fixed mesh to perform calculations related to space
derivatives, and using the particles to advect the information with time. The
idea of combining Lagrangian particles and a fixed mesh goes back to
Particle-in-Cell methods, and is here considered within the context of the
finite element method (FEM) for the fixed mesh, and the particle FEM (pFEM) for
the particles.
  Our results, in agreement with recent works, show that interpolation
(&quot;projection&quot;) errors, especially from particles to mesh, are the culprits of
slow convergence of the method if standard, linear, FEs, are employed. By
including quadratically consistent shape functions for the particles, the rate
of convergence is restored to values competitive with purely Lagrangian
simulations.
  The procedure is validated on the Zalesak's disk problem, the Taylor-Green
vortex sheet flow, and the Rayleigh-Taylor instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09642</id><created>2016-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmelzer</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>About a &quot;contextuality loophole&quot; in Bell's theorem claimed to exist by
  Nieuwenhuizen</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>accepted by Foundations of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Found. Phys. 47(1), 117-119 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0047-2</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Nieuwenhuizen argued that there exists some &quot;contextuality loophole&quot; in
Bell's theorem. This claim is unjustified. In Bell's theorem non-contextuality
is not presupposed but derived from Einstein causality using the EPR argument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03672</id><created>2016-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiemann</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichl</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xe4;lt</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietsche</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegscheider</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>Improvement of the transport properties of a high-mobility electron
  system by intentional parallel conductance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 110, 042106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4975055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a gating scheme to separate even strong parallel conductance from
the magneto-transport signatures and properties of a two-dimensional electron
system. By varying the electron density in the parallel conducting layer, we
can study the impact of mobile charge carriers in the vicinity of the dopant
layer on the properties of the two-dimensional electron system. It is found
that the parallel conducting layer is indeed capable to screen the remote
ionized impurity potential fluctuations responsible for the fragility of
fractional quantum Hall states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05832</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boero</keyname><forenames>Ezequiel F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreschi</keyname><forenames>Osvaldo M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical models for the study of astrophysical systems with
  spheroidal symmetry imbedded in a standard cosmology: The case of cosmic
  voids</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a class of general prolate and oblate spheroidal spacetimes for
the description of cosmic structures in the Universe. They are exact geometries
which represent, in an appropriated way, the imbedding of spheroidal
matter-energy distributions within a standard cosmological scenario, and
therefore they allow for an improved description of a wider class of
astrophysical systems from a more accurate point of view. These spacetimes can
be used to describe overdensity or underdensity regions; in this work we
consider the last case, that is, the description of cosmic voids. We introduce
and study a model of void which is a generalization of a simpler one in
spherical symmetry and we use it for the calculation of weak lensing optical
scalars as a non-trivial and interesting application. In this particular
example we show the rich observable features that can be found in such models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07997</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Runzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Go</keyname><forenames>Ara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millis</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron interactions, spin-orbit coupling, intersite correlations in
  pyrochlore iridates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045133 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045133</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform combined density functional and dynamical mean-field calculations
to study the pyrochlore iridates Lu$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$, Y$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$ and
Eu$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$. Both single-site and cluster dynamical mean-field
calculations are performed and spin-orbit coupling is included. Paramagnetic
metallic phases, antiferromagnetic metallic phases with tilted Weyl cones and
antiferromagnetic insulating phases are found. The magnetic phases display
all-in/all-out magnetic ordering, consistent with previous studies. Unusually
for electronically three dimensional materials, the single-site dynamical
mean-field approximation fails to reproduce qualitative material trends,
predicting in particular that the paramagnetic phase properties of
Y$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$ and Eu$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$ are almost identical, although in
experiments the Y compound has a much higher resistance than the Eu compound.
This qualitative failure is attributed to the importance of intersite magnetic
correlations in the physics of these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08924</id><created>2016-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Alam</keyname><forenames>Jahrul M</forenames></author></authors><title>A wavelet based numerical simulation technique for the two-phase flow
  using the phase field method</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures, submitted to Computers and Fluids</comments><journal-ref>Computers and Fluids, 146, pages 143-153, 26 March 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.compfluid.2017.01.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In multiphase flow phenomena, bubbles and droplets are advected, deformed,
break up into smaller ones, and coalesce with each other. A primary challenge
of classical computational fluid dynamics (CFD) methods for such flows is to
effectively describe a transition zone between phases across which physical
properties vary steeply but continuously. Based on the van der Waals theory,
Allen-Cahn phase field method describes the face-to-face existence of two
fluids with a free-energy functional of mass density or molar concentration,
without imposing topological constraints on interface as phase boundary. In
this article, a CFD simulation methodology is described by solving the
Allen-Cahn-Navier-Stokes equations using a wavelet collocation method. The
second order temporal accuracy is verified by simulating a moving sharp
interface. The average terminal velocity of a rising gas bubble in a liquid
that is computed by the present method has agreed with that computed by a
laboratory experiment. The calculation of the surface tension force by the
present method also shows an excellent agreement with what was obtained by an
experiment. The up-welling and down-welling disturbances in a Rayleigh-Taylor
instability are computed and compared with that from a reference numerical
simulation. These results show that the wavelet based phase-field method is an
efficient CFD simulation technique for gas-liquid or liquid-liquid flows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00232</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fabr&#xe8;ges</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menelle</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauvin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwindling</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Letourneau</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchix</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alba-Simionesco</keyname><forenames>Christiane</forenames></author></authors><title>Performances of Neutron Scattering Spectrometers on a Compact Neutron
  Source</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  There is currently a big effort put into the operation and construction of
world class neutron scattering facilities (SNS and SNS-TS2 in the US, J-PARC in
Japan, ESS in Europe, CSS in China, PIK in Russia). On the other hand, there
exists a network of smaller neutron scattering facilities which play a key role
in creating a large neutron scattering community who is able to efficiently use
the existing facilities. With the foreseen closure of the ageing nuclear
research reactors, especially in Europe there is a risk of seeing a shrinking
of the community who would then be able to use efficiently the world class
facilities. There is thus a reflection being conducted in several countries for
the replacement of smaller research reactors with low energy accelerator based
sources. We consider here a reference design for a compact neutron source based
on existing accelerator components. We estimate the performances of various
types of neutron scattering instruments built around such a source. The results
suggest that nowadays state of the art neutron scattering experiments could be
successfully performed on such a compact source and that it is thus a viable
replacement solution for neutron research reactors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00237</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Menelle</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prunes</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Homatter</keyname><forenames>Benoit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Annigh&#xf6;fer</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porcher</keyname><forenames>Florence</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alba-Simionesco</keyname><forenames>Christiane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauvin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwindling</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Letourneau</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchix</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Ngoc-Hoang</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrons production on the IPHI accelerator for the validation of the
  design of the compact neutron source SONATE</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We aim at building an accelerator based compact neutron source which would
provide a thermal neutron flux on the order of 4E12 n.s-1.cm-2.sr-1. Such
brilliance would put compact neutron sources on par with existing medium flux
neutron research reactors. We performed the first neutron production tests on
the IPHI proton accelerator at Saclay. The neutron fluxes were measured using
gold foil activation and 3He detectors. The measured fluxes were compared with
MCNP and GEANT4 Monte Carlo simulations in which the whole experimental setup
was modelled. There is a good agreement between the experimental measurements
and the Monte-Carlo simulations. The available modelling tools will allow us to
optimize the whole Target Moderator Reflector assembly together with the
neutron scattering spectrometer geometries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00871</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Torcheboeuf</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchs</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kundermann</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portuondo-Campa</keyname><forenames>Erwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benn&#xe8;s</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lecomte</keyname><forenames>Steve</forenames></author></authors><title>Repetition rate stabilization of an optical frequency comb based on
  solid-state laser technology with an intra-cavity electro-optic modulator</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><doi>10.1364/OE.25.002215</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The repetition rate stabilization of an optical frequency comb based on
diode-pumped solid-state laser technology is demonstrated using an intra-cavity
electro-optic modulator. The large feedback bandwidth of such modulators allows
disciplining the comb repetition rate on a cavity-stabilized continuous-wave
laser with a locking bandwidth up to 700 kHz. This surpasses what can be
achieved with any other type of actuator reported so far. An in-loop integrated
phase noise of 133 mrad has been measured and the PM-to-AM coupling of the
electro-optic modulator has been investigated as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01451</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Benet</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jorba</keyname><forenames>&#xc0;ngel</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple model for the location of Saturn's F ring</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>37 pages, 17 figures (png). Accepted for publication in Icarus</comments><journal-ref>Icarus 285 (2017), 224-236</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.12.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce a simplified model to understand the location of
Saturn's F ring. The model is a planar restricted five-body problem defined by
the gravitational field of Saturn, including its second zonal harmonic $J_2$,
the shepherd moons Prometheus and Pandora, and Titan. We compute accurate
long-time numerical integrations of (about 2.5 million) non-interacting
test-particles initially located in the region between the orbits of Prometheus
and Pandora, and address whether they escape or remain trapped in this region.
We obtain a wide region of initial conditions of the test particles that remain
confined. We consider a dynamical stability indicator for the test particles'
motion defined by computing the ratio of the standard deviation over the
average value of relevant dynamical quantities, in particular, for the
mean-motion and the semi-major axis. This indicator separates clearly a subset
of trapped initial conditions that appear as very localized stripes in the
initial semi-major axis and eccentricity space for the most stable orbits.
Retaining only these test particles, we obtain a narrow eccentric ring which
displays sharp edges and collective alignment. The semi-major axis of the
accumulation stripes of the stable ring-particles can be associated with
resonances, mostly involving Prometheus' outer Lindblad and co-rotation
resonances, but not exclusively. Pandora's inner Lindblad and co-rotation
resonances as well as low-order three-body resonances typically coincide with
gaps, i.e., regions of instabilities. Comparison of our results with the
nominal data for the F ring shows some correspondence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08332</id><created>2016-12-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Yonemitsu</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoinduced Enhancement of Anisotropic Charge Correlations on
  Triangular Lattices with Trimers</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 024711 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.024711</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To explore nontrivial photoinduced modulations of charge correlations, we
theoretically study photoinduced dynamics in quarter-filled extended Hubbard
models with competing intersite repulsive interactions on triangular lattices
with trimers, where the end points are crystallographically equivalent. The
exact diagonalization method is used and the time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger
equation is numerically solved during and after photoexcitation. Time-averaged
double occupancy and intersite density-density correlations can be interpreted
as due to effective on-site and intersite repulsive interactions, respectively,
relative to transfer energies. In the case where the intersite repulsive
interactions compete with each other, the anisotropy of their effective
interactions can be enhanced with the help of the trimers, irrespective of
whether the trimers are linear or bent. In particular, in the case where the
arrangement of the trimers is close to that in
$\alpha$-(bis[ethylenedithio]-tetrathiafulvalene)$_2$I$_3$
[$\alpha$-(BEDT-TTF)$_2$I$_3$] in the metallic phase, the effective on-site
repulsion is enhanced relative to the transfer energies. The relevance of this
theoretical finding to the experimentally observed optical freezing of charge
motion is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08893</id><created>2016-12-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Junjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Yafei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kunhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phase transition from trigonal warping in van der Waals
  multilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4+1 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 045424 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.045424</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  In van der Waals multilayers of triangular lattice, trigonal warping occurs
universally due to the interlayer hopping. We theoretically investigate the
effect of trigonal warping upon distinctive topological phases, like the
quantum anomalous Hall effect (QAHE) and the quantum valley Hall effect (QVHE).
Taking Bernal-stacked bilayer graphene as an example, we find that the trigonal
warping plays a crucial role in the formation of QAHE in large exchange field
and/or interlayer potential difference by inducing extra band inversion points
at momentum further away from high symmetric point. The presence of trigonal
warping shrinks the phase space of QAHE and QVHE, leading to the emergence of
valley-polarized QAHE with high Chern numbers ranging from $ \mathcal{C}=-7 $
to $ 7 $. These results suggest that the universal trigonal warping may play
important role when the Bloch states at momentum away from high-symmetric
points are involved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00245</id><created>2017-01-01</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Olesen</keyname><forenames>Poul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Abelian bootstrap of primordial magnetism</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages. Magnetic energy formula for the flat expanding universe
  added. Misprint corrected. Some clarifying remarks on energy minimization
  added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We point out that a primordial magnetic field can be generated in the
electroweak phase transition by a non-Abelian bootstrap, where the field is
generated by currents of W's, which in turn are extracted from the vacuum by
the magnetic field. This magnetic field is produced as a vortex condensate at
the electroweak phase transition. It becomes stringy as a consequence of the
dynamical evolution due to magnetohydrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00527</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Basti</keyname><forenames>Gianfranco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capolupo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitiello</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Field Theory and Coalgebraic Logic in Theoretical Computer
  Science</title><categories>quant-ph cs.LO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we suggest that in the framework of the Category Theory it is
possible to demonstrate the mathematical and logical \textit{dual equivalence}
between the category of the $q$-deformed Hopf Coalgebras and the category of
the $q$-deformed Hopf Algebras in QFT, interpreted as a thermal field theory.
Each pair algebra-coalgebra characterizes, indeed, a QFT system and its
mirroring thermal bath, respectively, so to model dissipative quantum systems
persistently in far-from-equilibrium conditions, with an evident significance
also for biological sciences. The $q$-deformed Hopf Coalgebras and the
$q$-deformed Hopf Algebras constitute two dual categories because characterized
by the same functor $T$, related with the Bogoliubov transform, and by its
contravariant application $T^{op}$, respectively. The \textit{q}-deformation
parameter, indeed, is related to the Bogoliubov angle, and it is effectively a
thermal parameter. Therefore, the different values of $q$ identify univocally,
and then label, the vacua appearing in the foliation process of the quantum
vacuum. This means that, in the framework of Universal Coalgebra, as general
theory of dynamic and computing systems (&quot;labelled state-transition systems&quot;),
the so labelled infinitely many quantum vacua can be interpreted as the Final
Coalgebra of an &quot;Infinite State Black-Box Machine&quot;. All this opens the way to
the possibility of designing a new class of universal quantum computing
architectures based on this coalgebraic formulation of QFT, as its ability of
naturally generating a Fibonacci progression demonstrates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00949</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Harshman</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identical Wells, Symmetry Breaking, and the Near-Unitary Limit</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure, accepted in Few-Body Systems</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst (2017) 58: 41</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-017-1214-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Energy level splitting from the unitary limit of contact interactions to the
near unitary limit for a few identical atoms in an effectively one-dimensional
well can be understood as an example of symmetry breaking. At the unitary limit
in addition to particle permutation symmetry there is a larger symmetry
corresponding to exchanging the $N!$ possible orderings of $N$ particles. In
the near unitary limit, this larger symmetry is broken, and different shapes of
traps break the symmetry to different degrees. This brief note exploits these
symmetries to present a useful, geometric analogy with graph theory and build
an algebraic framework for calculating energy splitting in the near unitary
limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01657</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekanthan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>Kenneth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Terence</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samid</keyname><forenames>Nader Abu El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Alexander D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Eleuterio</keyname><forenames>Gabriele M. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Autonomous Multirobot Excavation for Lunar Applications</title><categories>cs.RO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>38 pages, 32 figures, archive of journal article, in Robotica, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a control approach called Artificial Neural Tissue (ANT) is
applied to multirobot excavation for lunar base preparation tasks including
clearing landing pads and burying of habitat modules. We show for the first
time, a team of autonomous robots excavating a terrain to match a given 3D
blueprint. Constructing mounds around landing pads will provide physical
shielding from debris during launch/landing. Burying a human habitat modules
under 0.5 m of lunar regolith is expected to provide both radiation shielding
and maintain temperatures of -25 $^{o}$C. This minimizes base life-support
complexity and reduces launch mass. ANT is compelling for a lunar mission
because it doesn't require a team of astronauts for excavation and it requires
minimal supervision. The robot teams are shown to autonomously interpret
blueprints, excavate and prepare sites for a lunar base. Because little
pre-programmed knowledge is provided, the controllers discover creative
techniques. ANT evolves techniques such as slot-dozing that would otherwise
require excavation experts. This is critical in making an excavation mission
feasible when it is prohibitively expensive to send astronauts. The controllers
evolve elaborate negotiation behaviors to work in close quarters. These and
other techniques such as concurrent evolution of the controller and team size
are shown to tackle problem of antagonism, when too many robots interfere
reducing the overall efficiency or worse, resulting in gridlock. While many
challenges remain with this technology our work shows a compelling pathway for
field testing this approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01742</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kalita</keyname><forenames>Himangshu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekan</forenames></author></authors><title>Automated Design of CubeSats and Small Spacecrafts</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cs.SY</categories><comments>6 pages, 11 figures, Proceedings of the International Astronautical
  Congress, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The miniaturization of electronics, sensors and actuators has enabled the
growing use of CubeSats and sub-20 kg spacecraft. Their reduced mass and volume
has the potential to translate into significant reductions in required
propellant and launch mass for interplanetary missions, earth observation and
for astrophysics applications. There is an important need to optimize the
design of these spacecraft to better ascertain their maximal capabilities by
finding optimized solution, where mass, volume and power is a premium. Current
spacecraft design methods require a team of experts, who use their engineering
experience and judgement to develop a spacecraft design. Such an approach can
miss innovative designs not thought of by a human design team. In this work we
present a compelling alternative approach that extends the capabilities of a
spacecraft engineering design team to search for and identify near-optimal
solutions using machine learning. The approach enables automated design of a
spacecraft that requires specifying quantitative goals, requiring reaching a
target location or operating at a predetermined orbit for a required time. Next
a virtual warehouse of components is specified that be selected to produce a
candidate design. Candidate designs are produced using an artificial Darwinian
approach, where fittest design survives and reproduce, while unfit individuals
are culled off. Our past work in space robotic has produced systems designs and
controllers that are human competitive. Finding a near-optimal solution
presents vast improvements over a solution obtained through engineering
judgment and point design alone. The approach shows a credible pathway to
identify and evaluate many more candidate designs than it would be otherwise
possible with a human design team alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03742</id><created>2017-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Klimchitskaya</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostepanenko</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical properties of dielectric plates coated with gapped graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures; accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B, v.95, 035425 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.035425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The optical properties of dielectric plates coated with gapped graphene are
investigated on the basis of first principles of quantum electrodynamics. The
reflection coefficients and reflectivities of graphene-coated plates are
expressed in terms of the polarization tensor of gapped graphene and the
dielectric permittivity of plate material. Simple approximate expressions for
the required combinations of components of the polarization tensor applicable
in the wide frequency region, where the presence of a gap influences the
optical properties, are found. Numerical computations of the reflectivities of
graphene-coated SiO${}_2$ plates are performed for different values of the
mass-gap parameter at different temperatures. It is shown that with an
increasing gap width the reflectivity of a graphene-coated plate at the normal
incidence decreases by up to a factor of 8 depending on the values of frequency
and mass-gap parameter. The angle dependences of reflectivities for both
polarizations of the incident electromagnetic waves have been computed for Si
and SiO${}_2$ plates coated with gapped graphene. We demonstrate that the TM
reflectivity has a minimum value at some angle of incidence depending on the
mass-gap parameter, frequency and temperature, whereas the TE reflectivity
depends on the angle of incidence monotonously. However, for the graphene
coatings with a nonzero mass-gap parameter the reflected light cannot be fully
polarized. Possible applications of the obtained results are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04731</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Klepser</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>The optimal on-source region size for detections with counting-type
  telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures. Accepted for publication in Astropart. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Astropart. Phys. 89 (2017) 10-13</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2017.01.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Source detection in counting type experiments such as Cherenkov telescopes
often involves the application of the classical Eq. 17 from the paper of Li &amp;
Ma (1983) to discrete on- and off-source regions. The on- source region is
typically a circular area with radius {\theta} in which the signal is expected
to appear with the shape of the instrument point spread function (PSF). This
paper addresses the question of what is the {\theta} that maximises the
probability of detection for a given PSF width and background event density. In
the high count number limit and assuming a Gaussian PSF profile, the optimum is
found to be at $\zeta_\infty^2 \approx 2.51$ times the squared PSF width
$\sigma_\mathrm{PSF39}^2$. While this number is shown to be a good choice in
many cases, a dynamic formula for cases of lower count numbers, which favour
larger on-source regions, is given. The recipe to get to this parametrisation
can also be applied to cases with a non-Gaussian PSF. This result can
standardise and simplify analysis procedures, reduce trials and eliminate the
need for experience-based ad hoc cut definitions or expensive case-by-case
Monte Carlo simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05662</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yangyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yen</keyname><forenames>Jeannette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanso</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection and tracking of chemical trails by local sensory systems</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn q-bio.CB</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many aquatic organisms exhibit remarkable abilities to detect and track
chemical signals when foraging, mating and escaping. For example, the male
copepod { \em T. longicornis} identifies the female in the open ocean by
following its chemically-flavored trail. Here, we develop a mathematical
framework in which a local sensory system is able to detect the local
concentration field and adjust its orientation accordingly. We show that this
system is able to detect and track chemical trails without knowing the trail's
global or relative position.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06713</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mej&#xed;a-Mendoza</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vald&#xe9;z-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;iz</keyname><forenames>Jesus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuentas-Gallegos</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robles</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical approach to the nanoporous phase diagram of carbon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>23 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanoporous carbon has been extensively used in a wide range of applications
ranging from water treatment to electrochemical applications, such as in energy
storage devices. An effort to relate structural to thermodynamical properties
has not been explored from an atomistic approach. In this work we present
numerical strategies to produce and study nanoporous carbon structures, using
molecular dynamics simulations and a many-body potential. We designed a
heating-quenching procedure in a thermodynamic region bounded by the critical,
and triple point densities of carbon to study an ensemble of 1750 atomic
arrangements produced at different densities, quench rates, and using graphite
and diamond unit cells as precursor structures. All these samples were
numerically characterized through the calculation of the free volumes, surface
areas, radial distribution functions, and structure factors. We found
particularly useful the potential energy dependence with $sp^3$ hybridization
content, to determine structural phases through clustering methods. Three
phases were related to graphite-like, sponge-like, and unstable states. We
showed that our results are compatible with available experiments and different
theoretical schemes, concluding that the use of Tersoff potential is a reliable
choice to produce nanoporous structures with low computational cost.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07120</id><created>2017-01-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Chung</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Daniel Guti&#xe9;rrez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergara</keyname><forenames>J. David</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac's method for time-dependent Hamiltonian systems in the extended
  phase space</title><categories>math-ph math.MP physics.class-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac's method for constrained systems is applied to the analysis of
time-dependent Hamiltonians in the extended phase space. Our analysis provides
a conceptually complete description and offers a different point of view of
earlier works. We show that the Lewis invariant is a Dirac's observable and in
consequence, it is invariant under time-reparametrizations. We compute the
Feynman propagator using the extended phase space description and show that the
quantum phase of the Feynman propagator is given by the boundary term of the
canonical transformation of the extended phase space. We also give a new light
to the physical character of this phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07431</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wlokka</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fierlinger</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frei</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geltenbort</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xf6;schl</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmid</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreyer</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steffen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Consistent description of UCN transport properties</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the diffuse reflection probabilities of Replica guides
for ultra-cold neutrons (UCN) using the so-called helium method. For the first
time we could establish a consistent description of the diffuse reflection
mechanism for different lengths of the guide system. The transmission of the
guides is measured depending on the helium pressure inside of the guides. A
series of simulations was done to reproduce the experimental data. These
simulations showed that a diffuse reflection probability of $d = (3.0 \pm 0.5)
\cdot 10^{-2}$ sufficiently describes the experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07451</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Franco-P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gidea</keyname><forenames>Marian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Chavela</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability interchanges in a curved Sitnikov problem</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP nlin.CD</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a curved Sitnikov problem, in which an infinitesimal particle
moves on a circle under the gravitational influence of two equal masses in
Keplerian motion within a plane perpendicular to that circle. There are two
equilibrium points, whose stability we are studying. We show that one of the
equilibrium points undergoes stability interchanges as the semi-major axis of
the Keplerian ellipses approaches the diameter of that circle. To derive this
result, we first formulate and prove a general theorem on stability
interchanges, and then we apply it to our model. The motivation for our model
resides with the $n$-body problem in spaces of constant curvature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07462</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoodzadeh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malekolkalami</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quartic time-dependent oscillatons</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages 13 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:gr-qc/0104093 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we will study some properties of oscillaton, spherically
symmetric object made of a real time-dependent scalar field, Using a self-
interaction quartic scalar potential instead of a quadratic or exponential ones
discussed in previous works. Since the oscillatons can be regarded as models
for astrophysical objects which play the role of dark matter, there- fore
investigation of their properties has more importance place in present time of
physics; research. Therefore we investigate the properties of these objects by
Solving the system of differential equations obtained from the Einstein Klein
Gordon (EKG) equations and will show their importance as new candidates for the
role of dark matter in the galactic scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07486</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Frauendiener</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaber</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient computation of multidimensional theta functions</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An important step in the efficient computation of multi-dimensional theta
functions is the construction of appropriate symplectic transformations for a
given Riemann matrix assuring a rapid convergence of the theta series. An
algorithm is presented to approximately map the Riemann matrix to the Siegel
fundamental domain. The shortest vector of the lattice generated by the Riemann
matrix is identified exactly, and the algorithm ensures that its length is
larger than $\sqrt{3}/2$. The approach is based on a previous algorithm by
Deconinck et al. using the LLL algorithm for lattice reductions. Here, the LLL
algorithm is replaced by exact Minkowski reductions for small genus and an
exact identification of the shortest lattice vector for larger values of the
genus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07499</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Che</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric Stability of Pseudo-plane Ideal Flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>25 papges, 3 figures, 2 tables, under consideration at Physical
  Review Fluids</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geometric analysis of steady pseudo-plane ideal flow reveals a fundamental
relation between vertical coherence and streamline topology. It shows vertical
alignment only exists in straightline jet and circular vortex. A geometric
stability theory is then developed as a structural stability in contrast to
traditional dynamical stability, suggesting all vertical-aligned pseudo-plane
flows are geometrically stable and all non-aligned non-straightline flows are
unstable. It provides a topological explanation for the tendency of
axisymmetrization and vertical alignment observed in vortex experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07504</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Cirrone</keyname><forenames>GAP</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manti</keyname><forenames>L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margarone</keyname><forenames>D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuffrida</keyname><forenames>L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picciotto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuttone</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korn</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchese</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milluzzo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petringa</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perozziello</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scuderi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear fusion enhances cancer cell killing efficacy in a protontherapy
  model</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Original paper on a significative improvement of proton
  radiobiological effect</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Protontherapy is hadrontherapy fastest-growing modality and a pillar in the
battle against cancer. Hadrontherapy superiority lies in its inverted
depth-dose profile, hence tumour-confined irradiation. Protons, however, lack
distinct radiobiological advantages over photons or electrons. Higher LET
(Linear Energy Transfer) $^{12}$C ions can overcome cancer radioresistance: DNA
lesion complexity increases with LET, resulting in efficient cell killing, i.e.
higher Relative Biological Effectiveness (RBE). However, economic and
radiobiological issues hamper $^{12}$C-ion clinical amenability. Thus,
enhancing proton RBE is desirable. To this end, we exploited the p + $^{11}$B
$\rightarrow$3$\alpha$ reaction to generate high-LET alpha particles with a
clinical proton beam. To maximize the reaction rate, we used sodium borocaptate
(BSH) with natural boron content. Boron-Neutron Capture Therapy (BNCT) uses
$^{10}$B-enriched BSH for neutron irradiation-triggered alpha-particles. We
recorded significantly increased cellular lethality and chromosome aberration
complexity. A strategy combining protontherapy ballistic precision with the
higher RBE promised by BNCT and $^{12}$C-ion therapy is thus demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07505</id><created>2017-01-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author></authors><title>Extracting single crystal diffraction pattern from powder diffraction by
  intensity correlation functions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We applied the analysis of x-ray intensity angular correlation function to
dilute ensembles of identical spinel crystals. Firstly, we show that the
angular correlation from measured diffraction patterns with many crystals per
shot converges to the correlation for single crystal. Secondly, we determined
the diffraction pattern from single crystal from diffraction patterns of many
crystals. Finally, we discussed the full 3D reciprocal space retrieval and its
potential application in solving structure with dilute powder diffraction data,
where the intensity fluctuation could be observed on each ring.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07509</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajagopalan</keyname><forenames>Jagannathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Thin films with precisely engineered nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Synthesis of rationally designed nanostructured materials with optimized
mechanical properties, e.g., high strength with considerable ductility,
requires rigorous control of diverse microstructural parameters including the
mean size, size dispersion and spatial distribution of grains. However,
currently available synthesis techniques can seldom satisfy these requirements.
Here, we report a new methodology to synthesize thin films with unprecedented
microstructural control via systematic, in-situ seeding of nanocrystals into
amorphous precursor films. When the amorphous films are subsequently
crystallized by thermal annealing, the nanocrystals serve as preferential grain
nucleation sites and control their microstructure. We demonstrate the
capability of this approach by precisely tailoring the size, geometry and
spatial distribution of nanostructured grains in structural (TiAl) as well as
functional (TiNi) thin films. The approach, which is applicable to a broad
class of metallic alloys and ceramics, enables explicit microstructural control
of thin film materials for a wide spectrum of applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07530</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sevlian</keyname><forenames>Raffi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajagopal</keyname><forenames>Ram</forenames></author></authors><title>Actively Calibrated Line Mountable Capacitive Voltage Transducer For
  Power Systems Applications</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A class of Actively Calibrated Line Mounted Capacitive Voltage Transducers
(LMCVT) are introduced as a viable line mountable instrumentation option for
deploying large numbers of voltage transducers onto the medium and high voltage
systems. Active Calibration is shown to reduce the error of line mounted
voltage measurements by an order of magnitude from previously published
techniques. The instrument physics and sensing method is presented and the
performance is evaluated in a laboratory setting. Finally, a roadmap to a fully
deployable prototype is shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07543</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07543</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Gankidi</keyname><forenames>Pranay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekan</forenames></author></authors><title>FPGA Architecture for Deep Learning and its application to Planetary
  Robotics</title><categories>cs.LG astro-ph.IM cs.RO</categories><comments>8 pages, 10 figures in Proceedings of the IEEE Aerospace Conference
  2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Autonomous control systems onboard planetary rovers and spacecraft benefit
from having cognitive capabilities like learning so that they can adapt to
unexpected situations in-situ. Q-learning is a form of reinforcement learning
and it has been efficient in solving certain class of learning problems.
However, embedded systems onboard planetary rovers and spacecraft rarely
implement learning algorithms due to the constraints faced in the field, like
processing power, chip size, convergence rate and costs due to the need for
radiation hardening. These challenges present a compelling need for a portable,
low-power, area efficient hardware accelerator to make learning algorithms
practical onboard space hardware. This paper presents a FPGA implementation of
Q-learning with Artificial Neural Networks (ANN). This method matches the
massive parallelism inherent in neural network software with the fine-grain
parallelism of an FPGA hardware thereby dramatically reducing processing time.
Mars Science Laboratory currently uses Xilinx-Space-grade Virtex FPGA devices
for image processing, pyrotechnic operation control and obstacle avoidance. We
simulate and program our architecture on a Xilinx Virtex 7 FPGA. The
architectural implementation for a single neuron Q-learning and a more complex
Multilayer Perception (MLP) Q-learning accelerator has been demonstrated. The
results show up to a 43-fold speed up by Virtex 7 FPGAs compared to a
conventional Intel i5 2.3 GHz CPU. Finally, we simulate the proposed
architecture using the Symphony simulator and compiler from Xilinx, and
evaluate the performance and power consumption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07545</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nallapu</keyname><forenames>Ravi Teja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tallapragada</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekan</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiometric Actuators for Spacecraft Attitude Control</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages, 11 figures in Proceedings of the IEEE Aerospace Conference
  2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CubeSats and small satellites are emerging as low-cost tools to perform
astronomy, exoplanet searches and earth observation. These satellites can be
dedicated to pointing at targets for weeks or months at a time. This is
typically not possible on larger missions where usage is shared. Current
satellites use reaction wheels and where possible magneto-torquers to control
attitude. However, these actuators can induce jitter due to various sources. In
this work, we introduce a new class of actuators that exploit radiometric
forces induced by gasses on surface with a thermal gradient. Our work shows
that a CubeSat or small spacecraft mounted with radiometric actuators can
achieve precise pointing of few arc-seconds or less and avoid the jitter
problem. The actuator is entirely solid-state, containing no moving mechanical
components. This ensures high-reliability and long-life in space. A preliminary
design for these actuators is proposed, followed by feasibility analysis of the
actuator performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07547</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nallapu</keyname><forenames>Ravi Teja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thoesen</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garvie</keyname><forenames>Laurence</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asphaug</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekanthan</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimized Bucket Wheel Design for Asteroid Excavation</title><categories>cs.RO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 16 figures, International Astronautic Congress 2016,
  Guadalajara, Mexico</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current spacecraft need to launch with all of their required fuel for travel.
This limits the system performance, payload capacity, and mission flexibility.
One compelling alternative is to perform In-Situ Resource Utilization (ISRU) by
extracting fuel from small bodies in local space such as asteroids or small
satellites. Compared to the Moon or Mars, the microgravity on an asteroid
demands a fraction of the energy for digging and accessing hydrated regolith
just below the surface. Previous asteroid excavation efforts have focused on
discrete capture events (an extension of sampling technology) or whole-asteroid
capture and processing. This paper proposes an optimized bucket wheel design
for surface excavation of an asteroid or small-body. Asteroid regolith is
excavated and water extracted for use as rocket propellant. Our initial study
focuses on system design, bucket wheel mechanisms, and capture dynamics applied
to ponded materials known to exist on asteroids like Itokawa and Eros and small
satellites like Phobos and Deimos. For initial evaluation of
material-spacecraft dynamics and mechanics, we assume lunar-like regolith for
bulk density, particle size and cohesion. We shall present our estimates for
the energy balance of excavation and processing versus fuel gained.
Conventional electrolysis of water is used to produce hydrogen and oxygen. It
is compared with steam for propulsion and both show significant delta-v. We
show that a return trip from Deimos to Earth is possible for a 12 kg craft
using ISRU processed fuel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07561</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sonawane</keyname><forenames>Nikhil S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekan</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision Pointing of Antennas in Space Using Arrays of Shape Memory
  Alloy Based Linear Actuators</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures in Proceedings of the 40th Annual AAS Guidance,
  Navigation and Control Conference 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Space systems such as communication satellites, earth observation satellites
and space telescopes require precise pointing to observe fixed targets over
prolonged time. These systems typically use reaction-wheels to slew the
spacecraft and gimballing systems containing motors to achieve precise
pointing. Motor based actuators have limited life as they contain moving parts
that require lubrication in space. Alternate methods have utilized
piezoelectric actuators. This paper presents Shape memory alloys (SMA)
actuators for control of a deployable antenna placed on a satellite. The SMAs
are operated as a series of distributed linear actuators. These distributed
linear actuators are not prone to single point failures and although each
individual actuator is imprecise due to hysteresis and temperature variation.
The system as a whole achieves reliable results. The SMAs can be programmed to
perform a series of periodic motion and operate as a mechanical guidance system
that is not prone to damage from radiation or space weather. Efforts are
focused on developing a system that can achieve one degree pointing accuracy at
first, with an ultimate goal of achieving a few arc seconds accuracy. Bench top
models of the actuator system has been developed and working towards testing
the system under vacuum. A demonstration flight of the technology is planned
aboard a CubeSat.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07562</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nallapu</keyname><forenames>Ravi teja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekan</forenames></author></authors><title>Precise Pointing of Cubesat Telescopes: Comparison Between Heat and
  Light Induced Attitude Control Methods</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures in Proceedings of the 40th Annual AAS Guidance,
  Navigation and Control Conference 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CubeSats are emerging as low-cost tools to perform astronomy, exoplanet
searches and earth observation. These satellites can target an object for
science observation for weeks on end. This is typically not possible on larger
missions where usage time is shared. The problem of designing an attitude
control system for CubeSat telescopes is very challenging because current
choice of actuators such as reaction-wheels and magnetorquers can induce jitter
on the spacecraft due to moving mechanical parts and due to external
disturbances. These telescopes may contain cryo-pumps and servos that introduce
additional vibrations. A better solution is required. In our paper, we analyze
the feasibility of utilizing solar radiation pressure (SRP) and radiometric
force to achieve precise attitude control. Our studies show radiometric
actuators to be a viable method to achieve precise pointing. The device uses 8
thin vanes of different temperatures placed in a near-vacuum chamber. These
chambers contain trace quantities of lightweight, inert gasses like argon. The
temperature gradient across the vanes causes the gas molecules to strike the
vanes differently and thus inducing a force. By controlling these forces, it's
possible to produce a torque to precisely point or spin a spacecraft. We
present a conceptual design of a CubeSat that is equipped with these actuators.
We then analyze the potential slew maneuver and slew rates possible with these
actuators by simulating their performance. Our analytical and simulation
results point towards a promising pathway for laboratory testing of this
technology and demonstration of this technology in space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07574</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Morr</keyname><forenames>Dirk K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of Scanning Tunneling Spectroscopy: from Kondo Impurities to
  Heavy Fermion Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Brief review article published in Reports on Progress in Physics in a
  special issue on Strongly Correlated Electron Systems. This is the
  author-created, un-copyedited version</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 80, 014502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/80/1/014502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kondo systems ranging from the single Kondo impurity to heavy fermion
materials present us with a plethora of unconventional properties whose
theoretical understanding is still one of the major open problems in condensed
matter physics. Over the last few years, groundbreaking scanning tunneling
spectroscopy (STS) experiments have provided unprecedented new insight into the
electronic structure of Kondo systems. Interpreting the results of these
experiments -- the differential conductance and the quasi-particle interference
spectrum -- however, has been complicated by the fact that electrons tunneling
from the STS tip into the system can tunnel either into the heavy magnetic
moment or the light conduction band states. In this article, we briefly review
the theoretical progress made in understanding how quantum interference between
these two tunneling paths affects the experimental STS results. We show how
this theoretical insight has allowed us to interpret the results of STS
experiments on a series of heavy fermion materials providing detailed knowledge
of their complex electronic structure. It is this knowledge that is a conditio
sine qua non for developing a deeper understanding of the fascinating
properties exhibited by heavy fermion materials, ranging from unconventional
superconductivity to non-Fermi-liquid behavior in the vicinity of quantum
critical points.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07585</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Araki</keyname><forenames>Takeaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagura</keyname><forenames>Jumpei</forenames></author></authors><title>Bistable director alignments of nematic liquid crystals confined in
  frustrated substrates</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 95, 012706, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.012706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We studied in-plane bistable alignments of nematic liquid crystals confined
by two frustrated surfaces by means of Monte Carlo simulations of the
Lebwohl-Lasher spin model. The surfaces are prepared with orientational
checkerboard patterns, on which the director field is locally anchored to be
planar yet orthogonal between the neighboring blocks. We found the director
field in the bulk tends to be aligned along the diagonal axes of the
checkerboard pattern, as reported experimentally [J.-H. Kim et al., Appl. Phys.
Lett. 78, 3055 (2001)]. The energy barrier between the two stable orientations
is increased, when the system is brought to the isotropic-nematic transition
temperature. Based on an elastic theory, we found that the bistability is
attributed to the spatial modulation of the director field near the frustrated
surfaces. As the block size is increased and/or the elastic modulus is reduced,
the degree of the director inhomogeneity is increased, enlarging the energy
barrier. We also found that the switching rate between the stable states is
decreased when the block size is comparable to the cell thickness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07597</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohyama</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokura</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Memory effect and pseudomode amplitude in non-Markovian dynamics of a
  two level system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study non-Markovian dynamics of a two level atom using pseudomode method.
Because of the memory effect of non-Markovian dynamics, the atom receives back
information and excited energy from the reservoir at a later time, which causes
more complicated behaviors than Markovian dynamics. With pseudomode method,
non-Markovian dynamics of the atom can be mapped into Markovian dynamics of the
atom and pseudomode. We show that by using pseudomode method and quantum jump
approach for Markovian dynamics, we get a physically intuitive insight into the
memory effect of non-Markovian dynamics. It suggests a simple physical meaning
of the memory time of a non-Markovian reservoir.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07598</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Heonhwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yun Won</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Soon-Gul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Mahn-Soo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Min-Seok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Jae-Hyuk</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision determination of a fluxoid quantum's magnetic moment in a
  superconducting micro-ring</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>To appear in Phys. Rev. B with 7 pages and 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using dynamic cantilever magnetometry and experimentally determining the
cantilever's vibrational mode shape, we precisely measured the magnetic moment
of a lithographically defined micron-sized superconducting Nb ring, a key
element for the previously proposed subpiconewton force standard. The magnetic
moments due to individual magnetic fluxoids and a diamagnetic response were
independently determined at T = 4.3 K, with a subfemtoampere-square-meter
resolution. The results show good agreement with the theoretical estimation
yielded by the Brandt and Clem model within the spring constant determination
accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07613</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Denner</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Par&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Gouns&#xe9;ti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaleski</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispersion and viscous attenuation of capillary waves with finite
  amplitude</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted manuscript for publication in European Physical Journal
  Special Topics</comments><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60199-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comprehensive study of the dispersion of capillary waves with
finite amplitude, based on direct numerical simulations. The presented results
show an increase of viscous attenuation and, consequently, a smaller frequency
of capillary waves with increasing initial wave amplitude. Interestingly,
however, the critical wavenumber as well as the wavenumber at which the maximum
frequency is observed remain the same for a given two-phase system,
irrespective of the wave amplitude. By devising an empirical correlation that
describes the effect of the wave amplitude on the viscous attenuation, the
dispersion of capillary waves with finite initial amplitude is shown to be, in
very good approximation, self-similar throughout the entire underdamped regime
and independent of the fluid properties. The results also shown that analytical
solutions for capillary waves with infinitesimal amplitude are applicable with
reasonable accuracy for capillary waves with moderate amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07635</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ubiali</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Precise predictions for charged Higgs boson production</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the proceedings of the conference: Prospects for
  Charged Higgs Discovery at Colliders (CHARGED2016), 3-6 October 2016,
  Uppsala, Sweden</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review some of the major progress in the accurate calculation of the cross
section for the production of a charged Higgs boson in a generic two-Higgs
double model, by focussing on the high-mass region, for which new calculations
have been made available in the past few years, both at the level of total and
of differential cross sections. Furthermore, we illustrate some recent progress
in the calculation of the total cross section for a charged Higgs boson with
mass in the intermediate range m_{H^\pm} \sim m_{t}, including top-resonant
contributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07637</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ayryan</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hnatic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrosyan</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gevorgyan</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmailian</keyname><forenames>N. Sh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oganesyan</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>X-Ray Radiation Generation in Heat Engines Using Electron Cooling</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a relativistic quantum heat engine that goes through a
thermodynamical cycle consisting of stages involving laser-assisted cooling of
electrons and the generation of Xray radiation. Quantum treatment of the
processes makes it possible to obtain the necessary condition and the amount of
work extracted from the interaction ingredients, as well as the efficiency of
the heat engine. We have also found that the efficiency of the relativistic
engine is less than the one for the nonrelativistic case for the same momenta.
The obtained results set the limits to the cooling, as well as the intensity of
X-ray radiation, in the quantum regime of the interaction of electrons with
laser fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07651</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mike&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Karel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jir&#xe1;sek</keyname><forenames>Milan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasicontinuum Method Extended to Irregular Lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasicontinuum (QC) method, originally proposed by Tadmor, Ortiz and
Phillips in 1996, is a computational technique that can efficiently handle
regular atomistic lattices by combining continuum and atomistic approaches. In
the present work, the QC method is extended to irregular systems of particles
that represent a heterogeneous material. The paper introduces five QC-inspired
approaches that approximate a discrete model consisting of particles connected
by elastic links with axial interactions. Accuracy is first checked on simple
examples in two and three spatial dimensions. Computational efficiency is then
assessed by performing three-dimensional simulations of an L-shaped specimen
with elastic-brittle links. It is shown that the QC-inspired approaches
substantially reduce the computational cost and lead to macroscopic crack
trajectories and global load-displacement curves that are very similar to those
obtained by a fully resolved particle model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07655</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Yakui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun-Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic and electronic properties of La$_3M$O$_7$ and possible polaron
  formation in hole-doped La$_3M$O$_7$ ($M$=Ru and Os)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens Matter 29, 095803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa552c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oxides with $4d$/$5d$ transition metal ions are physically interesting for
their particular crystalline structures as well as the spin-orbit coupled
electronic structures. Recent experiments revealed a series of $4d$/$5d$
transition metal oxides $R_3M$O$_7$ ($R$: rare earth; $M$: $4d$/$5d$ transition
metal) with unique quasi-one-dimensional $M$ chains. Here first-principles
calculations have been performed to study the electronic structures of
La$_3$OsO$_7$ and La$_3$RuO$_7$. Our study confirm both of them to be Mott
insulating antiferromagnets with identical magnetic order. The reduced magnetic
moments, which are much smaller than the expected value for ideal high-spin
state ($3$ $t_{2g}$ orbitals occupied), are attributed to the strong $p-d$
hybridization with oxygen ions, instead of the spin-orbit coupling. The
Ca-doping to La$_3$OsO$_7$ and La$_3$RuO$_7$ can not only modulate the nominal
carrier density but also affect the orbital order as well as the local
distortions. The Coulombic attraction and particular orbital order would prefer
to form polarons, which might explain the puzzling insulating behavior of doped
$5d$ transition metal oxides. In addition, our calculation predict that the
Ca-doping can trigger ferromagnetism in La$_3$RuO$_7$ but not in La$_3$OsO$_7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07661</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gammaldi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avila-Reese</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenzuela</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Morales</keyname><forenames>A. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salucci</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesti</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the possible enhancement of the dark matter density distribution at
  the galactic center</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>1 page, 1 figure. To appear on the proceedings of LARIM 2016 &quot;XV
  Latin American Regional IAU Meeting&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dark matter spike induced by the adiabatic growth of a massive black hole
in a cuspy environment, may explain the thermal dark matter density required to
fit the cut-off in the HESSJ1745-290 gamma-ray spectra as TeV dark matter
signal with a background component. The spike extension appears comparable with
the HESS angular resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07663</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Blondel</keyname><forenames>Oriane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toninelli</keyname><forenames>Cristina</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetically constrained lattice gases: tagged particle diffusion</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 p</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kinetically constrained lattice gases (KCLG) are interacting particle systems
on the integer lattice $\mathbb Z^d$ with hard core exclusion and
  Kawasaki type dynamics. Their peculiarity is that jumps are allowed only if
the configuration satisfies a constraint which asks for enough empty sites in a
certain local neighborhood. KCLG have been introduced and extensively studied
in physics literature as models of glassy dynamics. We focus on the most
studied class of KCLG, the Kob Andersen (KA) models. We analyze the behavior of
a tracer (i.e. a tagged particle) at equilibrium. We prove that for all
dimensions $d\geq 2$ and for any equilibrium particle density, under diffusive
rescaling the motion of the tracer converges to a $d$-dimensional Brownian
motion with non-degenerate diffusion matrix. Therefore we disprove the
occurrence of a diffusive/non diffusive transition which had been conjectured
in physics literature. Our technique is flexible enough and can be extended to
analyse the tracer behavior for other choices of constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07672</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadi</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naqib</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>A. K. M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab-initio study of mechanical and electronic properties of MoAlB</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using first-principles calculations, the structural, elastic and electronic
properties of MoAlB have been investigated for the first time. The optimized
lattice constants exhibit fair agreement with the experimental values. The
computed elastic constants satisfy the mechanical stability conditions for the
MoAlB. The Mo-based boride MoAlB is elastically anisotropic and can be
classified as brittle material. This boride is expected to show reasonable
thermal conductivity due to its high Debye temperature of 693 K. The metallic
electrical conductivity of this compound is predicted from the electronic band
structure calculations. The chemical bonding in MoAlB is basically covalent in
nature which is supported by the calculated electronic density of states (DOS),
Mulliken population, and charge density distribution. The estimated hardness
value of 11.6 GPa for MoAlB suggests that it is softer compared to many other
borides. The Fermi surface is formed due to low dispersive Mo 4d-like bands,
which makes the compound a conductive one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07673</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Finkenrath</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexandrou</keyname><forenames>Constantia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berlin</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brida</keyname><forenames>Mattia Dalla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leontiou</keyname><forenames>Theodoros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>Using a new analysis method to extract excited states in the scalar
  meson sector</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures; Proceedings of the 34th annual International
  Symposium on Lattice Field Theory, 24-30 July 2016, University of
  Southampton, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore a method to extract energy eigenstates, called Athens Model
Independent Analysis Scheme (AMIAS), which is an alternative to solving
standard Generalized Eigenvalue Problems (GEVP). The method is based on
statistically sampling the space of fit parameters according to the $\chi^2$
value of the fit function. The method is particularly suited for correlators or
correlation matrices with strong contributions from several energy eigenstates
and for rather noisy data, e.g. for correlators with disconnected and partly
disconnected diagrams. We apply the method to the analysis of the $J^P = 0^+$
channel in the context of our investigation of the $a_0(980)$ meson and point
out advantages compared to the GEVP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07685</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Colombo</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galli</keyname><forenames>Davide Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Caro</keyname><forenames>Liberato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scattarella</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlino</keyname><forenames>Elvio</forenames></author></authors><title>Facing the phase problem in Coherent Diffractive Imaging via Memetic
  Algorithms</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.OC</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures. To be published on Sci. Rep. 7, 42236 (2017)</comments><doi>10.1038/srep42236</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coherent Diffractive Imaging is a lensless technique that allows imaging of
matter at a spatial resolution not limited by lens aberrations. This technique
exploits the measured diffraction pattern of a coherent beam scattered by
periodic and non-periodic objects to retrieve spatial information. The
diffracted intensity, for weak-scattering objects, is proportional to the
modulus of the Fourier Transform of the object scattering function. Any phase
information, needed to retrieve its scattering function, has to be retrieved by
means of suitable algorithms. Here we present a new approach, based on a
memetic algorithm, i.e. a hybrid genetic algorithm, to face the phase problem,
which exploits the synergy of deterministic and stochastic optimization
methods. The new approach has been tested on simulated data and applied to the
phasing of transmission electron microscopy coherent electron diffraction data
of a $\text{SrTiO}_\text{3}$ sample. We have been able to quantitatively
retrieve the projected atomic potential, and also image the oxygen columns,
which are not directly visible in the relevant high-resolution transmission
electron microscopy images. Our approach proves to be a new powerful tool for
the study of matter at atomic resolution and opens new perspectives in those
applications in which effective phase retrieval is necessary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07692</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Shaikhislamov</keyname><forenames>I. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khodachenko</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lammer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kislyakova</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fossati</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokopov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berezutsky</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakharov</keyname><forenames>Yu. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posukh</keyname><forenames>V. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two regimes of interaction of a Hot Jupiter's escaping atmosphere with
  the stellar wind and generation of energized atomic hydrogen corona</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Published on ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 832, 2016, 173</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/2/173</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction of escaping upper atmosphere of a hydrogen rich
non-magnetized analog of HD209458b with a stellar wind of its host G-type star
at different orbital distances is simulated with a 2D axisymmetric multi-fluid
hydrodynamic model. A realistic sun-like spectrum of XUV radiation which
ionizes and heats the planetary atmosphere, hydrogen photo-chemistry, as well
as stellar-planetary tidal interaction are taken into account to generate
self-consistently an atmospheric hydrodynamic outflow. Two different regimes of
the planetary and stellar winds interaction have been modelled. These are: 1)
the &quot;captured by the star&quot; regime, when the tidal force and pressure gradient
drive the planetary material beyond the Roche lobe towards the star, and 2) the
&quot;blown by the wind&quot; regime, when sufficiently strong stellar wind confines the
escaping planetary atmosphere and channels it into the tail. The model
simulates in details the hydrodynamic interaction between the planetary atoms,
protons and the stellar wind, as well as the production of energetic neutral
atoms (ENAs) around the planet due to charge-exchange between planetary atoms
and stellar protons. The revealed location and shape of the ENA cloud either as
a paraboloid shell between ionopause and bowshock (for the &quot;blown by the wind&quot;
regime), or a turbulent layer at the contact boundary between the planetary
stream and stellar wind (for the &quot;captured by the star&quot; regime) are of
importance for the interpretation of Ly{\alpha} absorption features in
exoplanetary transit spectra and characterization of the plasma environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07708</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07708</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertaina</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forza</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfrin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mignone</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Youssef</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bacholle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorodetzky</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parizot</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prev&#xf4;t</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrillon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dagoret-Campagne</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reina</keyname><forenames>J. Rabanal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The EUSO@TurLab Project</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures, &quot;XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The TurLab facility is a laboratory, equipped with a 5 m diameter and 1 m
depth rotating tank, located in the Physics Department of the University of
Turin. The tank has been built mainly to study problems where system rotation
plays a key role in the fluid behaviour such as in atmospheric and oceanic
flows at different scales. The tank can be filled with different fluids of
variable density, which enables studies in layered conditions such as sea
waves. The tank can be also used to simulate the terrestrial surface with the
optical characteristics of different environments such as snow, grass, ocean,
land with soil, stones etc., fogs and clouds. As it is located in an extremely
dark place, the light intensity can be controlled artificially. Such
capabilities of the TurLab facility are applied to perform experiments related
to the observation of Extreme Energy Cosmic Rays (EECRs) from space using the
fluorescence technique, as in the case of the JEM-EUSO mission, where the
diffuse night brightness and artificial light sources can vary significantly in
time and space inside the Field of View (FoV) of the telescope. Here we will
report the currently ongoing activity at the TurLab facility in the framework
of the JEM-EUSO mission (EUSO@TurLab).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07711</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07711</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cowley</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Stephen W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the Dynamics of a Hypothetical Planet X by way of
  Gravitational N-body Simulator</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, published in Eur. J. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Cowley, M., &amp; Hughes, S. 2017, Eur J Phys, 38 (IOP Publishing),
  025602</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6404/aa5448</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes a novel activity to model the dynamics of a
Jupiter-mass, trans-Neptunian planet of a highly eccentric orbit. Despite a
history rooted in modern astronomy, &quot;Planet X&quot;, a hypothesised hidden planet
lurking in our outer Solar System, has often been touted by conspiracy
theorists as the cause of past mass extinction events on Earth, as well as
other modern-day doomsday scenarios. Frequently dismissed as pseudoscience by
astronomers, these stories continue to draw the attention of the public by
provoking mass media coverage. Targeted at junior undergraduate levels, this
activity allows students to debunk some of the myths surrounding Planet X by
using simulation software to demonstrate that such a large-mass planet with
extreme eccentricity would be unable to enter our Solar System unnoticed, let
alone maintain a stable orbit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07713</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Enlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swerts</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devolder</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couet</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertens</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spampinato</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franquet</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conard</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Elshocht</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furnemont</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Boeck</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kar</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seed Layer Impact on Structural and Magnetic Properties of [Co/Ni]
  Multilayers with Perpendicular Magnetic Anisotropy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 121, 043905 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4974885</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  [Co/Ni] multilayers with perpendicular magnetic anisotropy (PMA) have been
researched and applied in various spintronic applications. Typically the seed
layer material is studied to provide the desired face-centered cubic
(\textit{fcc}) texture to the [Co/Ni] to obtain PMA. The integration of [Co/Ni]
in back-end-of-line (BEOL) processes also requires the PMA to survive
post-annealing. In this paper, the impact of NiCr, Pt, Ru, and Ta seed layers
on the structural and magnetic properties of [Co(0.3 nm)/Ni(0.6 nm)]
multilayers is investigated before and after annealing. The multilayers were
deposited \textit{in-situ} on different seeds via physical vapor deposition at
room temperature. The as-deposited [Co/Ni] films show the required
\textit{fcc}(111) texture on all seeds, but PMA is only observed on Pt and Ru.
In-plane magnetic anisotropy (IMA) is obtained on NiCr and Ta seeds, which is
attributed to strain-induced PMA loss. PMA is maintained on all seeds after
post-annealing up to 400$^{\circ}$C. The largest effective perpendicular
anisotropy energy ($K_U^{\mathrm{eff}}\approx 2\times10^5$J/m$^3$) after
annealing is achieved on NiCr seed. The evolution of PMA upon annealing cannot
be explained by further crystallization during annealing or strain-induced PMA,
nor can the observed magnetization loss and the increased damping after
annealing. Here we identify the diffusion of the non-magnetic materials from
the seed into [Co/Ni] as the major driver of the changes in the magnetic
properties. By selecting the seed and post-annealing temperature, the [Co/Ni]
can be tuned in a broad range for both PMA and damping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07729</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Garas</keyname><forenames>Antonios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lapatinas</keyname><forenames>Athanasios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poulios</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author></authors><title>The relation between migration and FDI in the OECD from a complex
  network perspective</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 3 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Advs. Complex Syst. 19, 1650009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219525916500090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the relationship between human migration and OECD's foreign direct
investment (FDI) using a gravity equation enriched with variables that account
for complex-network effects. Based on a panel data analysis, we find a strong
positive correlation between the migration network and the FDI network, which
can be mostly explained by countries' economic/demographic sizes and
geographical distance. We highlight the existence of a stronger positive FDI
relationship in pairs of countries that are more central in the migration
network. Both intensive and extensive forms of centrality are FDI enhancing.
Illuminating this result, we show that bilateral FDI between any two countries
is further affected positively by the complex web of &quot;third party&quot;
corridors/migration stocks of the international migration network (IMN). Our
findings are consistent whether we consider bilateral FDI and bilateral
migration figures, or we focus on the outward FDI and the respective inward
migration of the OECD countries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07734</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07734</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Wissocq</keyname><forenames>Gauthier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gourdain</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malaspinas</keyname><forenames>Orestis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyssartier</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Regularized characteristic boundary conditions for the Lattice-Boltzmann
  methods at high Reynolds number flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>16 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Comp. Phys., 331, p. 1-18 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.11.037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports the investigations done to adapt the Characteristic
Boundary Conditions (CBC) to the Lattice-Boltzmann formalism for high Reynolds
number applications. Three CBC formalisms are implemented and tested in an open
source LBM code: the baseline local one-dimension inviscid (BL-LODI) approach,
its extension including the effects of the transverse terms (CBC-2D) and a
local streamline approach in which the problem is reformulated in the incident
wave framework (LS-LODI). Then all implementations of the CBC methods are
tested for a variety of test cases, ranging from canonical problems (such as 2D
plane and spherical waves and 2D vortices) to a 2D NACA profile at high
Reynolds number ($Re = 10^5$), representative of aeronautic applications. The
LS-LODI approach provides the best results for pure acoustics waves (plane and
spherical waves). However, it is not well suited to the outflow of a convected
vortex for which the CBC-2D associated with a relaxation on density and
transverse waves provides the best results. As regards numerical stability, a
regularized adaptation is necessary to simulate high Reynolds number flows. The
so-called regularized FD (Finite Difference) adaptation, a modified regularized
approach where the off-equilibrium part of the stress tensor is computed thanks
to a finite difference scheme, is the only tested adaptation that can handle
the high Reynolds computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07746</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Gregory W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Mechanics With Noncommutative Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>50 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate a Born rule for families of quantum systems parametrized by a
noncommutative space of control parameters. The resulting formalism may be
viewed as a generalization of quantum mechanics where overlaps take values in a
noncommutative algebra, rather than in the complex numbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07753</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Janiuk</keyname><forenames>Agnieszka</forenames><affiliation>CTP PAS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bejger</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames><affiliation>NCAC PAS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sukova</keyname><forenames>Petra</forenames><affiliation>CTP PAS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Charzynski</keyname><forenames>Szymon</forenames><affiliation>CTP PAS</affiliation><affiliation>Warsaw Univ</affiliation></author></authors><title>Black hole accretion in gamma ray bursts</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures. Accepted to Special Issue of Galaxies. Gamma-Ray
  Bursts. Recent Theoretical Models and Observations. Based on the
  contributions presented during Symposium 11 at the European Week of Astronomy
  and Space Science (4-5 July, 2016, Athens, Greece). Eds. I. Contopoulos, S.
  Oates</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the structure and evolution of the hyperaccreting disks and outflows
in the gamma ray bursts central engines. The torus around a stellar mass black
hole is composed of free nucleons, Helium, electron-positron pairs, and is
cooled by neutrino emission. Accretion of matter powers the relativistic jets,
responsible for the gamma ray prompt emission. The significant number density
of neutrons in the disk and outflowing material will cause subsequent formation
of heavier nuclei. We study the process of nucleosynthesis and its possible
observational consequences. We also apply our scenario to the recent
observation of the gravitational wave signal, detected on September 14th, 2015
by the two Advanced LIGO detectors, and related to an inspiral and merger of a
binary black hole system. A gamma ray burst that could possibly be related with
the GW150914 event was observed by the Fermi satellite. It had a duration of
about 1 second and appeared about 0.4 seconds after the gravitational-wave
signal. We propose that a collapsing massive star and a black hole in a close
binary could lead to the event. The gamma ray burst was powered by a weak
neutrino flux produced in the star remnant's matter. Low spin and kick velocity
of the merged black hole are reproduced in our simulations. Coincident
gravitational-wave emission originates from the merger of the collapsed core
and the companion black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07757</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Boyer</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodutch</keyname><forenames>Aharon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mor</keyname><forenames>Tal</forenames></author></authors><title>Extrapolated Quantum States, Void States, and a Huge Novel Class of
  Distillable Entangled States</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>A preliminary version of this work was presented at the 3rd
  International Conference on the Theory and Practice of Natural Computing TPNC
  2014 (Boyer and Mor (2014))</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A nice and interesting property of any pure tensor-product state is that each
such state has distillable entangled states at an arbitrarily small distance
$\epsilon$ in its neighborhood. We say that such nearby states are
$\epsilon$-entangled, and we call the tensor product state in that case, a
&quot;boundary separable state&quot;, as there is entanglement at any distance from this
&quot;boundary&quot;. Here we find a huge class of separable states that also share that
property mentioned above -- they all have $\epsilon$-entangled states at any
small distance in their neighborhood. Furthermore, the entanglement they have
is proven to be distillable. We then extend this result to the
discordant/classical cut and show that all classical states (correlated and
uncorrelated) have discordant states at distance $\epsilon$, and provide a
constructive method for finding $\epsilon$-discordant states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07759</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuhar</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krucker</keyname><forenames>S&#xe4;m</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannah</keyname><forenames>Iain G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glesener</keyname><forenames>Lindsay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saint-Hilaire</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grefenstette</keyname><forenames>Brian W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Hugh S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Stephen M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Paul J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boggs</keyname><forenames>Steven E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>Finn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hailey</keyname><forenames>Charles J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Fiona A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of Significant Energy Input in the Late Phase of a Solar Flare
  from NuSTAR X-Ray Observations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in ApJ, 8 pages</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 835:6, 2017 January 20</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/835/1/6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present observations of the occulted active region AR12222 during the
third {\em NuSTAR} solar campaign on 2014 December 11, with concurrent {\em
SDO/}AIA and {\em FOXSI-2} sounding rocket observations. The active region
produced a medium size solar flare one day before the observations, at
$\sim18$UT on 2014 December 10, with the post-flare loops still visible at the
time of {\em NuSTAR} observations. The time evolution of the source emission in
the {\em SDO/}AIA $335\textrm{\AA}$ channel reveals the characteristics of an
extreme-ultraviolet late phase event, caused by the continuous formation of new
post-flare loops that arch higher and higher in the solar corona. The spectral
fitting of {\em NuSTAR} observations yields an isothermal source, with
temperature $3.8-4.6$ MK, emission measure $0.3-1.8 \times 10^{46}\textrm{
cm}^{-3}$, and density estimated at $2.5-6.0 \times 10^8 \textrm{ cm}^{-3}$.
The observed AIA fluxes are consistent with the derived {\em NuSTAR}
temperature range, favoring temperature values in the range $4.0-4.3$ MK. By
examining the post-flare loops' cooling times and energy content, we estimate
that at least 12 sets of post-flare loops were formed and subsequently cooled
between the onset of the flare and {\em NuSTAR} observations, with their total
thermal energy content an order of magnitude larger than the energy content at
flare peak time. This indicates that the standard approach of using only the
flare peak time to derive the total thermal energy content of a flare can lead
to a large underestimation of its value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07773</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Amerio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behari</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brochmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Culbertson</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diesburg</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garren</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenlee</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herner</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Illingworth</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayatilaka</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonckheere</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naymola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oleynik</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakumotob</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varnes</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vellidis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watts</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Data preservation at the Fermilab Tevatron</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-552-CD</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl. Instrum. Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A, 851, 1 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.01.043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Fermilab Tevatron collider's data-taking run ended in September 2011,
yielding a dataset with rich scientific potential. The CDF and D0 experiments
each have approximately 9 PB of collider and simulated data stored on tape. A
large computing infrastructure consisting of tape storage, disk cache, and
distributed grid computing for physics analysis with the Tevatron data is
present at Fermilab. The Fermilab Run II data preservation project intends to
keep this analysis capability sustained through the year 2020 and beyond. To
achieve this goal, we have implemented a system that utilizes virtualization,
automated validation, and migration to new standards in both software and data
storage technology and leverages resources available from currently-running
experiments at Fermilab. These efforts have also provided useful lessons in
ensuring long-term data access for numerous experiments, and enable
high-quality scientific output for years to come.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07780</id><created>2017-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Samarasekara</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Silva</keyname><forenames>T. H. Y. I. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic films with three to twenty spin layers as described using
  second order perturbed Heisenberg Hamiltonian</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures, one table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modified second order perturbed Heisenberg Hamiltonian was employed to
describe the magnetic properties of ferromagnetic films with three to twenty
spin layers for the first time. Previously, the solution of second order
perturbed Heisenberg Hamiltonian was found for ferromagnetic films with two to
five layers under some assumptions by us. In this report, the exact solution is
presented without any assumptions by calculating the pseudo inverse of matrix
C. All eight magnetic parameters such as spin exchange interaction, second
order magnetic anisotropy, fourth order magnetic anisotropy, stress induced
magnetic anisotropy, demagnetization factor, in plane magnetic field, out of
plane magnetic field and magnetic dipole interaction were taken into account.
The easy and hard directions were found using 3-D and 2-D plots of total
magnetic energy versus these magnetic parameters. Angle between easy and hard
directions was nearly 107 degrees in many cases. The magnetic easy axis
gradually rotates from out of plane to in plane direction by indicating a
preferred in plane orientation of magnetic easy axis for films with higher
number of spin layers. These theoretical results agree with some experimental
research data of ferromagnetic thin films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07782</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Pica</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond the Standard Model: Charting Fundamental Interactions via Lattice
  Simulations</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>Plenary talk presented at the 34th International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory (Lattice 2016)</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2017-003 DNRF90</report-no><journal-ref>PoS(LATTICE2016)015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After the discovery of the Higgs boson, the primary objective of the Large
Hadron Collider (LHC) experiments is to identify new physics beyond the
Standard Model (SM). One of the most intriguing possibilities would be the
discovery of non-perturbative phenomena in electroweak physics. In fact both
ATLAS and CMS are providing crucial precision tests of the Higgs sector. Most
strikingly, there is no conclusive evidence yet on whether the Higgs boson is
elementary or composite. Lattice simulations can play a key role in advancing
our theoretical understanding of strongly coupled gauge theories relevant for
extensions of the SM and the LHC program. In this talk I will review the state
of beyond the SM (BSM) lattice studies aimed to chart the phase diagram and to
uncover the properties of strongly coupled gauge theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07799</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Thangavelautham</keyname><forenames>Jekanthan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robinson</keyname><forenames>Mark S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taits</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKinney</keyname><forenames>Tyler</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amidan</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polak</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Flying, Hopping Pit-Bots for Cave and Lava Tube Exploration on the Moon
  and Mars</title><categories>cs.RO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>in Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Instrumentation
  for Planetary Missions 2014</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wheeled ground robots are limited from exploring extreme environments such as
caves, lava tubes and skylights. Small robots that utilize unconventional
mobility through hopping, flying and rolling can overcome many roughness
limitations and thus extend exploration sites of interest on Moon and Mars. In
this paper we introduce a network of 3 kg, 0.30 m diameter ball robots
(pit-bots) that can fly, hop and roll using an onboard miniature propulsion
system. These pit-bots can be deployed from a lander or large rover. Each robot
is equipped with a smartphone sized computer, stereo camera and laser
rangefinder to per-form navigation and mapping. The ball robot can carry a
payload of 1 kg or perform sample return. Our studies show a range of 5 km and
0.7 hours flight time on the Moon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
