<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:40:15Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-18" from="2016-07-18" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.7326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.7326</id><created>2013-04-27</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Amey</forenames></author></authors><title>Plane Poiseuille flow through a porous medium - an analytical solution</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>76Sxx</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper develops a closed-form, analytical expression for the Darcy
velocity of a Newtonian fluid flowing through a channel filled with a porous
medium, bound by rigid walls and driven by a constant pressure gradient. We
express the Darcy velocity as a Weierstrass elliptic function of the transverse
coordinate. It allows us to get analytical expressions for volume flux and the
rate of dissipation. The Weierstrass elliptic function is a doubly-periodic,
complex-valued function defined over the complex plane. It takes real values
only on certain segments in the complex plane. We show how to align the
transverse coordinate axis along these segments to ensure real values of Darcy
velocity. Lastly, we give an algorithm to generate velocity profile and compute
volume flux given the flow parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05497</id><created>2015-02-19</created><updated>2015-11-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tosiek</keyname><forenames>Jaromir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cordero</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turrubiates</keyname><forenames>Francisco J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Wentzel - Kramers - Brillouin approximation method applied to the
  Wigner function</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 062103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4954071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An adaptation of the WKB method in the deformation quantization formalism is
presented with the aim to obtain an approximate technique of solving the
eigenvalue problem for energy in the phase space quantum approach. A
relationship between the phase $\sigma(\vec{r})$ of a wave function $\exp
\left(\frac{i}{\hbar} \sigma(\vec{r}) \right)$ and its respective Wigner
function is derived. Formulas to calculate the Wigner function of a product and
of a superposition of wave functions are proposed. Properties of a Wigner
function of interfering states are also investigated. Examples of this quasi -
classical approximation in deformation quantization are analysed. A strict form
of the Wigner function for states represented by tempered generalised functions
has been derived. Wigner functions of unbound states in the Poeschl - Teller
potential have been found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07200</id><created>2015-02-25</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kramar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomczyk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Observation of Coronal Magnetic Fields by Vector Tomography of
  the Coronal Emission Line Polarizations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/819/2/L36</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article presents the first direct &quot;observation&quot; of the global-scale, 3D
coronal magnetic fields of Carrington Rotation (CR) Cycle 2112 using vector
tomographic inversion techniques. The Vector tomographic inversion uses
observational measurements of the Fe {\sc{xiii}} 10747 \AA\ Hanle effect
polarization signals by the Coronal Multichannel Polarimeter (CoMP) and coronal
density and temperature structures derived from scalar tomographic inversion of
STEREO/EUVI coronal emission lines (CELs) intensity images as inputs to derive
a coronal magnetic field model that best reproduces the observed polarization
signals. While independent verifications of the vector tomography results
cannot be performed, we compared the tomography inverted coronal magnetic
fields with those constructed by MagnetoHydroDynamic (MHD) simulation based on
observed photospheric magnetic fields of CR 2112 and 2113. We found that the
MHD model for CR 2112 is qualitatively consistent with the tomography inverted
result for most of the reconstruction domain except for a couple of regions.
Particularly for one of the most noticeable exception region, we found that the
MHD simulation for CR 2113 predicted a model that more closely resemble the
vector tomography inverted magnetic fields. We discuss the utilities and
limitations of the tomographic inversion technique, and present ideas for
future developments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01805</id><created>2015-06-05</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khachaturyan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mekhitarian</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the magnetization process of ferromagnetic materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>In processing</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present article concludes that a ferromagnetic sample could be considered
like a paramagnetic system where the role of magnetic moments plays magnetic
domains. Based on this conclusion and taking into account presence of an
anisotropic field the formula which describes magnetization dependence on the
external magnetic field is derived. Expressions for a remanent magnetization
and a coercive force are presented. The new parameter to characterize a
magnetic stiffness of a material is introduced. A physical expression for a
dynamic magnetic susceptibility as a function of material's characteristics,
external magnetic field, and a temperature is given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08344</id><created>2015-06-27</created><updated>2015-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alinea</keyname><forenames>Allan L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubota</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naylor</keyname><forenames>Wade</forenames></author></authors><title>Logarithmic divergences in the $k$-inflationary power spectra computed
  through the uniform approximation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>version 4 : extended Section 6 on remarks on logarithmic divergences</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 02 (2016) 028</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/02/028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a calculation method for solving the Mukhanov-Sasaki equation
in slow-roll $k$-inflation based on the uniform approximation (UA) in
conjunction with an expansion scheme for slow-roll parameters with respect to
the number of $e$-folds about the so-called \textit{turning point}. Earlier
works on this method has so far gained some promising results derived from the
approximating expressions for the power spectra among others, up to second
order with respect to the Hubble and sound flow parameters, when compared to
other semi-analytical approaches (e.g., Green's function and WKB methods).
However, a closer inspection is suggestive that there is a problem when
higher-order parts of the power spectra are considered; residual logarithmic
divergences may come out that can render the prediction physically
inconsistent. Looking at this possibility, we map out up to what order with
respect to the mentioned parameters several physical quantities can be
calculated before hitting a logarithmically divergent result. It turns out that
the power spectra are limited up to second order, the tensor-to-scalar ratio up
to third order, and the spectral indices and running converge to all orders.
This indicates that the expansion scheme is incompatible with the working
equations derived from UA for the power spectra but compatible with that of the
spectral indices. For those quantities that involve logarithmically divergent
terms in the higher-order parts, existing results in the literature for the
convergent lower-order parts calculated in the equivalent fashion should be
viewed with some caution; they do not rest on solid mathematical ground.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06068</id><created>2015-08-25</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soibelman</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author></authors><title>Cohomological Hall algebras, semicanonical bases and Donaldson-Thomas
  invariants for $2$-dimensional Calabi-Yau categories (with an appendix by Ben
  Davison)</title><categories>math.QA hep-th math.AG math.RT</categories><comments>The revised version contains the Appendix written by Ben Davison
  about the relationship of Kontsevich-Soibelman product with the one of
  Schiffmann-Vasserot</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss semicanonical bases from the point of view of Cohomological Hall
algebras via the &quot;dimensional reduction&quot; from 3-dimensional Calabi-Yau
categories to 2-dimensional ones. Also, we discuss the notion of motivic
Donaldson-Thomas invariants (as defined by M. Kontsevich and Y. Soibelman) in
the framework of 2-dimensional Calabi-Yau categories. In particular we propose
a conjecture which allows one to define Kac polynomials for a 2-dimensional
Calabi-Yau category (this is a theorem of S. Mozgovoy in the case of
preprojective algebras).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04601</id><created>2015-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bianchini</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravanini</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy from Corner Transfer Matrix in Forrester Baxter
  non-unitary RSOS models</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 154005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/15/154005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a Corner Transfer Matrix approach, we compute the bipartite
entanglement R\'enyi entropy in the off-critical perturbations of non-unitary
conformal minimal models realised by lattice spin chains Hamiltonians related
to the Forrester Baxter RSOS models in regime III. This allows to show on a set
of explicit examples that the R\'enyi entropies for non-unitary theories
rescale near criticality as the logarithm of the correlation length with a
coefficient proportional to the effective central charge. This complements a
similar result, recently established for the size rescaling at the critical
point, showing the expected agreement of the two behaviours. We also compute
the first subleading unusual correction to the scaling behaviour, showing that
it is expressible in terms of expansions of various fractional powers of the
correlation length, related to the differences $\Delta-\Delta_{\min}$ between
the conformal dimensions of fields in the theory and the minimal conformal
dimension. Finally, a few observations on the limit leading to the off-critical
logarithmic minimal models of Pearce and Seaton are put forward.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06683</id><created>2015-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Gui-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas</keyname><forenames>Alma. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaquera-Araujo</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valle</keyname><forenames>J. W. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Warped flavor symmetry predictions for neutrino physics</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 2 figues</comments><report-no>IFIC/15-XX</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2016)007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A realistic five-dimensional warped scenario with all standard model fields
propagating in the bulk is proposed. Mass hierarchies would in principle be
accounted for by judicious choices of the bulk mass parameters, while fermion
mixing angles are restricted by a $\Delta(27)$ flavor symmetry broken on the
branes by flavon fields. The latter gives stringent predictions for the
neutrino mixing parameters, and the Dirac CP violation phase, all described in
terms of only two independent parameters at leading order. The scheme also
gives an adequate CKM fit and should be testable within upcoming oscillation
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04318</id><created>2015-10-14</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galleas</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stokman</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On connection matrices of quantum Knizhnik-Zamolodchikov equations based
  on Lie super algebras</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>27 pages; v2: typos fixed and references added; v3: small
  corrections; v4: version accepted for publication in Adv. Stud. Pure Math</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new method to compute connection matrices of quantum
Knizhnik-Zamolodchikov equations associated to integrable vertex models with
super algebra and Hecke algebra symmetries. The scheme relies on decomposing
the underlying spin representation of the affine Hecke algebra in principal
series modules and invoking the known solution of the connection problem for
quantum affine Knizhnik-Zamolodchikov equations associated to principal series
modules. We apply the method to the spin representation underlying the
$\mathcal{U}_q\bigl(\hat{\mathfrak{gl}}(2|1)\bigr)$ Perk-Schultz model. We show
that the corresponding connection matrices are described by an elliptic
solution of a supersymmetric version of the dynamical quantum Yang-Baxter
equation with spectral parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06265</id><created>2015-10-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Dell</keyname><forenames>Zachary E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schweizer</keyname><forenames>Kenneth S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic Theory for the Role of Attractive Forces in the Dynamics of
  Supercooled Liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Accepted to Physical Review Letters. Main Text: 6 pages, 4 figures.
  Supplementary Materials (appended at end of file): 6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.205702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate a microscopic, no adjustable parameter, theory of activated
relaxation in supercooled liquids directly in terms of the repulsive and
attractive forces within the framework of pair correlations. Under isochoric
conditions, attractive forces can nonperturbatively modify slow dynamics, but
at high enough density their influence vanishes. Under isobaric conditions,
attractive forces play a minor role. High temperature apparent Arrhenius
behavior and density-temperature scaling are predicted. Our results are
consistent with recent isochoric simulations and isobaric experiments on a
deeply supercooled molecular liquid. The approach can be generalized to treat
colloidal gelation and glass melting, and other soft matter slow dynamics
problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06924</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xing-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author></authors><title>The longitudinal and transverse distributions of the pion wavefunction
  from the present experimental data on the pion-photon transition form factor</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C76 (2016) no.7, 390</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4236-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is noted that the low-energy behavior of the pion-photon transition form
factor $F_{\pi\gamma}(Q^2)$ is sensitive to the transverse distribution of the
pion wavefunction, and its high-energy behavior is sensitive to the
longitudinal one. Thus a careful study on $F_{\pi\gamma}(Q^2)$ can provide
helpful information on the pion wavefunction precisely. In this paper, we
present a combined analysis of the data on $F_{\pi\gamma}(Q^2)$ reported by the
CELLO, the CLEO, the BABAR and the BELLE collaborations. It is performed by
using the method of least squares. By using the combined measurements of BELLE
and CLEO Collaborations, the pion wavefunction longitudinal and transverse
behavior can be fixed to a certain degree, i.e. we obtain $\beta \in
[0.691,0.757] \rm GeV$ and $B \in [0.00,0.235]$ for $P_{\chi^2} \geq 90\%$,
where $\beta$ and $B$ are two parameters of a convenient pion wavefunction
model whose distribution amplitude can mimic the various longitudinal behavior
under proper choice of parameters. We observe that the CELLO, CLEO and BELLE
data are consistent with each other, all of which prefers the asymptotic-like
distribution amplitude; while the BABAR data prefers a more broad distribution
amplitude, such as the CZ-like one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02649</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Se-Wan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jaehak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Jiyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nha</keyname><forenames>Hyunchul</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum steering of Gaussian states via non-Gaussian measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Published version, 9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 29729 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29729</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum steering---a strong correlation to be verified even when one party or
its measuring device is fully untrusted---not only provides a profound insight
into quantum physics but also offers a crucial basis for practical
applications. For continuous-variable (CV) systems, Gaussian states among
others have been extensively studied, however, mostly confined to Gaussian
measurements. While the fulfillment of Gaussian criterion is sufficient to
detect CV steering, whether it is also necessary for Gaussian states is a
question of fundamental importance in many contexts. This critically questions
the validity of characterizations established only under Gaussian measurements
like the quantification of steering and the monogamy relations. Here, we
introduce a formalism based on local uncertainty relations of non-Gaussian
measurements, which is shown to manifest quantum steering of some Gaussian
states that Gaussian criterion fails to detect. To this aim, we look into
Gaussian states of practical relevance, i.e. two-mode squeezed states under a
lossy and an amplifying Gaussian channel. Our finding significantly modifies
the characteristics of Gaussian-state steering so far established such as
monogamy relations and one-way steering under Gaussian measurements, thus
opening a new direction for critical studies beyond Gaussian regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03981</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Cesar A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disconnected, fragmented, or united? A trans-disciplinary review of
  network science</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During decades the study of networks has been divided between the efforts of
social scientists and natural scientists, two groups of scholars who often do
not see eye to eye. In this review I present an effort to mutually translate
the work conducted by scholars from both of these academic fronts hoping to
continue to unify what has become a diverging body of literature. I argue that
social and natural scientists fail to see eye to eye because they have
diverging academic goals. Social scientists focus on explaining how context
specific social and economic mechanisms drive the structure of networks and on
how networks shape social and economic outcomes. By contrast, natural
scientists focus primarily on modeling network characteristics that are
independent of context, since their focus is to identify universal
characteristics of systems instead of context specific mechanisms. In the
following pages I discuss the differences between both of these literatures by
summarizing the parallel theories advanced to explain link formation and the
applications used by scholars in each field to justify their approach to
network science. I conclude by providing an outlook on how these literatures
can be further unified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06898</id><created>2015-11-21</created><updated>2016-07-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kataev</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molokoedov</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the flavour dependence of the $\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^4)$ correction to
  the relation between running and pole heavy quark masses</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-th</categories><comments>Text a bit modified. Additioinal discusions in favor of the results
  obtained are added in Note Added; extra references added; Modified
  INR-TH-2015-014 preprint, accepted for publication in Euro Phys. J. Plus</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently the four-loop perturbative QCD contributions to the relations
between pole and running masses of charm, bottom and top quarks were evaluated
in the $\rm{\overline{MS}}$-scheme with identical numerical error bars. In this
work the flavour dependence of the $\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^4)$ correction to
these asymptotic series is obtained in the semi-analytical form with the help
of the least squares method. The numerical structure of the corresponding
asymptotic perturbative relations between pole and running $c$, $b$ and
$t$-quark masses is considered and the theoretical errors of the
$\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^4)$-contributions are discussed. The explicit dependence
for these relations on the renormalization scale $\mu^2$ and the flavour number
$n_l$ is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01396</id><created>2015-12-04</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>McClarty</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jegenyes</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaudet</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toccafondi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ossikovski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaurette</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arscott</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowe</keyname><forenames>A. C. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric and chemical components of the giant piezoresistance in
  silicon nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 023102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4955403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A wide variety of apparently contradictory piezoresistance (PZR) behaviors
have been reported in p-type silicon nanowires (SiNW), from the usual positive
bulk effect to anomalous (negative) PZR and giant PZR. The origin of such a
range of diverse phenomena is unclear, and consequently so too is the
importance of a number of parameters including SiNW type (top down or bottom
up), stress concentration, electrostatic field effects, or surface chemistry.
Here we observe all these PZR behaviors in a single set of nominally p-type,
$\langle 110 \rangle$ oriented, top-down SiNWs at uniaxial tensile stresses up
to 0.5 MPa. Longitudinal $\pi$-coefficients varying from $-800\times10^{-11}$
Pa$^{-1}$ to $3000\times10^{-11}$ Pa$^{-1}$ are measured. Micro-Raman
spectroscopy on chemically treated nanowires reveals that stress concentration
is the principal source of giant PZR. The sign and an excess PZR similar in
magnitude to the bulk effect are related to the chemical treatment of the SiNW.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02123</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2016-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#x160;ibali&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Nikola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wade</keyname><forenames>Christopher G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>Charles S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weatherill</keyname><forenames>Kevin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Driven-dissipative many-body systems with mixed power-law interactions:
  Bistabilities and temperature-driven non-equilibrium phase transitions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 94, 011401(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.011401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the non-equilibrium dynamics of a driven-dissipative spin
ensemble with competing power-law interactions. We demonstrate that dynamical
phase transitions as well as bistabilities can emerge for asymptotic van der
Waals interactions, but critically rely on the presence of a slower decaying
potential-core. Upon introducing random particle motion, we show that a finite
gas temperature can drive a phase transition with regards to the spin degree of
freedom and eventually leads to mean-field behaviour in the high-temperature
limit. Our work reconciles contrasting observations of recent experiments with
Rydberg atoms in the cold-gas and hot-vapour domain, and introduces an
efficient theoretical framework in the latter regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01622</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2016-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garrity</keyname><forenames>Kevin F.</forenames></author></authors><title>First principles search for $n$-type oxide, nitride, and sulfide
  thermoelectrics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, plus 10 pages supplementary materials</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045122 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oxides have many potentially desirable characteristics for thermoelectric
applications, including low cost and stability at high temperatures, but thus
far there are few known high $zT$ $n$-type oxide thermoelectrics. In this work,
we use high-throughput first principles calculations to screen transition metal
oxides, nitrides, and sulfides for candidate materials with high power factors
and low thermal conductivity. We find a variety of promising materials, and we
investigate these materials in detail in order to understand the mechanisms
that cause them to have high power factors. These materials all combine a high
density of states near the Fermi level with dispersive bands, reducing the
trade-off between the Seebeck coefficient and the electrical conductivity, but
they do so for several different reasons. In addition, our calculations
indicate that many of our candidate materials have low thermal conductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03356</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>A&#xe7;&#x131;k</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zg&#xfc;r</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ertem</keyname><forenames>&#xdc;mit</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden symmetries and Lie algebra structures from geometric and
  supergravity Killing spinors</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, published version</comments><report-no>EMPG 16-05</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 165002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/16/165002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider geometric and supergravity Killing spinors and the spinor
bilinears constructed out of them. The spinor bilinears of geometric Killing
spinors correspond to the antisymmetric generalizations of Killing vector
fields which are called Killing-Yano forms. They constitute a Lie superalgebra
structure in constant curvature spacetimes. We show that the Dirac currents of
geometric Killing spinors satisfy a Lie algebra structure up to a condition on
2-form spinor bilinears. We propose that the spinor bilinears of supergravity
Killing spinors give way to different generalizations of Killing vector fields
to higher degree forms. It is also shown that those supergravity Killing forms
constitute a Lie algebra structure in six and ten dimensional cases. For five
and eleven dimensional cases, the Lie algebra structure depends on an extra
condition on supergravity Killing forms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03569</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2016-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Hua-Tong</forenames></author></authors><title>Cusps in the quench dynamics of a Bloch state</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>To appear in EPL. New cusps found</comments><journal-ref>EPL 114, 60001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/60001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report some nonsmooth dynamics of a Bloch state in a one-dimensional tight
binding model with the periodic boundary condition. After a sudden change of
the potential of an arbitrary site, quantities like the survival probability of
the particle in the initial Bloch state show cusps periodically, with the
period being the Heisenberg time associated with the energy spectrum. This
phenomenon is a \emph{nonperturbative} counterpart of the nonsmooth dynamics
observed previously (Zhang and Haque, arXiv:1404.4280) in a periodically driven
tight binding model. Underlying the cusps is an exactly solvable model, which
consists of equally spaced levels extending from $-\infty$ to $+\infty $,
between which two arbitrary levels are coupled to each other by the same
strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04521</id><created>2016-01-18</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valentinis</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Marel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthod</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>BCS superconductivity near the band edge: Exact results for one and
  several bands</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 024511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.024511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the problem of a BCS superconductor in the regime where the Fermi
energy is smaller than the Debye energy. This regime is relevant for
low-density superconductors such as SrTiO$_3$ that are not in the BEC limit, as
well as in the problem of &quot;shape resonances&quot; associated with the confinement of
a three-dimensional superconductor. While the problem is not new, exact results
were lacking in the low-density limit. In two dimensions, we find that the
initial rise of the pairing temperature $T_c$ at low density $n$ is nonanalytic
and faster than any power of $n$. In three dimensions, we also find that $T_c$
is nonanalytic, but starts with zero slope at weak coupling and infinite slope
at strong coupling. Self-consistent treatment of the chemical potential and
energy dependence of the density of states are crucial ingredients to obtain
these results. We also present exact results for multiband systems and confirm
our analytical expressions by numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01324</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gulshani</keyname><forenames>Parviz</forenames></author></authors><title>A microscopic nuclear collective rotation-vibration model: 2D submodel</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop in this article a microscopic version of the successful
phenomenological hydrodynamic Bohr-Davydov-Faessler-Greiner (BDFG) model for
the collective rotation-vibration motion of a deformed nucleus. The model
derivation is not limited to small oscillation amplitudes. The model
generalizes the author's previous model to include interaction between
collective oscillations in each pair of spatial directions, and to remove many
of the previous-model approximations. To derive the model, the nuclear
Schrodinger equation is canonically transformed to collective coordinates and
then linearized using a constrained variational method. The associated
transformation constraints are imposed on the wavefunction and not on the
particle co-ordinates. This approach yields four self-consistent, time-reversal
invariant, cranking-type Schrodinger equations for the rotation-vibration and
intrinsic motions, and a self-consistency equation. To facilitate comparison
with the BDFG model, simplify the solution of the equations, and gain physical
insight, we restrict in this article the collective oscillations to only two
space dimensions. For harmonic oscillator mean-field potentials, the equations
are then solved in closed forms and applied to the ground-state rotational
bands in some even-even light and rare-earth nuclei. The computed ground-state
rotational band excitation energy, quadrupole moment and electric quadrupole
transition probabilities are found to agree favourably with measured data and
the results from mean-field, Sp(3,R), and SU(3) models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01457</id><created>2016-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Voronova</keyname><forenames>Nina S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elistratov</keyname><forenames>Andrei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lozovik</keyname><forenames>Yurii E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverted pendulum state of a polariton Rabi oscillator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures (including Supplemental Material)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045413 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exciton-photon beats known as polariton Rabi oscillations in semiconductor
microcavities are usually excited by short pulses of light. We consider a
different pumping scheme, assuming a cw pumping of the Rabi oscillator from an
exciton reservoir. We account for the initial pulse of light setting the phase,
exciton decay due to exciton-phonon and exciton-exciton scattering, photon
leakage, and blueshift of the exciton resonance due to interactions. We find
non-trivial stationary solutions reminiscent of Kapitza pendulum, where
polaritons are accumulated at the upper branch while the lower branch empties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04979</id><created>2016-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>Nzar Rauf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chi-Shung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manolescu</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudmundsson</keyname><forenames>Vidar</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical switching of electron transport in a waveguide-QED system</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages with 6 included eps figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 84, 280 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2016.06.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron switching in waveguides coupled to a photon cavity is found to be
strongly influenced by the photon energy and polarization. Therefore, the
charge dynamics in the system is investigated in two different regimes, for
off- and on-resonant photon fields. In the off-resonant photon field, the
photon energy is smaller than the energy spacing between the first two lowest
subbands of the waveguide system, the charge splits between the waveguides
implementing a $\sqrt{\rm NOT}$-quantum logic gate action. In the on-resonant
photon field, the charge is totally switched from one waveguide to the other
due to the appearance of photon replica states of the first subband in the
second subband region instigating a quantum-NOT transition.In addition, the
importance of the photon polarization to control the charge motion in the
waveguide system is demonstrated.The idea of charge switching in electronic
circuits may serve to built quantum bits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07230</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pershin</keyname><forenames>Yuriy V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Qubit-based memcapacitors and meminductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 6, 014006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.6.014006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that superconducting charge and phase qubits are quantum versions
of memory capacitive and inductive systems, respectively. We demonstrate that
such quantum memcapacitive and meminductive devices offer remarkable and rich
response functionalities. In particular, when subjected to periodic input,
qubit-based memcapacitors and meminductors exhibit unusual hysteresis curves.
Our work not only extends the set of known memcapacitive and meminductive
systems to qubit-based quantum devices but also highlights their unique
properties potentially useful for future technological applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07589</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coslovich</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jack</keyname><forenames>Robert L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of inactive states of a binary Lennard-Jones mixture</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures, contribution to the special issue &quot;The role of
  structure in glassy and jammed systems&quot;. Data underlying this paper are
  available at http://doi.org/10.15125/BATH-00209</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment 2016,
  074012 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/074012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the structure of inactive states in a prototypical model glass, the
Kob-Andersen binary Lennard-Jones mixture. These inactive states are obtained
by transition path sampling and are at dynamical phase coexistence with an
active equilibrium state. Configurations in the inactive states are kinetically
stable and are located in deeper basins of the energy landscape than their
active counterparts. By analyzing trajectory-to-trajectory fluctuations within
the inactive state, we assess correlations between kinetic stability, energy
and other structural properties. We show that measures of local order
associated to stable local packings and bond-orientational order are weakly
correlated with energy and kinetic stability. We discuss what kinds of
structural measurement might capture the relevant dynamical features of the
inactive state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07866</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lazarides</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafi</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Diphoton resonances in a U(1)_{B-L} extension of the minimal
  supesymmetric standard model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages including 2 figures, uses Revtex, version published in
  Physical Review D</comments><report-no>UT-STPD-16/01</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 111702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.111702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by the 750 GeV diphoton state recently reported by ATLAS and CMS, we
propose a U(1)_{B-L} extension of the MSSM which predicts the existence of four
spin zero resonance states that are degenerate in mass in the supersymmetric
limit. Vector-like fields, a gauge singlet field, as well as the MSSM Higgsinos
are prevented from acquiring arbitrary large masses by a U(1) R-symmetry.
Indeed, these masses can be considerably lighter than the Z' gauge boson mass.
Depending on kinematics the resonance states could decay into right handed
neutrinos and sneutrinos, and/or MSSM Higgs fields and Higgsinos with total
decay widths in the multi-GeV range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08093</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiaopeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Dong-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiong-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>S. Das</forenames></author></authors><title>Majorana spintronics</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures, replaced with published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a systematic magnetic-flux-free approach to detect, manipulate and
braid Majorana fermions in a semiconductor nanowire-based topological Josephson
junction by utilizing the Majorana spin degree of freedom. We find an intrinsic
$\pi$-phase difference between spin-triplet pairings enforced by the Majorana
zeros modes (MZMs) at the two ends of a one-dimensional spinful topological
superconductor. This $\pi$-phase is identified to be a spin-dependent
superconducting phase, referred to as the spin-phase, which we show to be
tunable by controlling spin-orbit coupling strength via electric gates. This
electric controllable spin-phase not only affects the coupling energy between
MZMs but also leads to a fractional Josephson effect in the absence of any
applied magnetic flux, which enables the efficient topological qubit readout.
We thus propose an all-electrically controlled superconductor-semiconductor
hybrid circuit to manipulate MZMs and to detect their non-Abelian braiding
statistics properties. Our work on spin properties of topological Josephson
effects potentially opens up a new thrust for spintronic applications with
Majorana-based semiconductor quantum circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01267</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haisch</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kahlhoefer</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tait</keyname><forenames>Tim M. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Mono-W Signatures in Spin-1 Simplified Models</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures; v2: matches published version</comments><report-no>CERN-TH-2016-047, DESY 16-042, UCI-HEP-TR-2016-05</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B760 (2016) 207-213</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.063</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The potential sensitivity to isospin-breaking effects makes LHC searches for
mono-W signatures promising probes of the coupling structure between the
Standard Model and dark matter. It has been shown, however, that the strong
sensitivity of the mono-W channel to the relative magnitude and sign of the
up-type and down-type quark couplings to dark matter is an artefact of
unitarity violation. We provide three different solutions to this mono-W
problem in the context of spin-1 simplified models and briefly discuss the
impact that our findings have on the prospects of mono-W searches at future LHC
runs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02236</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vieira</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezerra</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Class of solutions of the Wheeler-DeWitt equation in the
  Friedmann-Robertson-Walker universe</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94 (2016) 023511</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.023511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the solutions of the Wheeler-DeWitt equation in a homogeneous
and isotropic universe are given by triconfluent Heun functions for the
spatially closed, flat, and open geometries of the Friedmann-Robertson-Walker
universe filled with different forms of energy. In a matter-dominated universe,
we find the polynomial solution and the energy density spectrum. In the cases
of radiation-dominated and vacuum universes, there are no polynomial solutions
as shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02986</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jing-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Chang-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Xue-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yan-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Chen-Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of a portable and fast wire tension measurement system for
  MWPC's construction</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages,12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin.Phy.C.9(2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/9/096201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a multi-wire proportional chamber detector(MWPC), the anode and signal
wires must maintain suitable tensions, which is very important for the
detector's stable and perfect performance. As a result, wire tension control
and measurement is essential in MWPC's construction. The thermal neutron
detector of multi-functional reflectometer at China Spallation Neutron Source
is designed using a high pressure $^{3}$He MWPC detector, and in the
construction of the detector, we developed a wire tension measurement system.
This system is accurate, portable and time-saving. With it, the wires' tension
on a anode wire plane has been tested, the measurement results show that the
wire tension control techniques used in detector manufacture is reliable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03544</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rupprecht</keyname><forenames>Jean-Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe9;nichou</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voituriez</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal search strategies of run-and-tumble walks</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94, 012117 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.012117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The run-and-tumble walk, consisting in randomly reoriented ballistic
excursions, models phenomena ranging from gas kinetics to bacteria motility. We
evaluate the mean time required for this walk to find a fixed target within a
2D or 3D spherical confinement. We find that the mean search time admits a
minimum as a function of the mean run duration for various types of boundary
conditions and run duration distributions (exponential, power-law,
deterministic). Our result stands in sharp contrast to the pure ballistic
motion, which is predicted to be the optimal search strategy in the case of
Poisson distributed targets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04288</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bylicka</keyname><forenames>Bogna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Acin</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Constructive method for detecting the information backflow of bijective
  non-completely-positive-divisible dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Replaces arXiv:1603.04288v1. Error in proof of Lemma 1 for
  non-bijective dynamical maps in [v1]. Results unchanged for bijective
  dynamical maps. 7 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the relation between two approaches to the characterisation of
quantum Markovianity, divisibility and lack of information backflow. We show
that a bijective dynamical map is completely-positive-divisible if and only if
a monotonic non-increase of distinguishability is observed for two equiprobable
states of the evolving system and an ancilla. Moreover our proof is
constructive: given any such map that is not completely-positive-divisible, we
give an explicit construction of two states that, when taken with the same a
priori probability, exhibit information back-flow. Finally, while an ancilla is
necessary for the equivalence to hold in general, we show that it is always
possible to witness the non-Markovianity of bijective maps without using any
entanglement between system and ancilla.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04689</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caux</keyname><forenames>Jean-S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>The Quench Action</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Article for the JSTAT special issue: Quantum Integrability in Out of
  Equilibrium Systems</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 064006</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/06/064006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a pedagogical introduction to the methodology of the Quench Action,
which is an effective representation for the calculation of time-dependent
expectation values of physical operators following a generic out-of-equilibrium
state preparation protocol (for example a quantum quench). The representation,
originally introduced in [Caux and Essler, Phys. Rev. Lett. 110, 257203
(2013)], is founded on a mixture of exact data for overlaps together with
variational reasonings. It is argued to be quite generally valid and
thermodynamically exact for arbitrary times after the quench (from short times
all the way up to the steady state), and applicable to a wide class of
physically relevant observables. Here, we introduce the method and its
language, give an overview of some recent results, suggest a roadmap and offer
some perspectives on possible future research directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05616</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Bellido</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesseris</keyname><forenames>Savvas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trashorras</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational wave source counts at high redshift and in models with
  extra dimensions</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, changes match published version</comments><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-16-028</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP07(2016)021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/07/021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitational wave (GW) source counts have been recently shown to be able to
test how gravitational radiation propagates with the distance from the source.
Here, we extend this formalism to cosmological scales, i.e. the high redshift
regime, and we discuss the complications of applying this methodology to high
redshift sources. We also allow for models with compactified extra dimensions
like in the Kaluza-Klein model. Furthermore, we also consider the case of
intermediate redshifts, i.e. $0&lt;z\lesssim1$, where we show it is possible to
find an analytical approximation for the source counts $\frac{dN}{d(S/N)}$.
This can be done in terms of cosmological parameters, such as the matter
density $\Omega_{m,0}$ of the cosmological constant model or the cosmographic
parameters for a general dark energy model. Our analysis is as general as
possible, but it depends on two important factors: a source model for the black
hole binary mergers and the GW source to galaxy bias. This methodology also
allows us to obtain the higher order corrections of the source counts in terms
of the signal-to-noise $S/N$. We then forecast the sensitivity of future
observations in constraining GW physics but also the underlying cosmology by
simulating sources distributed over a finite range of signal-to-noise with a
number of sources ranging from 10 to 500 sources as expected from future
detectors. We find that with 500 events it will be possible to provide
constraints on the matter density parameter at present $\Omega_{m,0}$ on the
order of a few percent and with the precision growing fast with the number of
events. In the case of extra dimensions we find that depending on the
degeneracies of the model, with 500 events it may be possible to provide
stringent limits on the existence of the extra dimensions if the aforementioned
degeneracies can be broken.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05975</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Araujo</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; C. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coelho</keyname><forenames>Jaziel G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Cesar A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational wave emission by the high braking index pulsar PSR
  J1640-4631</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 07 (2016 ) 023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/07/023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, a braking index for the pulsar PSR J1640-4631 has been measured.
With a braking index of $n = 3.15 \pm 0.03$, this pulsar has the highest
braking index ever measured. As it is well known, a pure magnetic dipole brake
yields $n = 3$, whereas a pure gravitational wave brake yields $n = 5$.
Therefore, each of these mechanisms alone can not account for the braking index
found for PSR J1640-4631. Here we show that such a braking index can be
accounted for if the spindown model combines magnetic dipole and gravitational
wave brakes. Then, we briefly discuss the detectability of this pulsar by aLIGO
and the planned Einstein Telescope. In particular, we show that the amplitude
of the gravitational wave that comes from our model is around a factor four
lower than the amplitude modeled exclusively by gravitational wave energy loss.
Another interesting outcome of our modeling is that we are able to obtain the
ellipticity from the braking index and other pulsar parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06000</id><created>2016-03-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Huan Y. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plavchan</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieke</keyname><forenames>George H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cody</keyname><forenames>Ann Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;th</keyname><forenames>Tina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stauffer</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Covey</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carey</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciardi</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duran-Rojas</keyname><forenames>Maria C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutermuth</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales-Calder&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Mar&#xed;a</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebull</keyname><forenames>Luisa M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>Alan M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photo-reverberation Mapping of a Protoplanetary Accretion Disk around a
  T Tauri Star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables, Accepted for publication in the
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal, 823, 58 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/823/1/58</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretical models and spectroscopic observations of newborn stars suggest
that protoplantary disks have an inner &quot;wall&quot; at a distance set by the disk
interaction with the star. Around T Tauri stars, the size of this disk hole is
expected to be on a 0.1-AU scale that is unresolved by current adaptive optics
imaging, though some model-dependent constraints have been obtained by
near-infrared interferometry. Here we report the first measurement of the inner
disk wall around a solar-mass young stellar object, YLW 16B in the {\rho}
Ophiuchi star-forming region, by detecting the light travel time of the
variable radiation from the stellar surface to the disk. Consistent time lags
were detected on two nights, when the time series in H (1.6 {\mu}m) and K (2.2
{\mu}m) bands were synchronized while the 4.5 {\mu}m emission lagged by 74.5
+/- 3.2 seconds. Considering the nearly edge-on geometry of the disk, the inner
rim should be 0.084 AU from the protostar on average, with an error of order
0.01 AU. This size is likely larger than the range of magnetospheric
truncations, and consistent with an optically and geometrically thick disk
front at the dust sublimation radius at ~1500 K. The widths of the
cross-correlation functions between the data in different wavebands place
possible new constraints on the geometry of the disk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06108</id><created>2016-03-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Chui-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Qi-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Shi-Biao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Crosstalk-insensitive method for simultaneously coupling multiple pairs
  of resonators</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures, accepted by Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a circuit consisting of two or more resonators, the inter-cavity crosstalk
is inevitable, which could create some problems, such as degrading the
performance of quantum operations and the fidelity of various quantum states.
The focus of this work is to propose a crosstalk-insensitive method for
simultaneously coupling multiple pairs of resonators, which is important in
large-scale quantum information processing and communication in a network
consisting of resonators or cavities. In this work, we consider 2N resonators
of different frequencies, which are coupled to a three-level quantum system
(qutrit). By applying a strong pulse to the coupler qutrit, we show that an
effective Hamiltonian can be constructed for simultaneously coupling multiple
pairs of resonators.~The main advantage of this proposal is that the effect of
inter-resonator crosstalks is greatly suppressed by using resonators of
different frequencies. In addition, by employing the qutrit-resonator
dispersive interaction, the intermediate higher-energy level of the qutrit is
virtually excited and thus decoherence from this level is suppressed. This
effective Hamiltonian can be applied to implement quantum operations with
photonic qubits distributed in different resonators. As one application of this
Hamiltonian, we show how to simultaneously generate multiple EPR pairs of
photonic qubits distributed in 2N resonators. Numerical simulations show that
it is feasible to prepare two high-fidelity EPR photonic pairs using a setup of
four one-dimensional transmission line resonators coupled to a superconducting
flux qutrit with current circuit QED technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07159</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-07-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pilnyak</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Istrati</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retzker</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenberg</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Demonstration of quantum error correction for enhanced sensitivity of
  photonic measurements</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012324 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012324</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensitivity of classical and quantum sensing is impaired in a noisy
environment. Thus, one of the main challenges facing sensing protocols is to
reduce the noise while preserving the signal. State of the art quantum sensing
protocols that rely on dynamical decoupling achieve this goal under the
restriction of long noise correlation times. We implement a proof-of-principle
experiment of a protocol to recover sensitivity by using an error correction
for photonic systems that does not have this restriction. The protocol uses a
protected entangled qubit to correct a single error. Our results show a
recovery of about 87% of the sensitivity, independent of the noise rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07278</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rivasseau</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Tensors and Quantum Gravity</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Section 6 is essentially reproduced from author's arXiv:1507.04190
  for self-contained purpose of the review</comments><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 069, 17 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.069</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We provide an informal introduction to tensor field theories and to their
associated renormalization group. We focus more on the general motivations
coming from quantum gravity than on the technical details. In particular we
discuss how asymptotic freedom of such tensor field theories gives a concrete
example of a natural &quot;quantum relativity&quot; postulate: physics in the deep
ultraviolet regime becomes asymptotically more and more independent of any
particular choice of Hilbert basis in the space of states of the universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07634</id><created>2016-03-24</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grundland</keyname><forenames>Alfred Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Decio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martina</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author></authors><title>On immersion formulas for soliton surfaces</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is devoted to a study of the connections between three different
analytic descriptions for the immersion functions of 2D-surfaces corresponding
to the following three types of symmetries: gauge symmetries of the linear
spectral problem, conformal transformations in the spectral parameter and
generalized symmetries of the associated integrable system. After a brief
exposition of the theory of soliton surfaces and of the main tool used to study
classical and generalized Lie symmetries, we derive the necessary and
sufficient conditions under which the immersion formulas associated with these
symmetries are linked by gauge transformations. We illustrate the theoretical
results by examples involving the sigma model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00939</id><created>2016-04-04</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vekua</keyname><forenames>Temo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Gaoyong</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact asymptotic correlation functions of bilinear spin operators of the
  Heisenberg antiferromagnetic spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ chain</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014417 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exact asymptotic expressions of the uniform parts of the two-point
correlation functions of bilinear spin operators in the Heisenberg
antiferromagnetic spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ chain are obtained. Apart from the
algebraic decay, the logarithmic contribution is identified, and the numerical
prefactor is determined. We also confirm numerically the multiplicative
logarithmic correction of the staggered part of the bilinear spin operators
$\langle\langle S^{a}_0S^{a}_{1}S^{b}_{r}S^{b}_{r+1} \rangle\rangle=(-1)^rd/(r
\ln^{\frac{3}{2}}r) +(3\delta_{a,b}-1) \ln^2r /(12 \pi^4 r^4)$, and estimate
the numerical prefactor as $d\simeq 0.067$. The relevance of our results for
ground state fidelity susceptibility at the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless
quantum phase transition points in one-dimensional systems is discussed at the
end of our work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01132</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ponglertsakul</keyname><forenames>Supakchai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winstanley</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>Sam R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of gravitating charged-scalar solitons in a cavity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures, minor changes, accepted for publication in
  Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 024031 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new regular solutions of Einstein-charged scalar field theory in a
cavity. The system is enclosed inside a reflecting mirror-like boundary, on
which the scalar field vanishes. The mirror is placed at the zero of the scalar
field closest to the origin, and inside this boundary our solutions are
regular. We study the stability of these solitons under linear, spherically
symmetric perturbations of the metric, scalar and electromagnetic fields. If
the radius of the mirror is sufficiently large, we present numerical evidence
for the stability of the solitons. For small mirror radius, some of the
solitons are unstable. We discuss the physical interpretation of this
instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02397</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kraft</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>Avi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pendry</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bianisotropy and magnetism in plasmonic gratings</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.6b00206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple design to achieve bianisotropy at visible wavelengths: an
ultrathin plasmonic grating made of a gold grating covered by a thin flat layer
of gold. We show experimentally and through simulations that the grating
exhibits magneto-electric coupling and features asymmetric reflection and
absorption, all that with a device thickness of a tenth of the operating
wavelength. We compared the spectral results and retrieved the effective
material parameters of different polarizations and devices. We show that both
asymmetry and strong coupling between the incoming light and the optically
interacting surfaces are required for obtaining asymmetric optical behavior in
metasurfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03706</id><created>2016-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cornelissen</keyname><forenames>Ludo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>Kevin J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duine</keyname><forenames>Rembert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Gerrit E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Wees</keyname><forenames>Bart J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnon spin transport driven by the magnon chemical potential in a
  magnetic insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014412 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a linear-response transport theory of diffusive spin and heat
transport by magnons in magnetic insulators with metallic contacts. The magnons
are described by a position dependent temperature and chemical potential that
are governed by diffusion equations with characteristic relaxation lengths.
Proceeding from a linearized Boltzmann equation, we derive expressions for
length scales and transport coefficients. For yttrium iron garnet (YIG) at room
temperature we find that long-range transport is dominated by the magnon
chemical potential. We compare the model's results with recent experiments on
YIG with Pt contacts [L.J. Cornelissen, et al., Nat. Phys. 11, 1022 (2015)] and
extract a magnon spin conductivity of $\sigma_{m}=5\times10^{5}$ S/m. Our
results for the spin Seebeck coefficient in YIG agree with published
experiments. We conclude that the magnon chemical potential is an essential
ingredient for energy and spin transport in magnetic insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00484</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-05-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tursunov</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames><affiliation>INP, Tashkent</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kadyrov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames><affiliation>Curtin University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Turakulov</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames><affiliation>INP, Tashkent</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bray</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>Curtin University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Theoretical study of the $\alpha+d$ $\rightarrow$ $^6$Li + $\gamma $
  astrophysical capture process in a three-body model</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94 (2016), 015801</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.015801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The astrophysical capture process $\alpha+d$ $\rightarrow$ $^6$Li + $\gamma$
is studied in a three-body model.
  The initial state is factorized into the deuteron bound state and the
$\alpha+d$ scattering state. The final nucleus $^6$Li(1+) is described as a
three-body bound state $\alpha+n+p$ in the hyperspherical Lagrange-mesh method.
  The contribution of the E1 transition operator from the initial isosinglet
states to the isotriplet components of the final state is estimated to be
negligible. An estimation of the forbidden E1 transition to the isosinglet
components of the final state is comparable with the corresponding results of
the two-body model.
  However, the contribution of the E2 transition operator is found to be much
smaller than the corresponding estimations of the two-body model.
  The three-body model perfectly matches the new experimental data of the LUNA
collaboration with the spectroscopic factor 2.586 estimated from the
bound-state wave functions of $^6$Li and deuteron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01753</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>Abigail L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uttley</keyname><forenames>Phil</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase-Resolved Spectroscopy of Type B Quasi-Periodic Oscillations in GX
  339-4</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS. 17 pages, 12 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new spectral-timing technique for phase-resolved spectroscopy
and apply it to the low-frequency Type B quasi-periodic oscillation (QPO) from
the black hole X-ray binary GX 339-4. We show that on the QPO time-scale the
spectrum changes not only in normalisation, but also in spectral shape. Using
several different spectral models which parameterise the blackbody and
power-law components seen in the time-averaged spectrum, we find that both
components are required to vary, although the fractional rms amplitude of
blackbody emission is small, ~1.4 per cent compared to ~25 per cent for the
power-law emission. However the blackbody variation leads the power-law
variation by ~0.3 in relative phase (~110 degrees), giving a significant break
in the Fourier lag-energy spectrum that our phase-resolved spectral models are
able to reproduce. Our results support a geometric interpretation for the QPO
variations where the blackbody variation and its phase relation to the
power-law are explained by quasi-periodic heating of the approaching and
receding sides of the disc by a precessing Comptonising region. The small
amplitude of blackbody variations suggests that the Comptonising region
producing the QPO has a relatively large scale-height, and may be linked to the
base of the jet, as has previously been suggested to explain the binary orbit
inclination-dependence of Type B QPO amplitudes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03128</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hau</keyname><forenames>L. Ake</forenames></author></authors><title>Spacetimes Coverings and C-Boundary</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Corrections of Cor. 4.11 and Cor. 4.21 (33 pages, 6 figures)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the relation between the c-completion of a Lorentz manifold V and
its quotient M = V/G, where G is an isometry group acting freely and properly
discontinuously. First, we consider the future causal completion case,
characterizing virtually when such a quotient is well behaved with the future
chronological topology and improving the existing results on the literature.
Secondly, we show that under some general assumptions, there exists an
homeomorphism and chronological isomorphism between both, the c-completion of M
and some adequate quotient of the c-completion of V defined by G. Our results
are optimal, as we show in several examples. Finally, we give a practical
application by considering isometric actions over Robertson-Walker spacetimes,
including in particular the Anti-de Sitter model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03185</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Yi</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jun-Xian</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Wei-Min</forenames><affiliation>XMU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yu-Han</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Mao-Chun</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xing-Xing</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Yang</forenames><affiliation>USTC</affiliation></author></authors><title>Simulating the timescale dependent color variation in quasars with a
  revised inhomogeneous disk model</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>20 pages, 18 figures, ApJ accepted</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The UV/optical variability of active galactic nuclei and quasars is useful
for understanding the physics of the accretion disk and is gradually attributed
to the stochastic fluctuations over the accretion disk. Quasars generally
appear bluer when they brighten in the UV/optical, the nature of which remains
controversial. Recently \citeauthor{Sun2014} discovered that the color
variation of quasars is timescale dependent, in the way that faster variations
are even bluer than longer term ones. While this discovery can directly rule
out models that simply attribute the color variation to contamination from the
host galaxies, or to changes in the global accretion rates, it favors the
stochastic disk fluctuation model as fluctuations in the innermost hotter disk
could dominate the short-term variations. In this work, we show that a revised
inhomogeneous disk model, where the characteristic timescales of thermal
fluctuations in the disk are radius-dependent (i.e., $\tau \sim r$; based on
the one originally proposed by \citeauthor{DexterAgol2011}), can well reproduce
a timescale dependent color variation pattern, similar to the observed one and
unaffected by the un-even sampling and photometric error. This demonstrates
that one may statistically use variation emission at different timescales to
spatially resolve the accretion disk in quasars, thus opens a new window to
probe and test the accretion disk physics in the era of time domain astronomy.
Caveats of the current model, which ought to be addressed in future
simulations, are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09084</id><created>2016-05-29</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sellappan</keyname><forenames>Pathikumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garay</keyname><forenames>Javier E.</forenames></author></authors><title>An integrated approach to doped thin films with strain tunable magnetic
  anisotropy: Powder synthesis, target preparation and pulsed laser deposition
  of Bi:YIG</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures. Accepted for publication in Materials Research
  Letters (2016)</comments><doi>10.1080/21663831.2016.1195779</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a synthesis/processing method for fabricating ferrimagnetic
insulator (Bi-doped yttrium iron garnet) thin films with tunable magnetic
anisotropy. Since the desired magnetic properties rely on controllable
thickness and successful doping, we pay attention to the entire
synthesis/processing procedure (nanopowder synthesis, nanocrystalline target
preparation and pulsed laser deposition (PLD)). Atomically flat films were
deposited by PLD on (111)-orientated yttrium aluminum garnet. We show a
significant enhancement of perpendicular anisotropy in the films, caused by
strain-induced anisotropy. In addition, the perpendicular anisotropy is tunable
by decreasing the film thickness and overwhelms the shape anisotropy at a
critical thickness of 3.5 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09325</id><created>2016-05-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kraft</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pendry</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation optics: a time- and frequency-domain analysis of
  electron-energy loss spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b02100</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron energy loss spectroscopy (EELS) and Cathodoluminescence (CL) play a
pivotal role in many of the cutting edge experiments in plasmonics. EELS and CL
experiments are usually supported by numerical simulations, which, whilst
accurate, may not provide as much physical insight as analytical calculations
do. Fully analytical solutions to EELS and CL systems in plasmonics are rare
and difficult to obtain. This paper aims to narrow this gap by introducing a
new method based on Transformation optics that allows to calculate the
quasi-static frequency and time-domain response of plasmonic particles under
electron beam excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02727</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Soszy&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Udalski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szyma&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyrzykowski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulaczyk</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poleski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietrukowicz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koz&#x142;owski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skowron</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skowron</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mr&#xf3;z</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pawlak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The OGLE Collection of Variable Stars. Over 45 000 RR Lyrae Stars in the
  Magellanic System</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Astronomica (2016) 66, 131</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the largest collection of RR Lyrae stars in the Magellanic System
and in its foreground. The sample consists of 45 451 RR Lyr stars, of which 39
082 were detected toward the Large Magellanic Cloud and 6369 toward the Small
Magellanic Cloud. We provide long-term time-series photometric measurements
collected during the fourth phase of the Optical Gravitational Lensing
Experiment (OGLE-IV).
  We discuss several potential astrophysical applications of our collection:
investigation of the structure of the Magellanic Clouds and the Galactic halo,
studies of the globular clusters in the Magellanic System, analysis of
double-mode RR Lyr stars, and search for RR Lyr stars in eclipsing binary
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02853</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02853</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kajuri</keyname><forenames>Nirmalya</forenames></author></authors><title>How is Lorentz Invariance encoded in the Hamiltonian?</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, no figures; v2: Typos corrected, acknowledgement added.
  Changed to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 23 (2016) 1650141</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the disadvantages of the Hamiltonian formulation is that Lorentz
invariance is not manifest in the former. Given a Hamiltonian, there is no
simple way to check whether it is relativistic or not. One would either have to
solve for the equations of motion or calculate the Poisson Brackets of the
Noether charges to perform such a check. In this paper we show that, for a
class of Hamiltonians, it is possible to check Lorentz invariance directly from
the Hamiltonian. Our work is particularly useful for theories where the other
methods may not be readily available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04627</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2016-07-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kao</keyname><forenames>Wil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaplan</keyname><forenames>David L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prince</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Sumin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ene</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Kyu Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levitan</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Shrinivas R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laher</keyname><forenames>Russ R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photometric variability of candidate white dwarf binary systems from
  Palomar Transient Factory archival data</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>MNRAS 461 (2016) 2747-2761</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1434</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a sample of 59 periodic variables from the Palomar Transient
Factory, selected from published catalogues of white dwarf (WD) candidates. The
variability can likely be attributed to ellipsoidal variation of the tidally
distorted companion induced by the gravity of the primary (WD or hot subdwarf)
or to the reflection of hot emission by a cooler companion. We searched 11311
spectroscopically or photometrically selected WD candidates from three hot
star/WD catalogues, using the Lomb-Scargle periodogram to single out promising
sources. We present period estimates for the candidates, 45 of which were not
previously identified as periodic variables, and find that most have a period
shorter than a few days. Additionally, we discuss the eclipsing systems in our
sample and present spectroscopic data on selected sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06735</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buras</keyname><forenames>Andrzej J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Renaissance of Kaon Flavour Physics</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 Figures, invited talk presented at Beauty 16, Marseille,
  France, May 2-6, 2016. To be published in Proceedings of Science.
  FLAVOUR(267104)-ERC-122, V2: One Table, references and clarifying comments
  added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is no doubt that in the coming years we will witness the renaissance of
kaon flavour physics with crucial measurements of the branching ratios for the
rare decays $K^+\rightarrow\pi^+\nu\bar\nu$ and
$K_{L}\rightarrow\pi^0\nu\bar\nu$ that are very sensitive to new physics (NP)
and are theoretically very clean. Simultaneously the role of
$\varepsilon'/\varepsilon$, $\varepsilon_K$, $\Delta M_K$, $K_L\to\mu^+\mu^-$
and $K_L\to\pi^0\ell^+\ell^-$ in searching for NP will significantly increase
through their improved estimates within the SM. In fact the hints for NP
contributing to $\varepsilon'/\varepsilon$ have been signalled last year
through improved estimates of hadronic matrix elements of QCD and electroweak
penguin operators $Q_6$ and $Q_8$ by lattice QCD and large $N$ dual QCD
approach. Also recent increased tensions between $\varepsilon_K$ and $\Delta
M_{s,d}$ mass differences in $B_{s,d}^0-\bar B_{s,d}^0$ mixing within the SM
and models with constrained MFV tell us that we should have tremendous fun in
chasing NP through all these observables. The present talk discusses the hinted
anomalies in $\varepsilon'/\varepsilon$,and $\Delta F=2$ transitions and
summarizes possible implications of simultaneous anomalies in
$\varepsilon'/\varepsilon$ and $\varepsilon_K$ for
$K^+\rightarrow\pi^+\nu\bar\nu$ and $K_{L}\rightarrow\pi^0\nu\bar\nu$ and
$\Delta M_K$ in models with tree-level $Z$ and $Z^\prime$ exchanges. The
anomalies in $\varepsilon'/\varepsilon$ and $\varepsilon_K$, if confirmed,
would signal new sources of CP violation. This is in contrast to the recent
anomalies in $B$ physics that signal lepton flavour non-universalities and NP
in CP-conserving observables. Highlights from recent flavour analyses of 331
models are briefly described.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07700</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grollier</keyname><forenames>Julie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Querlioz</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stiles</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spintronic nano-devices for bio-inspired computing</title><categories>cs.ET cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bio-inspired hardware holds the promise of low-energy, intelligent and highly
adaptable computing systems. Applications span from automatic classification
for big data management, through unmanned vehicle control, to control for
bio-medical prosthesis. However, one of the major challenges of fabricating
bio-inspired hardware is building ultra-high density networks out of complex
processing units interlinked by tunable connections. Nanometer-scale devices
exploiting spin electronics (or spintronics) can be a key technology in this
context. In particular, magnetic tunnel junctions are well suited for this
purpose because of their multiple tunable functionalities. One such
functionality, non-volatile memory, can provide massive embedded memory in
unconventional circuits, thus escaping the von-Neumann bottleneck arising when
memory and processors are located separately. Other features of spintronic
devices that could be beneficial for bio-inspired computing include tunable
fast non-linear dynamics, controlled stochasticity, and the ability of single
devices to change functions in different operating conditions. Large networks
of interacting spintronic nano-devices can have their interactions tuned to
induce complex dynamics such as synchronization, chaos, soliton diffusion,
phase transitions, criticality, and convergence to multiple metastable states.
A number of groups have recently proposed bio-inspired architectures that
include one or several types of spintronic nanodevices. In this article we show
how spintronics can be used for bio-inspired computing. We review the different
approaches that have been proposed, the recent advances in this direction, and
the challenges towards fully integrated spintronics-CMOS (Complementary metal -
oxide - semiconductor) bio-inspired hardware.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08917</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niwa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikado</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shamoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarrige</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant inelastic x-ray scattering study of entangled spin-orbital
  excitations in superconducting PrFeAsO0.7</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 035134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.035134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-energy electron excitation spectra were measured on a single crystal of a
typical iron-based superconductor PrFeAsO$_{0.7}$ using resonant inelastic
X-ray scattering (RIXS) at the Fe-$L_3$ edge. Characteristic RIXS features are
clearly observed around 0.5, 1-1.5 and 2-3 eV energy losses. These excitations
are analyzed microscopically with theoretical calculations using a 22-orbital
model derived from first-principles electronic structure calculation. Based on
the agreement with the experiment, the RIXS features are assigned to Fe-$d$
orbital excitations which, at low energies, are accompanied by spin flipping
and dominated by Fe $d_{yz}$ and $d_{xz}$ orbital characters. Furthermore, our
calculations suggest dispersive momentum dependence of the RIXS excitations
below 0.5 eV, and predict remarkable splitting and merging of the lower-energy
excitations in momentum space. Those excitations, which were not observed in
the present experiment, highlight the potential of RIXS with an improved energy
resolution to unravel new details of the electronic structure of the iron-based
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09172</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hodos&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Gabriella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helling</keyname><forenames>Christiane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asensio-Torres</keyname><forenames>Rub&#xe9;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorgul</keyname><forenames>Irena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rimmer</keyname><forenames>Paul B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lightning climatology of exoplanets and brown dwarfs guided by Solar
  System data</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>References updated, typos fixed. 24 pages, 7 figures, 7 tables,
  accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1571</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Clouds form on extrasolar planets and brown dwarfs where lightning could
occur. Lightning is a tracer of atmospheric convection, cloud formation and
ionization processes as known from the Solar System, and may be significant for
the formation of prebiotic molecules. We study lightning climatology for the
different atmospheric environments of Earth, Venus, Jupiter and Saturn. We
present lightning distribution maps for Earth, Jupiter and Saturn, and flash
densities for these planets and Venus, based on optical and/or radio
measurements from the WWLLN and STARNET radio networks, the LIS/OTD satellite
instruments, the Galileo, Cassini, New Horizons and Venus Express spacecraft.
We also present flash densities calculated for several phases of two volcano
eruptions, Eyjafjallaj\&quot;okull's (2010) and Mt Redoubt's (2009). We estimate
lightning rates for sample, transiting and directly imaged extrasolar planets
and brown dwarfs. Based on the large variety of exoplanets, six categories are
suggested for which we use the lightning occurrence information from the Solar
System. We examine lightning energy distributions for Earth, Jupiter and
Saturn. We discuss how strong stellar activity may support lightning activity.
We provide a lower limit of the total number of flashes that might occur on
transiting planets during their full transit as input for future studies. We
find that volcanically very active planets might show the largest lightning
flash densities. When applying flash densities of the large Saturnian storm
from 2010/11, we find that the exoplanet HD 189733b would produce high
lightning occurrence even during its short transit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09254</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bourne</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunne</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maddox</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dye</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furlanetto</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoyos</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>D. J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eales</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>M. W. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valiante</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alpaslan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrae</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldry</keyname><forenames>I. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cluver</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooray</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Driver</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlop</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grootes</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivison</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarrett</keyname><forenames>T. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liske</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madore</keyname><forenames>B. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popescu</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robotham</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowlands</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seibert</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuffs</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viaene</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Herschel-ATLAS Data Release 1 Paper II: Multi-wavelength
  counterparts to submillimetre sources</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1654</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is the second in a pair of articles presenting data release 1
(DR1) of the Herschel Astrophysical Terahertz Large Area Survey (H-ATLAS), the
largest single open-time key project carried out with the Herschel Space
Observatory. The H-ATLAS is a wide-area imaging survey carried out in five
photometric bands at 100, 160, 250, 350 and 500$\mu$m covering a total area of
600deg$^2$. In this paper we describe the identification of optical
counterparts to submillimetre sources in DR1, comprising an area of 161 deg$^2$
over three equatorial fields of roughly 12$^\circ$x4.5$^\circ$ centred at
9$^h$, 12$^h$ and 14.5$^h$ respectively. Of all the H-ATLAS fields, the
equatorial regions benefit from the greatest overlap with current
multi-wavelength surveys spanning ultraviolet (UV) to mid-infrared regimes, as
well as extensive spectroscopic coverage. We use a likelihood-ratio technique
to identify SDSS counterparts at r&lt;22.4 for 250-$\mu$m-selected sources
detected at $\geq$ 4$\sigma$ ($\approx$28mJy). We find `reliable' counterparts
(reliability R$\geq$0.8) for 44,835 sources (39 per cent), with an estimated
completeness of 73.0 per cent and contamination rate of 4.7 per cent. Using
redshifts and multi-wavelength photometry from GAMA and other public
catalogues, we show that H-ATLAS-selected galaxies at $z&lt;0.5$ span a wide range
of optical colours, total infrared (IR) luminosities, and IR/UV ratios, with no
strong disposition towards mid-IR-classified AGN in comparison with optical
selection. The data described herein, together with all maps and catalogues
described in the companion paper (Valiante et al. 2016), are available from the
H-ATLAS website at www.h-atlas.org.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09289</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09289</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rottoli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Fitting EMC structure functions with intrinsic charm</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. To appear in the proceedings of the XXIV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects,
  11-15 April, 2016, DESY Hamburg, Germany. v2: added one reference and
  corrected figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed study of the impact of the data collected by the European Muon
Collaboration (EMC) on the parton distribution function (PDF) of the charm
quark is presented. The analysis is performed in the NNPDF framework, and the
charm PDF is freely parametrized on equal footing as light quark and gluon
distributions. We find that variations in the treatment of EMC data do not
modify the charm PDF and do not affect our previous conclusion on the presence
of an intrinsic component in the charm PDF.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01182</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bilicki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peacock</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarrett</keyname><forenames>T. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cluver</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maddox</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>M. J. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hambly</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solarz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holwerda</keyname><forenames>B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldry</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loveday</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moffett</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Driver</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alpaslan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>WISE x SuperCOSMOS photometric redshift catalog: 20 million galaxies
  over 3pi steradians</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Data available from http://ssa.roe.ac.uk/WISExSCOS</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, Volume 225, Number 1
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/225/1/5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We cross-match the two currently largest all-sky photometric catalogs,
mid-infrared WISE and SuperCOSMOS scans of UKST/POSS-II photographic plates, to
obtain a new galaxy sample that covers 3pi steradians. In order to characterize
and purify the extragalactic dataset, we use external GAMA and SDSS
spectroscopic information to define quasar and star loci in multicolor space,
aiding the removal of contamination from our extended-source catalog. After
appropriate data cleaning we obtain a deep wide-angle galaxy sample that is
approximately 95% pure and 90% complete at high Galactic latitudes. The catalog
contains close to 20 million galaxies over almost 70% of the sky, outside the
Zone of Avoidance and other confused regions, with a mean surface density of
over 650 sources per square degree. Using multiwavelength information from two
optical and two mid-IR photometric bands, we derive photometric redshifts for
all the galaxies in the catalog, using the ANNz framework trained on the final
GAMA-II spectroscopic data. Our sample has a median redshift of z_{med} = 0.2
but with a broad dN/dz reaching up to z&gt;0.4. The photometric redshifts have a
mean bias of |delta_z|~10^{-3}, normalized scatter of sigma_z = 0.033 and less
than 3% outliers beyond 3sigma_z. Comparison with external datasets shows no
significant variation of photo-z quality with sky position. Together with the
overall statistics, we also provide a more detailed analysis of photometric
redshift accuracy as a function of magnitudes and colors. The final catalog is
appropriate for `all-sky' 3D cosmology to unprecedented depths, in particular
through cross-correlations with other large-area surveys. It should also be
useful for source pre-selection and identification in forthcoming surveys such
as TAIPAN or WALLABY.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02394</id><created>2016-07-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Tricco</keyname><forenames>Terrence S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bate</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained hyperbolic divergence cleaning in smoothed particle
  magnetohydrodynamics with variable cleaning speeds</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>23 pages, 16 figures, accepted for publication in Journal of
  Computational Physics</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.06.053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an updated constrained hyperbolic/parabolic divergence cleaning
algorithm for smoothed particle magnetohydrodynamics (SPMHD) that remains
conservative with wave cleaning speeds which vary in space and time. This is
accomplished by evolving the quantity $\psi / c_h$ instead of $\psi$. Doing so
allows each particle to carry an individual wave cleaning speed, $c_h$, that
can evolve in time without needing an explicit prescription for how it should
evolve, preventing circumstances which we demonstrate could lead to runaway
energy growth related to variable wave cleaning speeds. This modification
requires only a minor adjustment to the cleaning equations and is trivial to
adopt in existing codes. Finally, we demonstrate that our constrained
hyperbolic/parabolic divergence cleaning algorithm, run for a large number of
iterations, can reduce the divergence of the field to an arbitrarily small
value, achieving $\nabla \cdot B=0$ to machine precision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04269</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Szolnoki</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perc</keyname><forenames>Matjaz</forenames></author></authors><title>Zealots tame oscillations in the spatial rock-paper-scissors game</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>6 two-column pages, 4 figures; accepted for publication in Physical
  Review E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93 (2016) 062307</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.062307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rock-paper-scissors game is a paradigmatic model for biodiversity, with
applications ranging from microbial populations to human societies. Research
has shown, however, that mobility jeopardizes biodiversity by promoting the
formation of spiral waves, especially if there is no conservation law in place
for the total number of competing players. Firstly, we show that even if such a
conservation law applies, mobility still jeopardizes biodiversity in the
spatial rock-paper-scissors game if only a small fraction of links of the
square lattice is randomly rewired. Secondly, we show that zealots are very
effective in taming the amplitude of oscillations that emerge due to mobility
and/or interaction randomness, and this regardless of whether the later is
quenched or annealed. While even a tiny fraction of zealots brings significant
benefits, at 5\% occupancy zealots practically destroy all oscillations
regardless of the intensity of mobility, and regardless of the type and
strength of randomness in the interaction structure. Interestingly, by annealed
randomness the impact of zealots is qualitatively the same as by mobility,
which highlights that fast diffusion does not necessarily destroy the
coexistence of species, and that zealotry thus helps to recover the stable
mean-field solution. Our results strengthen the important role of zealots in
models of cyclic dominance, and they reveal fascinating evolutionary outcomes
in structured populations that are a unique consequence of such uncompromising
behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04274</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Merxhani</keyname><forenames>Andi</forenames></author></authors><title>An introduction to linear poroelasticity</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This study is an introduction to the theory of three-dimensional
consolidation. The point of departure in the description are the basic
equations of elasticity (i.e. constitutive law, equations of equilibrium in
terms of stresses, and the definition of strain), together with the principle
of effective stress, and the law of Darcy for fluid flow in porous media. These
equations, together with the principle of mass conservation, are the only
premises used to derive a drained description of consolidation theory. Next,
the increment of fluid content is defined and its constitutive law is derived -
with its derivation following naturally from the equation of fluid mass
balance. Pore pressure, storage, and undrained coefficients are also introduced
and useful relations are proven. Where appropriate, the physical meaning of
these coefficients is proven mathematically. Equations of equilibrium and fluid
mass conservation are subsequently expressed in terms of the increment of fluid
content and undrained coefficients, leading to an undrained description of
consolidation theory. Thus the initial approach of using drained description is
extended to the formalism of Rice and Cleary. This approach to
three-dimensional consolidation is useful for its simplicity. It does not
require the ad-hoc definition of constants and that of an elastic energy
potential. Instead, it is a direct extension to linear elasticity that accounts
for the coupling of skeletal deformations and fluid behaviour.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04302</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hawley</keyname><forenames>Suzanne L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angus</keyname><forenames>Ruth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzasi</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davenport</keyname><forenames>James R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giampapa</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashyap</keyname><forenames>Vinay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meibom</keyname><forenames>Soren</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximizing Science in the Era of LSST, Stars Study Group Report:
  Rotation and Magnetic Activity in the Galactic Field Population and in Open
  Star Clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the stars chapter of the Kavli workshop report, which resulted from
the community-based study of needed US OIR capabilities in the LSST era. The
full report, which will include this chapter, is anticipated to be available in
Fall 2016. See NOAO website (http://www.noao.edu/meetings/lsst-oir-study/) for
more details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04305</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sesto</keyname><forenames>Leandro A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faifer</keyname><forenames>Favio R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forte</keyname><forenames>Juan C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The complex star cluster system of NGC 1316 (Fornax A)</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1627</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents Gemini-$gri'$ high quality photometry for cluster
candidates in the field of NGC 1316 (Fornax A) as part of a study that also
includes GMOS spectroscopy. A preliminary discussion of the photometric data
indicates the presence of four stellar cluster populations with distinctive
features in terms of age, chemical abundance and spatial distribution. Two of
them seem to be the usually old (metal poor and metal rich) populations
typically found in elliptical galaxies. In turn, an intermediate-age (5 Gyr)
globular cluster population is the dominant component of the sample (as
reported by previous papers). We also find a younger cluster population with a
tentative age of $\approx$ 1 Gyr.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04308</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Marquet</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments on &quot;Isentropic Analysis of a Simulated Hurricane&quot;</title><categories>physics.ao-ph physics.flu-dyn physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 color Figures, 2 Tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes Comments to the paper of Mrowiec et al. published in the
J. Atmos. Sci. in May 2016 (Vol 73, Issue 5, pages 1857-1870) and entitled
&quot;Isentropic analysis of a simulated hurricane&quot;.
  It is explained that the plotting of isentropic surfaces (namely the
isentropes) requires a precise definition of the specific moist-air entropy,
and that most of existing &quot;equivalent potential temperatures&quot; lead to
inaccurate definitions of isentropes.
  It is shown that the use of the third law of thermodynamics leads to a
definition of the specific moist-air entropy (and of a corresponding potential
temperature) which allow the plotting of unambigous moist-air isentropes.
  Numerical applications are shown by using a numerical simulation of the
hurricane DUMILE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04312</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kundys</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roulland</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lefevre</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meny</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomasson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viart</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Room temperature polarization in the ferrimagnetic Ga2-xFexO3 ceramics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Multiferroic GaFeO3</comments><journal-ref>J. Eur. Ceram. Soc. 35, 2277(2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2015.02.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of the Fe-Ga ratio on the magnetic and electric properties of the
multiferroic Ga2-xFexO3 compound has been studied in order to determine the
composition range exhibiting magnetic and electric orders coexistence and their
critical temperatures. A magnetoelectric phase diagram, showing the evolution
of both the Neel magnetic ordering temperature and the electric ordering
temperature, versus the iron content has been established for x values between
0.9 and 1.4. While the ferrimagnetic Neel temperature increases with the iron
content, the electric ordering temperature shows an opposite trend. The
electric polarization has been found to exist far above room temperature for
the x value of 1.1 composition which shows the highest observed electric
ordering temperature of approx. 580K. The compounds with x values of 1.3 and
1.4 are ferrimagnetic-electric relaxors with both properties coexisting at room
temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04329</id><created>2016-07-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Farook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Nupur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Ayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Saibal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usmani</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Finslerian wormhole models</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages and 7 figues</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:246</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4066-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present models of wormhole under the Finslerian structure of spacetime.
This is a sequel of our previous work (Eur Phys J 75:564, 2015) where we
constructed a toy model for compact stars based on the Finslerian spacetime
geometry. In the present investigation, a wide variety of solutions are
obtained that explore wormhole geometry by considering different choices for
the form function and energy density. The solutions, like the previous work,
are revealed to be physically interesting and viable models for the explanation
of wormholes as far as the background theory and literature are concerned.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04349</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04349</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Si Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amili</keyname><forenames>Abdelkrim El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallini</keyname><forenames>Felipe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fainman</keyname><forenames>Yeshaiahu</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic Hysteresis Probes High-{\beta} Nanolaser Emission Regimes</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quest for an integrated light source that promises high energy efficiency
and fast modulation for high-performance photonic circuits has led to the
development of room-temperature telecom-wavelength nanoscale laser with high
spontaneous emission factors, \beta. The coherence characterization of this
type of lasers is inherently difficult with the conventional measurement of
output light intensity versus input pump intensity due to the diminishing kink
in the measurement curve. We demonstrate the transition from chaotic to
coherent emission of a high-{\beta} pulse-pump metallo-dielectric nanolaser can
be determined by examining the width of a second order intensity correlation
peak, which shrinks below and broadens above threshold. Photon fluctuation
study, first one ever reported for this type of nanolaser, confirms the
validity of this measurement technique. Additionally, we show that the width
variation above threshold results from the delayed threshold phenomenon,
providing the first indirect observation of dynamical hysteresis in a
nanolaser.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04356</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Shikun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Zhaoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Lisen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yap</keyname><forenames>Lee Koon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Tiejun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagopoulos</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author></authors><title>A versatile rotary-stage high frequency probe station for studying
  magnetic films and devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages,8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rev.Sci.Instrum.87,074704(2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4958036</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a rotary-stage microwave probe station suitable for magnetic films
and spintronic devices. Two stages, one for field rotation from parallel to
perpendicular to the sample plane (Out-of-Plane) and the other intended for
field rotation within the sample plane (In-Plane) have been designed. The
sample, probes and micro positioners are rotated simultaneously with the
stages, which allows the field orientation to cover $\theta$ from 0 to
$90^{\circ}$ and $\varphi$ from 0 to $360^{\circ}$. $\theta$ and $\varphi$
being the angle between the direction of current flow and field in a
Out-of-Plane and an In-Plane rotation, respectively. The operation frequency is
up to 40 GHz and the magnetic field up to 1 T. The sample holder, vision system
and probe assembly are compactly designed for the probes to land on a wafer
with diameter up to 3$\,$cm. Using homemade multi-pin probes and commercially
available high frequency probes, several applications including 4-probe DC
measurements, the determination of domain wall velocity and spin transfer
torque ferromagnetic resonance are demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04369</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zanzi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum mechanics before the big bang in heterotic-M-theory</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter we investigate the role played by quantum mechanics before the
big-bang in heterotic-M-theory assuming an orbifold compactification of time.
As we will see particles are localized around a black hole but only in regions
where a constructive quantum interference takes place. We infer that the
creation of this interference pattern is interesting for many reasons: (A) it
is a mechanism to localize particles on $S^4$ branes; (B) the Casimir potential
for the dilaton can be interpreted as a gravitational effective potential for a
two-body problem; (C) the quantum interference is a new way to define the
branes in heterotic-M-theory. Remarkably, a modified Schroedinger equation is
obtained. The stabilization of the branes' position is related to the absence
of a cosmological singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04380</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Sijing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Weijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Lixing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yidong</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-photon stimulated four wave mixing at telecom band</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-photon stimulated four wave mixing (StFWM) processes have great
potential for photonic quantum information processing, compatible with optical
communication technologies and integrated optoelectronics. In this paper, we
demonstrate single-photon StFWM process in a piece of optical fiber, with
seeded photons generated by spontaneous four wave mixing process (SpFWM). The
effect of the single-photon StFWM is confirmed by time-resolved four-photon
coincidence measurement and variation of four-photon coincidence counts under
different seed-pump delays. According to the experiment results, the potential
performance of quantum cloning machine based on the process is analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04391</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Jian-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Jia-ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Dirac semimetal phases in InSb/$\alpha$-Sn semiconductor
  superlattices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate theoretically the coexistence of Dirac semimetal and
topological insulator phases in InSb/$\alpha$-Sn conventional semiconductor
superlattices, based on advanced first-principles calculations combined with
low-energy $k\cdot p$ theory. By proper interfaces designing, a large interface
polarization emerges when the growth direction is chosen along {[}111{]}. Such
an intrinsic polarized electrostatic field reduces band gap largely and invert
the band structure finally, leading to emerge of the topological Dirac
semimetal phase with a pair of Dirac nodes appearing along the (111)
crystallographic direction near the $\Gamma$ point. The surface states and
Fermi arc are clearly observed in (100) projected surface. In addition, we also
find a two-dimensional topological insulator phase with large nontrivial band
gap approaching 70 meV, which make it possible to observe the quantum spin Hall
effect at room temperature. Our proposal paves a way to realize topological
nontrivial phases coexisted in conventional semiconductor superlattices by
proper interface designing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04396</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Taeyoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Phillial</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous symmetry breaking in 5D conformally invariant gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>1+12 pages, 1 figure, accepted for publication in Adv.High Energy
  physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the possibility of the spontaneous symmetry breaking in 5D
conformally invariant gravity, whose action consists of a scalar field
nonminimally coupled to the curvature with its potential. Performing
dimensional reduction via ADM decomposition, we find that the model allows an
exact solution giving rise to the 4D Minkowski vacuum. Exploiting the conformal
invariance with Gaussian warp factor, we show that it also admits a solution
which implement the spontaneous breaking of conformal symmetry. We investigate
its stability by performing the tensor perturbation and find the resulting
system is described by the conformal quantum mechanics. Possible applications
to the spontaneous symmetry breaking of time-translational symmetry along the
dynamical fifth direction and the brane-world scenario are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04413</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kristoffel</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>On quantum critical destruction of the pseudogap phase</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent data on the critical events accompanying the quenching of the
pseudogap (PG) phase in hole-doped cuprates are analysed. An original multiband
model with the spectrum influenced by doping has been used. Two critical
dopings are expected in evolving of the PG to destruction. The first of them
corresponds to metallization (antinodal) of the sample. Extended doping leads
to a second critical point where the PG is lost. In between the restoration of
the full Fermi surface proceeds. Band overlaps besides the location of the
chemical potential ({\mu}) are decisive.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04426</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Stoica</keyname><forenames>Sabin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirea</keyname><forenames>Mihail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nitescu</keyname><forenames>Ovidiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nabi</keyname><forenames>Jameel-Un</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishfaq</keyname><forenames>Mavra</forenames></author></authors><title>New phase space calculations for beta-decay half-lives</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the computation of the phase space factors (PSF) involved in the
positron decay and electron capture (EC) processes for a large number of nuclei
of experimental interest. To obtain the electron/positron wave functions needed
in computation, we develop a code for solving accurately the Dirac equation
with a nuclear potential derived from a realistic proton density distribution
in the nucleus. The finite nuclear size (FNS) and screening effects are
included through recipes which differ from those used in previous calculations.
Comparing our results with former calculations employing approximate methods
but computed with the same Q-values, we find a close agreement for positron
decays, while for the EC process there are relevant differences. For the EC
process we also find that the screening effect has a notable influence on the
computed PSF values specially for light nuclei. Further, we re-computed the
same PSF values but using the most recent Q-values reported in literature. In
several cases these new Q-values differ significantly from the older ones,
which results in large differences in the PSF values as compared with previous
results. These new PSF values proposed here, can contribute to a more reliable
calculation of the beta decay rates, which are key quantities in the study of
nuclei far from the stability line, as well as to better understanding of the
stellar evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04432</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Elyasi</keyname><forenames>Mehrdad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Hyunsoo</forenames></author></authors><title>Optically induced spin-dependent diffusive transport in the presence of
  spin-orbit interaction for all-optical magnetization reversal</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 024417 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.024417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have considered the effect of different spin-orbit interaction mechanisms
on the process of demagnetization under the influence of short-pulse lasers.
All-optical magnetization reversal of perpendicularly magnetized thin films can
occur if there are sufficient strong spin-Hall, skew scattering, and Rashba
interactions. In the presence of spin-orbit interactions, the transient charge
currents provide the generation of transverse-spin currents and accumulations,
which eventually exert spin-transfer torque on the magnetization. By combining
the optically excited spin-dependent diffusive transport with the spin and
charge currents due to skew scattering, spin-Hall, inverse spin-Hall and Rashba
interactions, into a numerical model, we demonstrate a possibility of
ultra-fast all-optical magnetization reversal. This understanding provokes
intriguing, more in-depth experimental studies on the role of spin-orbit
interaction mechanisms in optimizing structures for all-optical magnetization
reversal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04437</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozansoy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ar&#x131;</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc7;etinkaya</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for excited spin-3/2 neutrinos at LHeC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures, 5 Tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the potential of the next $ep$ collider, namely LHeC, with two
options $\sqrt{s}=1.3$ TeV $\sqrt{s}=1.98$ TeV, to search for excited spin-1/2
and spin-3/2 neutrinos. We calculate the single production cross section of
excited spin-1/2 and spin-3/2 neutrinos according to their effective currents
describing their interactions between gauge bosons and SM leptons. We choose
the $\nu^{\star}\rightarrow eW$ decay mode of excited neutrinos and
$W\rightarrow jj$ decay mode of $W$-boson for the analysis. We put some
kinematical cuts for the final state detectable particles and plot the
invariant mass distributions for signal and the corresponding backgrounds. In
order to obtain accessible limits for excited neutrino couplings, we show the
$f-f^{\prime}$ and $c_{iV}-c_{iA}$ contour plots for excited spin-1/2 and
excited spin-3/2 neutrinos, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04438</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Linjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrell</keyname><forenames>Eoin C. T. O</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loh</keyname><forenames>Kianping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eda</keyname><forenames>Goki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozyilmaz</keyname><forenames>Barbaros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>Antonio H. Castro</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling many-body states by the electric-field effect in a
  two-dimensional material</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>22 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature 529,185 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature16175</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To understand complex physics of a system with strong electron electron
interactions, it is ideal to control and monitor its properties while tuning an
external electric field applied to the system. Indeed, complete electric field
control of many body states in strongly correlated electron systems is
fundamental to the next generation of condensed matter research and devices.
However, the material must be thin enough to avoid shielding of the electric
field in bulk material. Two-dimensional materials do not experience electrical
screening, and their charge carrier density can be controlled by gating. 1T
TiSe2 is a prototypical 2D material that shows charge density wave(CDW) and
superconductivity in its phase diagram, presenting several similarities with
other layered systems such as copper oxides, iron pnictides, crystals of
rare-earth and actinide atoms. By studying 1T TiSe2 single crystals with
thicknesses of 10 nm or less, encapsulated in 2D layers of hexagonal boron
nitride, we achieve unprecedented control over the CDW transition temperature,
tuned from 170 K to 40 K, and over the superconductivity transition
temperature, tuned from a quantum critical point at 0 K up to 3 K. Electrically
driving TiSe2 over different ordered electronic phases allows us to study the
details of the phase transitions between many-body states. Observations of
periodic oscillations of magnetoresistance induced by the Little Parks effect
show that the appearance of superconductivity is directly correlated to the
spatial texturing of the amplitude and phase of the superconductivity order
parameter, corresponding to a 2D matrix of superconductivity. We infer that
this superconductivity matrix is supported by a matrix of incommensurate CDW
states embedded in the commensurate CDW states. Our results show that spatially
modulated electronic states are fundamental to the appearance of 2D
superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04440</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Maciula</keyname><forenames>Rafal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczurek</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for walking technipion in four-jet sample</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss how to search for a possibe signal of the recently observed 750
GeV enhancement in the diphoton channel in the four-jet production. In the
present studies we assume that the produced state is pseudoscalar. This fact,
when combined with specificity of the corresponding amplitude, allows to
improve the signal-to-background (S/B) ratio. We discuss in detail how to
impose cuts on jets in rapidity and transverse momenta in order to find optimal
S/B ratio and not to loose too much statistics. Our study suggest a measurement
of two soft (low cut on $p_t$) large-rapidity jets and two hard (high cut on
$p_t$) mid-rapidity jets. Azimuthal correlation between the soft external jets
may be useful to further improve the situation. Several differential
distributions in rapidities and transverse momenta of jets as well as dijet
invariant mass are shown. The integrated cross sections corresponding to
different cuts are collected in a table and number of events are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04473</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Wei-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavan</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>(Anti-) de Sitter Electrically Charged Black Hole Solutions in
  Higher-Derivative Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters, 114, 60006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/60006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, static electrically charged black hole solutions with
cosmological constant are investigated in an Einstein-Hilbert theory of gravity
with additional quadratic curvature terms. Beside the analytic Schwarzschild
(Anti-) de Sitter solutions, non-Schwarzschild (Anti-) de Sitter solutions are
also obtained numerically by employing the shooting method. The results show
that there exist two groups of asymptotically (Anti-) de Sitter spacetimes for
both charged and uncharged black holes. In particular, it was found that for
uncharged black holes the first group can be reduced to the Schwarzschild
(Anti-) de Sitter solution, while the second group is intrinsically different
from a Schwarzschild (Anti-) de Sitter solution even when the charge and the
cosmological constant become zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04476</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Golovinski</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Astapenko</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakovets</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac-graphene in slow-light</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 21 formulas, 13 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtained exact solutions for the wave function and the Green function in
the slow light pulse with the group velocity, consistent with the Fermi
velocity in graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04477</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Xianlong</keyname><forenames>Gao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kelin</forenames></author></authors><title>Rederivation of the Casimir force under the completeness relation of
  continuum operator</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Casimir effects manifests that, the two closely paralleled plates, generally
produce a macroscopic attractive force due to the quantum vacuum fluctuations
of the electromagnetic fields. The derivation of the force requires an {\it
artificial} regulator by removing the divergent summation. By including
naturally a spectrum density factor, based on the observation that an
incomplete eigenvectors of observable, such as the eigenstates for the photons
in the free field, can form a complete set of eigenvectors by introducing a
unique spectrum transformation, an alternative way is presented to rederive the
force, without using a regulator. As a result, the Casimir forces are obtained
with the first term $-\pi^2 \hbar c/(240 a^4)$ attractive, and the second one,
$-\pi^4 \hbar c^3 \sigma^2/(1008 a^6)$, also attractive but smaller, with $a$
the plate separation, and $\sigma$ a to-be-determined small constant number in
the spectrum density factor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04496</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Schicker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiore</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenkovszky</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonance production in Pomeron-Pomeron collisions at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings XXIV Int. Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and
  Related Subjects (DIS16), DESY, 11-15 April 2016, 5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model for Pomeron-Pomeron total cross section in the resonance region
$\sqrt{M^{2}} \le$ 5 GeV is presented. This model is based on Regge poles from
the Pomeron and two different $f$ trajectories, and includes the isolated
f$_{0}(500)$ resonance in the region $\sqrt{M^{2}}\lesssim 1$ GeV. A slowly
varying background is included. The presented Pomeron-Pomeron cross section is
not directly measurable, but is an essential ingredient for calculating
exclusive resonance production at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04505</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Panahi</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baradaran</keyname><forenames>Marzieh</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified treatment of a class of spherically symmetric potentials:
  quasi-exact solution</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we investigate the Schr\&quot;odinger equation for a class of
spherically symmetric potentials in a simple and unified manner using the Lie
algebraic approach within the framework of quasi-exact solvability. We
illustrate that all models give rise to the same basic differential equation,
which is expressible as an element of the universal enveloping algebra of
sl(2). Then, we obtain the general exact solutions of the problem by employing
the representation theory of sl(2) Lie algebra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04518</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>von Kr&#xfc;chten</keyname><forenames>Cornelia</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svachiy</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohak</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schadschneider</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Empirical study of the influence of social groups in evacuation
  scenarios</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, to be published in Traffic and Granular Flow '15
  (Springer, 2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects of social groups on pedestrian dynamics, especially in evacuation
scenarios, have attracted some interest recently. However, due to the lack of
reliable empirical data, most of the studies focussed on modelling aspects. It
was shown that social groups can have a considerable effect, e.g. on evacuation
times. In order to test the model predictions we have performed laboratory
experiments of evacuations with different types and sizes of the social groups.
The experiments have been performed with pupils of different ages. Parameters
that have been considered are (1) group size, (2) strength of intra-group
interactions, and (3) composition of the groups (young adults, children, and
mixtures). For all the experiments high-quality trajectories for all
participants have been obtained using the PeTrack software. This allows for a
detailed analysis of the group effects. One surprising observation is a
decrease of the evacuation time with increasing group size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04541</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Harutyunyan</keyname><forenames>Arus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedrakian</keyname><forenames>Armen</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical conductivity tensor of dense plasma in magnetic fields</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, supplemental material contains 21 tables.
  Proceedings of &quot;The Modern Physics of Compact Stars and Relativistic Gravity
  2015&quot;, 30 September 2015 - 3 October 2015 Yerevan, Armenia</comments><journal-ref>PoS(MPCS2015)011</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrical conductivity of finite-temperature plasma in neutron star crusts
is studied for applications in magneto-hydrodynamical description of compact
stars. We solve the Boltzmann kinetic equation in relaxation time approximation
taking into account the anisotropy of transport due to the magnetic field, the
effects of dynamical screening in the scattering matrix element and corre-
lations among the nuclei. We show that conductivity has a minimum at a non-zero
temperature, a low-temperature decrease and a power-law increase with
increasing temperature. Selected numerical results are shown for matter
composed of carbon, iron, and heavier nuclei present in the outer crusts of
neutron star.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04560</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>The EDELWEISS Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Armengaud</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnaud</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beno&#xee;t</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billard</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Boissi&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broniatowski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camus</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cazes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapellier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charlieux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De J&#xe9;sus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumoulin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eitel</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foerster</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gascon</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuliani</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gros</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hehn</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heuermann</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juillard</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe9;f&#xe9;lian</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleifges</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraus</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudryavtsev</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le-Sueur</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marnieros</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navick</keyname><forenames>X. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nones</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivieri</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pari</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piro</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poda</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Queguiner</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanglard</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scorza</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siebenborn</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tcherniakhovski</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vagneron</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakushev</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the cosmogenic activation of germanium detectors in
  EDELWEISS-III</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ex nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a measurement of the cosmogenic activation in the germanium
cryogenic detectors of the EDELWEISS III direct dark matter search experiment.
The decay rates measured in detectors with different exposures to cosmic rays
above ground are converted into production rates of different isotopes. The
measured production rates in units of nuclei/kg/day are 82 $\pm$ 21 for $^3$H,
2.8 $\pm$ 0.6 for $^{49}$V, 4.6 $\pm$ 0.7 for $^{55}$Fe, and 106 $\pm$ 13 for
$^{65}$Zn. These results are the most accurate for these isotopes. A lower
limit on the production rate of $^{68}$Ge of 74 nuclei/kg/day is also
presented. They are compared to model predictions present in literature and to
estimates calculated with the ACTIVIA code.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04577</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kvam</keyname><forenames>Audrey K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latimer</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical dispersion of composite particles consisting of millicharged
  constituents</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1412.0708</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43, 085002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/8/085002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Composite dark matter (DM) comprised of electrically charged constituents can
interact with the electromagnetic field via the particle's dipole moment. This
interaction results in a dispersive optical index of refraction for the DM
medium. We compute this refractive index for atomic dark matter and more
strongly bound systems, modeled via a harmonic oscillator potential. The
dispersive nature of the index will result in a time lag between high and low
energy photons simultaneously emitted from a distant astrophysical observable.
This time lag, due to matter dispersion, could confound potential claims of
Lorentz invariance violation (LIV) which can also result in such time lags. We
compare the relative size of the two effects and determine that the dispersion
due to DM is dwarfed by potential LIV effects for energies below the Planck
scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04580</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Overduin</keyname><forenames>James M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Hamna</forenames></author></authors><title>Extra dimensions and violations of Lorentz symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use experimental limits on Lorentz violation to obtain new constraints on
Kaluza-Klein-type theories in which the extra dimensions may be large but do
not necessarily have units of length. The associated variation in fundamental
quantities such as rest mass must occur slowly, on cosmological scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04588</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Stang</keyname><forenames>Jared B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>Megan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ives</keyname><forenames>Joss</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roll</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author></authors><title>Active learning in pre-class assignments: Exploring the use of
  interactive simulations to enhance reading assignments</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, submitted to PERC Proceedings 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pre-class reading assignments help prepare students for active classes by
providing a first exposure to the terms and concepts to be used during class.
We investigate if the use of inquiry-oriented PhET-based activities in
conjunction with pre-class reading assignments can improve both the preparation
of students for in-class learning and student attitudes towards and engagement
with pre-class assignments. Over three course modules covering different
topics, students were assigned randomly to complete either a textbook-only
pre-class assignment or both a textbook pre-class assignment and a PhET-based
activity. The assignments helped prepare students for class, as measured by
performance on the pre-class quiz relative to a beginning-of-semester pre-test,
but no evidence for increased learning due the PhET activity was observed.
Students rated the assignments which included PhET as more enjoyable and, for
the topic latest in the semester, reported engaging more with the assignments
when PhET was included.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04592</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filonov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miroshnichenko</keyname><forenames>Andrey E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monticone</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kivshar</keyname><forenames>Yuri S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay of magnetic responses in all-dielectric oligomers to realize
  magnetic Fano resonances</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics, 2(6), 724-729, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.5b00082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interplay between collective and individual optically-induced
magnetic responses in quadrumers made of identical dielectric nanoparticles.
Unlike their plasmonic counterparts, all-dielectric nanoparticle clusters are
shown to exhibit multiple dimensions of resonant magnetic responses that can be
employed for the realization of anomalous scattering signatures. We focus our
analysis on symmetric quadrumers made from silicon nanoparticles and verify our
theoretical results in proof-of-concept radio frequency experiments
demonstrating the existence of a novel type of magnetic Fano resonance in
nanophotonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04594</id><created>2016-07-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Guowei</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate, robust and reliable calculations of Poisson-Boltzmann
  solvation energies</title><categories>math.NA physics.comp-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><msc-class>65-04</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Developing accurate solvers for the Poisson Boltzmann (PB) model is the first
step to make the PB model suitable for implicit solvent simulation. Reducing
the grid size influence on the performance of the solver benefits to increasing
the speed of solver and providing accurate electrostatics analysis for solvated
molecules. In this work, we explore the accurate coarse grid PB solver based on
the Green's function treatment of the singular charges, matched interface and
boundary (MIB) method for treating the geometric singularities, and posterior
electrostatic potential field extension for calculating the reaction field
energy. We made our previous PB software, MIBPB, robust and provides almost
grid size independent reaction field energy calculation. Large amount of the
numerical tests verify the grid size independence merit of the MIBPB software.
The advantage of MIBPB software directly make the acceleration of the PB solver
from the numerical algorithm instead of utilization of advanced computer
architectures. Furthermore, the presented MIBPB software is provided as a free
online sever.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04595</id><created>2016-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Hoover</keyname><forenames>William Graham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoover</keyname><forenames>Carol Griswold</forenames></author></authors><title>Singly-Thermostated Ergodicity in Gibbs' Canonical Ensemble and the 2016
  Ian Snook Prize</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Ten pages with four figures, prepared for Computational Methods in
  Science and Technology (http://www.cmst.eu)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a harmonic oscillator, Nos\'e's single-thermostat approach to simulating
Gibbs' canonical ensemble with dynamics samples only a small fraction of the
phase space. Nos\'e's approach has been improved in a series of three steps: [
1 ] several two-thermostat sets of motion equations have been found which cover
the complete phase space in an ergodic fashion, [ 2 ] sets of single-thermostat
motion equations, exerting &quot;weak control&quot; over both forces and momenta, have
been shown to be ergodic, and [ 3 ] sets of single-thermostat motion equations
exerting weak control over two velocity moments provide ergodic phase-space
sampling for the oscillator and for the rigid pendulum, but not for the quartic
oscillator or for the Mexican Hat potential. The missing fourth step, motion
equations providing ergodic sampling for anharmonic potentials requires a
further advance. The 2016 Ian Snook Prize will be awarded to the author(s) of
the most interesting original submission addressing the problem of finding
ergodic algorithms for Gibbs' canonical ensemble using a single thermostat.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04612</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>Nicholas A. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keyser</keyname><forenames>Ulrich F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct measurements reveal non-Markovian fluctuations of DNA threading
  through a solid-state nanopore</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.BM</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The threading of a polymer chain through a small pore is a classic problem in
polymer dynamics and underlies nanopore sensing technology. However important
experimental aspects of the polymer motion in a solid-state nanopore, such as
an accurate measurement of the velocity variation during translocation, have
remained elusive. In this work we analysed the translocation through conical
quartz nanopores of a 7 kbp DNA double-strand labelled with six markers equally
spaced along its contour. These markers, constructed from DNA hairpins, give
direct experimental access to the translocation dynamics. On average we measure
a 5% reduction in velocity during the translocation. We also find a striking
correlation in velocity fluctuations with a decay constant of 100s of {\mu}s.
These results shed light on hitherto unresolved problems in the dynamics of DNA
translocation and provide guidance for experiments seeking to determine
positional information along a DNA strand.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04616</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mayeshiba</keyname><forenames>Tam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Dane</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain Effects on Oxygen Migration in Perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>(This version was completely updated regarding the correction at DOI
  10.1039/C6CP90050J)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 2015,17, 2715-2721</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C4CP05554C, 10.1039/C6CP90050J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fast oxygen transport materials are necessary for a range of technologies,
including efficient and cost-effective solid oxide fuel cells, gas separation
membranes, oxygen sensors, chemical looping devices, and memristors. Strain is
often proposed as a method to enhance the performance of oxygen transport
materials, but the magnitude of its effect and its underlying mechanisms are
not well-understood, particularly in the widely-used perovskite-structured
oxygen conductors. This work reports on an ab initio prediction of strain
effects on migration energetics for nine perovskite systems of the form LaBO3,
where B = [Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Ga]. Biaxial strain, as might be
easily produced in epitaxial systems, is predicted to lead to approximately
linear changes in migration energy. We find that tensile biaxial strain reduces
the oxygen vacancy migration barrier across the systems studied by an average
of 66 meV per percent strain for a single selected hop, with a low of 36 and a
high of 89 meV decrease in migration barrier per percent strain across all
systems. The estimated range for the change in migration barrier within each
system is approximately 25 meV per percent strain when considering all hops.
These results suggest that strain can significantly impact transport in these
materials, e.g., a 2% tensile strain can increase the diffusion coefficient by
about three orders of magnitude at 300 K (one order of magnitude at 500 {\deg}C
or 773 K) for one of the most strain-responsive materials calculated here
(LaCrO3). We show that a simple elasticity model, which assumes only dilative
or compressive strain in a cubic environment and a fixed migration volume, can
qualitatively but not quantitatively model the strain dependence of the
migration energy, suggesting that factors not captured by continuum elasticity
play a significant role in the strain response.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04618</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Borges</keyname><forenames>Fernando da Silva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Protachevicz</keyname><forenames>Paulo Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lameu</keyname><forenames>Ewandson Luiz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonetti</keyname><forenames>Robson Conrado</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iarosz</keyname><forenames>Kelly Cristiane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldas</keyname><forenames>Iber&#xea; Luiz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baptista</keyname><forenames>Murilo da Silva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batista</keyname><forenames>Antonio Marcos</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronised firing patterns in a random network of adaptive exponential
  integrate-and-fire</title><categories>q-bio.NC physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied neuronal synchronisation in a random network of adaptive
exponential integrate-and-fire neurons. We study how spiking or bursting
synchronous behaviour appears as a function of the coupling strength and the
probability of connections, by constructing parameter spaces that identify
these synchronous behaviours from measurements of the inter-spike interval and
the calculation of the order parameter. Moreover, we verify the robustness of
synchronisaton by applying an external perturbation to each neuron. The
simulations show that bursting synchronisation is more robust than spike
synchronisation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04625</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Borcea</keyname><forenames>Liliana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocyigit</keyname><forenames>Ilker</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging in random media with convex optimization</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.NA math.OC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study an inverse problem for the wave equation where localized wave
sources in random scattering media are to be determined from time resolved
measurements of the waves at an array of receivers. The sources are far from
the array, so the measurements are affected by cumulative scattering in the
medium, but they are not further than a transport mean free path, which is the
length scale characteristic of the onset of wave diffusion that prohibits
coherent imaging. The inversion is based on the Coherent Interferometric (CINT)
imaging method which mitigates the scattering effects by introducing an
appropriate smoothing operation in the image formation. This smoothing
stabilizes statistically the images, at the expense of their resolution. We
complement the CINT method with a convex ($l_1$) optimization in order to
improve the source localization and obtain quantitative estimates of the source
intensities. We analyze the method in a regime where scattering can be modeled
by large random wavefront distortions, and quantify the accuracy of the
inversion in terms of the spatial separation of individual sources or clusters
of sources. The theoretical predictions are demonstrated with numerical
simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04627</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keten</keyname><forenames>Sinan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lueptow</keyname><forenames>Richard M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of water and solute transport in polymeric reverse osmosis
  membranes via molecular dynamics simulations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Membrane Science, Vol 506, Pages 95-108, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.memsci.2016.01.051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Angstrom-scale transport characteristics of water and six different
solutes, methanol, ethanol, 2-propanol, urea, Na+, and Cl-, were studied for a
polyamide reverse osmosis (RO) membrane, FT-30, using non-equilibrium molecular
dynamics (NEMD) simulations. Results indicate that water transport increases
with an increasing fraction of connected percolated free volume, or
water-accessible open space, in the membrane polymer structure. This free
volume is enhanced by the dynamic structure of the membrane at the molecular
level as it swells when hydrated and vibrates due to molecular collisions
allowing a continuous path connecting the opposite membrane surfaces. The
tortuous paths available for transport of solutes result in Brownian motion of
solute molecules and hopping from pore to pore as they pass through the polymer
network structure of the membrane. The transport of alcohol solutes decreases
for solutes with larger Van der Waals volume, which corresponds to less
available percolated free volume, or solute-accessible space, within the
membrane polymer structure. However, the Van der Waals size of the dehydrated
solutes is generally not a good measure to predict solute transport or
rejection. Urea has reduced transport compared to ethanol, most likely due to
more complex chemistry, even though urea has a smaller Van der Waals volume
than ethanol. Na+ and Cl- experience the lowest transport, likely due to strong
ion-water and ion-ion electrostatic interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
