<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:36:23Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-04" from="2016-07-04" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0901.3381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0901.3381</id><created>2009-01-21</created><updated>2010-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oldershaw</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards A Resolution Of The Vacuum Energy Density Crisis</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, revisions requested by ApSS</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Cosmology, vol. 17, November 2011, pgs, 7359-7375</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theoretical vacuum energy density estimated on the basis of the Standard
Model of particle physics and very general quantum assumptions is 59 to 123
orders of magnitude larger than the measured vacuum energy density for the
observable universe which is determined on the basis of the Standard Model of
cosmology and empirical data. This enormous disparity between the expectations
of two of our most widely accepted theoretical frameworks demands a credible
and self-consistent explanation, and yet even after decades of sporadic effort
a generally accepted resolution of this crisis has not surfaced. Very recently,
however, a discrete self-similar cosmological paradigm based on the fundamental
principle of discrete scale invariance has been found to offer a rationale for
reducing the vacuum energy density disparity by at least 115 orders of
magnitude, and possibly this new paradigm offers a means of eliminating the
vacuum energy density crisis entirely.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0906.3525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0906.3525</id><created>2009-06-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Oldershaw</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Scale Relativity And SX Phoenicis Variable Stars</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 tables, comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Astronomy and Astrophysics, vol. 1, no.
  2, pp. 38-43, 2011</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/ijaa.2011.12006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discrete Scale Relativity proposes a new symmetry principle called discrete
cosmological self-similarity which relates each class of systems and phenomena
on a given Scale of nature's discrete cosmological hierarchy to the equivalent
class of analogue systems and phenomena on any other Scale. The new symmetry
principle can be understood in terms of discrete scale invariance involving the
spatial, temporal and dynamic parameters of all systems and phenomena. This new
paradigm predicts a rigorous discrete self-similarity between Stellar Scale
variable stars and Atomic Scale excited atoms undergoing energy-level
transitions and sub-threshold oscillations. Previously, methods for
demonstrating and testing the proposed symmetry principle have been applied to
RR Lyrae, Delta Scuti and ZZ Ceti variable stars. In the present paper we apply
the same analytical methods and diagnostic tests to a new class of variable
stars: SX Phoenicis variables. Double-mode pulsators are shown to provide an
especially useful means of testing the uniqueness and rigor of the conceptual
principles and discrete self-similar scaling of Discrete Scale Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.2865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.2865</id><created>2010-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Oldershaw</keyname><forenames>Robert L.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Infinite Fractal Cosmos</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, published in Journal of Cosmology, Vol. 4, 674-677</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Cosmology, Vol. 4, pgs. 674-677, 2009</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paradigmatic transition from a small finite universe to an infinite
unbounded fractal cosmos is briefly put into historical context and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.4497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.4497</id><created>2010-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Durand-Manterola</keyname><forenames>Hector Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>Dipolar Magnetic Moment of the Bodies of the Solar System and the Hot
  Jupiters</title><categories>astro-ph.EP physics.space-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Planetary and Space Science 57:1405-1411 (october 2009)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The planets magnetic field has been explained based on the dynamo theory,
which presents as many difficulties in mathematical terms as well as in
predictions. It proves to be extremely difficult to calculate the dipolar
magnetic moment of the extrasolar planets using the dynamo theory. The aim is
to find an empirical relationship (justifying using first principles) between
the planetary magnetic moment, the mass of the planet, its rotation period and
the electrical conductivity of its most conductive layer. Then this is applied
to Hot Jupiters. Using all the magnetic planetary bodies of the solar system
and tracing a graph of the dipolar magnetic moment versus body mass parameter,
the rotation period and electrical conductivity of the internal conductive
layer is obtained. An empirical, functional relation was constructed, which was
adjusted to a power law curve in order to fit the data. Once this empirical
relation has been defined, it is theoretically justified and applied to the
calculation of the dipolar magnetic moment of the extra solar planets known as
Hot Jupiters. Almost all data calculated is interpolated, bestowing confidence
in terms of their validity. The value for the dipolar magnetic moment, obtained
for the exoplanet Osiris (HD209458b), helps understand the way in which the
atmosphere of a planet with an intense magnetic field can be eroded by stellar
wind. The relationship observed also helps understand why Venus and Mars do not
present any magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.2288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.2288</id><created>2012-06-11</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wetzel</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morelli</keyname><forenames>Luis G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oates</keyname><forenames>Andrew C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julicher</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ares</keyname><forenames>Saul</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization in the presence of distributed delays</title><categories>nlin.CD cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study systems of identical coupled oscillators introducing a distribution
of delay times in the coupling. For arbitrary network topologies, we show that
the frequency and stability of the fully synchronized states depend only on the
mean of the delay distribution. However, synchronization dynamics is sensitive
to the shape of the distribution. In the presence of coupling delays, the
synchronization rate can be maximal for a specific value of the coupling
strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.2001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.2001</id><created>2012-12-10</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Long-range angular correlations on the near and away side in p-Pb
  collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}$ = 5.02 TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 captioned figures, 1 table, authors from page 17,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/2858</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2012-359</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B719 (2013) 29-41</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2013.01.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Angular correlations between charged trigger and associated particles are
measured by the ALICE detector in p-Pb collisions at a nucleon-nucleon
centre-of-mass energy of 5.02 TeV for transverse momentum ranges within 0.5 &lt;
$p_{\rm T}^{\rm assoc}$ &lt; $p_{\rm T}^{\rm trig}$ &lt; 4 GeV/$c$. The correlations
are measured over two units of pseudorapidity and full azimuthal angle in
different intervals of event multiplicity, and expressed as associated yield
per trigger particle. Two long-range ridge-like structures, one on the near
side and one on the away side, are observed when the per-trigger yield obtained
in low-multiplicity events is subtracted from the one in high-multiplicity
events. The excess on the near-side is qualitatively similar to that recently
reported by the CMS collaboration, while the excess on the away-side is
reported for the first time. The two-ridge structure projected onto azimuthal
angle is quantified with the second and third Fourier coefficients as well as
by near-side and away-side yields and widths. The yields on the near side and
on the away side are equal within the uncertainties for all studied event
multiplicity and $p_{\rm T}$ bins, and the widths show no significant evolution
with event multiplicity or $p_{\rm T}$. These findings suggest that the
near-side ridge is accompanied by an essentially identical away-side ridge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.0254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.0254</id><created>2013-06-30</created><updated>2014-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Gopal</forenames></author></authors><title>The Art of Memory and the Growth of the Scientific Method</title><categories>physics.hist-ph math.HO</categories><comments>36 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Interdisciplinary Description of Complex Systems 13(3) (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.7906/indecs.13.3.4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I argue that European schools of thought on memory and memorization were
critical in enabling the growth of the scientific method. After giving a
historical overview of the development of the memory arts from ancient Greece
through 17th century Europe, I describe how the Baconian viewpoint on the
scientific method was fundamentally part of a culture and a broader dialogue
that conceived of memorization as a foundational methodology for structuring
knowledge and for developing symbolic means for representing scientific
concepts. The principal figures of this intense and rapidly evolving
intellectual milieu included some of the leading thinkers traditionally
associated with the scientific revolution; among others, Francis Bacon, Renes
Descartes, and Gottfried Leibniz. I close by examining the acceleration of
mathematical thought in light of the art of memory and its role in 17th century
philosophy, and in particular, Leibniz' project to develop a universal
calculus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.5861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.5861</id><created>2013-07-22</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hutchinson</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stojkovic</keyname><forenames>Dejan</forenames></author></authors><title>Icezones instead of firewalls: extended entanglement beyond the event
  horizon and unitary evaporation of a black hole</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Published in Class. Quant. Grav. 33 (2016) no.13, 135006 , references
  updated</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 33 (2016) no.13, 135006</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/13/135006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the basic assumptions in the original setup of the firewall
paradox. The main claim is that a single mode of the lathe radiation is
maximally entangled with the mode inside the horizon and simultaneously with
the modes of early Hawking radiation. We argue that this situation never
happens during the evolution of a black hole. Quantum mechanics tells us that
while the black hole exists, unitary evolution maximally entangles a late mode
located just outside the horizon with a combination of early radiation and
black hole states, instead of either of them separately. One of the reasons for
this is that the black hole radiation is not random and strongly depends on the
geometry and charge of the black hole, as detailed numerical calculations of
Hawking evaporation clearly show. As a consequence, one can't factor out the
state of the black hole. However, this extended entanglement between the black
hole and modes of early and late radiation indicates that, as the black hole
ages, the local Rindler horizon is modified out to macroscopic distances from
the black hole. Fundamentally non-local physics nor firewalls are not necessary
to explain this result. We propose an infrared mechanism called {\it icezone}
that is mediated by low energy interacting modes and acts near any event
horizon to entangle states separated by long distances. These interactions at
first provide small corrections to the thermal Hawking radiation. At the end of
evaporation however the effect of interactions is as large as the Hawking
radiation and information is recovered for an outside observer. We verify this
in an explicit construction and calculation of the density matrix of a spin
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1141</id><created>2014-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miao</keyname><forenames>Maosheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Fuhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Haiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Half metallic and insulating phases in BN/Graphene lateral
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>2D Mater. 2 041001 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate theoretically the electronic structure of graphene and boron
nitride (BN) lateral heterostructures, which were fabricated in recent
experiments. The first-principles density functional calculation demonstrates
that a huge intrinsic transverse electric field can be induced in the graphene
nanoribbon region, and depends sensitively on the edge configuration of the
lateral heterostructure. The polarized electric field originates from the
charge mismatch at the BN-graphene interfaces. This huge electric field can
open a significant bang gap in graphene nanoribbon, and lead to fully
spinpolarized edge states and induce half-metallic phase in the lateral
BN/Graphene/BN heterostructure with proper edge configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.1513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.1513</id><created>2014-06-05</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ilderton</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Localisation in worldline pair production and lightfront zero-modes</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 pdf figures. Version 3: minor update to simplify
  presentation, results and conclusions unchanged</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2014) 166</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2014)166</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonperturbative probability of pair production in electric fields
depending on lightfront time is given exactly by the locally constant
approximation. We explain this by showing that the worldline path integral
defining the effective action contains a constraint, which localises
contributing paths on hypersurfaces of constant lightfront time. These paths
are lightfront zero-modes and there can be no pair production without them; the
effective action vanishes if they are projected out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2736</id><created>2014-06-10</created><updated>2014-08-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Azimuthal quadrupole correlation from gluon interference in 200 GeV and
  7 TeV p+p collisions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 90, 054013 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.90.054013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Balitskii-Fadin-Kuraev-Lipatov (BFKL) multi-Pomeron model of Levin and
Rezaeian, with extension to the gluon saturation region, is applied to
long-range pseudorapidity correlations on relative azimuth for low momentum
final-state hadrons produced in $\sqrt{s}$ = 200~GeV and 7~TeV p+p collisions.
The multi-Pomeron exchange probabilities in the model were estimated by fitting
the minimum-bias p+p multiplicity frequency distributions. The multi-Pomeron
model prediction for the amplitude of the minimum-bias average quadrupole
correlation, proportional to $\cos 2(\phi_1 - \phi_2)$, is consistent with the
200~GeV data when theoretically expected gluon saturation momentum scales are
used. Correlation predictions for the high multiplicity 7~TeV p+p collision
data are also consistent with the long-range pseudorapidity correlations at
small relative azimuth observed in the data. The results presented here show
that the present application of a multiple parton-shower, gluon interference
mechanism for generating the long-range pseudorapidity, azimuthal quadrupole
correlation is not excluded by the data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.1649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.1649</id><created>2014-07-07</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bolognesi</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamb</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple indicators for Lorentzian causets</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>43 pages, 23 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several classes of directed acyclic graphs have been investigated in the last
two decades, in the context of the Causal Set Program, in search for good
discrete models of spacetime. We introduce some statistical indicators that can
be used for comparing these graphs and for assessing their closeness to the
ideal Lorentzian causal sets ('causets') -- those obtained by sprinkling points
in a Lorentzian manifold. In particular, with the reversed triangular
inequality of Special Relativity in mind, we introduce 'longest/shortest path
plots', an easily implemented tool to visually detect the extent to which a
generic causet matches the wide range of path lengths between events of
Lorentzian causets. This tool can attribute some degree of 'Lorentzianity' - in
particular 'non-locality' - also to causets that are not (directly) embeddable
and that, due to some regularity in their structure, would not pass the key
test for Lorentz invariance: the absence of preferred reference frames. We
compare the discussed indicators and use them for assessing causets both of
stochastic and of deterministic, algorithmic origin, finding examples of the
latter that behave optimally w.r.t. our longest/shortest path plots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.4761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.4761</id><created>2014-07-17</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mentink</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balzer</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckstein</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast and reversible control of the exchange interaction in Mott
  insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 6, 6708 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms7708</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strongest interaction between microscopic spins in magnetic materials is
the exchange interaction $J_\text{ex}$. Therefore, ultrafast control of
$J_\text{ex}$ holds the promise to control spins on ultimately fast timescales.
We demonstrate that time-periodic modulation of the electronic structure by
electric fields can be used to reversibly control $J_\text{ex}$ on ultrafast
timescales in extended antiferromagnetic Mott insulators. In the regime of weak
driving strength, we find that $J_\text{ex}$ can be enhanced and reduced for
frequencies below and above the Mott gap, respectively. Moreover, for strong
driving strength, even the sign of $J_\text{ex}$ can be reversed and we show
that this causes time reversal of the associated quantum spin dynamics. These
results suggest wide applications, not only to control magnetism in condensed
matter systems, for example, via the excitation of spin resonances, but also to
assess fundamental questions concerning the reversibility of the quantum
many-body dynamics in cold atom systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.6738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.6738</id><created>2014-07-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Chillingworth</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauterbach</keyname><forenames>Reiner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turzi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Molien series and low-degree invariants for a natural action of ${\bf
  SO}(3)\wr{\bf Z}_2$</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, 3 figures</comments><msc-class>15A72, 13A50, 76A15</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48, 015203 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/1/015203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the invariants of the $25$-dimensional real representation of
the group ${\bf SO}(3)\wr{\bf Z}_2$ given by the left and right actions of
${\bf SO}(3)$ on $5\times 5$ matrices together with matrix transposition; the
action on column vectors is the irreducible $5$-dimensional representation of
${\bf SO}(3)$. The $25$-dimensional representation arises naturally in the
study of nematic liquid crystals, where the second-rank orientational order
parameters of a molecule are represented by a symmetric $3\times3$ traceless
symmetric matrix, and where a rigid rotation in ${\bf R}^3$ induces a linear
transformation of this space of matrices. The entropy contribution to a free
energy density function in this context turns out to have ${\bf SO}(3)\wr{\bf
Z}_2$ symmetry. Although it is unrealistic to expect to describe the complete
algebraic structure of the ring of invariants, we are able to calculate the
Molien series giving the number of linearly independent invariants at each
homogeneous degree, and to express this as a rational function indicating the
degrees of invariant polynomials that constitute a basis of 19 primary
invariants. The algebra of invariants up to degree 4 is investigated in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.7824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.7824</id><created>2014-10-28</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auma&#xee;tre</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering of floaters on the free surface of a turbulent flow: an
  experimental study</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures. Accepted to publication in European Journal of
  Mechanics B/Fluids</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an experimental study of the statistical properties of
millimeter-size spheres floating on the surface of a turbulent flow. The flow
is generated in a layer of liquid metal by an electromagnetic forcing. By using
two magnet arrays, we are able to create one highly fluctuating flow and
another, more stationary flow. In both cases, we follow the motion of hundreds
of particles floating at the deformed interface of the liquid metal. We
evidence the clustering of floaters by a statistical study of the local
concentration of particles. Some dynamical properties of clusters are exposed.
We perform spatial correlations between particle concentration and
hydrodynamical quantities linked with inertial effects; with vortical motion,
and with horizontal divergence (corresponding to compressibility in the
surface). From comparing these correlations, we propose the so-called surface
compressibility as the main clustering mechanism in our system. Hence, although
floaters are not passive scalar and move on a deformed surface, the scenario is
similar to the one reported for passive scalar on an almost flat free surface
of a turbulent flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4636</id><created>2014-11-17</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mazumdar</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>Pramod</forenames></author></authors><title>Some inequalities bridging stringy parameters and cosmological
  observables</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>v2: 17 pages, 4 figures, 1 table; Significant text expansion (from 4
  pages to 17 pages) with better clarifications added, title changed, 4 figures
  included, improved referencing, No change in the results and conclusions</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By demanding the validity of an effective field theory description during
inflation, in this note we derive some peculiar inequalities among the three
interesting stringy and cosmological parameters, namely the tensor-to-scalar
ratio ($r$), the string coupling ($g_s$) and the compactification volume
(${\cal V}$). In deriving these inequalities, we explicitly demand that the
inflationary scale and the Hubble parameter during inflation are well below the
Kaluza-Klein (KK) mass scale, string scale, and the four dimensional Planck
mass. For the inflationary models developed within the framework of type IIB
orientifold comapctification, we investigate the regions of parameters space
spanned by the three parameters $(r, g_s, {\cal V})$ by satisfying our
inequalities, and we find that the same can reduce the size of available
parameter space quite significantly. Moreover, we comment on obtaining further
constraints on the parameters by comparing gravitino mass ($m_{3/2}$) with the
Hubble scale ($H$), which also provides a lower bound on tensor-to-scalar ratio
($r$), for the cases when $m_{3/2} &lt;H$. We also illustrate the outcome of our
bounds in some specific class of string(-inspired) models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06134</id><created>2015-04-23</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forbes</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deane</keyname><forenames>Jonathan H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousa</keyname><forenames>Marwan S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fowler-Nordheim Plot Analysis: a Progress Report</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.data-an</categories><comments>v7 is publication version, but with correction of typographic errors
  on pages 138 and 141 of published version</comments><journal-ref>Jordan Journal of Physics 8 (2015) 125-147</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The commonest method of characterizing a cold field electron emitter is to
measure its current-voltage characteristics, and the commonest method of
analysing these characteristics is by means of a Fowler-Nordheim (FN) plot.
This tutorial/review-type paper outlines a more systematic method of setting
out the Fowler-Nordheim-type theory of cold field electron emission, and brings
together and summarises the current state of work by the authors on developing
the theory and methodology of FN plot analysis. This has turned out to be far
more complicated than originally expected. Emphasis is placed in this paper on:
(a) the interpretation of FN-plot slopes, which is currently both easier and of
more experimental interest than the analysis of FN-plot intercepts; and (b)
preliminary explorations into developing methodology for interpreting
current-voltage characteristics when there is series resistance in the
conduction path from the high-voltage generator to the emitter's emitting
regions. This work reinforces our view that FN-plot analysis is best carried
out on the raw measured current-voltage data, without pre-conversion into
another data format, particularly if series resistance is present in the
measuring circuit. Relevant formulae are given for extracting
field-enhancement-factor values from such an analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04132</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2015-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Correggi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dell'Antonio</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finco</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michelangeli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Class of Hamiltonians for a Three-Particle Fermionic System at
  Unitarity</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math.MP</categories><comments>30 pages; pdfLaTeX. Some comments and remarks added</comments><journal-ref>Math. Phys. Anal. Geom. 18 (2015), 1-36</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11040-015-9195-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a quantum mechanical three-particle system made of two identical
fermions of mass one and a different particle of mass $ m $, where each fermion
interacts via a zero-range force with the different particle. In particular we
study the unitary regime, i.e., the case of infinite two-body scattering
length. The Hamiltonians describing the system are, by definition, self-adjoint
extensions of the free Hamiltonian restricted on smooth functions vanishing at
the two-body coincidence planes, i.e., where the positions of two interacting
particles coincide. It is known that for $ m $ larger than a critical value $
m^* \simeq (13.607)^{-1} $ a self-adjoint and lower bounded Hamiltonian $ H_0 $
can be constructed, whose domain is characterized in terms of the standard
point-interaction boundary condition at each coincidence plane. Here we prove
that for $ m \in( m^*,m^{**}) $, where $ m^{**} \simeq (8.62)^{-1} $, there is
a further family of self-adjoint and lower bounded Hamiltonians $ H_{0,\beta}
$, $ \beta \in \mathbb{R} $, describing the system. Using a quadratic form
method, we give a rigorous construction of such Hamiltonians and we show that
the elements of their domains satisfy a further boundary condition,
characterizing the singular behavior when the positions of all the three
particles coincide.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05058</id><created>2015-05-19</created><updated>2015-05-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Olchanyi</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames><affiliation>Newton South High School</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Moskovets</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames><affiliation>SESI/MassTech Inc</affiliation></author></authors><title>Two Poorly Measured Quantum Observables as a Complete Set of Commuting
  Observables</title><categories>quant-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>LaTeX, 8 pages, several misprints corrected</comments><journal-ref>Rose-Hulman Undergraduate Mathematics Journal, v. 16, n. 2, art. 9
  (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we revisit the century-old question of the minimal set of
observables needed to identify a quantum state: here, we replace the natural
coincidences in their spectra by effective ones, induced by an imperfect
measurement. We show that if the detection error is smaller than the mean level
spacing, then two observables with Poisson spectra will suffice, no matter how
large the system is. The primary target of our findings is the integrable (i.e.
exactly solvable) quantum systems whose spectra do obey the Poisson statistics.
We also consider the implications of our findings for classical pattern
recognition techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05542</id><created>2015-05-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Arruda</keyname><forenames>M. F. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valente</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werlang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovianity induced by a single-photon packet in a one-dimensional
  waveguide</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 41, 3126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.003126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of non-Markovianity (NM) in quantum dynamics is still an open
debate. Understanding how to generate and measure NM in specific models may aid
in this quest. In quantum optics, an engineered electromagnetic environment
coupled to a single atom can induce NM. The most common scenario of structured
electromagnetic environment is an optical cavity, composed by a pair of
mirrors. Here, we show how to generate and measure NM on a two-level system
coupled to a one-dimensional waveguide with no mirrors required. The origin of
the non-Markovian behavior lies in the initial state of the field, prepared as
a single-photon packet. We analyze how NM depends on two experimentally
controllable parameters, namely, the linewidth of the packet and its central
frequency. We relate the presence of NM to a $\pi$-phase shift between incoming
and emitted fields. We also show how the two output channels of the waveguide
provide distinct signatures of NM, both experimentally accessible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06171</id><created>2015-05-22</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Natori</keyname><forenames>W. M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miranda</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral spin-orbital liquids with nodal lines</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages + supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 017204 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.017204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strongly correlated materials with strong spin-orbit coupling hold promise
for realizing topological phases with fractionalized excitations. Here we
propose a chiral spin-orbital liquid as a stable phase of a realistic model for
heavy-element double perovskites. This spin liquid state has Majorana fermion
excitations with a gapless spectrum characterized by nodal lines along the
edges of the Brillouin zone. We show that the nodal lines are topological
defects of a non-Abelian Berry connection and that the system exhibits
dispersing surface states. We discuss some experimental signatures of this
state and compare them with properties of the spin liquid candidate Ba_2YMoO_6.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02333</id><created>2015-06-07</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Eylee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>DaeKil</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixedness and Entanglement in the presence of Localized Closed Timelike
  Curves</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure; V2 12 pages, references added, will appear in QIP</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf. Process, 15 (2016) 3055-3063</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1305-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine mixedness and entanglement of the chronology-respecting (CR)
system with assuming that quantum mechanical closed timelike curves (CTCs)
exist in nature and by introducing the qubit system and applying the general
controlled operations between CR and CTC systems. We use the magnitude of Bloch
vector as a measure of mixedness. While Deutschian-CTC (D-CTC) either preserves
or decreases the magnitude, postselected-CTC (P-CTC) can increases it.
Nonintuitively, even the completely mixed CR-qubit can be converted into a pure
state after CTC-qubit travels around the P-CTC. It is also shown that while
D-CTC cannot increase the entanglement of CR system, P-CTC can increase it.
Surprisingly, any partially entangled state can be maximally entangled pure
state if P-CTC exists. Thus, distillation of P-CTC-assisted entanglement can be
easily achieved without preparing the multiple copies of the partially
entangled state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07146</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2016-01-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Gouranga C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-Like Wilson Line in QCD Without Path Ordering</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>Final Version, 20 pages latex, Accepted for publication in Phys.
  Part. Nucl. Lett. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1506.02651, arXiv:1506.02593</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Part.Nucl.Lett.13 : 417-426, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1547477116040105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike the Wilson line in QED the Wilson line in QCD contains path ordering.
In this paper we get rid of the path ordering in the light-like Wilson line in
QCD by simplifying all the infinite number of non-commuting terms in the SU(3)
pure gauge. We prove that the light-like Wilson line in QCD naturally emerges
when path integral formulation of QCD is used to prove factorization of soft
and collinear divergences at all order in coupling constant in QCD processes at
high energy colliders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01632</id><created>2015-09-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaluna</keyname><forenames>Heather M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masiero</keyname><forenames>Joseph R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meech</keyname><forenames>Karen J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Space Weathering Trends Among Carbonaceous Asteroids</title><categories>astro-ph.EP physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in Icarus</comments><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2015.09.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present visible spectroscopic and albedo data of the 2.3 Gyr old Themis
family and the &lt;10 Myr old Beagle sub-family. The slope and albedo variations
between these two families indicate C-complex asteroids become redder and
darker in response to space weathering. Our observations of Themis family
members confirm previously observed trends where phyllosilicate absorption
features are less common among small diameter objects. Similar trends in the
albedos of large (&gt; 15 km) and small (&lt; 15 km) Themis members suggest these
phyllosilicate feature and albedo trends result from regolith variations as a
function of diameter. Observations of the Beagle asteroids show a small, but
notable fraction of members with phyllosilicate features. The presence of
phyllosilicates and the dynamical association of the main-belt comet
133P/Elst-Pizarro with the Beagle family imply the Beagle parent body was a
heterogenous mixture of ice and aqueously altered minerals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05094</id><created>2015-09-16</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hertzberg</keyname><forenames>Mark P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masoumi</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Can Compactifications Solve the Cosmological Constant Problem?</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages in double column format. V2: Updated references. Published in
  JCAP</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP 4671</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 06 (2016) 053</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/06/053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, there have been claims in the literature that the cosmological
constant problem can be dynamically solved by specific compactifications of
gravity from higher-dimensional toy models. These models have the novel feature
that in the four-dimensional theory, the cosmological constant $\Lambda$ is
much smaller than the Planck density and in fact accumulates at $\Lambda=0$.
Here we show that while these are very interesting models, they do not properly
address the real cosmological constant problem. As we explain, the real problem
is not simply to obtain $\Lambda$ that is small in Planck units in a toy model,
but to explain why $\Lambda$ is much smaller than other mass scales (and
combinations of scales) in the theory. Instead, in these toy models, all other
particle mass scales have been either removed or sent to zero, thus ignoring
the real problem. To this end, we provide a general argument that the included
moduli masses are generically of order Hubble, so sending them to zero
trivially sends the cosmological constant to zero. We also show that the
fundamental Planck mass is being sent to zero, and so the central problem is
trivially avoided by removing high energy physics altogether. On the other
hand, by including various large mass scales from particle physics with a high
fundamental Planck mass, one is faced with a real problem, whose only known
solution involves accidental cancellations in a landscape.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03185</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2016-02-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lay</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortunato</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitturi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum discretized BCS approach for weakly bound nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 figures, to be submitted</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43 (2016) 085103</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/8/085103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) formalism is extended by including the
single-particle continuum in order to analyse the evolution of pairing in an
isotopic chain from stability up to the drip line. We propose a continuum
discretized generalized BCS based on single-particle pseudostates (PS). These
PS are generated from the diagonalization of the single-particle Hamiltonian
within a Transformed Harmonic Oscillator (THO) basis. The consistency of the
results versus the size of the basis is studied. The method is applied to
neutron rich Oxygen and Carbon isotopes and compared with similar previous
works and available experimental data. We make use of the flexibility of the
proposed model in order to study the evolution of the occupation of the
low-energy continuum when the system becomes weakly bound. We find a larger
influence of the non-resonant continuum as long as the Fermi level approaches
zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04096</id><created>2015-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Compelli</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Rossen</forenames></author></authors><title>On the dynamics of internal waves interacting with the equatorial
  undercurrent</title><categories>math-ph math.MP physics.flu-dyn physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure, accepted in Journal of Nonlinear Mathematical
  Physics</comments><msc-class>35Q35, 37K05, 74J30</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Nonlinear Mathematical Physics 22 (2015) pages 531-539</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/14029251.2015.1113052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction of the nonlinear internal waves with a nonuniform current
with a specific form, characteristic for the equatorial undercurrent, is
studied. The current has no vorticity in the layer, where the internal wave
motion takes place. We show that the nonzero vorticity that might be occuring
in other layers of the current does not affect the wave motion. The equations
of motion are formulated as a Hamiltonian system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00333</id><created>2015-11-01</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Chi-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krolik</keyname><forenames>Julian H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation-driven outflows from and radiative support in dusty tori of
  active galactic nuclei</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures, 5 appendices, with small corrections not
  included in published version</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 825, 67 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/1/67</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Substantial evidence points to dusty, geometrically thick tori obscuring the
central engines of active galactic nuclei (AGNs), but so far no mechanism
satisfactorily explains why cool dust in the torus remains in a puffy geometry.
Near-Eddington infrared (IR) and ultraviolet (UV) luminosities coupled with
high dust opacities at these frequencies suggest that radiation pressure on
dust can play a significant role in shaping the torus. To explore the possible
effects of radiation pressure, we perform three-dimensional radiative
hydrodynamics simulations of an initially smooth torus. Our code solves the
hydrodynamics equations, the time-dependent multi-angle group IR radiative
transfer (RT) equation, and the time-independent UV RT equation. We find a
highly dynamic situation. IR radiation is anisotropic, leaving primarily
through the central hole. The torus inner surface exhibits a break in
axisymmetry under the influence of radiation and differential rotation;
clumping follows. In addition, UV radiation pressure on dust launches a strong
wind along the inner surface; when scaled to realistic AGN parameters, this
outflow travels at $\sim 5000 (M/10^7 M_\odot)^{1/4} [L_\mathrm{UV}/(0.1
L_\mathrm E)]^{1/4} \mathrm{km}\,\mathrm s^{-1}$ and carries $\sim 0.1 (M/10^7
M_\odot)^{3/4} [L_\mathrm{UV}/(0.1 L_\mathrm E)]^{3/4}
M_\odot\,\mathrm{yr}^{-1}$, where $M$, $L_\mathrm{UV}$, and $L_\mathrm E$ are
the mass, UV luminosity, and Eddington luminosity of the central object
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02830</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matty</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lancaster</keyname><forenames>Lachlan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffin</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swendsen</keyname><forenames>Robert H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of canonical and microcanonical definitions of entropy</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For more than 100 years, one of the central concepts in statistical mechanics
has been the microcanonical ensemble, which provides a way of calculating the
thermodynamic entropy for a specified energy. A controversy has recently
emerged between two distinct definitions of the entropy based on the
microcanonical ensemble: (1) The Boltzmann entropy, defined by the density of
states at a specified energy, and (2) The Gibbs entropy, defined by the sum or
integral of the density of states below a specified energy. A critical
difference between the consequences of these definitions pertains to the
concept of negative temperatures, which by the Gibbs definition, cannot exist.
In this paper, we call into question the fundamental assumption that the
microcanonical ensemble should be used to define the entropy. Our argument is
based on a recently proposed canonical definition of the entropy as a function
of energy. We investigate the predictions of the Boltzmann, Gibbs, and
canonical definitions for a variety of classical and quantum models, including
models which exhibit a first-order phase transition. Our results support the
validity of the concept of negative temperature, but not for all models with a
decreasing density of states. We find that only the canonical entropy
consistently predicts the correct thermodynamic properties, while
microcanonical definitions of entropy, including those of Boltzmann and Gibbs,
are correct only for a limited set of simple models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02843</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flender</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleem</keyname><forenames>Lindsey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finkel</keyname><forenames>Hal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habib</keyname><forenames>Salman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heitmann</keyname><forenames>Katrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holder</keyname><forenames>Gilbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulations of the Pairwise Kinematic Sunyaev-Zel'dovich Signal</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Journal version</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 823 (2016) no.2, 98</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/823/2/98</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pairwise kinematic Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (kSZ) signal from galaxy clusters
is a probe of their line-of-sight momenta, and thus a potentially valuable
source of cosmological information. In addition to the momenta, the amplitude
of the measured signal depends on the properties of the intra-cluster gas and
observational limitations such as errors in determining cluster centers and
redshifts. In this work we simulate the pairwise kSZ signal of clusters at z&lt;1,
using the output from a cosmological N-body simulation and including the
properties of the intra-cluster gas via a model that can be varied in
post-processing. We find that modifications to the gas profile due to star
formation and feedback reduce the pairwise kSZ amplitude of clusters by ~50%,
relative to the naive 'gas traces mass' assumption. We demonstrate that
mis-centering can reduce the overall amplitude of the pairwise kSZ signal by up
to 10%, while redshift errors can lead to an almost complete suppression of the
signal at small separations. We confirm that a high-significance detection is
expected from the combination of data from current-generation, high-resolution
CMB experiments, such as the South Pole Telescope, and cluster samples from
optical photometric surveys, such as the Dark Energy Survey. Furthermore, we
forecast that future experiments such as Advanced ACTPol in conjunction with
data from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument will yield detection
significances of at least 20{\sigma}, and up to 57{\sigma} in an optimistic
scenario. Our simulated maps are publicly available at:
http://www.hep.anl.gov/cosmology/ksz.html
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02869</id><created>2015-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Savransky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrett</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>WFIRST-AFTA Coronagraph Science Yield Modeling with EXOSIMS</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>43 pages, 14 figures; accepted for publication in WFIRST Coronagraph
  special issue of JATIS</comments><journal-ref>J. Astron. Telesc. Instrum. Syst. 2(1), 011006 (Dec 10, 2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.2.1.011006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present and discuss the design details of an extensible, modular, open
source software framework called EXOSIMS, which creates end-to-end simulations
of space-based exoplanet imaging missions. We motivate the development and
baseline implementation of the component parts of this software with models of
the WFIRST-AFTA coronagraph, and present initial results of mission simulations
for various iterations of the WFIRST-AFTA coronagraph design. We present and
discuss two sets of simulations: The first compares the science yield of
completely different instruments in the form of early competing coronagraph
designs for WFIRST-AFTA. The second set of simulations evaluates the effects of
different operating assumptions, specifically the assumed post-processing
capabilities and telescope vibration levels. We discuss how these results can
guide further instrument development and the expected evolution of science
yields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07676</id><created>2015-11-24</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haack</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nampuri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nernst branes with Lifshitz asymptotics in N=2 gauged supergravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>v2: 32 pages, improved presentation, added references, matches
  published version</comments><report-no>LMU-ASC 73/15</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 06 (2016), 1-32</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2016)144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss two classes of non-supersymmetric interpolating solutions in N=2,
D=4 gauged supergravity, that flow from either a z=2 Lifshitz geometry or a
conformal AdS background to the near-horizon geometry of a Nernst brane. We
obtain these solutions by constructing a z=2 supersymmetric Lifshitz solution
in the STU model from a first-order rewriting of the action, then lifting it up
to a five-dimensional background and subsequently modifying this
five-dimensional solution by a two-parameter family of deformations. Under
reduction, these give four-dimensional non-supersymmetric Nernst brane
solutions. This is a step towards resolving the Lifshitz tidal force
singularity in the context of N=2 gauged supergravity and suggests an approach
to encoding the Nernst brane in terms of the Schroedinger symmetry group of the
holographically dual field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08438</id><created>2015-11-26</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bajkova</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of the Z Distribution of Young Objects in the Galactic Thin
  Disk</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, 2016, Vol. 42, No. 1, pp. 1-9</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773716010023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have obtained new estimates of the Sun's distance from the symmetry plane
Zo and the vertical disk scale height h using currently available data on
stellar OB associations, Wolf-Rayet stars, HII regions, and Cepheids. Based on
individual determinations, we have calculated the mean Zo=-16+/-2 pc. Based on
the model of a self-gravitating isothermal disk for the density distribution,
we have found the following vertical disk scale heights: h = 40.2+/-2.1 pc from
OB associations, h = 47.8+/-3.9 pc from Wolf-Rayet stars, h=48.4+/-2.5 pc from
HII regions, and h = 66.2+/-1.6 pc from Cepheids. We have estimated the
surface, \sum=6 kpc^{-2}, and volume, D(Zo) = 50.6 kpc^{-3}, densities from a
sample of OB associations. We have found that there could be approximately 5000
OB associations in the Galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08662</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Rudranil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riegler</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>Wilson Lines and Holographic Entanglement Entropy in Galilean Conformal
  Field Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 Pages and two Figures; v2&amp;v3 corrected minor typos</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 045003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.045003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we will present in more detail a construction using Wilson
lines and the corresponding dual Galilean conformal field theory calculations
for analytically determining holographic entanglement entropy for flat space in
$2+1$ dimensions first presented in hep-th/1410.4089. In addition we will show
how the construction using Wilson lines can be expanded to flat space
higher-spin theories and determine the thermal entropy of (spin-3 charged) flat
space cosmologies using this approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09288</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Girish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subrahmanyam</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jha</keyname><forenames>Anand. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic upper bound on two-qubit polarization entanglement
  predetermined by pump polarization correlations in parametric down-conversion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 063842 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.063842</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study how one-particle correlations transfer to manifest as two-particle
correlations in the context of parametric down-conversion (PDC), a process in
which a pump photon is annihilated to produce two entangled photons. We work in
the polarization degree of freedom and show that for any two-qubit generation
process that is both trace-preserving and entropy-nondecreasing, the
concurrence $C(\rho)$ of the generated two-qubit state $\rho$ follows an
intrinsic upper bound with $C(\rho)\leq (1+P)/2$, where $P$ is the degree of
polarization of the pump photon. We also find that for the class of two qubit
states that is restricted to have only two non-zero diagonal elements such that
the effective dimensionality of the two-qubit state is same as the
dimensionality of the pump polarization state, the upper bound on concurrence
is the degree of polarization itself, that is, $C(\rho)\leq P$. Our work shows
that the maximum manifestation of two-particle correlations as entanglement is
dictated by one-particle correlations. The formalism developed in this work can
be extended to include multi-particle systems and can thus have important
implications towards deducing the upper bounds on multi-particle entanglement,
for which no universally accepted measure exists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00544</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Camley</keyname><forenames>Brian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>Juliane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Herbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappel</keyname><forenames>Wouter-Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective signal processing in cluster chemotaxis: roles of adaptation,
  amplification, and co-attraction in collective guidance</title><categories>q-bio.CB cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>This article extends some results previously presented in
  arXiv:1506.06698</comments><doi>10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single eukaryotic cells commonly sense and follow chemical gradients,
performing chemotaxis. Recent experiments and theories, however, show that even
when single cells do not chemotax, clusters of cells may, if their interactions
are regulated by the chemoattractant. We study this general mechanism of
&quot;collective guidance&quot; computationally with models that integrate stochastic
dynamics for individual cells with biochemical reactions within the cells, and
diffusion of chemical signals between the cells. We show that if clusters of
cells use the well-known local excitation, global inhibition (LEGI) mechanism
to sense chemoattractant gradients, the speed of the cell cluster becomes
non-monotonic in the cluster's size - clusters either larger or smaller than an
optimal size will have lower speed. We argue that the cell cluster speed is a
crucial readout of how the cluster processes chemotactic signal; both
amplification and adaptation will alter the behavior of cluster speed as a
function of size. We also show that, contrary to the assumptions of earlier
theories, collective guidance does not require persistent cell-cell contacts
and strong short range adhesion to function. If cell-cell adhesion is absent,
and the cluster cohesion is instead provided by a co-attraction mechanism, e.g.
chemotaxis toward a secreted molecule, collective guidance may still function.
However, new behaviors, such as cluster rotation, may also appear in this case.
Together, the combination of co-attraction and adaptation allows for collective
guidance that is robust to varying chemoattractant concentrations while not
requiring strong cell-cell adhesion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01230</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ahuja</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Schaar</keyname><forenames>Mihaela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zame</keyname><forenames>William R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Theory of Individualism, Collectivism and Economic Outcomes</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-fin.GN</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a dynamic model to study the impact on the economic
outcomes in different societies during the Malthusian Era of individualism
(time spent working alone) and collectivism (complementary time spent working
with others). The model is driven by opposing forces: a greater degree of
collectivism provides a higher safety net for low quality workers but a greater
degree of individualism allows high quality workers to leave larger bequests.
The model suggests that more individualistic societies display smaller
populations, greater per capita income and greater income inequality. Some
(limited) historical evidence is consistent with these predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05649</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pital&#xfa;a-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Dami&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Spacetime-constrained oblivious transfer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Improved theorem on the impossibility of classical SCOT to allow for
  small errors. Figure added and discussion extended in response to referee
  comments. Protocol and security proof unaltered. Final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 062346 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.062346</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1-out-of-2 oblivious transfer (OT), Alice inputs numbers x_0, x_1, Bob
inputs a bit b and outputs x_b. Secure OT requires that Alice and Bob learn
nothing about b and x_{\bar{b}}, respectively. We define spacetime-constrained
oblivious transfer (SCOT) as OT in Minkowski spacetime in which Bob must output
x_b within R_b, where R_0 and R_1 are fixed spacelike separated spacetime
regions. We show that unconditionally secure SCOT is impossible with classical
protocols in Minkowski (or Galilean) spacetime, or with quantum protocols in
Galilean spacetime. We describe a quantum SCOT protocol in Minkowski spacetime,
and we show it unconditionally secure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06723</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guttridge</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>S A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemp</keyname><forenames>S L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boddy</keyname><forenames>D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freytag</keyname><forenames>R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>M P A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarbutt</keyname><forenames>M R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinds</keyname><forenames>E A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornish</keyname><forenames>S L</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct loading of a large Yb MOT on the $^{1}S_{0} \rightarrow \,
  ^{3}P_{1}$ transition</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 145006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/14/145006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a robust technique for laser frequency stabilisation that enables
the reproducible loading of in excess of 10$^{9}$ Yb atoms from a Zeeman slower
directly into a magneto-optical trap (MOT) operating on the $^{1}S_{0}
\rightarrow \, ^{3}P_{1}$ transition, without the need for a first stage MOT on
the $^{1}S_{0} \rightarrow \, ^{1}P_{1}$ transition. We use a simple atomic
beam apparatus to generate narrow fluorescence signals on both the 399 nm
$^{1}S_{0} \rightarrow \, ^{1}P_{1}$ transition used for the Zeeman slower and
the 556 nm $^{1}S_{0} \rightarrow \, ^{3}P_{1}$ transition. We present in
detail the methods for obtaining spectra with a high signal-to-noise ratio and
demonstrate error signals suitable for robust frequency stabilisation. Finally
we demonstrate the stability and precision of our technique through sensitive
measurements of the gravitational sag of the Yb MOT as a function of the
intensity of the laser cooling beams, which are in good agreement with theory.
These results will be important for efficient loading of the atoms into an
optical dipole trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00868</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coutant</keyname><forenames>Antonin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michel</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parentani</keyname><forenames>Renaud</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical instabilities and quasi-normal modes, a spectral analysis with
  applications to black-hole physics</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>31 pages, 13 figures. Small clarifications, title changed, matches
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 33 (2016) 125032</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/12/125032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Black hole dynamical instabilities have been mostly studied in specific
models. We here study the general properties of the complex-frequency modes
responsible for such instabilities, guided by the example of a charged scalar
field in an electrostatic potential. We show that these modes are square
integrable, have a vanishing conserved norm, and appear in mode doublets or
quartets. We also study how they appear in the spectrum and how their complex
frequencies subsequently evolve when varying some external parameter. When
working on an infinite domain, they appear from the reservoir of quasi-normal
modes obeying outgoing boundary conditions. This is illustrated by
generalizing, in a non-positive definite Krein space, a solvable model
(Friedrichs model) which originally describes the appearance of a resonance
when coupling an isolated system to a mode continuum. In a finite spatial
domain instead, they arise from the fusion of two real frequency modes with
opposite norms, through a process that closely resembles avoided crossing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02106</id><created>2016-01-09</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buyskikh</keyname><forenames>Anton S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fagotti</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schachenmayer</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Essler</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daley</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement growth and correlation spreading with variable-range
  interactions in spin and fermionic tunnelling models</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, minor updates to final submitted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 053620 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.053620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dynamics following a global parameter quench for two 1D
models with variable-range power-law interactions: a long-range transverse
Ising model, which has recently been realised in chains of trapped ions, and a
long-range lattice model for spinless fermions with long-range tunnelling. For
the transverse Ising model, the spreading of correlations and growth of
entanglement are computed using numerical matrix product state techniques, and
are compared with exact solutions for the fermionic tunnelling model. We
identify transitions between regimes with and without an apparent linear light
cone for correlations, which correspond closely between the two models. For
long-range interactions (in terms of separation distance r, decaying slower
than 1/r), we find that despite the lack of a light-cone, correlations grow
slowly as a power law at short times, and that -- depending on the structure of
the initial state -- the growth of entanglement can also be sublinear. These
results are understood through analytical calculations, and should be
measurable in experiments with trapped ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06429</id><created>2016-01-24</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Roberto E.</forenames></author></authors><title>PARAVT: Parallel Voronoi Tessellation code</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Astronomy and Computing. Code available
  at https://github.com/regonzar/paravt</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new open source code for massive parallel computation of Voronoi
tessellations(VT hereafter) in large data sets. The code is focused for
astrophysical purposes where VT densities and neighbors are widely used. There
are several serial Voronoi tessellation codes, however no open source and
parallel implementations are available to handle the large number of
particles/galaxies in current N-body simulations and sky surveys.
Parallelization is implemented under MPI and VT using Qhull library. Domain
decomposition takes into account consistent boundary computation between tasks,
and includes periodic conditions. In addition, the code computes neighbors
list, Voronoi density, Voronoi cell volume, density gradient for each particle,
and densities on a regular grid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07361</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kurzynski</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolodziejski</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laskowski</keyname><forenames>Wieslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markiewicz</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional visualization of a qutrit</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 062126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.062126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a surprisingly simple three-dimensional Bloch sphere
representation of a qutrit, i.e., a single three-level quantum system. We start
with a symmetric state of a two-qubit system and relate it to the spin-1
representation. Using this representation we associate each qutrit state with a
three-dimensional vector $\mathbf{a}$ and a metric tensor $\mathbf{\hat\Gamma}$
which satisfy $\mathbf{a}\cdot \mathbf{\hat\Gamma} \cdot \mathbf{a}\leq 1$.
This resembles the well known condition for qubit Bloch vectors in which case
$\mathbf{\hat\Gamma}=\hat{I}$. In our case the vector $\mathbf{a}$ corresponds
to spin-1 polarisation, whereas the tensor $\mathbf{\hat\Gamma}$ is a function
of polarisation uncertainties. Alternatively, $\mathbf{a}$ is a local Bloch
vector of a symmetric two-qubit state and $\mathbf{\hat\Gamma}$ is a function
of the corresponding correlation tensor. We also discuss how a purity of states
and state-dynamics is depicted in our representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00598</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yunus</keyname><forenames>Cagin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renklioglu</keyname><forenames>Basak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keskin</keyname><forenames>Mustafa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berker</keyname><forenames>A. Nihat</forenames></author></authors><title>Stepwise Positional-Orientational Order and the
  Multicritical-Multistructural Global Phase Diagram of the s=3/2 Ising Model
  from Renormalization-Group Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Published version. 9 pages, 5 figures, 1 table, 21 phase diagrams, 40
  fixed points</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 062113 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.062113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin-3/2 Ising model, with nearest-neighbor interactions only, is the
prototypical system with two different ordering species, with concentrations
regulated by a chemical potential. Its global phase diagram, obtained in d=3 by
renormalization-group theory in the Migdal-Kadanoff approximation or
equivalently as an exact solution of a d=3 hierarchical lattice, with flows
subtended by 40 different fixed points, presents a very rich structure
containing eight different ordered and disordered phases, with more than
fourteen different types of phase diagrams in temperature and chemical
potential. It exhibits phases with orientational and/or positional order. It
also exhibits quintuple phase transition reentrances. Universality of critical
exponents is conserved across different renormalization-group flow basins, via
redundant fixed points. One of the phase diagrams contains a plastic crystal
sequence, with positional and orientational ordering encountered consecutively
as temperature is lowered. The global phase diagram also contains double
critical points, first-order and critical lines between two ordered phases,
critical endpoints, usual and unusual (inverted) bicritical points, tricritical
points, multiple tetracritical points, and zero-temperature criticality and
bicriticality. The 4-state Potts permutation-symmetric subspace is contained in
this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02286</id><created>2016-02-06</created><updated>2016-03-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattarai</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical-noise reduction in correlation analysis of high-energy
  nuclear collisions with event-mixing</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>30 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Instrum. Meth. Phys. Res. A 821, 142 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.03.058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The error propagation and statistical-noise reduction method of Reid and
Trainor for two-point correlation applications in high-energy collisions is
extended to include particle-pair references constructed by mixing two
particles from all event-pair combinations within event subsets of arbitrary
size. The Reid-Trainor method is also applied to other particle-pair mixing
algorithms commonly used in correlation analysis of particle production from
high-energy nuclear collisions. The statistical-noise reduction, inherent in
the Reid-Trainor event-mixing procedure, is shown to occur for these other
event-mixing algorithms as well. Monte Carlo simulation results are presented
which verify the predicted degree of noise reduction. In each case the final
errors are determined by the bin-wise particle-pair number, rather than by the
bin-wise single-particle count.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02652</id><created>2016-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Machon</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Gareth P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Raymond E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pesci</keyname><forenames>Adriana I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Instabilities and Solitons in Minimal Strips</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures. Videos can be found at
  http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/staff/academic/galexander/research/soapfilm</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 017801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.017801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that highly twisted minimal strips can undergo a non-singular
transition, unlike the singular transitions seen in the M\&quot;obius strip and the
catenoid. If the strip is non-orientable this transition is topologically
frustrated, and the resulting surface contains a helical defect. Through a
controlled analytic approximation the system can be mapped onto a scalar
$\phi^4$ theory on a non-orientable line bundle over the circle, where the
defect becomes a topologically protected kink soliton or domain wall, thus
establishing their existence in minimal surfaces. Experimental studies of soap
films confirm these results and demonstrate how the position of the defect can
be controlled through boundary deformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03946</id><created>2016-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yeo</keyname><forenames>Kyongmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lushi</keyname><forenames>Enkeleida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlahovska</keyname><forenames>Petia M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of inert spheres in active suspensions of micro-rotors</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12 pg. 5645-5652 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM00360E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inert particles suspended in active fluids of self-propelled particles are
known to often exhibit enhanced diffusion and novel coherent structures. Here
we numerically investigate the dynamical behavior and self-organization in a
system consisting of passive and actively rotating spheres. The particles
interact through direct collisions and the fluid flows generated as they move.
In the absence of passive particles, three states emerge in a binary mixture of
spinning spheres depending on particle fraction: a dilute gas-like state where
the rotors move chaotically, a phase-separated state where like-rotors move in
lanes or vortices, and a jammed state where crystals continuously assemble,
melt and move (K. Yeo, E. Lushi, and P. M. Vlahovska, Phys. Rev. Lett. 114,
188301 (2015)). Passive particles added to the rotor suspension modify the
system dynamics and pattern formation: while states identified in the pure
active suspension still emerge, they occur at different densities and mixture
proportions. The dynamical behavior of the inert particles is also
non-trivially dependent on the system composition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04658</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Onken</keyname><forenames>Franziska</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Theoretische Physik and Center for Dynamics, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Physik komplexer Systeme</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Theoretische Physik and Center for Dynamics, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Physik komplexer Systeme</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ketzmerick</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Theoretische Physik and Center for Dynamics, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Physik komplexer Systeme</affiliation></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;cker</keyname><forenames>Arnd</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Theoretische Physik and Center for Dynamics, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Physik komplexer Systeme</affiliation></author></authors><title>Bifurcations of families of 1D-tori in 4D symplectic maps</title><categories>nlin.CD math.DS</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures. For videos of 3D phase-space slices see
  http://www.comp-phys.tu-dresden.de/supp/</comments><journal-ref>Chaos 26, 063124 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4954024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The regular structures of a generic 4D symplectic map with a mixed phase
space are organized by one-parameter families of elliptic 1D-tori. Such
families show prominent bends, gaps, and new branches. We explain these
features in terms of bifurcations of the families when crossing a resonance.
For these bifurcations no external parameter has to be varied. Instead, the
longitudinal frequency, which varies along the family, plays the role of the
bifurcation parameter. As an example we study two coupled standard maps by
visualizing the elliptic and hyperbolic 1D-tori in a 3D phase-space slice,
local 2D projections, and frequency space. The observed bifurcations are
consistent with analytical predictions previously obtained for
quasi-periodically forced oscillators. Moreover, the new families emerging from
such a bifurcation form the skeleton of the corresponding resonance channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05296</id><created>2016-02-16</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramsay</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrowell</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear Melting at the Crystal-Liquid Interface: Erosion and the
  Asymmetric Suppression of Interface Fluctuations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 042608 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.042608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of an applied shear on the planar crystal-melt interface is
modelled by a nonlinear stochastic partial differential equation of the
interface fluctuations. A feature of this theory is the asymmetric destruction
of interface fluctuations due to advection of the crystal protrusions on the
liquid side of the interface only. We show that this model is able to
qualitatively reproduce the nonequilibrium coexistence line found in
simulations. The impact of shear on spherical clusters is also addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05499</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bodendorfer</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Some notes on the Kodama state, maximal symmetry, and the isolated
  horizon boundary condition</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6+3 pages; v2: journal version, slight shortening and added
  clarifications</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 124042 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.124042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recall some well and some less known results about the Kodama state and
the related $\theta$ ambiguity in defining canonical variables. Based on them,
we make some comments highlighting that the Kodama state for real connection
variables can be given a precise meaning and that it implements a vacuum peaked
on a (in a suitable sense) maximally symmetric geometry. We also highlight the
similarity of this construction with the isolated horizon boundary condition $F
\propto \Sigma$ and stress that it is, in agreement with earlier work,
inadequate to define the notion of a quantum horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06604</id><created>2016-02-21</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lokhov</keyname><forenames>Andrey Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemons</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>McAndrew</keyname><forenames>Thomas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagberg</keyname><forenames>Aric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Backhaus</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of Cyber-Physical Faults and Intrusions from Physical
  Correlations</title><categories>cs.SY cs.SI physics.data-an physics.soc-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cyber-physical systems are critical infrastructures that are crucial both to
the reliable delivery of resources such as energy, and to the stable
functioning of automatic and control architectures. These systems are composed
of interdependent physical, control and communications networks described by
disparate mathematical models creating scientific challenges that go well
beyond the modeling and analysis of the individual networks. A key challenge in
cyber-physical defense is a fast online detection and localization of faults
and intrusions without prior knowledge of the failure type. We describe a set
of techniques for the efficient identification of faults from correlations in
physical signals, assuming only a minimal amount of available system
information. The performance of our detection method is illustrated on data
collected from a large building automation system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08222</id><created>2016-02-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xin-Qi</forenames></author></authors><title>Number-resolved master equation approach to quantum measurement and
  quantum transport</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 16 figures; review article to appear in Frontiers of
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>Front. Phys. 11(4), 110307 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In addition to the well-known Landauer-Buttiker scattering theory and the
nonequilibrium Green's function technique for mesoscopic transports, an
alternative (and very useful) scheme is quantum master equation approach. In
this article, we review the particle-number (n)-resolved master equation (n-ME)
approach and its systematic applications in quantum measurement and quantum
transport problems. The n-ME contains rich dynamical information, allowing
efficient study of topics such as shot noise and full counting statistics
analysis. Moreover, we also review a newly developed master equation approach
(and its n-resolved version) under self-consistent Born approximation. The
application potential of this new approach is critically examined via its
ability to recover the exact results for noninteracting systems under arbitrary
voltage and in presence of strong quantum interference, and the challenging
non-equilibrium Kondo effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00610</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bajkova</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hercules and Wolf 630 Stellar Streams and Galactic Bar Kinematics</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 tables, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, 2016, Vol. 42, No. 4, pp. 228-239</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773716040010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have identified the four most significant features in the UV velocity
distribution of solar neighborhood stars: H1, H2 in the Hercules stream and W1,
W2 in the Wolf 630 stream. We have formulated the problem of determining
several characteristics of the central Galactic bar independently from each of
the identified features by assuming that the Hercules and Wolf 630 streams are
of a bar-induced dynamical nature. The problem has been solved by constructing
2:1 resonant orbits in the rotating bar frame for each star in these streams.
Analysis of the resonant orbits found has shown that the bar pattern speed is
45-55 km/s/kpc, while the bar angle lies within the range 40-60 degrees. The
results obtained are consistent with the view that the Hercules and Wolf 630
streams could be formed by a long-term influence of the Galactic bar leading to
a characteristic bimodal splitting of the UV velocity plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01143</id><created>2016-03-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Wioland</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lushi</keyname><forenames>Enkeleida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Raymond E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directed collective motion of bacteria under channel confinement</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 075002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/075002</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Dense suspensions of swimming bacteria are known to exhibit collective
behaviour arising from the interplay of steric and hydrodynamic interactions.
Unconfined suspensions exhibit transient, recurring vortices and jets, whereas
those confinedin circular domains may exhibit order in the form of a spiral
vortex. Here we show that confinement into a long and narrow macroscopic
`racetrack' geometry stabilises bacterial motion to form a steady
unidirectional circulation. This motion is reproduced in simulations of
discrete swimmers that reveal the crucial role that bacteria-driven fluid flows
play in the dynamics. In particular, cells close to the channel wall produce
strong flows which advect cells in the bulk against their swimming direction.
We examine in detail the transition from a disordered state to persistent
directed motion as a function of the channel width,and show that the width at
the crossover point is comparable to the typical correlation length of swirls
seen in the unbounded system. Our results shed light on the mechanisms driving
the collective behaviour of bacteria and other active matter systems, and
stress the importance of the ubiquitous boundaries found in natural habitats.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01332</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>del Pino</keyname><forenames>Sim&#xf3;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toloza</keyname><forenames>Adolfo</forenames></author></authors><title>Torsion as a Gauge Field in a Lorentz-Chern-Simons Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore a model of gravity that arises from the consideration of the
Chern-Simons form in 2+1 dimensions for a spin connection with a contorsion
described by a scalar and a vector field. The effective Lagrangian presents a
local Weyl symmetry allowing us to gauge the scalar field to a constant value.
From a gauge field theory perspective, it is shown that the vector part of the
torsion (related to its trace) is a gauge field for the Weyl group, which
allows the interpretation of the torsion as an electromagnetic field. In the
gauge of constant scalar field we obtain Chiral Gravity coupled to a
Chern-Simons-Proca theory for the vector field, that at the level of equations
of motion is equivalent to Topologically Massive Electrodynamics minimally
coupled to Chiral Gravity. Electrodynamics and gravity appear here unified as
geometrical features of a Riemann-Cartan manifold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02969</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zazunov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egger</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeyati</keyname><forenames>A. Levy</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-energy theory of transport in Majorana wire junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures, published version (presentation improved, one
  subsection added)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate and apply a low-energy transport theory for hybrid quantum
devices containing junctions of topological superconductor (TS) wires and
conventional normal (N) or superconducting (S) leads. We model TS wires as
spinless $p$-wave superconductors and derive their boundary Keldysh Green's
function, capturing both the Majorana end state and continuum quasiparticle
excitations in a unified manner. We also specify this Green's function for a
finite-length TS wire. Junctions connecting different parts of the device are
described by the standard tunneling Hamiltonian. Using this Hamiltonian
approach, one also has the option to include many-body interactions in a
systematic manner. For N-TS junctions, we provide the current-voltage ($I$-$V$)
characteristics at arbitrary junction transparency and give exact results for
the shot noise power and the excess current. For TS-TS junctions, analytical
results for the thermal noise spectrum and for the $I$-$V$ curve in the
high-transparency low-bias regime are presented. For S-TS junctions, we compute
the entire $I$-$V$ curve and clarify the conditions for having a finite
Josephson current.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03444</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wierschem</keyname><forenames>Keola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beach</keyname><forenames>K. S. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of symmetry-protected topological order in AKLT states by
  exact evaluation of the strange correlator</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages and 17 figures, including appendices (the text of v3 mirrors
  the published version)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 245141 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.245141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strange correlator [Phys. Rev. Lett. 112, 247202 (2014)] has been
proposed as a measure of symmetry protected topological order in one- and
two-dimensional systems. It takes the form of a spin-spin correlation function,
computed as a mixed overlap between the state of interest and a trivial local
product state. We demonstrate that it can be computed exactly (asymptotically,
in the Monte Carlo sense) for various Affleck-Kennedy-Lieb-Tasaki states by
direct evaluation of the wave function within the valence bond loop gas
framework. We present results for lattices with chain, square, honeycomb, cube,
diamond, and hyperhoneycomb geometries. In each case, the spin quantum number S
is varied such that 2S (the number of valence bonds emerging from each site)
achieves various integer multiples of the lattice coordination number. We
introduce the concept of strange correlator loop winding number and point to
its utility in testing for the presence of symmetry protected topological
order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06278</id><created>2016-03-20</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mavalankar</keyname><forenames>Aquila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pei</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauger</keyname><forenames>Erik M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warner</keyname><forenames>Jamie H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briggs</keyname><forenames>G. Andrew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laird</keyname><forenames>Edward A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon-assisted tunneling and charge dephasing in a carbon nanotube
  double quantum dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235428 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235428</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report microwave-driven photon-assisted tunneling in a suspended carbon
nanotube double quantum dot. From the resonant linewidth at a temperature of 13
mK, the charge dephasing time is determined to be 280 +- 30 ps. The linewidth
is independent of driving frequency, but increases with increasing temperature.
The moderate temperature dependence is inconsistent with expectations from
electron-phonon coupling alone, but consistent with charge noise arising in the
device. The extracted level of charge noise is comparable with that expected
from previous measurements of a valley-spin qubit, where it was hypothesized to
be the main cause of qubit decoherence. Our results suggest a possible route
towards improved valley-spin qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07336</id><created>2016-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Purwanto</keyname><forenames>Wirawan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krakauer</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author></authors><title>Auxiliary-field quantum Monte Carlo calculations of the molybdenum dimer</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 244306 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4954245</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chemical accuracy is difficult to achieve for systems with transition metal
atoms. Third row transition metal atoms are particularly challenging due to
strong electron-electron correlation in localized d-orbitals. The Cr2 molecule
is an outstanding example, which we previously treated with highly accurate
auxiliary-field quantum Monte Carlo (AFQMC) calculations [Purwanto et al., J.
Chem. Phys. 142, 064302 (2015)]. Somewhat surprisingly, computational
description of the isoelectronic Mo2 dimer has also, to date, been scattered
and less than satisfactory. We present high-level theoretical benchmarks of the
Mo2 singlet ground state ($X ^1\Sigma_g^+$) and first triplet excited state ($a
^3\Sigma_u^+$), using the phaseless AFQMC calculations. Extrapolation to the
complete basis set limit is performed. Excellent agreement with experimental
spectroscopic constants is obtained. We also present a comparison of the
correlation effects in Cr2 and Mo2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08613</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Basiri-Esfahani</keyname><forenames>Sahar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myers</keyname><forenames>Casey R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milburn</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum and classical control of single photon states via a mechanical
  resonator</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 063023 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/6/063023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optomechanical systems typically use light to control the quantum state of a
mechanical resonator. In this paper, we propose a scheme for controlling the
quantum state of light using the mechanical degree of freedom as a controlled
beam splitter. Preparing the mechanical resonator in non-classical states
enables an optomechanical Stern-Gerlach interferometer. When the mechanical
resonator has a small coherent amplitude it acts as a quantum control,
entangling the optical and mechanical degrees of freedom. As the coherent
amplitude of the resonator increases, we recover single photon and two-photon
interference via a classically controlled beam splitter. The visibility of the
two-photon interference is particularly sensitive to coherent excitations in
the mechanical resonator and this could form the basis of an optically
transduced weak-force sensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02525</id><created>2016-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Belle Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>C. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aihara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asner</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aulchenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aushev</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayad</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babu</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badhrees</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakich</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barberio</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behera</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhardwaj</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhuyan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bobrov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonvicini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bra&#x10d;ko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Browder</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x10c;ervenkov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chekelian</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheon</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chilikin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chistov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chobanova</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>S. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cinabro</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalseno</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danilov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dash</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dole&#x17e;al</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dr&#xe1;sal</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eidelman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>W. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fast</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulsom</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaur</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabyshev</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garmash</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillard</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glattauer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldenzweig</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grzymkowska</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haba</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayasaka</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashii</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>W. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iijima</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inami</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inguglia</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itoh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaegle</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeon</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joo</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julius</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiesling</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kody&#x161;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korpar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotchetkov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kri&#x17e;an</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krokovny</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Y. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gioi</keyname><forenames>L. Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libby</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liventsev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubej</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matvienko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyabayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyata</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuk</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moll</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>H. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mussa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanut</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nath</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natkaniec</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishida</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostrowicz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakhlov</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakhlova</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>C. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pes&#xe1;ntez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pestotnik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petri&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piilonen</keyname><forenames>L. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pulvermacher</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandilya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santelj</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanuki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savinov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schl&#xfc;ter</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnell</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwanda</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seino</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semmler</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senyo</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seong</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevior</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>T. -A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiu</keyname><forenames>J. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shwartz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solovieva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stani&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stari&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strube</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stypula</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumihama</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumiyoshi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takizawa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamponi</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tenchini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trabelsi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uehara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uglov</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unno</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uno</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urquijo</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Hulse</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varner</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>M. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Won</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaoka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yelton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yook</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yusa</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhilich</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhukova</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhulanov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zupanc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>First observation of $\gamma \gamma \to p \bar{p} K^+ K^-$ and search
  for exotic baryons in $pK$ systems</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><report-no>Belle Preprint 2016-02, KEK Preprint 2016-1</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 112017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.112017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The process $\gamma \gamma \to p \bar{p} K^+ K^-$ and its intermediate
processes are measured for the first time using a 980~fb$^{-1}$ data sample
collected with the Belle detector at the KEKB asymmetric-energy $e^+e^-$
collider. The production of $p \bar{p} K^+ K^-$ and a
$\Lambda(1520)^0~(\bar{\Lambda}(1520)^0)$ signal in the $pK^-$~($\bar{p} K^+$)
invariant mass spectrum are clearly observed. However, no evidence for an
exotic baryon near 1540~MeV/$c^2$, denoted as
$\Theta(1540)^0$~($\bar{\Theta}~(1540)^0$) or
$\Theta(1540)^{++}$~($\Theta(1540)^{--}$), is seen in the $p
K^-$~($\bar{p}K^+$) or $pK^+$~($\bar{p} K^-$) invariant mass spectra. Cross
sections for $\gamma \gamma \to p \bar{p} K^+ K^-$, $\Lambda(1520)^0 \bar{p}
K^+ +c.c.$ and the products $\sigma(\gamma \gamma \to \Theta(1540)^0 \bar{p}
K^+ +c.c.)\BR(\Theta(1540)^0 \to p K^{-})$ and $\sigma(\gamma \gamma \to
\Theta(1540)^{++} \bar{p} K^- +c.c.)\BR(\Theta(1540)^{++}\to p K^{+})$ are
measured. We also determine upper limits on the products of the $\chi_{c0}$ and
$\chi_{c2}$ two-photon decay widths and their branching fractions to $p \bar{p}
K^+ K^-$ at the 90\% credibility level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03700</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sierra</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saiz-Bretin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominguez-Adame</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactions and thermoelectric effects in a parallel-coupled double
  quantum dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235452 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235452</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nonequilibrium transport properties of a double quantum
dot system connected in parallel to two leads, including intradot
electron-electron interaction. In the absence of interactions the system
supports a bound state in the continuum. This state is revealed as a Fano
antiresonance in the transmission when the energy levels of the dots are
detuned. Using the Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's function formalism, we find
that the occurrence of the Fano antiresonance survives in the presence of
Coulomb repulsion. We give precise predictions for the experimental detection
of bound states in the continuum. First, we calculate the differential
conductance as a function of the applied voltage and the dot level detuning and
find that crossing points in the diamond structure are revealed as minima due
to the transmission antiresonances. Second, we determine the thermoelectric
current in response to an applied temperature bias. In the linear regime,
quantum interference gives rise to sharp peaks in the thermoelectric
conductance. Remarkably, we find interaction induced strong current
nonlinearities for large thermal gradients that may lead to several nontrivial
zeros in the thermocurrent. The latter property is especially attractive for
thermoelectric applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03722</id><created>2016-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ngabonziza</keyname><forenames>Prosper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stehno</keyname><forenames>Martin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myoren</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neumann</keyname><forenames>Viola A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koster</keyname><forenames>Gertjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brinkman</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Gate-tunable transport properties of in-situ capped Bi$_2$Te$_3$
  topological insulator thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Electron. Mater. 2016, 1600157</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/aelm.201600157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combining the ability to prepare high-quality, intrinsic Bi$_2$Te$_3$
topological insulator thin films of low carrier density with in-situ protective
capping, we demonstrate a pronounced, gate-tunable change in transport
properties of Bi$_2$Te$_3$ thin films. Using a back-gate, the carrier density
is tuned by a factor of $\sim 7$ in Al$_2$O$_3$ capped Bi$_2$Te$_3$ sample and
by a factor of $\sim 2$ in Te capped Bi$_2$Te$_3$ films. We achieve full
depletion of bulk carriers, which allows us to access the topological transport
regime dominated by surface state conduction. When the Fermi level is placed in
the bulk band gap, we observe the presence of two coherent conduction channels
associated with the two decoupled surfaces. Our magnetotransport results show
that the combination of capping layers and electrostatic tuning of the Fermi
level provide a technological platform to investigate the topological
properties of surface states in transport experiments and pave the way towards
the implementation of a variety of topological quantum devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04049</id><created>2016-04-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Miyazaki</keyname><forenames>Masanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamauchi</keyname><forenames>Ichihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadono</keyname><forenames>Ryosuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Quest for the Origin of Heavy Fermion Behavior in $d$-Electron Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 091009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.091009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin fluctuation is presumed to be one of the key properties in understanding
the microscopic origin of heavy-fermion-like behavior in the class of
transition-metal compounds, including LiV$_2$O$_4$, Y(Sc)Mn$_2$, and
YMn$_2$Zn$_{20}$. In this review, we demonstrate by our recent study of muon
spin rotation/relaxation that the temperature ($T$) dependence of the
longitudinal spin relaxation rate ($\lambda\equiv 1/T_1$) in these compounds
exhibits a common trend of leveling off to a constant value ($\lambda\sim
const$.) below a characteristic temperature, $T^*$. This is in marked contrast
to the behavior predicted for normal metals from the Korringa relation,
$\lambda\propto T/\nu$, where the spin fluctuation rate ($\nu$) in the Pauli
paramagnetic state is given as a constant, $\nu\simeq 1/[h D(E_F)]$ [with
$D(E_F)$ being the density of states at the Fermi energy]. Thus, the observed
behavior of $\lambda$ implies that the spin fluctuation rate becomes linearly
dependent on temperature, $\nu\propto T$, suggesting that heavy quasiparticles
develop in a manner satisfying $D(E_F)\propto (m^*)^{\sigma}\propto 1/T$ at
lower temperatures ($\sigma$ determined by the electronic dispersion).
Considering that the theory of spin correlation for intersecting Hubbard chains
as a model of pyrochlore lattice predicts $\nu\propto T$, our finding strongly
indicates the crucial role of $t_{2g}$ bands which preserve the one-dimensional
character at low energies due to the geometrical frustration specific to the
undistorted pyrochlore lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05036</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huffman</keyname><forenames>B. Todd</forenames><affiliation>Oxford University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames><affiliation>Oxford University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tseng</keyname><forenames>Jeff</forenames><affiliation>Oxford University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Tagging $b$ quarks at extreme energies without tracks</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43 (2016) 085001 (10pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/8/085001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a new hit-based $b$-tagging technique for high energy jets and
study its performance with a Geant4-based simulation. The technique uses the
fact that at sufficiently high energy a B meson or baryon can live long enough
to traverse the inner layers of pixel detectors such as those in the ATLAS,
ALICE, or CMS experiments prior to decay. By first defining a &quot;jet&quot; via the
calorimeter, and then counting hits within that jet between pixel layers at
increasing radii, we show it is possible to identify jets that contain
$b$-quarks by detecting a jump in the number of hits. We show that the
technique maintains its efficiency at energies beyond the range of conventional
$b$-taggers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06944</id><created>2016-04-23</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Island</keyname><forenames>Joshua O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>Gary A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>Herre S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellanos-Gomez</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author></authors><title>Thickness dependent interlayer transport in vertical MoS2 Josephson
  junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures including Supporting Information</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 3, 031002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/3/3/031002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on observations of thickness dependent Josephson coupling and
multiple Andreev reflections (MAR) in vertically stacked molybdenum disulfide
(MoS2) - molybdenum rhenium (MoRe) Josephson junctions. MoRe, a chemically
inert superconductor, allows for oxide free fabrication of high transparency
vertical MoS2 devices. Single and bilayer MoS2 junctions display relatively
large critical currents (up to 2.5 uA) and the appearance of sub-gap structure
given by MAR. In three and four layer thick devices we observe orders of
magnitude lower critical currents (sub-nA) and reduced quasiparticle gaps due
to proximitized MoS2 layers in contact with MoRe. We anticipate that this
device architecture could be easily extended to other 2D materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07569</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huebner</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boehnke</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martens</keyname><forenames>Ulrike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Andy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmalhorst</keyname><forenames>Jan-Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiss</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;nzenberg</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuschel</keyname><forenames>Timo</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of laser induced and intrinsic tunnel magneto-Seebeck effect
  in CoFeB/MgAl$_2$O$_4$ and CoFeB/MgO magnetic tunnel junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 224433 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.224433</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparison of the tunnel magneto-Seebeck effect for laser
induced and intrinsic heating. Therefore,
Co$_{40}$Fe$_{40}$B$_{20}$/MgAl$_2$O$_4$ and Co$_{25}$Fe$_{55}$B$_{20}$/MgO
magnetic tunnel junctions have been prepared. The TMS ratio of 3\,\% in case of
the MAO MTJ agrees well with ratios found for other barrier materials, while
the TMS ratio of 23\,\% of the MgO MTJ emphasizes the influence of the CoFe
composition. We find results using the intrinsic method that differ in sign and
magnitude in comparison to the results of the laser heating. The intrinsic
contributions can alternatively be explained by the Brinkman model and the
given junction properties. Especially, we are able to demonstrate that the
symmetric contribution is solely influenced by the barrier asymmetry. Thus, we
conclude that the symmetry analysis used for the intrinsic method is not
suitable to unambiguously identify an intrinsic tunnel magneto-Seebeck effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08586</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ijjas</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ripley</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinhardt</keyname><forenames>Paul J.</forenames></author></authors><title>NEC violation in mimetic cosmology revisited</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 760 (2016), pp. 132-138</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of Einstein gravity, if the null energy condition (NEC) is
satisfied, the energy density in expanding space-times always decreases while
in contracting space-times the energy density grows and the universe eventually
collapses into a singularity. In particular, no non-singular bounce is
possible. It is, though, an open question if this energy condition can be
violated in a controlled way, i.e., without introducing pathologies, such as
unstable negative-energy states or an imaginary speed of sound. In this paper,
we will re-examine the claim that the recently proposed mimetic scenario can
violate the NEC without pathologies. We show that mimetic cosmology is prone to
gradient instabilities even in cases when the NEC is satisfied (except for
trivial examples). Most interestingly, the source of the instability is always
the Einstein-Hilbert term in the action. The matter stress-energy component
does not contribute spatial gradient terms but instead makes the problematic
curvature modes dynamical. We also show that mimetic cosmology can be
understood as a singular limit of known, well-behaved theories involving
higher-derivative kinetic terms and discuss ways of removing the instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00074</id><created>2016-04-30</created><updated>2016-06-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gorobets</keyname><forenames>A. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borrero</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berdyugina</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Markov properties of the magnetic field in the quiet solar photosphere</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/825/2/L18</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The observed magnetic field on the solar surface is characterized by a very
complex spatial and temporal behaviour. Although feature-tracking algorithms
have allowed us to deepen our understanding of this behaviour, subjectivity
plays an important role in the identification, tracking of such features. In
this paper we study the temporal stochasticity of the magnetic field on the
solar surface \textit{without} relying neither on the concept of magnetic
feature nor on subjective assumptions about their identification and
interaction. The analysis is applied to observations of the magnetic field of
the quiet solar photosphere carried out with the IMaX instrument on-board the
stratospheric balloon {\sc Sunrise}. We show that the joint probability
distribution functions of the longitudinal ($B_\parallel$) and transverse
($B_\perp$) components of the magnetic field, as well as of the magnetic
pressure ($B^2=B^2_\perp+B^2_\parallel$), verify the necessary and sufficient
condition for the Markov chains. Therefore we establish that the magnetic
field, as seen by IMaX with a resolution of 0.15\arcsec-0.18\arcsec and
$33$~sec cadence, can be considered as a memoryless temporal fluctuating
quantity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00567</id><created>2016-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Villois</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Proment</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krstulovic</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of a superfluid vortex filament tangle driven by the
  Gross-Pitaevskii equation</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.061103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development and decay of a turbulent vortex tangle driven by the
Gross-Pitaevskii equation is studied. Using a recently-developed accurate and
robust tracking algorithm, all quantised vortices are extracted from the
fields. The Vinen's decay law for the total vortex length with a coefficient
that is in quantitative agreement with the values measured in Helium II is
observed. The topology of the tangle is then studied showing that linked rings
may appear during the decay. The tracking also allows for determining the
statistics of small-scales quantities of vortex lines, exhibiting large
fluctuations of curvature and torsion. Finally, the temporal evolution of the
Kelvin wave spectrum is obtained providing evidence of the development of a
weak-wave turbulence cascade.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01487</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Izmaylov</keyname><forenames>Artur F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jiaru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joubert-Doriol</keyname><forenames>Loic</forenames></author></authors><title>A diabatic definition of geometric phase effects</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electronic wave-functions in the adiabatic representation acquire nontrivial
geometric phases (GPs) when corresponding potential energy surfaces undergo
conical intersection (CI). These GPs have profound effects on the nuclear
quantum dynamics and cannot be eliminated in the adiabatic representation
without changing the physics of the system. To define dynamical effects arising
from the GP presence the nuclear quantum dynamics of the CI containing system
is compared with that of the system with artificially removed GP. We explore a
new construction of the system with removed GP via a modification of the
diabatic representation for the original CI containing system. Using an
absolute value function of diabatic couplings we remove the GP while preserving
adiabatic potential energy surfaces and CI. We assess GP effects in dynamics of
a two-dimensional linear vibronic coupling model both for ground and excited
state dynamics. Results are compared with those obtained with a conventional
removal of the GP by ignoring double-valued boundary conditions of the real
electronic wave-functions. Interestingly, GP effects appear similar in two
approaches only for the low energy dynamics. In contrast with the conventional
approach, a new approach does not have substantial GP effects in the ultra-fast
excited state dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04290</id><created>2016-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sudhaker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganai</keyname><forenames>Prince A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite Field-dependent Symmetry in Thirring Model</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, Accepted for publication in Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. 2016, 063B04</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider a $D$-dimensional massive Thirring model with
($2&lt;D&lt;4$). We derive an extended BRST symmetry of the theory with finite
field-dependent parameter. Further we compute the Jacobian of functional
measure under such an extended transformation. Remarkably, we find that such
Jacobian extends the BRST exact part of the action which leads to a mapping
between different gauges. We illustrate this with the help of Lorentz and
$R_\xi$ gauges. We also discuss the results in Batalin-Vilkovisky framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08793</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Needleman</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of size on necking of dynamically loaded notched bars</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of material inertia on neck development in a notched round bar
is analyzed numerically. Dynamic axisymmetric calculations are carried out for
isotropically hardening elastic-viscoplastic solids so that both material
strain rate sensitivity and material inertia are accounted for. The focus is on
the effect of bar size on whether the notch triggers necking or necking
initiates away from the notch. The governing equations are presented in
non-dimensional form and two key non-dimensional groups that involve both
material and loading parameters are identified. For both non-dimensional
groups, with all parameters fixed except for bar size, it is found that for
sufficiently small bars, the notch triggers necking, whereas for sufficiently
large bars necking ultimately occurs away from the notch. With material
properties fixed, for one non-dimensional group the transition to necking away
from the notch corresponds to increasing imposed velocity whereas for the other
non- dimensional group this transition takes place for decreasing imposed
strain rate. Both these transitions correspond to increasing bar size. The
results indicate that this transition is governed by material inertia but the
bar size at which it occurs depends on the material properties, particularly
strain hardening and strain rate hardening.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00201</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>R&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aksyutina</keyname><forenames>Yulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcantara</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altstadt</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez-Pol</keyname><forenames>Hector</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashwood</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atar</keyname><forenames>Leyla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aumann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avdeichikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beceiro</keyname><forenames>Saul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bemmerer</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benlliure</keyname><forenames>Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertulani</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boretzky</keyname><forenames>Konstanze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borge</keyname><forenames>Maria J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgunder</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caamano</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caesar</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casarejos</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catford</keyname><forenames>Wilton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cederkall</keyname><forenames>Joakim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chartier</keyname><forenames>Marielle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chulkov</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cortina-Gil</keyname><forenames>Dolores</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crespo</keyname><forenames>Raquel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Ushasi Datta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Fernandez</keyname><forenames>Paloma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dillmann</keyname><forenames>Iris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elekes</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enders</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ershova</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Estrade</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farinon</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraile</keyname><forenames>Luis M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freer</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freudenberger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galaviz</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geissel</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gernh&#xe4;user</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;bel</keyname><forenames>Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golubev</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Diego Gonzalez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagdahl</keyname><forenames>Julius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heftrich</keyname><forenames>Tanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heil</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heine</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henriques</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holl</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ickert</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ignatov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobsson</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>Hakan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonson</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantar-Nayestanaki</keyname><forenames>Nasser</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanungo</keyname><forenames>Rituparna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelic-Heil</keyname><forenames>Aleksandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kn&#xf6;bel</keyname><forenames>Ronja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xf6;ll</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;cken</keyname><forenames>Reiner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurcewicz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurz</keyname><forenames>Nikolaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labiche</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleis</keyname><forenames>Tudi Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemmon</keyname><forenames>Roy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepyoshkina</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindberg</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machado</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marganiec</keyname><forenames>Justyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caro</keyname><forenames>Magdalena Mostazo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movsesyan</keyname><forenames>Alina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Najafi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nociforo</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panin</keyname><forenames>Valerii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paschalis</keyname><forenames>Stefanos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perea</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petri</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plag</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prochazka</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Md. Anisur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rastrepina</keyname><forenames>Ganna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reifarth</keyname><forenames>Rene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricciardi</keyname><forenames>M. Valentina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigollet</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riisager</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Dominic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saez</keyname><forenames>Jose Sanchez del Rio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savran</keyname><forenames>Deniz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheit</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Haik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorlin</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoica</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Streicher</keyname><forenames>Branislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tengblad</keyname><forenames>Olof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thies</keyname><forenames>Ronja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Togano</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uberseder</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Walle</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velho</keyname><forenames>Paulo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Vasily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wamers</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weick</keyname><forenames>Helmut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weigand</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wheldon</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wimmer</keyname><forenames>Christine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winfield</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakorev</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhukov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zilges</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuber</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Coulomb dissociation of $^{20,21}$N</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 065807 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.065807</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutron-rich light nuclei and their reactions play an important role for the
creation of chemical elements. Here, data from a Coulomb dissociation
experiment on $^{20,21}$N are reported. Relativistic $^{20,21}$N ions impinged
on a lead target and the Coulomb dissociation cross section was determined in a
kinematically complete experiment. Using the detailed balance theorem, the
$^{19}\mathrm{N}(\mathrm{n},\gamma)^{20}\mathrm{N}$ and
$^{20}\mathrm{N}(\mathrm{n},\gamma)^{21}\mathrm{N}$ excitation functions and
thermonuclear reaction rates have been determined. The
$^{19}\mathrm{N}(\mathrm{n},\gamma)^{20}\mathrm{N}$ rate is up to a factor of 5
higher at $T&lt;1$\,GK with respect to previous theoretical calculations, leading
to a 10\,\% decrease in the predicted fluorine abundance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02920</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhdanov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>C. -R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwabe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nosenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morfill</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wake turbulence observed behind an upstream &quot;extra&quot; particle in a
  complex (dusty) plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL 114 (2016) 55002</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/55002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An interaction of upstream extra particles with a monolayer highly-ordered
complex plasma is studied. A principally new abnormal turbulent wake formed
behind the supersonic upstream particle is discovered. An anomalous type of the
turbulence wake clearly manifests in anomalously low thermal diffusivity and
two orders of magnitude larger particle kinetic temperature compared to that of
the 'normal' wake (Mach cone) observed by Du et al [Europhys. Lett. 99, 55001
(2012)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03079</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Franovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosti&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Sr&#x111;an</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perc</keyname><forenames>Matjaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinshov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nekorkin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurths</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase response curves for models of earthquake fault dynamics</title><categories>physics.geo-ph nlin.CD</categories><comments>13 two-column pages, 9 figures; accepted for publication in Chaos</comments><journal-ref>Chaos 26 (2016) 063105</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953471</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We systematically study effects of external perturbations on models
describing earthquake fault dynamics. The latter are based on the framework of
the Burridge-Knopoff spring-block system, including the cases of a simple
mono-block fault, as well as the paradigmatic complex faults made up of two
identical or distinct blocks. The blocks exhibit relaxation oscillations, which
are representative for the stick-slip behavior typical for earthquake dynamics.
Our analysis is carried out by determining the phase response curves of first
and second order. For a mono-block fault, we consider the impact of a single
and two successive pulse perturbations, further demonstrating how the profile
of phase response curves depends on the fault parameters. For a homogeneous
two-block fault, our focus is on the scenario where each of the blocks is
influenced by a single pulse, whereas for heterogeneous faults, we analyze how
the response of the system depends on whether the stimulus is applied to the
block having a shorter or a longer oscillation period.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05258</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kopp</keyname><forenames>Greg</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnitudes and Timescales of Total Solar Irradiance Variability</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Journal of Space Weather and Space Climate, 2016, 19 pp., 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1051/swsc/2016025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Sun's net radiative output varies on timescales of minutes to gigayears.
Direct measurements of the total solar irradiance (TSI) show changes in the
spatially- and spectrally-integrated radiant energy on timescales as short as
minutes to as long as a solar cycle. Variations of ~0.01 % over a few minutes
are caused by the ever-present superposition of convection and oscillations
with very large solar flares on rare occasion causing slightly-larger
measureable signals. On timescales of days to weeks, changing photospheric
magnetic activity affects solar brightness at the ~0.1 % level. The 11-year
solar cycle shows variations of comparable magnitude with irradiances peaking
near solar maximum. Secular variations are more difficult to discern, being
limited by instrument stability and the relatively short duration of the
space-borne record. Historical reconstructions of the Sun's irradiance based on
indicators of solar-surface magnetic activity, such as sunspots, faculae, and
cosmogenic isotope records, suggest solar brightness changes over decades to
millennia, although the magnitudes of these variations have high uncertainties
due to the indirect historical records on which they rely. Stellar evolution
affects yet longer timescales and is responsible for the greatest solar
variabilities. In this manuscript I summarize the Sun's variability magnitudes
over different temporal regimes and discuss the irradiance record's relevance
for solar and climate studies as well as for detections of exo-solar planets
transiting Sun-like stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05952</id><created>2016-06-19</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>DeVore</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappaport</keyname><forenames>Saul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchis-Ojeda</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Kelsey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowe</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Detection of Non-Transiting Exoplanets with Dusty Tails</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>accepted for publication by Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical
  Society, 9 pages, 9 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1439</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a way of searching for non-transiting exoplanets with dusty tails.
In the transiting case, the extinction by dust during the transit removes more
light from the beam than is scattered into it. Thus, the forward scattering
component of the light is best seen either just prior to ingress, or just after
egress, but with reduced amplitude over the larger peak that is obscured by the
transit. This picture suggests that it should be equally productive to search
for positive-going peaks in the flux from non-transiting exoplanets with dusty
tails. We discuss what amplitudes are expected for different orbital
inclination angles. The signature of such objects should be distinct from
normal transits, starspots, and most - but not all - types of stellar
pulsations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09450</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Gontcharov</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Variations of the Interstellar Extinction Law within the Nearest
  Kiloparsec</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters 38 (2012) 12-24</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773711120048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multicolor photometry from the Tycho-2 and 2MASS catalogues for 11 990 OB and
30 671 K-type red giant branch stars is used to detect systematic large-scale
variations of the interstellar extinction law within the nearest kiloparsec.
The characteristic of the extinction law, the total-to-selective extinction
ratio $R_V$, which also characterizes the size and other properties of
interstellar dust grains, has been calculated for various regions of space by
the extinction law extrapolation method. The results for the two classes of
stars agree: the standard deviation of the &quot;red giants minus OB&quot; $R_V$
differences within 500 pc of the Sun is 0.2. The detected $R_V$ variations
between 2.2 and 4.4 not only manifest themselves in individual clouds but also
span the entire space near the Sun, following Galactic structures. In the Local
Bubble within about 100 pc of the Sun, $R_V$ has a minimum. In the inner part
of the Gould Belt and at high Galactic latitudes, at a distance of about 150 pc
from the Sun, $R_V$ reaches a maximum and then decreases to its minimum in the
outer part of the Belt and other directions at a distance of about 500 pc from
the Sun, returning to its mean values far from the Sun. The detected maximum of
$R_V$ at high Galactic latitudes is important when allowance is made for the
interstellar extinction toward extragalactic objects. In addition, a monotonic
increase in $R_V$ by 0.3 per kpc toward the Galactic center has been found near
the Galactic equator. It is consistent with the result obtained by Zasowski et
al. (2009) for much of the Galaxy. Ignoring the $R_V$ variations and
traditionally using a single value for the entire space must lead to systematic
errors in the calculated distances reaching 10\%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09483</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Gontcharov</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>3D Interstellar Extinction Map within the Nearest Kiloparsec</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters 38 (2012) 87-100</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773712010033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The product of the previously constructed 3D maps of stellar reddening
(Gontcharov 2010) and $R_V$ variations (Gontcharov 2012) has allowed us to
produce a 3D interstellar extinction map within the nearest kiloparsec from the
Sun with a spatial resolution of 50 pc and an accuracy of $0.2^m$. This map is
compared with the 2D reddening map by Schlegel et al. (1998), the 3D extinction
map at high latitudes by Jones et al. (2011), and the analytical extinction
models by Arenou et al. (1992) and Gontcharov (2009). In all cases, we have
found good agreement and show that there are no systematic errors in the new
map everywhere except the direction toward the Galactic center. We have found
that the map by Schlegel et al. (1998) reaches saturation near the Galactic
equator at $E_{(B-V)}&gt;0.8^m$, has a zero-point error and systematic errors
gradually increasing with reddening, and among the analytical models those that
take into account the extinction in the Gould Belt are more accurate. Our
extinction map shows that it is determined by reddening variations at low
latitudes and $R_V$ variations at high ones. This naturally explains the
contradictory data on the correlation or anticorrelation between reddening and
$R_V$ available in the literature. There is a correlation in a thin layer near
the Galactic equator, because both reddening and $R_V$ here increase toward the
Galactic center. There is an anticorrelation outside this layer, because higher
values of $R_V$ correspond to lower reddening at high and middle latitudes.
Systematic differences in sizes and other properties of the dust grains in
different parts of the Galaxy manifest themselves in this way. The largest
structures within the nearest kiloparsec, including the Local Bubble, the Gould
Belt, the Great Tunnel, the Scorpius, Perseus, Orion, and other complexes, have
manifested themselves in the constructed map.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00020</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Szczesny</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Twisted modules and co-invariants for commutative vertex algebras of jet
  schemes</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.AG math.MP math.RT</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $Z \subset \mathbb{A}^k$ be an affine scheme over $\C$ and $\J Z$ its jet
scheme. It is well-known that $\mathbb{C}[\J Z]$, the coordinate ring of $\J
Z$, has the structure of a commutative vertex algebra. This paper develops the
orbifold theory for $\mathbb{C}[\J Z]$. A finite-order linear automorphism $g$
of $Z$ acts by vertex algebra automorphisms on $\mathbb{C}[\J Z]$. We show that
$\mathbb{C}[\J^g Z]$, where $\J^g Z$ is the scheme of $g$--twisted jets has the
structure of a $g$-twisted $\mathbb{C}[\J Z]$ module. We consider spaces of
orbifold coinvariants valued in the modules $\mathbb{C}[\J^g Z]$ on orbicurves
$[Y/G]$, with $Y$ a smooth projective curve and $G$ a finite group, and show
that these are isomorphic to $\mathbb{C}[Z^G]$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00022</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Del Vicario</keyname><forenames>Michela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scala</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldarelli</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanley</keyname><forenames>H Eugene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quattrociocchi</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling confirmation bias and polarization</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Online users tend to select claims that adhere to their system of beliefs and
to ignore dissenting information. Confirmation bias, indeed, plays a pivotal
role in viral phenomena. Furthermore, the wide availability of content on the
web fosters the aggregation of likeminded people where debates tend to enforce
group polarization. Such a configuration might alter the public debate and thus
the formation of the public opinion. In this paper we provide a mathematical
model to study online social debates and the related polarization dynamics. We
assume the basic updating rule of the Bounded Confidence Model (BCM) and we
develop two variations a) the Rewire with Bounded Confidence Model (RBCM), in
which discordant links are broken until convergence is reached; and b) the
Unbounded Confidence Model, under which the interaction among discordant pairs
of users is allowed even with a negative feedback, either with the rewiring
step (RUCM) or without it (UCM). From numerical simulations we find that the
new models (UCM and RUCM), unlike the BCM, are able to explain the coexistence
of two stable final opinions, often observed in reality. Lastly, we present a
mean field approximation of the newly introduced models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00023</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Antipov</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames><affiliation>Chicago U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Didenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lebedev</keyname><forenames>Valeri</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Valishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Stripline kicker for integrable optics test accelerator</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-15-642-AD-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a design of a stripline kicker for Integrable Optics Test
Accelerator (IOTA). For its experimental program IOTA needs two full-aperture
kickers, capable to create an arbitrary controllable kick in 2D. For that
reason their strengths are variable in a wide range of amplitudes up to 16
mrad, and the pulse length 100 ns is less than a revolution period for
electrons. In addition, the kicker should have a physical aperture of 40 mm for
a proposed operation with proton beam, and an outer size of 70 mm to fit inside
existing quadrupole magnets to save space in the ring. Computer simulations
using CST Microwave Studio show high field uniformity and wave impedance close
to 50 {\Omega}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00028</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Neuffer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames><affiliation>UC, Riverside</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>UC, Riverside</affiliation></author></authors><title>Phase rotation of muon beams for producing intense low-energy muon beams</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-135-AD-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Low-energy muon beams are useful for rare decay searches, which provide
access to new physics that cannot be addressed at high-energy colliders.
However, muons are produced within a broad energy spread unmatched to the
low-energy required. In this paper we outline a phase rotation method to
significantly increase the intensity of low-energy muons. The muons are
produced from a short pulsed proton driver, and develop a time-momentum
correlation in a drift space following production. A series of rf cavities is
used to bunch the muons and phase-energy rotate the bunches to a momentum of
around 100 MeV/c. Then another group of rf cavities is used to decelerate the
muon bunches to low-energy. This obtains ~0.1 muon per 8 GeV proton, which is
significantly higher than currently planned Mu2e experiments, and would enable
a next generation of rare decay searches, and other intense muon beam
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00042</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>C.</keyname><forenames>W. A. Rojas</forenames></author><author><keyname>S</keyname><forenames>J. R. Arenas</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of hot quantum scalar field in a (D+1) dimensional curved
  spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the brick wall model to calculate the free energy of quantum scalar
field in a curved spacetime (D +1) dimensions. We find the thermodynamics
properties of quantum scalar field in several scenaries: Minkowski spacetime,
Schwarzschild spacetime and BTZ spacetime. For the cases analysed, the
thermodynamical properties of quantum scalar field is exactly with the
reported. It was found that the entropy of the gas is proportional to the
horizon area in a gravity field strong, which is consistent with the
holographic principle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00045</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>McGee</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Arkan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Peterson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Daly</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>Jefferson Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huque</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Jefferson Lab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Transport of LCLS-II 1.3 Ghz cryomodule to SLAC</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-136-AD-TD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In a partnership with SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory (SLAC) and
Jefferson Lab, Fermilab will assemble and test 17 of the 35 total 1.3 GHz
cryomodules for the Linac Coherent Light Source II (LCLS-II) Project. These
include a prototype built and delivered by each Lab. Another two 3.9 GHz
cryomodules will be built, tested and transported by Fermilab to SLAC. Each
assembly will be transported over-the-road from Fermilab or Jefferson Lab using
specific routes to SLAC. The transport system consists of a base frame,
isolation fixture and upper protective truss. The strongback cryomodule lifting
fixture is described along with other supporting equipment used for both
over-the-road transport and local (on-site) transport at Fermilab. Initially,
analysis of fragile components and stability studies will be performed in order
to assess the risk associated with over-the-road transport of a fully assembled
cryomodule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00073</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Nazari</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gole</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erramilli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narayan</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Cascade Bridge Rectifier Array in a 2-D lattice</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a novel rectification phenomenon in a 2-D lattice network
consisting of $N\times N$ sites with diode and AC source elements with
controllable phases. A phase cascade configuration is described in which the
current ripple in a load resistor goes to zero in the large $N$ limit,
enhancing the rectification efficiency without requiring any external capacitor
or inductor based filters. The integrated modular configuration is
qualitatively different from conventional rectenna arrays in which the source,
rectifier and filter systems are physically disjoint. Exact analytical results
derived using idealized diodes are compared to a realistic simulation of
commercially available diodes. Our results on nonlinear networks of
source-rectifier arrays are potentially of interest to a fast evolving field of
distributed power networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00085</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lencinas</keyname><forenames>Ver&#xf3;nica</forenames></author></authors><title>Metadata salad at the Cordoba Observatory</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Presented at Astroplate: International workshop on scientific use,
  digitization and preserving astronomical photographic records. Prague 14 - 18
  March 2016</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Plate Archive of the Cordoba Observatory includes 20.000 photographs and
spectra on glass plates dating from 1893 to 1983. This contribution describes
the work performed since the plate archive was transferred to the Observatory
Library in 2011. In 2014 an interdisciplinary team was assembled and a research
grant from the National University of Cordoba was obtained with the objectives
of preserving the glass plates and generate public access for astronomers and
other audiences. The preservation work not only includes practical intervention
to improve conservation conditions for the whole archive, but also a diagnose
of the preservation conditions for the plates and identification of best
practices for cleaning the plates. The access envisioned through digitization
requires not only the scanning of all the plates, but also careful definition
and provision of metadata. In this regard, each institutional level involved
-in this case: archive, library, astronomical observatory and public university
- demands and provides different bibliographic practices, involving multiple
standards of description and coding.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00114</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kovalchuk</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic Description of Diffractive Deuteron Breakup by He-3 Nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. At. Nucl., 2016, V.79, No.3, P.335-341</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063778816020101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A microscopic formalism for describing observed cross sections for deuteron
breakup by three-nucleon nuclei was developed on the basis of the diffraction
nuclear model. A general formula that describes the amplitude for the reaction
d+3He-&gt;3He+p+n and which involves only one adjustable parameter was obtained by
using expansions of the integrands involved in terms of a Gaussian basis. This
formula was used to analyze experimental data on the exclusive cross sections
for deuteron breakup by He-3 nuclei at the projectile energy of 89.4 MeV. The
importance of employing, in calculations, a deuteron wave function that has a
correct asymptotic behavior at large nucleon-nucleon distances was
demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00120</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Kyoohyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choe</keyname><forenames>Kibaek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Inwon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Pilhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>YongKeun</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic intravital microscopy for 2-D and 3-D imaging intact
  circulating blood cells in microcapillaries of live mice</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.med-ph physics.optics q-bio.QM</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intravital microscopy is an essential tool that reveals behaviours of live
cells under conditions close to natural physiological states. So far, although
various approaches for imaging cells in vivo have been proposed, most require
the use of labelling and also provide only qualitative imaging information.
Holographic imaging approach based on measuring the refractive index
distributions of cells, however, circumvent these problems and offer
quantitative and label-free imaging capability. Here, we demonstrate in vivo
two- and three-dimensional holographic imaging of circulating blood cells in
intact microcapillaries of live mice. The measured refractive index
distributions of blood cells provide morphological and biochemical properties
including three-dimensional cell shape, haemoglobin concentration, and
haemoglobin contents at the individual cell level. With the present method,
alterations in blood flow dynamics in live healthy and sepsis-model mouse were
also investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00121</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Narayan</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saniee</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling of random walk betweenness in networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The betweenness centrality of graphs using random walk paths instead of
geodesics is studied. A scaling collapse with no adjustable parameters is
obtained as the graph size $N$ is varied; the scaling curve depends on the
graph model. A normalized random betweenness, that counts each walk passing
through a node only once, is also defined. It is argued to be more useful and
seen to have simpler scaling behavior. In particular, the probability for a
random walk on a preferential attachment graph to pass through the root node is
found to tend to unity as $N\rightarrow\infty.$
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00126</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Nourmandipour</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tavassoly</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and Protecting of Entanglement in Two-Level Systems Interacting
  with a Dissipative Cavity: The Gardiner-Collett Approach</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 fidures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 48, 165502 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/48/16/165502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the exact entanglement dynamics of two two-level
atoms in a dissipative cavity. We use the Gardiner-Collett Hamiltonian to model
the dissipative cavity, in which, we assume that the two atoms resonantly
interact with the cavity field and the cavity field itself interacts with the
surrounding medium. Then, with the help of the Fano's technique, we show that,
this system can be regarded as two atoms interacting with a heat bath. In such
a case, we find that, there exists a decoherence-free state that does not
evolve in time. At this time, there exists a so-called super-radiant state
which decays in time due to dissipation. At last, we use the quantum Zeno
effect to preserve the entanglement which already has been stored in the
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00128</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwa</keyname><forenames>Terence</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Olivier C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Martino</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinari</keyname><forenames>Enzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained Allocation Flux Balance Analysis</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.dis-nn physics.bio-ph q-bio.QM</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures (main) + 33 pages, various figures and tables
  (supporting); for the supplementary MatLab code, see
  http://tinyurl.com/h763es8</comments><journal-ref>PLoS Comput Biol 12(6): e1004913 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004913</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New experimental results on bacterial growth inspire a novel top-down
approach to study cell metabolism, combining mass balance and proteomic
constraints to extend and complement Flux Balance Analysis. We introduce here
Constrained Allocation Flux Balance Analysis, CAFBA, in which the biosynthetic
costs associated to growth are accounted for in an effective way through a
single additional genome-wide constraint. Its roots lie in the experimentally
observed pattern of proteome allocation for metabolic functions, allowing to
bridge regulation and metabolism in a transparent way under the principle of
growth-rate maximization. We provide a simple method to solve CAFBA efficiently
and propose an &quot;ensemble averaging&quot; procedure to account for unknown protein
costs. Applying this approach to modeling E. coli metabolism, we find that, as
the growth rate increases, CAFBA solutions cross over from respiratory,
growth-yield maximizing states (preferred at slow growth) to fermentative
states with carbon overflow (preferred at fast growth). In addition, CAFBA
allows for quantitatively accurate predictions on the rate of acetate excretion
and growth yield based on only 3 parameters determined by empirical growth
laws.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00147</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Carilli</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sims</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>HERA Mock Observations: Looking for Closure HERA Memorandum Number 13</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages. HERA Memo Number 13 located at
  http://reionization.org/science/memos/ reload -- changed one word</comments><report-no>HERA Memo Number 13 located at
  http://reionization.org/science/memos/</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the use of closure phase as a method to detect the HI 21cm
signal from the neutral IGM during cosmic reionzation. Closure quantities have
the unique advantage of being independent of antenna-based calibration terms.
We employ realistic, large area sky models from Sims et al. (2016). These
include an estimate of the HI 21cm signal generated using 21cm FAST, plus
continuum models of both the diffuse Galactic synchrotron emission and the
extragalactic point sources. We employ the CASA simulator and adopt the
Dillon-Parsons HERA configuration to generate a uv measurement set. We then use
AIPS to calculate the closure phases as a function of frequency ('closure
spectra'), and python scripts for subsequent analysis. We find that the closure
spectra for the HI signal show dramatic structure in frequency, and based on
thermal noise alone, the redundant HERA-331 array should detect these
fluctuations easily. Comparatively, the frequency structure in the continuum
closure spectra is much smoother than that seen in the HI closure spectra.
Unfortunately, when the line and continuum signals are combined, the continuum
dominates the visibilities at the level of 10^3 to 10^4, and the line signal is
lost. We have investigated fitting and removing smooth curves in frequency to
the line plus continuum closure spectra, and find that the continuum itself
shows enough structure in frequency in the closure spectra to preclude
separation of the continuum and line based on such a process. We have also
considered the subtraction of the continuum from the visibilities using a sky
model, prior to calculation of the closure spectra. TRUNCATED.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00158</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>Mehedi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basith</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zubair</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Md. Sarowar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahbub</keyname><forenames>Rubayyat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakim</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>Md. Fakhrul</forenames></author></authors><title>Saturation magnetization and band gap tuning in BiFeO$_3$ nanoparticles
  via co-substitution of Gd and Mn</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7, in Journal of Alloys and Compounds, June 2016</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jallcom.2016.06.171</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this investigation, Gd and Mn co-doped
Bi$_{0.85}$Gd$_{0.15}$Fe$_{1-x}$Mn$_x$O$_3$ (x=0.0-0.15) nanoparticles have
been prepared to report the influence of co-substitution on their structural,
optical, magnetic and electrical properties. Due to simultaneous substitution
of Gd and Mn in BiFeO$_3$, the crystal structure has been modified from
rhombohedral (R3c) to orthorhombic (Pn21a) and the Fe-O-Fe bond angle and Fe-O
bond length have been changed. For Mn doping up to 10 % in
Bi$_{0.85}$Gd$_{0.15}$Fe$_{1-x}$Mn$_x$O$_3$ nanoparticles, the saturation
magnetization (Ms) has been enhanced significantly, however, for a further
increase of doping up to 15 %, the Ms has started to reduce again. The
co-substitution of Gd and Mn in BiFeO$_3$ nanoparticles also demonstrates a
strong reduction in the optical band gap energy and electrical resistivity
compared to that of undoped BiFeO$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00159</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pl&#xe4;tzer</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Parton-shower Effects in Vector-Boson-Fusion Processes</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, to appear in the proceedings of DIS2016</comments><report-no>MAN/HEP/2016/11, HERWIG-2016-07, KA-TP-18-2016, MCnet-16-25,
  IPPP/16/60</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effects of combining next-to-leading order QCD results
with parton-shower effects in $W^+W^-jj$ production via vector-boson fusion
including leptonic decays. Using the Herwig 7 framework interfaced to VBFNLO 3,
we compare the predictions obtained from the angular-ordered and dipole-based
parton shower algorithms combined with subtractive, MC@NLO-type, and
multiplicative, Powheg-type, matching. A consistent treatment of
renormalisation and factorisation scale variations in the hard process and the
parton shower allows to assign more reliable theory uncertainty predictions to
key distributions like the central rapidity gap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00160</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Murray</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Debashis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collins</keyname><forenames>Gary S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Trapping of solute atoms at grain boundaries in GdNi2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures, 1 table. To be presented at the International
  Conference on Hyperfine Interactions and Their Applications, Leuven, July
  3-8, 2015. http://www.hyperfine2016.be/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lattice locations of 111In impurity probe atoms in intermetallic GdNi2 were
studied as a function of alloy composition and temperature using perturbed
angular correlation spectroscopy (PAC). Three nuclear quadrupole interaction
signals were detected and their equilibrium site fractions were measured up to
700 oC. Two signals have well-defined electric field gradients (EFGs) and are
attributed to In-probes on Gd- and Ni-sites in a well-ordered lattice. A third,
inhomogeneously broadened signal was observed at low temperature. This is
attributed to trapping, or segregation, of In-probes to lattice sinks such as
grain boundaries (GB) that have a large multiplicity of local environments and
EFGs. Changes in site fractions were reversible above 300oC. Measurements were
made on a pair of samples that were richer and poorer in Gd. Remarkably, the
GB-site was populated only in the more Gd-rich sample. This is explained by the
hypothesis that excess Gd segregates to the grain boundaries and provides a
lower enthalpy environment for In-probe atoms. Observations are discussed in
relation to a three-level quantum system. Enthalpy differences between levels
were determined from measurements of temperature dependences of ratios of site
fractions. The enthalpy of transfer of In-probes from the Gd- to Ni-sublattice
was found to be much smaller in the Gd-rich sample. This is attributed to a
large temperature-dependence in the degeneracies of levels available to
In-solutes in the phase, leading to an effective transfer enthalpy that differs
greatly from the difference in site-enthalpies. A possible scenario is
discussed. Different segregation enthalpies were measured for In-solute
transferring from GB sites to Gd- and Ni-sites, whereas only an average value
can be determined through macroscopic measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00169</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>Mehedi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakim</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basith</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Md. Sarowar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmmad</keyname><forenames>Bashir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zubair</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>Md. Fakhrul</forenames></author></authors><title>Size dependent magnetic and electrical properties of Ba-doped
  nanocrystalline BiFeO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9</comments><journal-ref>AIP Advances, 6, 035314, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4944817</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Improvement in magnetic and electrical properties of multiferroic BiFeO$_3$
in conjunction with their dependence on particle size is crucial due to its
potential applications in multifunctional miniaturized devices. In this
investigation, we report a study on particle size dependent structural,
magnetic and electrical properties of sol-gel derived
Bi$_{0.9}$Ba$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ nanoparticles of different sizes ranging from
$\sim$ 12 to 49 nm. The substitution of Bi by Ba significantly suppresses
oxygen vacancies, reduces leakage current density and Fe$^{2+}$ state. An
improvement in both magnetic and electrical properties is observed for 10 %
Ba-doped BiFeO$_3$ nanoparticles compared to its undoped counterpart. The
saturation magnetization of Bi$_{0.9}$Ba$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ nanoparticles increase
with reducing particle size in contrast with a decreasing trend of
ferroelectric polarization. Moreover, a first order metamagnetic transition is
noticed for $\sim$ 49 nm Bi$_{0.9}$Ba$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ nanoparticles which
disappeared with decreasing particle size. The observed strong size dependent
multiferroic properties are attributed to the complex interaction between
vacancy induced crystallographic defects, multiple valence states of Fe,
uncompensated surface spins, crystallographic distortion and suppression of
spiral spin cycloid of BiFeO$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00172</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Boels</keyname><forenames>Rutger H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kniehl</keyname><forenames>Bernd A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>On a four-loop form factor in N=4</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages; to appear in the proceedings of &quot;Loops and Legs 2016&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on progress toward computing a four-loop supersymmetric form factor
in maximally supersymmetric Yang-Mills theory. A representative example
particle content from the involved supermultiplets is a stress-tensor operator
with two on-shell gluons. In previous work, the integrand for this form factor
was obtained using color-kinematic duality in a particularly simple form. Here
the result of applying integration-by-parts identities is discussed and
cross-checks of the result is performed. Rational IBP relations and their
reduction are introduced as a potentially useful aide.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00183</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Klioner</keyname><forenames>Sergei A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parametrized post-Newtonian equations of motion of N mass monopoles with
  the SEP violation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Post-Newtonian equations of motion of a system of $N$ mass monopoles in the
framework of the PPN formalism with two parameters $\beta$ and $\gamma$ are
derived for the case when the Strong Equivalence Principle can be violated. The
derivation is based on the previously published general framework. The
multipole moments of each body are defined as a PPN-generalization of the
corresponding Blanchet-Damour multiple moments in a relevant local reference
system defined for that body. The classical ten integrals of the derived
equations of motion are given. A special version of the equations of motion,
for which seven of these integrals are exact, is discussed. The derived
equations of motion can be used to test the Strong Equivalence Principle in
various solar system experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00191</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Gran</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutowski</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papadopoulos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>On supersymmetric Anti-de-Sitter, de-Sitter and Minkowski flux
  backgrounds</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, latex</comments><report-no>DMUS--MP--16/15</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We test the robustness of the conditions required for the existence of
(supersymmetric) warped flux anti-de Sitter, de Sitter, and Minkowski
backgrounds in supergravity theories using as examples suitable foliations of
anti-de Sitter spaces. We find that there are supersymmetric de Sitter
solutions in supergravity theories including maximally supersymmetric ones in
10- and 11-dimensional supergravities. Moreover, warped flux Minkowski
backgrounds can admit Killing spinors which are not Killing on the Minkowski
subspace and therefore cannot be put in a factorized form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00195</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Yiding</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jiezhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Cunbiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gad-el-Hak</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author></authors><title>Aerodynamic Heating in Hypersonic Boundary Layers:\ Role of Dilatational
  Waves</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evolution of multi-mode instabilities in a hypersonic boundary layer and
their effects on aerodynamic heating are investigated. Experiments are
conducted in a Mach 6 wind tunnel using Rayleigh-scattering flow visualization,
fast-response pressure sensors, fluorescent temperature-sensitive paint (TSP),
and particle image velocimetry (PIV). Calculations are also performed based on
both parabolized stability equations (PSE) and direct numerical simulations
(DNS). It is found that second-mode dilatational waves, accompanied by
high-frequency alternating fluid compression and expansion, produce intense
aerodynamic heating in a small region that rapidly heats the fluid passing
through it. As a result, the surface temperature rapidly increases and results
in an overshoot over the nominal transitional value. When the dilatation waves
decay downstream, the surface temperature decreases gradually until transition
is completed. A theoretical analysis is provided to interpret the temperature
distribution affected by the aerodynamic heating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00202</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>van der Kolk</keyname><forenames>Naomi</forenames><affiliation>for the ILC Physics and Detector Study</affiliation></author></authors><title>The International Linear Collider - Physics and Perspectives</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, presented at the 24th International Workshop on
  Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects (DIS 2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the discovery of a Higgs boson at LHC, all particles of the Standard
Model seem to have been observed experimentally, yet many questions are left
unanswered. The discovery has intensified the planning for future high-energy
colliders, which aim to probe the Standard Model and the mechanism of
electroweak symmetry breaking with higher precision and to extend and
complement the search for new particles currently under way at the LHC. The
most mature option for such a future facility is the International Linear
Collider ILC, an electron-positron collider with a centre-of-mass energy of 500
GeV, and the potential for upgrades into the TeV region. The ILC will fully
explore the Higgs sector, including model-independent coupling and width
measurements, direct measurements of the coupling to the top quark and the
Higgs self-coupling, enable precision measurements of top quark properties and
couplings as well as other electroweak precision measurements and provide
extensive discovery potential for new physics complementary to the capabilities
of hadron colliders. This paper will give an overview of the physics case of
the ILC, put in context of the running scenario covering different
centre-of-mass energies, and discuss the current status and perspectives of
this global facility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00207</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Philippe</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tragat</keyname><forenames>Rodolphe Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holleville</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lours</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minh-Pham</keyname><forenames>Tuam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hrabina</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burck</keyname><forenames>Frederic Du</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Acef</keyname><forenames>Ouali</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency tripled 1542 nm telecom laser diode stabilized to iodine
  hyperfine line in the 10-15 range</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>in 30th European Frequency and Time Forum (EFTF'2016), 4th - 7th
  April 2016, York, United Kingdom</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on telecom laser frequency stabilization to narrow iodine hyperfine
line in the green range of the optical domain, after a frequency tripling
process using two nonlinear PPLN crystals. We have generated up to 300 mW
optical power in the green (P3w), from 800 mW of infrared power (Pw). This
result corresponds to an optical conversion efficiency eta= P3w/Pw ~ 36 %. To
our knowledge, this is the best value ever demonstrated for a CW frequency
tripling process. We have used a narrow linewidth iodine hyperfine line
(component a1 of the 127I2 R 35 (44-0) line) to stabilize the IR laser yielding
to frequency stability of 4.8x10-14 t-1/2 with a minimum of 6x10-15 reached
after 50 s of integration time. The whole optical setup is very compact and
mostly optically fibered. This approach opens the way for efficient and elegant
architecture development for space applications as one of several potential
uses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00209</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bj&#xf6;rnham</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>Magnus</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Dynamic Force Spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Manuscript version, 17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamic force spectroscopy (DFS) is an experimental technique that is
commonly used to assess information of the strength, energy landscape, and
lifetime of noncovalent bio-molecular interactions. DFS traditionally requires
an applied force that increases linearly with time so that the bio-complex
under investigation is exposed to a constant loading rate. However, tethers or
polymers can modulate the applied force in a nonlinear regime. For example,
bacterial adhesion pili and polymers with worm-like chain properties are
examples of structures that show nonlinear force responses. In these
situations, the theory for traditional DFS cannot be readily applied. In this
work we expand the theory for DFS to also include nonlinear external forces
while still maintaining compatibility with the linear DFS theory. To validate
the theory we modeled a bio-complex expressed on a stiff, an elastic and a
worm-like chain polymer, using Monte Carlo methods, and assessed the
corresponding rupture force spectra. It was found that the nonlinear DFS
(NLDFS) theory correctly predicted the numerical results. We also present a
protocol suggesting an experimental approach and analysis method of the data to
estimate the bond length and the thermal off-rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00224</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trapp</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boehm</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraus</keyname><forenames>Marion</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tashima</keyname><forenames>Toshiyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liebermeister</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altpeter</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinfurter</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication and optical characterization of long-range
  surface-plasmon-polariton waveguides in the NIR</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally demonstrate the propagation of long-range surface
plasmon-polaritons in a nobel metal stripe waveguide at an optical wavelength
of 780 nm. To minimize propagation damping the lithographically structured
waveguide is produced from a thin gold stripe embedded in a dielectric polymer.
Our waveguide geometry supports a symmetric fundamental and anti-symmetric
first order mode. For the fundamental mode we measure a propagation loss of
$(6.12^{+0.66} _{-0.54})$ dB/mm, in good agreement with numerical simulations
using a vectorial eigenmode solver. Our results are a promising starting point
for coupling fluorescence of individual solid state quantum emitters to
integrated plasmonic waveguide structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00229</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Mathew</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Raj N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borah</keyname><forenames>Abhinandan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vijay</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deshmukh</keyname><forenames>Mandar M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical strong coupling and parametric amplification in mechanical
  modes of graphene drums</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published online in Nature Nanotechnology (2016)</comments><doi>10.1038/nnano.2016.94</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mechanical resonators are ubiquitous in modern information technology. With
the ability to couple them to electromagnetic and plasmonic modes, they hold
the promise to be the key building blocks in future quantum information
technology. Graphene based resonators are of interest for technological
applications due to their high resonant frequencies, multiple mechanical modes,
and low mass. The tension mediated non-linear coupling between various modes of
the resonator can be excited in a controllable manner. Here, we engineer a
graphene resonator to have large frequency tunability at low temperatures
resulting in large intermodal coupling strength. We observe the emergence of
new eigenmodes and amplification of the coupled modes using red and blue
parametric excitation respectively. We demonstrate that the dynamical
intermodal coupling is tunable. A cooperativity of 60 between two resonant
modes of ~100 MHz is achieved in the strong coupling regime. The ability to
dynamically control the coupling between high frequency eigenmodes of a
mechanical system opens up possibility for quantum mechanical experiments at
low temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00238</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Szczurek</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaefer</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Forward production of Drell-Yan dileptons at high energies and low
  dilepton invariant masses in a $k_t$-factorization approach: Do we see onset
  of saturation?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures a talk by A. Szczurek at the XXIV International
  Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjjects, 11-15 April,
  2016, DESY Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss Drell-Yan production of dileptons at high energies in forward
rapidity region in a hybrid high-energy approach. This approach uses
unintegrated gluon distributions in one proton and collinear quark/antiquark
distributions in the second proton. Corresponding momentum-space formula for
the differential cross sections in high-energy approximation has been derived.
The relation to the commonly used dipole approach is discussed. We conclude and
illustrate that some results of the dipole approaches are too approximate, as
far as kinemtics is considered, and in fact cannot be used for real
experiments. We find that the dipole formula is valid only in very
forward/backward rapidity regions ($|y| &gt;$ 5). Some differential cross sections
for low-mass dilepton production are shown and compared to the LHCb and ATLAS
experimental data. In distinction to dipole approaches, we include four
Drell-Yan structure functions (the impact of interference structure functions
is rather small for typical experimental cuts). We find that both side
contributions ($g q/\bar q$ and $q/\bar q g$) have to be included even for the
LHCb rapidity coverage which is in contradiction with what is usually done in
the dipole approach. We present results for different unintegrated gluon
distributions from the literature (some of them include saturation effects). We
see no clear hints of saturation even at small $M_{ll}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00256</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Martinez-Pedrero</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cebers</keyname><forenames>Andrejs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tierno</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Orientational dynamics of colloidal ribbons self-assembled from
  microscopic magnetic ellipsoids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2016, 12, 3688-3695</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5SM02823J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We combine experiments and theory to investigate the orientational dynamics
of dipolar ellipsoids, which self-assemble into elongated ribbon-like
structures due to the presence in each particle of a permanent magnetic moment
perpendicular to the long axis. Monodisperse hematite ellipsoids are
synthesized via sol-gel technique, and arrange into ribbons in presence of
static or time-dependent magnetic fields. We find that under an oscillating
field, the ribbons reorient perpendicular to the field direction, in contrast
with the behaviour observed under a static field. This observation is explained
theoretically by treating a chain of interacting ellipsoids as a single
particle with an orientational and demagnetizing field energy. The model allows
describing the orientational behaviour of the chain and captures well its
dynamics at different strengths of the actuating field. The understanding of
the complex dynamics and assembly of anisotropic magnetic colloids is a
necessary step towards controlling the structure formation which has direct
applications in different fluid-based microscale technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00275</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Anselmino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boglione</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Sivers asymmetry in $J/\Psi$ and lepton pair production at COMPASS</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The abundant production of lepton pairs via $J/\Psi$ creation at COMPASS,
$\pi ^\pm \, p^\uparrow \to J/\Psi \, X \to \ell^+ \ell^- X$, allows a
measurement of the transverse Single Spin Asymmetry generated by the Sivers
effect. The crucial issue of the sign change of the Sivers function in lepton
pair production, with respect to Semi Inclusive Deep Inelastic Scattering
processes, can be solved. Predictions for the expected magnitude of the Single
Spin Asymmetry, which turns out to be large, are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00281</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The System of Molecular Clouds in the Gould Belt</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, 2016, Vol. 42, No. 8, pp. 544-554</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773716070021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on high-latitude molecular clouds with highly accurate distance
estimates taken from the literature, we have redetermined the parameters of
their spatial orientation. This system can be approximated by a 350x235x140 pc
ellipsoid inclined by the angle i=17+/-2 degrees to the Galactic plane with the
longitude of the ascending node l{\Omega}=337+/-1 degrees. Based on the radial
velocities of the clouds, we have found their group velocity relative to the
Sun to be (u0,v0,w0) = (10.6,18.2,6.8)+/-(0.9,1.7,1.5) km/s. The trajectory of
the center of the molecular cloud system in the past in a time interval of ~60
Myr has been constructed. Using data on masers associated with low-mass
protostars, we have calculated the space velocities of the molecular complexes
in Orion, Taurus, Perseus, and Ophiuchus. Their motion in the past is shown to
be not random.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00295</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Hernandez-Garcia</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraslinikov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asova</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boonpornprasert</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Good</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huck</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isaev</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantaryan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khojoyan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kourkafas</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lishilin</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malyutin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melkumyan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oppelt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otevrel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renier</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rublack</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stephan</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vashchenko</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Studies on charge production from Cs2Te photocathodes in the PITZ L-band
  normal conducting radio frequency photo injector</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 16 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses the behavior of electron bunch charge produced in an
L-band normal conducting radio frequency cavity (RF gun) from Cs2Te
photocathodes illuminated with ps-long UV laser pulses when the laser
transverse distribution consists of a flat-top core with Gaussian-like decaying
halo. The produced charge shows a linear dependence at low laser pulse energies
as expected in the quantum efficiency limited emission regime, while its
dependence on laser pulse energy is observed to be much weaker for higher
values, due to space charge limited emission. However, direct plug-in of
experimental parameters into the space charge tracking code ASTRA yields lower
output charge in the space charge limited regime compared to measured values.
The rate of increase of the produced charge at high laser pulse energies close
to the space charge limited emission regime seems to be proportional to the
amount of halo present in the radial laser profile since the charge from the
core has saturated already. By utilizing core + halo particle distributions
based on measured radial laser profiles, ASTRA simulations and semi-analytical
emission models reproduce the behavior of the measured charge for a wide range
of RF gun and laser operational parameters within the measurement
uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00296</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Lomsadze</keyname><forenames>Ramaz A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gochitashvili</keyname><forenames>Malkhaz R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kezerashvili</keyname><forenames>RomanYa.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge-exchange, ionization and excitation in low-energy Li$^{+}-$ Ar,
  K$^{+}-$ Ar, and Na$^{+}-$He collisions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Absolute cross sections are measured for charge-exchange, ionization, and
excitation within the same experimental setup for the Li$^{+}-$Ar, K$^{+}-$ Ar,
and Na$^{+}-$ He collisions in the ion energy range $0.5-10$ keV. Results of
our measurements along with existing experimental data and the schematic
correlation diagrams are used to analyze and determine the mechanisms for these
processes. The experimental results show that the charge-exchange processes are
realized with high probabilities and electrons are predominately captured in
ground states. The cross section ratio for charge exchange, ionization and
excitation processes roughly attains the value $10:2:1$, respectively. The
contributions of various partial inelastic channels to the total ionization
cross sections are estimated and a primary mechanism for the process is
defined. The energy-loss spectrum, in addition, is applied to estimate the
relative contribution of different inelastic channels and to determine the
mechanisms for the ionization and for some excitation processes of Ar resonance
lines for the K$^{+}-$Ar collision system. The excitation function for the
helium, as well as for the sodium doublet lines for the Na$^{+}-$He collision
system, reveals some unexpected features and a mechanism to explain this
observation is suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00302</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ashby</keyname><forenames>James M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>Peter D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlosshauer</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of the quantum paradox of separation of a single photon from
  one of its properties</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, identical to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental realization of the quantum paradox of the
separation of a single photon from one of its properties (the so-called
&quot;quantum Cheshire cat&quot;). We use a modified Sagnac interferometer with displaced
paths to produce appropriately pre- and postselected states of heralded single
photons. Weak measurements of photon presence and circular polarization are
performed in each arm of the interferometer by introducing weak absorbers and
small polarization rotations and analyzing changes in the postselected signal.
The absorber is found to have an appreciable effect only in one arm of the
interferometer, while the polarization rotation significantly affects the
signal only when performed in the other arm. We carry out both sequential and
simultaneous weak measurements and find good agreement between measured and
predicted weak values. In the language of Aharonov et al. and in the sense of
the ensemble averages described by weak values, the experiment establishes the
separation of a particle from one its properties during the passage through the
interferometer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00303</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Stratakis</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Convery</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Syphers</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab and Northern Illinois U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Crmkovic</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames><affiliation>Brookhaven</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morse</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames><affiliation>Brookhaven</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tishchenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Brookhaven</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Froemming</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames><affiliation>Washington U., Seattle</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Korostelev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Cockcroft Inst. Accel. Sci. Tech. and Lancaster U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Performance analysis for the new G-2 experiment</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-141-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The new g-2 experiment at Fermilab aims to measure the muon anomalous
magnetic moment by a fourfold improvement in precision compared to the BNL
experiment. Achieving this goal requires the delivery of highly polarized 3.094
GeV/c muons with a narrow +-0.5% {\Delta}p/p acceptance to the storage ring. In
this study, we describe a muon capture and transport scheme that should meet
this requirement. First, we present the conceptual design of our proposed
scheme wherein we describe its basic features. Then, we detail our numerical
model and present a complete end-to-end simulation of all g-2 beamlines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00304</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Montmerle</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benvenuti</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheung</keyname><forenames>Sze-leung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Etangs</keyname><forenames>A. Lecavelier des</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaowei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubowich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamajek</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valsecchi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Public Naming of Planets and Planetary Satellites</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Transactions IAU, Volume XXIXA, Proc. XXIXA IAU General Assembly
  (Honolulu, USA), August 2015, Cambridge University Press</comments><doi>10.1017/S1743921316001009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While one of the IAU's missions is to &quot;serve as the internationally
recognized authority for assigning designations to celestial bodies and surface
features on them&quot;, the participation of the public in the naming of celestial
objects has been a little-known, but decade-long tradition of the IAU. While
reiterating its opposition to having the public pay to give a name to an
exoplanet, the IAU Executive Committee nonetheless recognized the right of
organizations to invite public, international exoplanet naming or voting
campaigns. To this end, clear selection rules were to be defined by the IAU,
inviting mutual collaboration, the goal being to sanction the campaign and
officially approve the resulting names, for the sake of boosting the public's
interest in astronomy and at the same time reaffirm the authority of the IAU.
In no way were these names supposed to supersede the designations in use by
professional astronomers. Since the field of exoplanet research was still
&quot;virgin&quot; for naming but is now becoming scientifically mature (with hundreds of
well-characterized, confirmed objects) and so appealing to the public's
interest and imagination, IAU decided to organize a naming contest as the
leader of a new project with a potentially high worldwide impact, the first
since the International Year of Astronomy in 2009, called &quot;NameExoWorlds&quot;.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00308</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>McGee</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Andrews</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leibfritz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nobrega</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Valishev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Mechanical stability study for Integrable Optics Test Accelerator at
  Fermilab</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-151-AD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Integrable Optics Test Accelerator (IOTA) is proposed for operation at
Fermilab. The goal of IOTA is to create practical nonlinear accelerator
focusing systems with a large frequency spread and stable particle motion. The
IOTA is a 40 m circumference, 150 MeV (e-), 2.5 MeV (p+) diagnostic test ring.
A heavy low frequency steel floor girder is proposed as the primary tier for
IOTA device component support. Two design lengths; (8) 3.96 m and (2) 3.1 m
long girders with identical cross section completely encompass the ring. This
study focuses on the 3.96 m length girder and the development of a working
prototype. Hydrostatic Level Sensor (HLS), temperature, metrology and fast
motion measurements characterize the anticipated mechanical stability of the
IOTA ring.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00311</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Badger</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mogull</keyname><forenames>Gustav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peraro</keyname><forenames>Tiziano</forenames></author></authors><title>Local integrands for two-loop QCD amplitudes</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Proceedings for Loops and Legs in Quantum Field Theory, 24-29 April
  2016, Leipzig, Germany. 8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this talk we review the recent computation of the five- and six-gluon
two-loop amplitudes in Yang-Mills theory using local integrands which make the
infrared pole structure manifest. We make some remarks on the connection with
BCJ relations and the all-multiplicity structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00317</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Congyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dharmasena</keyname><forenames>Ruchira Ravinath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumanasekera</keyname><forenames>Gamini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Phosphorene as an Anode Material for High Performance Lithium-Ion
  Battery: First Principle Study and Experimental Measurement</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>52 pages, 5 tables, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The prospects of phosphorene as an anode material for high performance Li-ion
battery was systematically investigated from the first principle calculations
and experimental measurements. The diffusion energy barriers of a Li atom
moving along various orientations on phosphorene layer were calculated from the
Li adsorption energy landscape. It was found that the diffusion mobility of a
Li atom along the zigzag direction in the valley of phosphorene could be about
7 to 11 orders of magnitude faster than that along the other directions,
indicating its ultrafast and anisotropic diffusivity. The lithium insertion in
phosphorene was studied considering various LinP16 configurations (n=1~16). It
was found that phosphorene could accommodate up to one Li per P atom (i.e.,
Li16P16), and the predicted theoretical value of the Li capacity for a single
layered phosphorene can reach about 865 mAh/g. Our experimental measurement on
the Li capacity for a network of a few layered phosphorene can reach a
reversible stable value of ~ 453 mAh/g even after 50 cycles. In particular, it
was found that, even at the high Li concentration (e.g., x = 1 in LixP), there
was no Li clustering and the structure of phosphorene is reversible during the
lithium intercalation. Our results clearly show that phosphorene has promise as
a novel anode material for high performance Li-ion batteries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00322</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhatti</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakos</keyname><forenames>G. &#xc1;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartman</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penev</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayliss</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jord&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brahm</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espinoza</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mancini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Val-Borro</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bento</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciceri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csubry</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arriagada</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butler</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crane</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shectman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suc</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xe1;z&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papp</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;ri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>HATS-19b, HATS-20b, HATS-21b: Three Transiting Hot-Saturns Discovered by
  the HATSouth Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Submitted to AAS journals. IPython notebook at
  https://github.com/waqasbhatti/hats19to21 and all HATSouth planet data at
  http://hatsouth.org</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the discovery by the HATSouth exoplanet survey of three hot-Saturn
transiting exoplanets: HATS-19b, HATS-20b, and HATS-21b. The planet host
HATS-19 is a slightly evolved V = 13.0 G0 star with [Fe/H] = 0.240, a mass of
1.303 Msun, and a radius of 1.75 Rsun. HATS-19b is in an eccentric orbit (e =
0.30) around this star with an orbital period of 4.5697 days and has a mass of
0.427 Mjup and a highly inflated radius of 1.66 Rjup. The planet HATS-20b has a
Saturn-like mass and radius of 0.273 Mjup and 0.776 Rjup respectively. It
orbits the V = 13.8 G9V star HATS-20 (Ms = 0.910 Msun; Rs = 0.892 Rsun) with a
period of 3.7993 days. Finally, HATS-21 is a V = 12.2 G4V star with [Fe/H] =
0.300, a mass of 1.080 Msun, and a radius of 1.021 Rsun. Its accompanying
planet HATS-21b has a 3.5544-day orbital period, a mass of 0.332 Mjup, and a
moderately inflated radius of 1.123 Rjup. With the addition of these three very
different planets to the growing sample of hot-Saturns, we re-examine the
relations between the observed giant planet radii, stellar irradiation, and
host metallicity. We find a significant positive correlation between planet
equilibrium temperature and radius, and a weak negative correlation between
host metallicity and radius. To assess the relative influence of various
physical parameters on observed planet radii, we train and fit models using
Random Forest regression. We find that for hot-Saturns (0.1 &lt; Mp &lt; 0.5 Mjup),
the planetary mass and equilibrium temperature play dominant roles in
determining radii. For hot-Jupiters (0.5 &lt; Mp &lt; 2.0 Mjup), the most important
parameter is equilibrium temperature alone. Finally, for irradiated higher-mass
planets (Mp &gt; 2.0 Mjup), we find that equilibrium temperature dominates in
influence, with smaller contributions from planet mass and host metallicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00349</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00349</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Shubina</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Painlev\'e analysis for two 1D parabolic-parabolic models of chemotaxis;
  some travelling wave solutions</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>8 pages, 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the Painlev\'e analysis for two models of chemotaxis.
We find that in some cases the reductions of these models in terms of
travelling wave variable allow exact analytical solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00353</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Pomorski</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nerlo-Pomorska</keyname><forenames>Bozena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanyuk</keyname><forenames>Fedir A.</forenames></author></authors><title>To fission or not to fission</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fission-fragments mass-yield of 236U is obtained by an approximate
solution of the eigenvalue problem of the collective Hamiltonian that describes
the dynamics of the fission process whose degrees of freedom are: the fission
(elongation), the neck and the mass-asymmetry mode. The macroscopic-microscopic
method is used to evaluate the potential energy surface. The macroscopic energy
part is calculated using the liquid drop model and the microscopic corrections
are obtained using the Woods-Saxon single-particle levels. The four dimensional
modified Cassini ovals shape parametrization is used to describe the shape of
the fissioning nucleus. The mass tensor is taken within the cranking-type
approximation. The final fragment mass distribution is obtained by weighting
the adiabatic density distribution in the collective space with the
neck-dependent fission probability. The neck degree of freedom is found to play
a significant role in determining that final fragment mass distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00358</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>McGee</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Harms</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Klebaner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leibfritz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pischalnikov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schappert</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Investigation of thermal acoustic effects on SRF cavities within CM1 at
  Fermilab</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-152-AD-TD</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Radio Frequency (RF) power studies are in progress following the cryogenic
commissioning of Cryomodule #1 (CM1) at Fermilab's Superconducting Radio
Frequency (SRF) Accelerator Test Facility. These studies are complemented by
the characterization of thermal acoustic effects on cavity microphonics
manifested by apparent noisy boiling of helium involving vapor bubble and
liquid vibration. The thermal acoustic measurements also consider pressure and
temperature spikes which drive the phenomenon at low and high frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00361</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames><affiliation>MUONS Inc., Batavia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cummings</keyname><forenames>Mary Anne Clare</forenames><affiliation>MUONS Inc., Batavia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Rolland Paul</forenames><affiliation>MUONS Inc., Batavia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Neuffer</keyname><forenames>David Vincent</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>MuSim, a graphical user interface for multiple simulation programs</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>3 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-187-AD-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  MuSim is a new user-friendly program designed to interface to many different
particle simulation codes, regardless of their data formats or geometry
descriptions. It presents the user with a compelling graphical user interface
that includes a flexible 3-D view of the simulated world plus powerful editing
and drag-and-drop capabilities. All aspects of the design can be parameterized
so that parameter scans and optimizations are easy. It is simple to create
plots and display events in the 3-D viewer (with a slider to vary the
transparency of solids), allowing for an effortless comparison of different
simulation codes. Simulation codes: G4beamline 3.02 and MCNP 6.1; more are
coming. Many accelerator design tools and beam optics codes were written long
ago, with primitive user interfaces by today's standards. MuSim is specifically
designed to make it easy to interface to such codes, providing a common user
experience for all, and permitting the construction and exploration of models
with very little overhead. For today's technology-driven students, graphical
interfaces meet their expectations far better than text based tools, and
education in accelerator physics is one of our primary goals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00365</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring new horizons of the Gribov problem in Yang-Mills theories</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>202 pages, 10 figures, Ph.D Thesis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The understanding of the non-perturbative regime of YM theories remains a
challenging open problem in theoretical physics. Notably, a satisfactory
description of the confinement of gluons is not at our disposal so far. In this
thesis, the RGZ framework, designed to provide a proper quantization of YM
theories by taking into account the existence of the so-called Gribov copies is
explored. Successfully introduced in the Landau gauge, the RGZ set up does not
extend easily to different gauges. The main reason is that a clear formulation
of the analogue of the Gribov horizon in the Landau gauge is obstructed by
technical difficulties when more sophisticated gauges are chosen. Moreover, the
RGZ action breaks BRST symmetry explicitly, making the task of extracting gauge
invariant results even more difficult. The main goal of the present thesis is
precisely to provide a consistent framework to extend the RGZ action to gauges
that are connected to Landau gauge via a gauge parameter. Our main result is
the reformulation of the theory in the Landau gauge with appropriate variables
such that a non-perturbative BRST symmetry is constructed. This symmetry
corresponds to a deformation of the standard BRST symmetry by taking into
account non-perturbative effects. This opens a toolbox which allow us to
explore what would be the Gribov horizon in different gauges as linear
covariant and Curci-Ferrari gauges. Consistency with gauge independence of
physical quantities as well as the computation of the gluon propagator in these
gauges is provided. Remarkably, when lattice or functional methods results are
available, we verify very good agreement with our analytical proposal giving
support that it could provide some insights about the non-perturbative regime
of YM theories. A positivity violating gluon propagator in the infrared seems
to be a general feature of the formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0510147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0510147</id><created>2005-10-05</created><updated>2008-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oldershaw</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Self-Similarity Between RR Lyrae Stars And Singly-Excited
  Helium Atoms</title><categories>astro-ph nlin.CD physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure, 2 tables, final published version, comments
  welcome</comments><journal-ref>Electronic Journal of Theoretical Physics, 5(17), 207-214, March
  2008</journal-ref><abstract>  Classical variable stars called RR Lyrae stars have pulsating outer envelopes
comprised of excited atoms. Here we demonstrate that the qualitative and
quantitative properties of RR Lyrae variables and one subclass of their atomic
scale constituents: singly-excited helium atoms undergoing transitions between
Rydberg states, share a remarkable degree of self-similarity. In terms of
masses, radii, oscillation periods, morphologies and kinematics the stellar and
atomic analogues obey a simple set of discrete self-similar scaling equations.
The concept of stellar/atomic self-similarity may prove useful in the search
for a deeper understanding of both stellar and atomic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/0603219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/0603219</id><created>2006-03-26</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aitchison</keyname><forenames>Ian J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Close</keyname><forenames>Frank E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gal</keyname><forenames>Avraham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millener</keyname><forenames>D. John</forenames></author></authors><title>The scientific heritage of Richard Henry Dalitz, FRS (1925-2006)</title><categories>physics.hist-ph hep-ph nucl-th physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>updates the original edition by including several publications,
  mostly in category III, that were unknown to us in 2006</comments><report-no>v1: SLAC-PUB-11776</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. A771 (2006) 2-7, Nucl.Phys. A771 (2006) 8-25</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2006.03.007 10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2006.03.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Professor Richard H. Dalitz passed away on January 13, 2006. He was almost 81
years old and his outstanding contributions are intimately connected to some of
the major breakthroughs of the 20th century in particle and nuclear physics.
These outstanding contributions go beyond the Dalitz Plot, Dalitz Pair and CDD
poles that bear his name. He pioneered the theoretical study of strange baryon
resonances, of baryon spectroscopy in the quark model, and of hypernuclei, to
all of which he made lasting contributions. His formulation of the
&quot;$\theta-\tau$ puzzle&quot; led to the discovery that parity is not a symmetry of
the weak interactions. A brief scientific evaluation of Dalitz's major
contributions to particle and nuclear physics is hereby presented, followed by
the first comprehensive list of his scientific publications, as assembled from
several sources. The list is divided into two categories: the first, main part
comprises Dalitz's research papers and reviews, including topics in the history
of particle physics, biographies and reminiscences; the second part lists book
reviews, public lectures and obituaries authored by Dalitz, and books edited by
him. This provides the first necessary step towards a more systematic research
of the Dalitz heritage in modern physics.
  The present 2016 edition updates the original 2006 edition, published in
Nucl. Phys. A 771 (2006) 2-7, doi:10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2006.03.007, and 8-25,
doi:10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2006.03.008, by including for the first time a dozen or
so of publications, found recently in a list submitted to the Royal Society by
Dalitz in 2004, that escaped our attention in the original version.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/0701132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/0701132</id><created>2007-01-11</created><updated>2007-12-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oldershaw</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Scale Relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, minor revisions, accepted at Astrophys. Space Sci., comments
  welcome</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and Space Science, Vol. 311, No. 4, pgs. 431-433,
  October 2007</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-007-9557-x</doi><abstract>  The possibility that global discrete dilation invariance is a fundamental
symmetry principle of nature is explored. If the discrete self-similarity
observed in nature is exact, then the Principle of General Covariance needs to
be broadened in order to accommodate this form of discrete conformal
invariance, and a further generalization of relativity theory is required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
