<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:40:16Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-08-17" from="2017-08-17" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0710.1236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0710.1236</id><created>2007-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Ines</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirac</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porras</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of Spin Correlations in Optical Lattices by Light Scattering</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 77, 051804(R) (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.77.051804</doi><abstract>  We show that spin correlations of atoms in an optical lattice can be
reconstructed by coupling the system to the light, and by measuring
correlations between the emitted photons. This principle is the basis for a
method to characterize states in quantum computation and simulation with
optical lattices. As examples, we study the detection of spin correlations in a
quantum magnetic phase, and the characterization of cluster states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0711.1499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0711.1499</id><created>2007-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Ines</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Emission spectra of atoms with non-Markovian interaction: Fluorescence
  in a photonic crystal</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 77, 043836 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.77.043836</doi><abstract>  We present a formula to evaluate the spontaneous emission spectra of an atom
in contact with a radiation field with non-Markovian effects. This formula is
written in terms of a two-time correlation of system observables and the
environmental correlation function, and depends on the distance between the
emitting atom and the detector. As an example, we use it to analyze the
fluorescence spectra of a two level atom placed as an impurity in a photonic
crystal. The radiation field within those materials has a gap or discontinuity
where electromagnetic modes cannot propagate in the stationary limit. In that
situation, the atomic emission occurs in the form of evanescent waves which are
detected with less efficiency the farther we place the detector. The
methodology presented in this paper may be useful to study the non-Markovian
dynamics of any quantum open system in linear interaction with a harmonic
oscillator reservoir and within the weak coupling approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0807.1901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0807.1901</id><created>2008-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Ines</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porras</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirac</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author></authors><title>Matter--wave emission in optical lattices: Single particle and
  collective effects</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 101, 260404 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.101.260404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a simple set--up corresponding to the matter-wave analogue of
impurity atoms embedded in an infinite photonic crystal and interacting with
the radiation field. Atoms in a given internal level are trapped in an optical
lattice, and play the role of the impurities. Atoms in an untrapped level play
the role of the radiation field. The interaction is mediated by means of lasers
that couple those levels. By tuning the lasers parameters, it is possible to
drive the system through different regimes, and observe phenomena like matter
wave superradiance, non-Markovian atom emission, and the appearance of bound
atomic states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1005.0465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1005.0465</id><created>2010-05-04</created><updated>2010-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Ines</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovian stochastic description of quantum transport in
  photosynthetic systems</title><categories>quant-ph physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 44 245501 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/44/24/245501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze several aspects of the transport dynamics in the LH1-RC core of
purple bacteria, which consists basically in a ring of antenna molecules that
transport the energy into a target molecule, the reaction center, placed in the
center of the ring. We show that the periodicity of the system plays an
important role to explain the relevance of the initial state in the transport
efficiency. This picture is modified, and the transport enhanced for any
initial state, when considering that molecules have different energies, and
when including their interaction with the environment. We study this last
situation by using stochastic Schr{\&quot;o}dinger equations, both for Markovian and
non-Markovian type of interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1006.0461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1006.0461</id><created>2010-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Ines</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ba&#xf1;uls</keyname><forenames>Mari Carmen</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of dissipation in an adiabatic quantum search algorithm</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 12 123010 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/12/12/123010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the effect of two different environments on the performance of
the quantum adiabatic search algorithm, a thermal bath at finite temperature,
and a structured environment similar to the one encountered in systems coupled
to the electromagnetic field that exists within a photonic crystal. While for
all the parameter regimes explored here, the algorithm performance is worsened
by the contact with a thermal environment, the picture appears to be different
when considering a structured environment. In this case we show that, by tuning
the environment parameters to certain regimes, the algorithm performance can
actually be improved with respect to the closed system case. Additionally, the
relevance of considering the dissipation rates as complex quantities is
discussed in both cases. More particularly, we find that the imaginary part of
the rates can not be neglected with the usual argument that it simply amounts
to an energy shift, and in fact influences crucially the system dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3905</id><created>2014-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Rajak</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>B K</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Annealing search of Ising spin glass ground state(s) with
  tunable transverse &amp; longitudinal fields</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ind. J Phys. 88, 951-955 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12648-014-0483-9</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  Here we first discuss briefly the quantum annealing technique. We then study
the quantum annealing of Sherrington-Kirkpatrick spin glass model with the
tuning of both transverse and longitudinal fields. Both the fields are
time-dependent and vanish adiabatically at the same time, starting from high
values. We solve, for rather small systems, the time-dependent Schrodinger
equation of the total Hamiltonian by employing a numerical technique. At the
end of annealing we obtain the final state having high overlap with the exact
ground state(s) of classical spin glass system (obtained independently).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.3555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.3555</id><created>2014-06-13</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moura</keyname><forenames>Filipe</forenames></author></authors><title>Absorption of scalars by extremal black holes in string theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Published version with minor corrections. 23 pages</comments><journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravitation 49 (2017) 117</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2285-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the low frequency absorption cross section of minimally coupled
test massless scalar fields by extremal spherically symmetric black holes in d
dimensions is equal to the horizon area, even in the presence of
string--theoretical $\alpha'$ corrections. Classically one has the relation
$\sigma = 4 G S$ between that absorption cross section and the black hole
entropy. By comparing in each case the values of the horizon area and Wald's
entropy, we discuss the validity of such relation in the presence of higher
derivative corrections for extremal black holes in many different contexts: in
the presence of electric and magnetic charges, for nonsupersymmetric and
supersymmetric black holes, in d=4 and d=5 dimensions. The examples we consider
seem to indicate that this relation is not verified in the presence of
$\alpha'$ corrections in general, although being valid in some specific cases
(electrically charged maximally supersymmetric black holes in d=5). We argue
that the relation $\sigma = 4 G S$ should in general be valid for the
absorption cross section of scalar fields which, although being independent
from the black hole solution, have their origin from string theory, and
therefore are not minimally coupled.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05926</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2016-04-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faustino</keyname><forenames>Nelson</forenames></author></authors><title>Hypercomplex Fock States for Discrete Electromagnetic Schr\&quot;odinger
  Operators: A Bayesian Probability Perspective</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>28 pages; Section 2. on the previous version (v3) was reformulated;
  subsequent sections were readjusted; title has slightly changed</comments><msc-class>26A33, 30G35, 33C20, 62F15, 81Q60</msc-class><journal-ref>Applied Mathematics and Computation, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.amc.2017.07.080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present and study a new class of Fock states underlying to discrete
electromagnetic Schr\&quot;odinger operators from a multivector calculus
perspective. This naturally lead to hypercomplex versions of Poisson-Charlier
polynomials, Meixner polynomials, among other ones. The foundations of this
work are based on the exploitation of the quantum probability formulation '\`a
la Dirac' to the setting of Bayesian probabilities, on which the Fock states
arise as discrete quasi-probability distributions carrying a set of independent
and identically distributed (i.i.d) random variables. By employing
Mellin-Barnes integrals in the complex plane we obtain counterparts for the
well-known multidimensional Poisson and hypergeometric distributions, as well
as quasi-probability distributions that may take negative or complex values on
the lattice $h\mathbb{Z}^n$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07748</id><created>2015-05-17</created><updated>2015-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mali</keyname><forenames>Provash</forenames></author></authors><title>Multifractal detrended moving average analysis of global temperature
  records</title><categories>physics.ao-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures and 1 table, Corrected version to be published in
  Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment (JSTAT)</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/01/013201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multifractal structure of global monthly mean temperature anomaly time series
over the period of 1850-2012 are studied in terms of the multifractal detrended
moving average (MFDMA) analysis. We try to address the possible source(s) and
the nature of multifractality in the time series data by comparing the results
derived from the actual series with those from a set of shuffled and surrogate
series. It is seen that the MFDMA method predicts a multifractal structure of
the temperature anomaly records that is more or less similar to what was
obtained from the multifractal detrended analysis for the same set of data. In
our analysis the major contribution of multifractality in the data is found to
be due to the long-range temporal correlation among the measurements, however
the contribution of a fat-tail distribution function of the variables is not
negligible. The existence of long-range correlation is also confirmed by the
constancy of the local slopes of the fluctuation function over a sufficient
scale intervals. The results of the moving average analysis are found to depend
upon the location of the detrending window and tend to the observations of the
multifractal detrended analysis for a specific choice of the location of the
detrending window.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06767</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-04-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>McEwen</keyname><forenames>Jason D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durastanti</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiaux</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>Localisation of directional scale-discretised wavelets on the sphere</title><categories>cs.IT astro-ph.IM math.IT</categories><comments>28 pages, 8 figures, minor changes to match version accepted for
  publication by ACHA</comments><doi>10.1016/j.acha.2016.03.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scale-discretised wavelets yield a directional wavelet framework on the
sphere where a signal can be probed not only in scale and position but also in
orientation. Furthermore, a signal can be synthesised from its wavelet
coefficients exactly, in theory and practice (to machine precision).
Scale-discretised wavelets are closely related to spherical needlets (both were
developed independently at about the same time) but relax the axisymmetric
property of needlets so that directional signal content can be probed. Needlets
have been shown to satisfy important quasi-exponential localisation and
asymptotic uncorrelation properties. We show that these properties also hold
for directional scale-discretised wavelets on the sphere and derive similar
localisation and uncorrelation bounds in both the scalar and spin settings.
Scale-discretised wavelets can thus be considered as directional needlets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05438</id><created>2015-11-17</created><updated>2016-01-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Feichtner</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selig</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hecht</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic nanoantenna design and fabrication based on evolutionary
  optimization</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>3 figures; please see the supplementary information for additional
  data</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express, 25(10), 2017, p. 10828</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.010828</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Nanoantennas for light enhance light-matter interaction at the nanoscale
making them useful in optical communication, sensing, and spectroscopy. So far
nanoantenna engineering has been largely based on rules derived from the radio
frequency domain which neglect the inertia of free metal electrons at optical
frequencies causing phenomena such as complete field penetration, ohmic losses
and plasmon resonances. Here we introduce a general and scalable evolutionary
algorithm that accounts for topological constrains of the fabrication method
and therefore yields unexpected nanoantenna designs exhibiting strong light
localization and enhancement which can directly be &quot;printed&quot; by focused-ion
beam milling. The fitness ranking in a hierarchy of such antennas is validated
experimentally by two-photon photoluminescence. Analysis of the best antennas'
operation principle shows that it deviates fundamentally from that of classical
radio wave-inspired designs. Our work sets the stage for a widespread
application of evolutionary optimization to a wide range of problems in nano
photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02278</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Geloun</keyname><forenames>Joseph Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caravelli</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>On an ordering-dependent generalization of Tutte polynomial</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 168, 5 pp. 1105-1124 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-017-1831-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generalization of Tutte polynomial involved in the evaluation of the
moments of the integrated geometric Brownian in the Ito formalism is discussed.
The new combinatorial invariant depends on the order in which the sequence of
contraction-deletions have been performed on the graph. Thus, this work
provides a motivation for studying an order-dependent Tutte polynomial in the
context of stochastic differential equations. We show that in the limit of the
control parameters encoding the ordering going to zero, the multivariate
Tutte-Fortuin-Kasteleyn polynomial is recovered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08998</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Onofrio Rosario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Paola</keyname><forenames>Benedetto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster Analysis of Educational Data: an Example of Quantitative Study
  on the answers to an Open-Ended Questionnaire</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>30 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the last years many studies examined the consistency of students' answers
in a variety of contexts. Some of these papers tried to develop more detailed
models of the consistency of students' reasoning, or to subdivide a sample of
students into intellectually similar subgroups. The problem of taking a set of
data and separating it into subgroups where the elements of each subgroup are
more similar to each other than they are to elements not in the subgroup has
been extensively studied through the methods of Cluster Analysis. This method
can separate students into groups that can be recognized and characterized by
common traits in their answers, without any prior knowledge of what form those
groups would take (unbiased classification). In this paper we start from a
detailed analysis of the data coding needed in Cluster Analysis, in order to
discuss the meaning and the limits of the interpretation of quantitative
results. Then two methods commonly used in Cluster Analysis are described and
the variables and parameters involved are outlined and criticized. Section III
deals with the application of these methods to the analysis of data from an
open-ended questionnaire administered to a sample of university students, and
the quantitative results are discussed. Finally, the quantitative results are
related to student answers and compared with previous results reported in the
literature, by pointing out the new insights resulting from the application of
such new methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00966</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pirandola</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Capacities of repeater-assisted quantum communications</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other math-ph math.MP physics.optics</categories><comments>Results largely improved. Now includes the simulation and stretching
  of quantum networks connected by arbitrary quantum channels. The end-to-end
  capacities for quantum and private communication cannot beat a single-letter
  bound in terms of the relative entropy of entanglement</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider quantum and private communications assisted by repeaters, from
the basic scenario of a single repeater chain to the general case of an
arbitrarily-complex quantum network, where systems may be routed through single
or multiple paths. In this context, we investigate the ultimate rates at which
two end-parties may transmit quantum information, distribute entanglement, or
generate secret keys. These end-to-end capacities are defined by optimizing
over the most general adaptive protocols that are allowed by quantum mechanics.
Combining techniques from quantum information and classical network theory, we
derive single-letter upper bounds for the end-to-end capacities in repeater
chains and quantum networks connected by arbitrary quantum channels,
establishing exact formulas under basic decoherence models, including bosonic
lossy channels, quantum-limited amplifiers, dephasing and erasure channels. For
the converse part, we adopt a teleportation-inspired simulation of a quantum
network which leads to upper bounds in terms of the relative entropy of
entanglement. For the lower bounds we combine point-to-point quantum protocols
with classical network algorithms. Depending on the type of routing (single or
multiple), optimal strategies corresponds to finding the widest path or the
maximum flow in the quantum network. Our theory can also be extended to
simultaneous quantum communication between multiple senders and receivers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05017</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Molteni</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitanza</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Onofrio Rosario</forenames></author></authors><title>Smoothed Particles Hydrodynamics numerical simulations of droplets
  walking on viscous vibrating liquid</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>21 pages, published on Computers &amp; Fluids</comments><journal-ref>Computers &amp; Fluids, vol. 156 (2017) pp. 449 - 455</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the phenomenon of the &quot;walking droplet&quot;, by means of numerical fluid
dynamics simulations using the Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics numerical
method. This phenomenon occurs when a millimetric drop is released on the
surface of an oil of the same composition, contained in a tank and subjected to
vertical oscillations of frequency and amplitude very close to the Faraday
instability threshold. At appropriate values of the parameters of the system
under study, the oil droplet jumps permanently on the surface of the vibrating
liquid forming a localized wave-particle system, reminding the behaviour of a
wave particle quantum system as suggested by de Broglie. In our study, we made
relevant simplifying assumptions, however we observe that the wave-drop
coupling is surely obtained. Moreover, the droplet and the wave travel at
nearly constant velocity, as observed in experiments. These facts suggest that
the phenomenon may occur in many contexts and opens the possibility to study it
in an extremely wide range of physical configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02252</id><created>2016-02-06</created><updated>2016-12-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faustino</keyname><forenames>Nelson</forenames></author></authors><title>A conformal group approach to the Dirac-K\&quot;ahler system on the lattice</title><categories>math-ph math.CV math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><msc-class>30G35, 32M12, 33C05, 35Q41</msc-class><journal-ref>Math. Meth. Appl. Sci. 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/mma.4291</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from the representation of the $(n-1)+n-$dimensional Lorentz
pseudo-sphere on the projective space $\mathbb{P}\mathbb{R}^{n,n}$, we propose
a method to derive a class of solutions underlying to a Dirac-K\&quot;ahler type
equation on the lattice. We make use of the Cayley transform $\varphi({\bf
w})=\dfrac{1+{\bf w}}{1-{\bf w}}$ to show that the resulting group
representation arise from the same mathematical framework as the conformal
group representation in terms of the {\it general linear group}
$GL\left(2,\Gamma(n-1,n-1)\cup\{ 0\}\right)$. That allows us to describe such
class of solutions as a commutative $n-$ary product, involving the
quasi-monomials $\varphi\left({\bf z}_j\right)^{-\frac{x_j}{h}}$ ($x_j \in
h\mathbb{Z}$) with membership in the paravector space $\mathbb{R}\oplus
\mathbb{R}{\bf e}_j{\bf e}_{n+j}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01091</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monnig</keyname><forenames>Nathan D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Francois G</forenames></author></authors><title>The Resistance Perturbation Distance: A Metric for the Analysis of
  Dynamic Networks</title><categories>cs.SI cs.DM physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To quantify the fundamental evolution of time-varying networks, and detect
abnormal behavior, one needs a notion of temporal difference that captures
significant organizational changes between two successive instants. In this
work, we propose a family of distances that can be tuned to quantify structural
changes occurring on a graph at different scales: from the local scale formed
by the neighbors of each vertex, to the largest scale that quantifies the
connections between clusters, or communities. Our approach results in the
definition of a true distance, and not merely a notion of similarity. We
propose fast (linear in the number of edges) randomized algorithms that can
quickly compute an approximation to the graph metric. The third contribution
involves a fast algorithm to increase the robustness of a network by optimally
decreasing the Kirchhoff index. Finally, we conduct several experiments on
synthetic graphs and real networks, and we demonstrate that we can detect
configurational changes that are directly related to the hidden variables
governing the evolution of dynamic networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06102</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2017-05-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zumalacarregui</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawicki</keyname><forenames>Ignacy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesgourgues</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Pedro G.</forenames></author></authors><title>hi_class: Horndeski in the Cosmic Linear Anisotropy Solving System</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages + appendices, 4 figures, code available on
  https://github.com/miguelzuma/hi_class_public</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2016-41</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP08(2017)019</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/08/019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the public version of hi_class (www.hiclass-code.net), an
extension of the Boltzmann code CLASS to a broad ensemble of modifications to
general relativity. In particular, hi_class can calculate predictions for
models based on Horndeski's theory, which is the most general scalar-tensor
theory described by second-order equations of motion and encompasses any
perfect-fluid dark energy, quintessence, Brans-Dicke, $f(R)$ and covariant
Galileon models. hi_class has been thoroughly tested and can be readily used to
understand the impact of alternative theories of gravity on linear structure
formation as well as for cosmological parameter extraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09200</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2017-04-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kashefi</keyname><forenames>Elham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pappa</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiparty Delegated Quantum Computing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages</comments><journal-ref>Cryptography 2017, 1(2), 12</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/cryptography1020012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum computing has seen tremendous progress in the past years. However,
due to limitations in scalability of quantum technologies, it seems that we are
far from constructing universal quantum computers for everyday users. A more
feasible solution is the delegation of computation to powerful quantum servers
on the network. This solution was proposed in previous studies of Blind Quantum
Computation, with guarantees for both the secrecy of the input and of the
computation being performed. In this work, we further develop this idea of
computing over encrypted data, to propose a multiparty delegated quantum
computing protocol in the measurement-based quantum computing framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00156</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Massa</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignolo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Newton-Euler, Lagrange and Kirchhoff formulations of rigid body
  dynamics: a unified approach</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Meccanica, 51, 2016, pp. 2019</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11012-015-0333-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A unified formulation of rigid body dynamics based on Gauss principle is
proposed. The Lagrange, Kirchhoff and Newton-Euler equations are seen to arise
from different choices of the quasicoordinates in the velocity space. The
group-theoretical aspects of the method are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05080</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Biju</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagchi</keyname><forenames>Joydeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>H.</keyname><forenames>Ishwara-Chandra C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey-Pommier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>Joe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patil</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P.</keyname><forenames>Sunil Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandge</keyname><forenames>Mahadev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabhade</keyname><forenames>Pratik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaikwad</keyname><forenames>Madhuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abraham</keyname><forenames>Sheelu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vivek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahabal</keyname><forenames>Ashish A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djorgovski</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>`Zwicky's Nonet': a compact merging ensemble of nine galaxies and 4C
  35.06, a peculiar radio galaxy with dancing radio jets</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS | No. of pages 12, 10 figures and 4 tables.
  Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, vol. 471,
  10-2017, issue 11, pp. 617-628</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1476</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results of our radio, optical and infra-red studies of a
peculiar radio source 4C~35.06, an extended radio-loud AGN at the center of
galaxy cluster Abell 407 ($z=0.047$). The central region of this cluster hosts
a remarkably tight ensemble of nine galaxies, the spectra of which resemble
those of passive red ellipticals, embedded within a diffuse stellar halo of
$\sim$1~arcmin size. This system (named the `Zwicky's Nonet') provides unique
and compelling evidence for a multiple-nucleus cD galaxy precursor.
Multifrequency radio observations of 4C~35.06 with the Giant Meterwave Radio
Telescope (GMRT) at 610, 235 and 150 MHz reveal a system of 400~kpc scale
helically twisted and kinked radio jets and outer diffuse lobes. The outer
extremities of jets contain extremely steep spectrum (spectral index -1.7 to
-2.5) relic/fossil radio plasma with a spectral age of a few$\,\times (10^7 -
10^8)$ yr. Such ultra-steep spectrum relic radio lobes without definitive
hot-spots are rare, and they provide an opportunity to understand the
life-cycle of relativistic jets and physics of black hole mergers in dense
environments. We interpret our observations of this radio source in the context
of the growth of its central black hole, triggering of its AGN activity and jet
precession, all possibly caused by galaxy mergers in this dense galactic
system. A slow conical precession of the jet axis due to gravitational
perturbation between interacting black holes is invoked to explain the unusual
jet morphology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07238</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bernardin</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;dric</forenames><affiliation>UCA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gon&#xe7;alves</keyname><forenames>Patricia</forenames><affiliation>IST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jara</keyname><forenames>Milton</forenames><affiliation>IMPA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Marielle</forenames><affiliation>LPP, MEPHYSTO</affiliation></author></authors><title>Interpolation process between standard diffusion and fractional
  diffusion</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>to appear in AIHP B</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a Hamiltonian lattice field model with two conserved quantities,
energy and volume, perturbed by stochastic noise preserving the two previous
quantities. It is known that this model displays anomalous diffusion of energy
of fractional type due to the conservation of the volume [5, 3]. We superpose
to this system a second stochastic noise conserving energy but not volume. If
the intensity of this noise is of order one, normal diffusion of energy is
restored while it is without effect if intensity is sufficiently small. In this
paper we investigate the nature of the energy fluctuations for a critical value
of the intensity. We show that the latter are described by an
Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process driven by a L\'evy process which interpolates
between Brownian motion and the maximally asymmetric 3/2-stable L\'evy process.
This result extends and solves a problem left open in [4].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00553</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2017-08-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wallis</keyname><forenames>Christopher G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiaux</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEwen</keyname><forenames>Jason D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sparse image reconstruction on the sphere: analysis and synthesis</title><categories>cs.IT astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM math.IT</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 Figures</comments><doi>10.1109/TIP.2017.2716824</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop techniques to solve ill-posed inverse problems on the sphere by
sparse regularisation, exploiting sparsity in both axisymmetric and directional
scale-discretised wavelet space. Denoising, inpainting, and deconvolution
problems, and combinations thereof, are considered as examples. Inverse
problems are solved in both the analysis and synthesis settings, with a number
of different sampling schemes. The most effective approach is that with the
most restricted solution-space, which depends on the interplay between the
adopted sampling scheme, the selection of the analysis/synthesis problem, and
any weighting of the l1 norm appearing in the regularisation problem. More
efficient sampling schemes on the sphere improve reconstruction fidelity by
restricting the solution-space and also by improving sparsity in wavelet space.
We apply the technique to denoise Planck 353 GHz observations, improving the
ability to extract the structure of Galactic dust emission, which is important
for studying Galactic magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02551</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lushi</keyname><forenames>Enkeleida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kantsler</keyname><forenames>Vasily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Raymond E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering of biflagellate microswimmers from surfaces</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Open Access article and supplementary movies at
  https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.96.023102</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 023102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.023102</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We use a three-bead-spring model to investigate the dynamics of bi-flagellate
micro-swimmers near a surface. While the primary dynamics and scattering are
governed by geometric-dependent direct contact, the fluid flows generated by
the swimmer locomotion are important in orienting it toward or away from the
surface. Flagellar noise and in particular cell spinning about the main axis
help a surface-trapped swimmer escape, whereas the time a swimmer spends at the
surface depends on the incident angle. The dynamics results from a nuanced
interplay of direct collisions, hydrodynamics, noise and the swimmer geometry.
We show that to correctly capture the dynamics of a biflagellate swimmer,
minimal models need to resolve the shape asymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03731</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huh</keyname><forenames>Joonsuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yung</keyname><forenames>Man-Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Vibronic Boson Sampling: Generalized Gaussian Boson Sampling for
  Molecular Vibronic Spectra at Finite Temperature</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 7462 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-07770-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular vibroic spectroscopy, where the transitions involve non-trivial
Bosonic correlation due to the Duschinsky Rotation, is strongly believed to be
in a similar complexity class as Boson Sampling. At finite temperature, the
problem is represented as a Boson Sampling experiment with correlated Gaussian
input states. This molecular problem with temperature effect is intimately
related to the various versions of Boson Sampling sharing the similar
computational complexity. Here we provide a full description to this relation
in the context of Gaussian Boson Sampling. We find a hierarchical structure,
which illustrates the relationship among various Boson Sampling schemes.
Specifically, we show that every instance of Gaussian Boson Sampling with an
initial correlation can be simulated by an instance of Gaussian Boson Sampling
without initial correlation, with only a polynomial overhead. Since every
Gaussian state is associated with a thermal state, our result implies that
every sampling problem in molecular vibronic transitions, at any temperature,
can be simulated by Gaussian Boson Sampling associated with a product of vacuum
modes. We refer such a generalized Gaussian Boson Sampling motivated by the
molecular sampling problem as Vibronic Boson Sampling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05356</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-07-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Penna-Lima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartlett</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melin</keyname><forenames>J. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merten</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evrard</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calibrating the Planck Cluster Mass Scale with CLASH</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, 5 tables. The new version includes an analysis
  considering a non-Gaussian prior on the lensing bias, and other improvements
  on the text. Accepted by Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 604, A89 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629971</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the mass scale of Planck galaxy clusters using gravitational
lensing mass measurements from the Cluster Lensing And Supernova survey with
Hubble (CLASH). We have compared the lensing masses to the Planck
Sunyaev-Zeldovich (SZ) mass proxy for 21 clusters in common, employing a
Bayesian analysis to simultaneously fit an idealized CLASH selection function
and the distribution between the measured observables and true cluster mass. We
used a tiered analysis strategy to explicitly demonstrate the importance of
priors on weak lensing mass accuracy. In the case of an assumed constant bias,
$b_{SZ}$, between true cluster mass, $M_{500}$, and the Planck mass proxy,
$M_{PL}$, our analysis constrains $1- b_{SZ} = 0.73\pm 0.10$ when moderate
priors on weak lensing accuracy are used, including a zero-mean Gaussian with
standard deviation of 8% to account for possible bias in lensing mass
estimations. Our analysis explicitly accounts for possible selection bias
effects in this calibration sourced by the CLASH selection function. Our
constraint on the cluster mass scale is consistent with recent results from the
Weighing the Giants program and the Canadian Cluster Comparison Project. It is
also consistent, at 1.34$\sigma$, with the value needed to reconcile the Planck
SZ cluster counts with Planck's base $\Lambda$CDM model fit to the primary
cosmic microwave background anisotropies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02971</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zinger</keyname><forenames>Aleksey</forenames></author></authors><title>Some conjectures on the asymptotic behavior of Gromov-Witten invariants</title><categories>math.AG hep-th math.CO math.SG</categories><comments>26 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>05A16, 14N35, 53D45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this note is to share some observations and speculations
concerning the asymptotic behavior of Gromov-Witten invariants. They may be
indicative of some deep phenomena in symplectic topology that in full
generality are outside of the reach of current techniques. On the other hand,
many interesting cases can perhaps be treated via combinatorial techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04545</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Savage</keyname><forenames>Martin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shanahan</keyname><forenames>Phiala E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiburzi</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagman</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beane</keyname><forenames>Silas R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoudi</keyname><forenames>Zohreh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Detmold</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orginos</keyname><forenames>Kostas</forenames></author></authors><title>Proton-proton fusion and tritium $\beta$-decay from lattice quantum
  chromodynamics</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Published version with supplementary material</comments><report-no>INT-PUB-16-033, JLAB-THY-16-2362, MIT-CTP-4844, NT@UW-16-12</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 062002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.062002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nuclear matrix element determining the $pp\to d e^+ \nu$ fusion cross
section and the Gamow-Teller matrix element contributing to tritium
$\beta$-decay are calculated with lattice Quantum Chromodynamics (QCD) for the
first time. Using a new implementation of the background field method, these
quantities are calculated at the SU(3)-flavor-symmetric value of the quark
masses, corresponding to a pion mass of $m_\pi$ ~ 806 MeV. The Gamow-Teller
matrix element in tritium is found to be 0.979(03)(10) at these quark masses,
which is within $2\sigma$ of the experimental value. Assuming that the
short-distance correlated two-nucleon contributions to the matrix element
(meson-exchange currents) depend only mildly on the quark masses, as seen for
the analogous magnetic interactions, the calculated $pp\to d e^+ \nu$
transition matrix element leads to a fusion cross section at the physical quark
masses that is consistent with its currently accepted value. Moreover, the
leading two-nucleon axial counterterm of pionless effective field theory is
determined to be $L_{1,A}=3.9(0.1)(1.0)(0.3)(0.9)\ {\rm fm}^3$ at a
renormalization scale set by the physical pion mass, also in agreement with the
accepted phenomenological range. This work concretely demonstrates that weak
transition amplitudes in few-nucleon systems can be studied directly from the
fundamental quark and gluon degrees of freedom and opens the way for subsequent
investigations of many important quantities in nuclear physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05995</id><created>2016-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Qi-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jin-Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Shao-Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jin-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Chui-Ping</forenames></author></authors><title>Transferring arbitrary d-dimensional quantum states of a superconducting
  qudit in circuit QED</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 7039 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-07225-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A qudit ($d$-level quantum systems) has a large Hilbert space and thus can be
used to achieve many quantum information and communication tasks. Here, we
propose a method to transfer arbitrary $d$-dimensional quantum states (known or
unknown) between two superconducting qudits coupled to a single cavity. The
state transfer can be performed fast because of employing resonant interactions
only. In addition, quantum states can be deterministically transferred without
measurement. Numerical simulations show that high-fidelity transfer of quantum
states between two superconducting transmon qudits ($d\leq5$) is feasible with
current circuit QED technology. This proposal is quite general and can be
applied to accomplish the same task with various superconducting qudits,
quantum dots, or natural atoms coupled to a cavity or resonator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00165</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-01-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruban</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The dynamics of straight vortex filaments in a Bose-Einstein condensate
  with a Gaussian density profile</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.PS physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>revtex, 10 pages, 7 figures, Introduction improved, English
  translation of Russian text accepted to JETP</comments><journal-ref>JETP 124 (6), 932-942 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776117050041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of interacting quantized vortex filaments in a rotating trapped
Bose-Einstein condensate, which is in the Thomas-Fermi regime at zero
temperature and described by the Gross-Pitaevskii equation, is considered in
the hydrodynamic &quot;anelastic&quot; approximation. In the presence of a smoothly
inhomogeneous array of filaments (vortex lattice), a non-canonical Hamiltonian
equation of motion is derived for the macroscopically averaged vorticity, with
taking into account the spatial non-uniformity of the equilibrium condensate
density determined by the trap potential. A minimum of the corresponding
Hamiltonian describes a static configuration of deformed vortex lattice against
a given density background. The minimum condition is reduced to a vector
nonlinear partial differential equation of the second order, for which some
approximate and exact solutions are found. It is shown that if the condensate
density has an anisotropic Gaussian profile then equation of motion for the
averaged vorticity admits solutions in the form of a spatially uniform vector
with a nontrivial time dependence. An integral representation is obtained for
the matrix Green function determining the non-local Hamiltonian of a system of
arbitrary shaped vortex filaments in a condensate with Gaussian density. ... A
simple approximate expression for the two-dimensional Green function is
suggested at rather arbitrary density profile, and its successful comparison to
the exact result in the Gaussian case is done. Approximate equations of motion
are derived which describe a long-wave dynamics of interacting vortex filaments
in condensates with the density depending on the transverse coordinates only.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00647</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2016-12-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bieniek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wozniak</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potasz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of topological properties of bismuth (111) bilayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29 (2017) 155501</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa5e79</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate electronic and transport properties of bismuth (111) bilayer
in the context of stability of its topological properties against different
perturbations. The effects of spin-orbit coupling variations, geometry
relaxation and an interaction with a substrate are considered. Transport
properties are studied in the presence of Anderson disorder. Band structure
calculations are performed within multi-orbital tight-binding model and density
functional theory methods. A band inversion process in bismuth (111) infinite
bilayer and an evolution of edge states dispersion in ribbons as a function of
spin-orbit coupling strength are analyzed. A significant change of orbital
composition of the conduction and valence bands during a topological phase
transition is observed. A topological phase is shown to be robust when the
effect of geometry relaxation is taken into account. An interaction with a
substrate has similar effect to an external perpendicular electric field. The
robust quantized conductance is observed when the Fermi energy lies within the
bulk energy gap, where only two counter-propagating edge states are present.
For energies where the Fermi level crosses more in-gap states, a scattering is
possible between channels lying close in $k-$space. When the energy of edge
states overlaps with bulk states, no topological protection is observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03436</id><created>2016-12-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hongwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Lixin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>Cameron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xifan</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic origin of spin-phonon coupling effect in transition-metal
  perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075121 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By applying Wannier-based extended Kugel-Khomskii model, we carry out
first-principles calculations and electronic structure analysis to understand
the spin-phonon coupling effect in transition-metal perovskites. We demonstrate
the successful application of our approach to SrMnO$_3$ and BiFeO$_3$. We show
that both the electron orbitals under crystal field splitting and the
electronic configuration should be taken into account in order to understand
the large variances of spin-phonon coupling effects among various phonon modes
as well as in different materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08966</id><created>2016-12-28</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Centrality dependence of the pseudorapidity density distribution for
  charged particles in Pb-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}=5.02$ TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 captioned figures, authors from page 13, published
  version, figures at http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/3337</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-327</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B 772 (2017) 567-577</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.07.017</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present the charged-particle pseudorapidity density in Pb-Pb collisions at
$\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}=5.02\,\mathrm{Te\kern-.25exV}$ in centrality classes
measured by ALICE. The measurement covers a wide pseudorapidity range from
$-3.5$ to $5$, which is sufficient for reliable estimates of the total number
of charged particles produced in the collisions. For the most central (0-5%)
collisions we find $21\,400\pm 1\,300$ while for the most peripheral (80-90%)
we find $230\pm 38$. This corresponds to an increase of $(27\pm4)\%$ over the
results at $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}=2.76\,\mathrm{Te\kern-.25exV}$ previously
reported by ALICE. The energy dependence of the total number of charged
particles produced in heavy-ion collisions is found to obey a modified
power-law like behaviour. The charged-particle pseudorapidity density of the
most central collisions is compared to model calculations --- none of which
fully describes the measured distribution. We also present an estimate of the
rapidity density of charged particles. The width of that distribution is found
to exhibit a remarkable proportionality to the beam rapidity, independent of
the collision energy from the top SPS to LHC energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02825</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ram</keyname><forenames>Panch</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Brijesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of Quantum Oscillations of Magnetization in Kondo Insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075115 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kondo lattice model of spin-1/2 local moments coupled to the conduction
electrons at half-filling is studied for its orbital response to magnetic field
on bipartite lattices. Through an effective charge dynamics, in a canonical
representation of electrons that appropriately describes the Kondo insulating
ground state, the magnetization is found to show de Haas-van Alphen
oscillations from intermediate to weak Kondo coupling. These oscillations are
ascribed to Lifshitz-like inversion of a dispersion of the gapped
quasiparticles, whose chemical potential surface is measured by the oscillation
frequency. Such oscillations are also predicted to occur in spin-density wave
insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04953</id><created>2017-01-18</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kashiwa</keyname><forenames>Kouji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohnishi</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological deconfinement transition in QCD at finite isospin density</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><report-no>YITP-17-04</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett.B772:669-674,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.07.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The confinement-deconfinement transition is discussed from topological
viewpoints. The topological change of the system is achieved by introducing the
dimensionless imaginary chemical potential ($\theta$). Then, the non-trivial
free-energy degeneracy becomes the signal of the deconfinement transition and
it can be visualized by using the map of the thermodynamic quantities to the
circle $S^1$ along $\theta$. To understand this &quot;topological&quot; deconfinement
transition at finite real quark chemical potential ($\mu_\mathrm{R}$), we
consider the isospin chemical potential ($\mu_\mathrm{iso}$) in the effective
model of QCD. The phase diagram at finite $\mu_\mathrm{iso}$ is identical with
that at finite $\mu_\mathrm{R}$ outside of the pion-condensed phase at least in
the large-$N_\mathrm{c}$ limit via the well-known orbifold equivalence. In the
present effective model, the topological deconfinement transition does not show
a significant dependence on $\mu_\mathrm{iso}$ and then we can expect that this
tendency also appears at small $\mu_\mathrm{R}$. Also, the chiral transition
and the topological deconfinement transition seems to be weakly correlated. If
we will access lattice QCD data for the temperature dependence of the quark
number density at finite $\mu_\mathrm{iso}$ with $\theta=\pi/3$, our surmise
can be judged.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00896</id><created>2017-02-02</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Chui-Ping</forenames></author></authors><title>Transferring multiqubit entanglement onto memory qubits in a
  decoherence-free subspace</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, accepted by Quantum Inf Process. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1702.00895</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf Process 16, 67 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-017-1523-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Different from the previous works on generating entangled states, this work
is focused on how to transfer the prepared entangled states onto memory qubits
for protecting them against decoherence. We here consider a physical system
consisting of $n$ operation qubits and $2n$ memory qubits placed in a cavity or
coupled to a resonator. A method is presented for transferring $n$-qubit
Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) entangled states from the operation qubits
(i.e., information processing cells) onto the memory qubits (i.e., information
memory elements with long decoherence time). The transferred GHZ states are
encoded in a decoherence-free subspace against collective dephasing, and thus
can be immune from decoherence induced by a dephasing environment. In addition,
the state transfer procedure has nothing to do with the number of qubits, the
operation time does not increase with the number of qubits, and no measurement
is needed for the state transfer. This proposal can be applied to a wide range
of hybrid qubits such as natural atoms and artificial atoms (e.g., various
solid-state qubits).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01642</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weatherall</keyname><forenames>James Owen</forenames></author></authors><title>Conservation, Inertia, and Spacetime Geometry</title><categories>physics.hist-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>48 pages; Forthcoming in Studies in History and Philosophy of Modern
  Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As Harvey Brown emphasizes in his book Physical Relativity, inertial motion
in general relativity is best understood as a theorem, and not a postulate.
Here I discuss the status of the &quot;conservation condition&quot;, which states that
the energy-momentum tensor associated with non-interacting matter is
covariantly divergence-free, in connection with such theorems. I argue that the
conservation condition is best understood as a consequence of the differential
equations governing the evolution of matter in general relativity and many
other theories. I conclude by discussing what it means to posit a certain
spacetime geometry and the relationship between that geometry and the dynamical
properties of matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02091</id><created>2017-02-07</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>Pramod</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rey</keyname><forenames>Soo-Jong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teixeira</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trancanelli</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric Many-Body Systems from Partial Symmetries: Integrability,
  Localization and Scrambling</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>45 pages, 7 figures; v2: 50 pages, Sec. 4 expanded and improved,
  published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1705 (2017) 136</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Partial symmetries are described by generalized group structures known as
symmetric inverse semigroups. We use the algebras arising from these structures
to realize supersymmetry in (0+1) dimensions and to build many-body quantum
systems on a chain. This construction consists in associating appropriate
supercharges to chain sites, in analogy to what is done in spin chains. For
simple enough choices of supercharges, we show that the resulting states have a
finite non-zero Witten index, which is invariant under perturbations, therefore
defining supersymmetric phases of matter protected by the index. The
Hamiltonians we obtain are integrable and display a spectrum containing both
product and entangled states. By introducing disorder and studying the
out-of-time-ordered correlators (OTOC), we find that these systems are in the
many-body localized phase and do not thermalize. Finally, we reformulate a
theorem relating the growth of the second Renyi entropy to the OTOC on a
thermal state in terms of partial symmetries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02457</id><created>2017-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>K&#xf6;ttig</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Travers</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>P. St. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>PHz-wide spectral interference through coherent plasma-induced fission
  of higher-order solitons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 263902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.263902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We identify a novel regime of soliton-plasma interactions in which
high-intensity ultrashort pulses of intermediate soliton order undergo coherent
plasma-induced fission. Experimental results obtained in gas-filled hollow-core
photonic crystal fibers are supported by rigorous numerical simulations. The
cumulative blueshift of higher-order input solitons with ionizing intensities
results in pulse splitting before the ultimate self-compression point, leading
to the generation of robust pulse pairs with PHz bandwidths. The novel dynamics
closes the gap between plasma-induced adiabatic soliton compression and
modulational instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04675</id><created>2017-02-15</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mazza</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Georges</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium superconductivity in driven alkali-doped fullerides</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 064515 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the formation of non-equilibrium superconducting states in
driven alkali-doped fullerides A$_3$C$_{60}$. Within a minimal three-orbital
model for the superconductivity of these materials, it was recently
demonstrated theoretically that an orbital-dependent imbalance of the
interactions leads to an enhancement of superconductivity at equilibrium [M.
Kim et al. Phys. Rev. B 94, 155152 (2016)]. We investigate the dynamical
response to a time periodic modulation of this interaction imbalance, and show
that it leads to the formation of a transient superconducting state which
survives much beyond the equilibrium critical temperature $T_c$. For a specific
range of modulation frequencies, we find that the driving reduces
superconductivity when applied to a superconducting state below $T_c$, while
still inducing a superconducting state when the initial temperature is larger
than $T_c$. These findings reinforce the relevance of the interaction-imbalance
mechanism as a possible explanation of the recent experimental observation of
light-induced superconductivity in alkali-doped fullerenes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04885</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Dam</keyname><forenames>Suzanne B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Humphreys</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozp&#x119;dek</keyname><forenames>Filip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehner</keyname><forenames>Stephanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiplexed entanglement generation over quantum networks using
  multi-qubit nodes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa7446</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum networks distributed over distances greater than a few kilometers
will be limited by the time required for information to propagate between
nodes. We analyze protocols that are able to circumvent this bottleneck by
employing multi-qubit nodes and multiplexing. For each protocol, we investigate
the key network parameters that determine its performance. We model achievable
entangling rates based on the anticipated near-term performance of
nitrogen-vacancy centres and other promising network platforms. This analysis
allows us to compare the potential of the proposed multiplexed protocols in
different regimes. Moreover, by identifying the gains that may be achieved by
improving particular network parameters, our analysis suggests the most
promising avenues for research and development of prototype quantum networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03735</id><created>2017-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Metcalf</keyname><forenames>Mekena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Chen-Yen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chien</keyname><forenames>Chih-Chun</forenames></author></authors><title>Protocols for dynamically probing topological edge states and
  dimerization with fermionic atoms in optical potentials</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL (Europhysics Letters), Volume 118, Number 5, Page 56004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/56004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological behavior has been observed in quantum systems including ultracold
atoms. However, background harmonic traps for cold-atoms hinder direct
detection of topological edge states arising at the boundary because the
distortion fuses the edge states into the bulk. We propose experimentally
feasible protocols to probe localized edge states and dimerization of ultracold
fermions. By confining cold-atoms in a ring lattice and changing the boundary
condition from periodic to open using an off-resonant laser sheet to cut open
the ring, topological edge states can be generated. A lattice in a topological
configuration can trap a single particle released at the edge as the system
evolves in time. Alternatively, depleting an initially filled lattice away from
the boundary reveals the occupied edge states. Signatures of dimerization in
the presence of contact interactions can be found in selected correlations as
the system boundary suddenly changes from periodic to open and exhibit memory
effects of the initial state distinguishing different configurations or phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10735</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dhargyal</keyname><forenames>Lobsang</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for more sensitive observables to charged scalars in $B
  \rightarrow D^{(*)}\tau\nu_{\tau}$ decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Improved in write up and also typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been known that $B \rightarrow D^{(*)} \tau \nu_{\tau}$ are good
observables in the search for the charged Higgs. The recent obervation of
deviation from standard-model by almost 4$\sigma$ by Babar, Belle and LHCb in
$R(D^{(*)})$ revived the interest in possible signal of presence of charged
Higgs in these modes. But such a large deviation in the rates, where
standard-model has tree level contribution, coming from a charged Higgs alone
is highly unlikely. However these decay modes are good probes to search for
small charged Higgs signal if we can construct sensitive observables in these
modes. In this work we would like to propose four new observables which shows
much more sensitivity to the presence of charged Higgs than the usual
observables such as $A_{\lambda}^{D^{(*)}}$ and $A_{\theta}^{D^{(*)}}$. These
four observable are (1) $\frac{1}{A_{\lambda}^{D}}$,\ (2) $Y_{1}(q^{2}) =
\frac{A^{D}_{\theta}}{A^{D}_{\lambda}}$,\ (3) $Y_{2}(q^{2}) = \frac{d\Gamma(B
\rightarrow D^{*}\tau\nu_{\tau})}{d\Gamma_{D}(\lambda_{\tau}=+1/2) -
d\Gamma_{D}(\lambda_{\tau}=-1/2)}$ and (4) $Y_{3}(q^{2}) =
(\frac{q^{2}}{m^{2}_{\tau}})(A^{D}_{\lambda} + 1)\frac{1}{A^{D}_{\lambda}}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00131</id><created>2017-04-01</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bercx</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goth</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Johannes S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Assaad</keyname><forenames>Fakher F.</forenames></author></authors><title>The ALF (Algorithms for Lattice Fermions) project release 1.0.
  Documentation for the auxiliary field quantum Monte Carlo code</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-lat physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>59 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.2.013</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Algorithms for Lattice Fermions package provides a general code for the
finite temperature auxiliary field quantum Monte Carlo algorithm. The code is
engineered to be able to simulate any model that can be written in terms of
sums of single-body operators, of squares of single-body operators and
single-body operators coupled to an Ising field with given dynamics. We provide
predefined types that allow the user to specify the model, the Bravais lattice
as well as equal time and time displaced observables. The code supports an MPI
implementation. Examples such as the Hubbard model on the honeycomb lattice and
the Hubbard model on the square lattice coupled to a transverse Ising field are
provided and discussed in the documentation. We furthermore discuss how to use
the package to implement the Kondo lattice model and the
$SU(N)$-Hubbard-Heisenberg model. One can download the code from our Git
instance at https://alf.physik.uni-wuerzburg.de and sign in to file issues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01784</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vostrosablin</keyname><forenames>Nikita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakhubovsky</keyname><forenames>Andrey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filip</keyname><forenames>Radim</forenames></author></authors><title>Pulsed quantum continuous-variable optoelectromechanical transducer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 25, 18974-18989 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.018974</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a setup allowing to entangle two directly non-interacting
radiation modes applying four sequential pulsed quantum resonant interactions
with a noisy vibrational mode of a mechanical oscillator which plays the role
of the mediator. We analyze Gaussian entanglement of the radiation modes
generated by the transducer and confirm that the noisy mechanical mode can
mediate generation of entanglement. The entanglement, however, is limited if
the interaction gains are not individually optimized. We prove the robustness
of the transducer to optical losses and the influence of the mechanical bath
and propose the ways to achieve maximal performance through the individual
optimization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03232</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Shan-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Run-Qiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments on Joint Terms in Gravitational Action</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Published version with little modifications compared with previous
  one</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 175017 (18pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa8053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper compares three different methods about computing joint terms in
on-shell action of gravity, which are identifying the joint term by the
variational principle in Dirichlet boundary condition, treating the joint term
as the limit contribution of smooth boundary and finding the joint term by
local SO(1,$d-1$) transformation. In general metric gravitational theory, we
show that the differences between these joint terms are some variational
invariants under fixed boundary condition. We also give an explicit condition
to judge the existence of joint term determined by variational principle and
apply it into general relativity as an example.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04593</id><created>2017-04-15</created><updated>2017-08-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishihara</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author></authors><title>Proposal of highly efficient photoemitter with strong photon-harvesting
  capability and exciton superradiance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 111, 063108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4998444</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a system of highly efficient photoemitters comprising
metal-dielectric (plasmonic-excitonic) multilayered structures. In the proposed
structure, the absorption in the excitonic layer is greatly enhanced through
quantum interference between the split modes arising from the coupling of the
layered excitons and the plasmons sustained by the metallic layer. Furthermore,
the large interaction volume between surface plasmons and excitons causes
exciton superradiance, which results in the extremely efficient photoemission.
This finding indicates the possibility of designing highly efficient
photoemitters based on simple layered structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04851</id><created>2017-04-16</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Peter D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author></authors><title>Rational Solutions of the Painlev\'e-II Equation Revisited</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 065, 29 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.065</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The rational solutions of the Painlev\'e-II equation appear in several
applications and are known to have many remarkable algebraic and analytic
properties. They also have several different representations, useful in
different ways for establishing these properties. In particular,
Riemann-Hilbert representations have proven to be useful for extracting the
asymptotic behavior of the rational solutions in the limit of large degree
(equivalently the large-parameter limit). We review the elementary properties
of the rational Painlev\'e-II functions, and then we describe three different
Riemann-Hilbert representations of them that have appeared in the literature: a
representation by means of the isomonodromy theory of the Flaschka-Newell Lax
pair, a second representation by means of the isomonodromy theory of the
Jimbo-Miwa Lax pair, and a third representation found by Bertola and Bothner
related to pseudo-orthogonal polynomials. We prove that the Flaschka-Newell and
Bertola-Bothner Riemann-Hilbert representations of the rational Painlev\'e-II
functions are explicitly connected to each other. Finally, we review recent
results describing the asymptotic behavior of the rational Painlev\'e-II
functions obtained from these Riemann-Hilbert representations by means of the
steepest descent method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05631</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-07-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beznasyuk</keyname><forenames>Daria V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robin</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hertog</keyname><forenames>Martien Den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claudon</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hocevar</keyname><forenames>Mo&#xef;ra</forenames></author></authors><title>Dislocation-free axial InAs-on-GaAs nanowires on silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa7d40</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the growth of axial InAs-on-GaAs nanowire heterostructures on
silicon by molecular beam epitaxy using 20 nm diameter Au catalysts. First, the
growth parameters of the GaAs nanowire segment were optimized to achieve a pure
wurtzite crystal structure. Then, we developed a two-step growth procedure to
enhance the yield of vertical InAs-on-GaAs nanowires. We achieved 90% of
straight InAs-on-GaAs nanowires by further optimizing the growth parameters. We
investigated the composition change at the interface by energy dispersive X-ray
spectroscopy and the nanowire crystal structure by transmission electron
microscopy. The nominal composition of the InAs segment is found to be
In$_{x}$Ga$_{1-x}$As with $x$=0.85 and corresponds to 6% of lattice mismatch
with GaAs. Strain mapping performed by the geometrical phase analysis of
high-resolution images revealed a dislocation-free GaAs/InAs interface. In
conclusion, we successfully fabricated highly mismatched heterostructures,
confirming the prediction that axial GaAs/InAs interfaces are pseudomorphic in
nanowires below 40 nm diameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02545</id><created>2017-05-06</created><updated>2017-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Yungui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Zhu</forenames></author></authors><title>The reconstruction of tachyon inflationary potentials</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, major revision and conclusion unchanged, add discussion on
  attractor, jcap in press</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1708 (2017) 018</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/08/018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a lower bound on the field excursion for the tachyon inflation,
which is determined by the amplitude of the scalar perturbation and the number
of $e$-folds before the end of inflation. Using the relation between the
observables like $n_s$ and $r$ with the slow-roll parameters, we reconstruct
three classes of tachyon potentials. The model parameters are determined from
the observations before the potentials are reconstructed, and the observations
prefer the concave potential. We also discuss the constraints from the
reheating phase preceding the radiation domination for the three classes of
models by assuming the equation of state parameter $w_{re}$ during reheating is
a constant. Depending on the model parameters and the value of $w_{re}$, the
constraints on $N_{re}$ and $T_{re}$ are different. As $n_s$ increases, the
allowed reheating epoch becomes longer for $w_{re}=-1/3$, 0 and $1/6$ while the
allowed reheating epoch becomes shorter for $w_{re}=2/3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06639</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06639</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bielska</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wojtewicz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morzynski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ablewski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cygan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bober</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zawada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciurylo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maslowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisak</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Absolute frequency determination of molecular transition in the Doppler
  regime at kHz level of accuracy</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer,
  Volume 201, November 2017, Pages 156-160</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jqsrt.2017.07.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present absolute frequency measurement of the unperturbed P7 P7 O$_2$
B-band transition with relative standard uncertainty of $2\times10^{-11}$. We
reached the level of accuracy typical for Doppler-free techniques, with
Doppler-limited spectroscopy. The Doppler-limited shapes of the P7 P7 spectral
line were measured with a frequency-stabilized cavity ring-down spectrometer
referenced to an $^{88}$Sr optical atomic clock by an optical frequency comb.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08248</id><created>2017-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kher</keyname><forenames>Virendrasinh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devlani</keyname><forenames>Nayneshkumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Ajay Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopy, Decay properties and Regge trajectories of the $B$ and
  $B_s$ mesons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 10 figures and 12 tables, it is to be published in Chinese
  Physics C. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1704.00439</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C Vol. 41, No. 9 (2017) 093101</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/9/093101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Gaussian wave function is used for detailed study of mass spectra of the
$B$ and $B_S$ mesons using a Cornell potential incorporated with a
$\mathcal{O}(1/m)$ correction in the potential energy term and expansion of the
kinetic energy term up to a ${{\cal{O}}\left({\bf p}^{10}\right)}$ for
relativistic correction of the Hamiltonian. The predicted excited states for
the $B$ and $B_s$ mesons are in very good agreement with results obtained by
experiment. We assigned the $B_{2}(5747)$ and $B_{s2}(5840)$ as $1^{3}p_{2}$
state, the $B_{1}(5721)$ and $B_{s1}(5830)$ as $1 p_{1}$ state, the
$B_{0}(5732)$ as $1^{3}p_{0}$ state, the $B_{s1}(5850)$ as $1p_{1}^{'}$ state
and the $B(5970)$ as $2^{3}S_{1}$ state. We investigate the Regge trajectories
in the $(J,M^{2})$ and $(n_r,M^{2})$ planes with their corresponding
parameters. Branching ratio for leptonic and radiative-leptonic decays are
estimated for the $B$ and $B_S$ mesons. Our results are in good agreement with
experimental observation as well as outcomes of other theoretical models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.11012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.11012</id><created>2017-05-31</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambassi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical field theory with constraints: application to critical
  Casimir forces in the canonical ensemble</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>46 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022135 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of imposing a constraint on a fluctuating scalar order parameter
field in a system of finite volume is studied within statistical field theory.
The canonical ensemble, corresponding to a fixed total integrated order
parameter, is obtained as a special case of the theory. A perturbative
expansion is developed which allows one to systematically determine the
constraint-induced finite-volume corrections to the free energy and to
correlation functions. In particular, we focus on the Landau-Ginzburg model in
a film geometry (i.e., a rectangular parallelepiped with a small aspect ratio)
with periodic, Dirichlet, or Neumann boundary conditions in the transverse
direction and periodic boundary conditions in the remaining, lateral
directions. Within the expansion in terms of $\epsilon=4-d$, where $d$ is the
spatial dimension of the bulk, the finite-size contribution to the free energy
and the associated critical Casimir force are calculated to leading order in
$\epsilon$ and are compared to the corresponding expressions for an
unconstrained (grand canonical) system. The constraint restricts the
fluctuations within the system and it accordingly modifies the residual
finite-size free energy. The resulting Casimir force is shown to depend on
whether it is defined by assuming a fixed transverse area or a fixed total
volume. In the former case, the constraint is typically found to significantly
enhance the attractive character of the force as compared to the grand
canonical case. In contrast to the grand canonical Casimir force, which, for
supercritical temperatures, vanishes in the limit of thick films, the canonical
Casimir force defined for fixed transverse area attains for thick films a
negative value for all boundary conditions studied here. Typically, the
dependence of the Casimir force both on the temperature- and on the field-like
scaling variables is different in the two ensembles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01815</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maggio</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kresse</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>$GW$ vertex corrected calculations for molecular systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Hedin's scheme is solved with the inclusion of the vertex function
($GW\Gamma$) for a set of small molecules.
  The computational scheme allows for the consistent inclusion of the vertex
both at the polarizability level and in the self-energy.
  A diagrammatic analysis shows that the self-energy formed with this
four-point vertex does not lead to double counting of diagrams, that can be
classified as direct &quot;bubbles&quot; and exchange diagrams.
  By removing the exchange diagrams from the self-energy, a simpler
approximation is obtained, called $GW^{\rm{tc-tc}}$.
  Very good agreement with expensive wavefunction-based methods is obtained for
both approximations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01894</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Biondini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Re-derived overclosure bound for the inert doublet model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages. v2: clarifications added, published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1708 (2017) 047</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2017)047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply a formalism accounting for thermal effects (such as modified
Sommerfeld effect; Salpeter correction; decohering scatterings; dissociation of
bound states), to one of the simplest WIMP-like dark matter models, associated
with an &quot;inert&quot; Higgs doublet. A broad temperature range T ~ M/20...M/10^4 is
considered, stressing the importance and less-understood nature of late
annihilation stages. Even though only weak interactions play a role, we find
that resummed real and virtual corrections increase the tree-level overclosure
bound by 1...18%, depending on quartic couplings and mass splittings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04293</id><created>2017-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Elvira</keyname><forenames>V. Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Detector Simulation in Particle Physics Collider Experiments</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Physics Reports (of Physics Letters) 94
  pages, 57 figures</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-17-067-CD</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Reports 695 (2017) 1-54</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2017.06.002</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Through the last three decades, accurate simulation of the interactions of
particles with matter and modeling of detector geometries has proven to be of
critical importance to the success of the international high-energy physics
(HEP) experimental programs. For example, the detailed detector modeling and
accurate physics of the Geant4-based simulation software of the CMS and ATLAS
particle physics experiments at the European Center of Nuclear Research (CERN)
Large Hadron Collider (LHC) was a determinant factor for these collaborations
to deliver physics results of outstanding quality faster than any hadron
collider experiment ever before.
  This review article highlights the impact of detector simulation on particle
physics collider experiments. It presents numerous examples of the use of
simulation, from detector design and optimization, through software and
computing development and testing, to cases where the use of simulation samples
made a difference in the precision of the physics results and publication
turnaround, from data-taking to submission. It also presents estimates of the
cost and economic impact of simulation in the CMS experiment.
  Future experiments will collect orders of magnitude more data with
increasingly complex detectors, taxing heavily the performance of simulation
and reconstruction software. Consequently, exploring solutions to speed up
simulation and reconstruction software to satisfy the growing demand of
computing resources in a time of flat budgets is a matter that deserves
immediate attention. The article ends with a short discussion on the potential
solutions that are being considered, based on leveraging core count growth in
multicore machines, using new generation coprocessors, and re-engineering HEP
code for concurrency and parallel computing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07434</id><created>2017-06-22</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>Adam R. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Toby</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical drivers of galaxies' cold-gas content: exploring environmental
  and evolutionary effects with DARK SAGE</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS. Correction
  to errorbars in Figs 3,4,9</comments><journal-ref>2017, MNRAS, 471, 447</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1596</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We combine the latest spectrally stacked data of 21-cm emission from the
ALFALFA survey with an updated version of the Dark Sage semi-analytic model to
investigate the relative contributions of secular and environmental
astrophysical processes on shaping the HI fractions and quiescence of galaxies
in the local Universe. We calibrate the model to match the observed mean HI
fraction of all galaxies as a function of stellar mass. Without consideration
of stellar feedback, disc instabilities, and active galactic nuclei, we show
how the slope and normalisation of this relation would change significantly. We
find Dark Sage can reproduce the relative impact that halo mass is observed to
have on satellites' HI fractions and quiescent fraction. However, the model
satellites are systematically gas-poor. We discuss how this could be affected
by satellite--central cross-contamination from the group-finding algorithm
applied to the observed galaxies, but that it is not the full story. From our
results, we suggest the anti-correlation between satellites' HI fractions and
host halo mass, seen at fixed stellar mass and fixed specific star formation
rate, can be attributed almost entirely to ram-pressure stripping of cold gas.
Meanwhile, stripping of hot gas from around the satellites drives the
correlation of quiescent fraction with halo mass at fixed stellar mass. Further
detail in the modelling of galaxy discs' centres is required to solidify this
result, however. We contextualise our results with those from other
semi-analytic models and hydrodynamic simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01177</id><created>2017-07-04</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Globus</keyname><forenames>Noemie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allard</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parizot</keyname><forenames>Etienne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lachaud</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piran</keyname><forenames>Tsvi</forenames></author></authors><title>Can we reconcile the TA excess and hotspot with Auger observations?</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, to appear in the Proceedings of the 35th
  International Cosmic Ray Conference 10-20 July, 2017 Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Telescope Array (TA) shows a 20$^{\circ}$ hotspot as well as an excess of
UHECRs above 50~EeV when compared with the Auger spectrum. We consider the
possibility that both the TA excess and hotspot are due to a dominant source in
the Northern sky. We carry out detailed simulations of UHECR propagation in
both the intergalactic medium and the Galaxy, using different values for the
intergalactic magnetic field. We consider two general classes of sources:
transients and steady, adopting a mixed UHECR composition that is consistent
with the one found by Auger. The spatial location of the sources is draw
randomly. We generate Auger-like and TA-like data sets from which we determine
the spectrum, the sky maps and the level of anisotropy. We find that, while
steady sources are favored over transients, it is unlikely to account for all
the currently available observational data. While we reproduce fairly well the
Auger spectrum for the vast majority of the simulated data sets, most of the
simulated data sets with a spectrum compatible with that of TA (at most a few
percent depending on density model tested) show a much stronger anisotropy than
the one observed. We find that the rare cases in which both the spectrum and
the anisotropy are consistent require a steady source within $\sim 10$ Mpc, to
account for the flux excess, and a strong extragalactic magnetic field $\sim
10$ nG, to reduce the excessive anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01064</id><created>2017-08-03</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Guo Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ming Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hua</keyname><forenames>Yao Zu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abareshi</keyname><forenames>Bagher</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Equilibrium Molecular Dynamics Simulation of Poiseuille Flow in a
  Carbon Nanochannel</title><categories>physics.atm-clus physics.chem-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>International Conference on Physical and Theoretical Chemistry,
  Jun 2017, Dublin, Ireland. 4 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The numerical simulation of a Poiseuille flow in a narrow channel using the
molecular dynamics simulation (MDS) is performed. Poiseuille flow of liquid
Argon in a carbon nanochannel is simulated by embedding the fluid particles in
a uniform force field. Density, velocity and Temperature profiles across the
channel are investigated. When particles will be inserted into the flow, it is
expected that the dynamics of flow will depend on the thermostat chosen. To
obtain a more uniform temperature distribution across the channel we use local
thermostating near the wall. The obtained results show that velocity profile,
slip length and slip velocity depends on the driving force.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01612</id><created>2017-08-04</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>T. -W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulence Momentum Transport and Prediction of the Reynolds Stress in
  Canonical Flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1708.00966</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a unique method for solving for the Reynolds stress in turbulent
canonical flows, based on the momentum balance for a control volume moving at
the local mean velocity. A differential transform converts this momentum
balance to a solvable form. Comparisons with experimental and computational
data in simple geometries show quite good agreements. An alternate picture for
the turbulence momentum transport is offered, as verified with data, where the
turbulence momentum is transported by the mean velocity while being dissipated
by viscosity. The net momentum transport is the Reynolds stress. This
turbulence momentum balance is verified using DNS and experimental data.
Implications of this work are that the Reynolds stress can be written
explicitly in terms of basic turbulence parameters in a simple form, derived
from pure fluid physics, and that potential exists for applications of this
concept to more complex turbulent flows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01613</id><created>2017-08-04</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barzegari</keyname><forenames>Mojtaba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayani</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirbagheri</keyname><forenames>S. M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shetabivash</keyname><forenames>Hasan</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiphase Aluminum A356 Foam Formation Process Simulation Using Lattice
  Boltzmann Method</title><categories>cs.CE physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Shan-Chen model is a numerical scheme to simulate multiphase fluid flows
using Lattice Boltzmann approach. The original Shan-Chen model suffers from
inability to accurately predict behavior of air bubbles interacting in a
non-aqueous fluid. In the present study, we extended the Shan-Chen model to
take the effect of the attraction-repulsion barriers among bubbles in to
account. The proposed model corrects the interaction and coalescence criterion
of the original Shan-Chen scheme in order to have a more accurate simulation of
bubbles morphology in a metal foam. The model is based on forming a thin film
(narrow channel) between merging bubbles during growth. Rupturing of the film
occurs when an oscillation in velocity and pressure arises inside the channel
followed by merging of the bubbles. Comparing numerical results obtained from
proposed model with mettallorgraphy images for aluminum A356 demonstrated a
good consistency in mean bubble size and bubbles distribution
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02911</id><created>2017-08-09</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Avneet</forenames></author></authors><title>Primordial non-Gaussianity in Horndeski-type model for Inflation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>59 pages, 5 figures, Master Thesis Dissertation, Review in Quantum
  Cosmology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a member of the family of scalar-tensor theories of Inflation -
the so-called Horndeski model for Inflation, for which we calculate the
non-Gaussianity (NG) and the power spectrum of curvature perturbations. We
concentrate on the determination of the power spectrum, and the bi-spectrum
along with the associated $f_\mathrm{NL}$ parameter and the Spectral Index. We
follow the methodology outlined within the Quantum field theory framework
(S-matrix approach and Weinberg's 'in-in' formalism) and compare - whenever
necessary - our findings with those obtained via the traditional $\delta$N
formalism. The work contained herein is an extensive review of the existing
literature on this subject and the 'Inflationary theory' in general, along with
some newly developed techniques and calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03459</id><created>2017-08-11</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cantoni</keyname><forenames>Mara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imalini</keyname><forenames>Edovardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Water flow in Carbon and Silicon Carbide nanotubes</title><categories>physics.atm-clus physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Macromolecular Structures, 2017</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work the conduction of ion-water solution through two discrete
bundles of armchair carbon and silicon carbide nanotubes, as useful membranes
for water desalination, is studied. In order that studies on different types of
nanotubes be comparable, the chiral vectors of C and Si-C nanotubes are
selected as (7,7) and (5,5), respectively, so that a similar volume of fluid is
investigated flowing through two similar dimension membranes. Different
hydrostatic pressures are applied and the flow rates of water and ions are
calculated through molecular dynamics simulations. Consequently, according to
conductance of water per each nanotube, per nanosecond, it is perceived that at
lower pressures (below 150 MPa) the Si-C nanotubes seem to be more applicable,
while higher hydrostatic pressures make carbon nanotube membranes more suitable
for water desalination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03727</id><created>2017-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Schimoia</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Storchi-Bergmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winge</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemmen</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eracleous</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the accretion disk around the supermassive black hole of
  NGC 7213</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 tables, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present observations of the double-peaked broad H$\alpha$ profile emitted
by the active nucleus of NGC 7213 using the the Gemini South Telescope in 13
epochs between 2011 September 27 and 2013 July 23. This is the first time that
the double-peaked line profile of this nucleus -- typical of gas emission from
the outer parts of an accretion disk surrounding a supermassive black hole
(SMBH) -- is reported to vary. From the analysis of the line profiles we find
two variability timescales: (1) the shortest one, between 7 and 28 days, is
consistent with the light travel time between the ionizing source and the part
of the disk emitting the line; and (2) a longer one of $\gtrsim 3$ months
corresponding to variations in the relative intensity of the blue and red sides
of the profile, which can be identified with the dynamical timescale of this
outer part of the the accretion disk. We modeled the line profiles as due to
emission from a region between $\approx$ 300 and 3000 gravitational radii of a
relativistic, Keplerian accretion disk surrounding the SMBH. Superposed on the
disk emissivity, the model includes an asymmetric feature in the shape of a
spiral arm with a rotation period of $\approx$ 21 months, which reproduces the
variations in the relative intensity of the blue and red sides of the profile.
Besides these variations, the $rms$ variation profile reveals the presence of
another variable component in the broad line, with smaller velocity width
W$_{68}$ (the width of the profile corresponding to 68$\%$ of the flux) of
$\sim 2100$ km s$^{-1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04314</id><created>2017-08-14</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Elton Yechao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Quntao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Min-Hsiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shor</keyname><forenames>Peter W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superadditivity in trade-off capacities of quantum channels</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>15 pages. v2: typo corrected</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4917</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we investigate the additivity phenomenon in the dynamic
capacity of a quantum channel for trading classical communication, quantum
communication and entanglement. Understanding such additivity property is
important if we want to optimally use a quantum channel for general
communication purpose. However, in a lot of cases, the channel one will be
using only has an additive single or double resource capacity, and it is
largely unknown if this could lead to an superadditive double or triple
resource capacity. For example, if a channel has an additive classical and
quantum capacity, can the classical-quantum capacity be superadditive? In this
work, we answer such questions affirmatively.
  We give proof-of-principle requirements for these channels to exist. In most
cases, we can provide an explicit construction of these quantum channels. The
existence of these superadditive phenomena is surprising in contrast to the
result that the additivity of both classical-entanglement and classical-quantum
capacity regions imply the additivity of the triple capacity region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04633</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Cepellotti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzari</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Boltzmann Transport in Nanostructures as a Friction Effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2017, 17 (8), pp 4675-4682</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface scattering is the key limiting factor to thermal transport in
dielectric crystals as the length scales are reduced or when temperature is
lowered. To explain this phenomenon, it is commonly assumed that the mean free
paths of heat carriers are bound by the crystal size and that thermal
conductivity is reduced in a manner proportional to such mean free paths. We
show here that these conclusions rely on simplifying assumptions and
approximated transport models. Instead, starting from the linearized Boltzmann
transport equation in the relaxon basis, we show how the problem can be reduced
to a set of decoupled linear differential equations. Then, the heat flow can be
interpreted as a hydrodynamic phenomenon, with the relaxon gas being slowed
down in proximity of a surface by friction effects, similar to the flux of a
viscous fluid in a pipe. As an example, we study a ribbon and a trench of
monolayer molybdenum disulphide, describing the procedure to reconstruct the
temperature and thermal conductivity profile in the sample interior and showing
how to estimate the effect of nanostructuring. The approach is general and
could be extended to other transport carriers, such as electrons, or extended
to materials of higher dimensionality and to different geometries, such as thin
films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04644</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bae</keyname><forenames>Jin-Beom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joung</keyname><forenames>Euihun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Shailesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring Free Matrix CFT Holographies at One-Loop</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>37 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend our recent study on the duality between stringy higher spin
theories and free CFTs in the $SU(N)$ adjoint representation to other matrix
models namely the free $SO(N)$ and $Sp(N)$ adjoint models as well as the free
$U(N)\times U(M)$ bi-fundamental and $O(N)\times O(M)$ bi-vector models. After
determining the spectrum of the theories in the planar limit by Polya counting,
we compute the one loop vacuum energy and Casimir energy for their respective
bulk duals by means of the CIRZ method that we have introduced recently. We
also elaborate on possible ambiguities in the application of this method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04652</id><created>2017-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Rosaev</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plavalova</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author></authors><title>On age of 6070 Rheinland and 54827 (2001 NQ8) asteroid pair</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present results of our studying of famous very young pair of
asteroids 6070 Rheinland and 54827 (2001 NQ8). We have done numeric integration
of orbits of pair with only planet perturbations and include Ceres and Vesta
effect. We have confirmed results of previous studying, obtained with different
integrators. And we confirm significant effect of Ceres and Vesta perturbation
on dynamic of this pair. We find that effect of other massive asteroids is
insignificant. According our results, more probable age of 6070 Rheinland and
54827 (2001 NQ8) pair is 16.2 kyrs. Our value of age is very close to most
recent age determination by Vokrouhlicky et al [12], obtained with different
method. After the compare our results, we can conclude, that non-gravitational
forces are small and large number of clones is not necessary in studying of
this pair. As an additional way of studying of close orbits dynamics, we
calculate relative velocity in pair during numeric integration. Normal
component of velocity show a very good convergence at epoch of closest
encounter in pair.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04665</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Gustavo E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bunge on gravitational waves</title><categories>gr-qc physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, accepted for publication in Foundations of Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I discuss the recent claims made by Mario Bunge on the philosophical
implications of the discovery of gravitational waves. I think that Bunge is
right when he points out that the detection implies the materiality of
spacetime, but I reject his identification of spacetime with the gravitational
field. I show that Bunge's analysis of the spacetime inside a hollow sphere is
defective, but this in no way affects his main claim.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04666</id><created>2017-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Reid</keyname><forenames>M. T. Homer</forenames></author></authors><title>Taylor-Duffy Method for Singular Tetrahedron-Product Integrals:
  Efficient Evaluation of Galerkin Integrals for VIE Solvers</title><categories>math.NA physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I present an accurate and efficient technique for numerical evaluation of
singular 6-dimensional integrals over tetrahedon-product domains, with
applications to calculation of Galerkin matrix elements for discretized
volume-integral-equation (VIE) solvers using Schaubert-Wilton-Glisson (SWG) and
other tetrahedral basis functions. My method extends the generalized
Taylor-Duffy strategy---used to handle the singular \textit{triangle}-product
integrals arising in discretized surface-integral-equation (SIE)
formulations---to the tetrahedron-product case; it effects an exact
transformation of a singular 6-dimensional integral to an nonsingular
lower-dimensional integral that may be evaluated by simple numerical cubature
The method is highly general and may---with the aid of automatic code
generation facilitated by computer-algebra systems---be applied to a wide
variety of singular integrals arising in various VIE formulations with various
types of tetrahedral basis function, of which I present several examples. To
demonstrate the accuracy and efficiency of my method, I apply it to the
calculation of matrix elements for the volume electric-field integral equation
(VEFIE) discretized with SWG basis functions, where the method yields 12-digit
or higher accuracy with low computational cost---an improvement of many orders
of magnitude compared to existing techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04685</id><created>2017-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Rychtarikova</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soucek</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stys</keyname><forenames>Dalibor</forenames></author></authors><title>Colorimetric Calibration of a Digital Camera</title><categories>cs.CV astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce a novel - physico-chemical - approach for
calibration of a digital camera chip. This approach utilizes results of
measurement of incident light spectra of calibration films of different levels
of gray for construction of calibration curve (number of incident photons vs.
image pixel intensity) for each camera pixel. We show spectral characteristics
of such corrected digital raw image files (a primary camera signal) and
demonstrate their suitability for next image processing and analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04688</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04688</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Renbin</forenames><affiliation>University of Kentucky</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Team</keyname><forenames>the MaStar</forenames></author></authors><title>SDSS-IV MaStar: a Large, Comprehensive, and High Quality Empirical
  Stellar Library</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Conference proceeding for the International Workshop on Spectral
  Stellar Libraries held in Campos de Jordao, SP, Brazil in Feburary 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the ongoing MaStar project, which is going to construct a large,
well-calibrated, high quality empirical stellar library with more than 8000
stars covering the wavelength range from 3622 to 10,354A at a resolution of
R~2000, and with better than 3% relative flux calibration. The spectra are
taken using hexagonal fiber bundles feeding the BOSS spectrographs on the 2.5m
Sloan Foundation Telescope, by piggybacking on the SDSS-IV/APOGEE-2
observations. Compared to previous efforts of empirical libraries, the MaStar
Library will have a more comprehensive stellar parameter coverage, especially
in cool dwarfs, low metallicity stars, and stars with different [alpha/Fe].
This is achieved by a target selection method based on large spectroscopic
catalogs from APOGEE, LAMOST, and SEGUE, combined with photometric selection.
This empirical library will provide a new basis for calibrating theoretical
spectral libraries and for stellar population synthesis. In addition, with
identical spectral coverage and resolution to the ongoing integral field
spectroscopy survey of nearby galaxies --- SDSS-IV/MaNGA (Mapping Nearby
Galaxies at APO). This library is ideal for spectral modeling and stellar
population analysis of MaNGA data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04693</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Chowdhury</keyname><forenames>Shwetadwip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eldridge</keyname><forenames>Will J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wax</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izatt</keyname><forenames>Joseph A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structured illumination microscopy for dual-modality 3D sub-diffraction
  resolution fluorescence and refractive-index reconstruction</title><categories>q-bio.QM physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 6 figures in main text, 3 figures in supplementary text</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Though structured illumination (SI) microscopy is a popular imaging technique
conventionally associated with fluorescent super-resolution, recent works have
suggested its applicability towards sub-diffraction coherent imaging with
quantitative endogenous biological contrast. Here, we demonstrate that SI can
efficiently integrate the principles of fluorescent super-resolution and
coherent synthetic aperture to achieve 3D dual-modality sub-diffraction
resolution, fluorescence and refractive-index (RI) visualizations of biological
samples. Such a demonstration can enable future biological studies to
synergistically explore molecular and biophysical/biochemical mechanisms at
sub-diffraction resolutions. We experimentally demonstrate this framework by
introducing a SI microscope capable of 3D sub-diffraction fluorescence and RI
imaging, and verify its biological visualization capabilities by experimentally
reconstructing 3D RI/fluorescence visualizations of fluorescent calibration
microspheres as well as alveolar basal epithelial adenocarcinoma (A549) and
human colorectal adenocarcinmoa (HT-29) cells, fluorescently stained for
F-actin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04700</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Finn</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brennan</keyname><forenames>Dylan P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Real frequency tearing layers with parallel dynamics and the effect on
  locking and resistive wall modes</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>27 Pages, 8 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tearing modes with real frequencies in the plasma frame (i.e. in addition to
the Doppler shift due to $E\times B$ rotation) are of potential importance
because of their effect on the locking process. In particular, it has recently
been shown [J. M. Finn, A. J. Cole, and D. P. Brennan, Phys. Plasmas (Letters),
22:120701, 2015] that the Maxwell torque on the plasma in the presence of an
applied error field is modified significantly for tearing modes having real
frequencies near marginal stability. In addition, it is known [J. M. Finn and
R. A. Gerwin, Phys. Plasmas, 3:2344, 1996] that resistive wall tearing modes
can be destabilized below their no-wall limits by rotation, if the tearing
modes have real frequencies near marginal stability. In this paper we first
derive the tearing mode dispersion relation with pressure gradient, field line
curvature and parallel dynamics in the resistive-inertial (RI) regime,
neglecting the divergence of the $E\times B$ drift and perpendicular
resistivity. The results show that the usual Glasser effect, a toroidal effect
which involves real frequencies, occurs in this simplified model, which ignores
perpendicular resistivity and the divergence of the $E\times B$ drift. We also
find, using a similar simple model, the surprising result that in the
viscoresistive regime with pressure gradient, favorable curvature due to
toroidal effects, and parallel dynamics, a similar Glasser-like effect is
found. We show that in both regimes the existence of tearing modes with complex
frequencies is related to nearby electrostatic resistive interchange modes with
complex frequencies. We discuss the effect on locking to an error field and the
significant lowering of the threshold for destabilization of resistive wall
tearing modes, which can be much more pronounced than the weak effect observed
for RI tearing modes without pressure-curvature drive in Finn and Gerwin, 1996.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04702</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kyeyune-Nyombi</keyname><forenames>Eru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morone</keyname><forenames>Flaviano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wenwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shuiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilchrist</keyname><forenames>M. Lane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makse</keyname><forenames>Hernan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-resolution of particle contacts via fluorophore exclusion in
  deep-imaging of jammed colloidal packings</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the structural properties of random packings of jammed colloids
requires an unprecedented high-resolution determination of the contact network
providing mechanical stability to the packing. Here, we address the
determination of the contact network by a novel strategy based on fluorophore
signal exclusion of quantum dot nanoparticles from the contact points. We use
fluorescence labeling schemes on particles inspired by biology and biointerface
science in conjunction with fluorophore exclusion at the contact region. The
method provides high-resolution contact network data that allows us to measure
structural properties of the colloidal packing near marginal stability. We
determine scaling laws of force distributions, soft modes, correlation
functions, coordination number and free volume that define the universality
class of jammed colloidal packings and can be compared with theoretical
predictions. The contact detection method opens up further experimental testing
at the interface of jamming and glass physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04724</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Keivani</keyname><forenames>Azadeh</forenames><affiliation>for the AMON core team</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ayala</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames><affiliation>for the AMON core team</affiliation></author><author><keyname>DeLaunay</keyname><forenames>James</forenames><affiliation>for the AMON core team</affiliation></author></authors><title>Astrophysical Multimessenger Observatory Network (AMON): Science,
  Infrastructure, and Status</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Proceedings of the 35th International Cosmic Ray Conference
  (ICRC2017), Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><journal-ref>PoS(ICRC2017)629</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The realization of multimessenger astrophysics will open new vistas upon the
most energetic events in the universe. Messenger particles of all four of
nature's fundamental forces, recorded by detectors on the ground and satellites
in space, enable coincidence searches for multimessenger phenomena that will
allow us to discover, observe, and explore these sources. The Astrophysical
Multimessenger Observatory Network (AMON) links multiple high-energy neutrino,
cosmic ray, and gamma-ray observatories as well as gravitational wave
facilities into a single virtual system, enabling near real-time coincidence
searches for multimessenger astrophysical transients and their electromagnetic
counterparts, and providing alerts to follow-up observatories. The science
case, design elements, partner observatories, and status of the AMON project
are presented, followed by recent results from AMON real-time and archival
analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04732</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04732</id><created>2017-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Narikiyo</keyname><forenames>Osamu</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral function method for Hall conductivity of incoherent metals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1204.5300</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics B, Vol. 31, No. 14 (2017)
  1750112</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217979217501120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a model spectral function of the electron the Hall conductivity in the
normal metallic state of the Pr_{2-x}Ce_xCuO_4 (PCCO) superconductor is
calculated neglecting the current vertex-correction. The result is
qualitatively consistent with the experiment. Consequently the reason becomes
clear why the Fermi-liquid theory fails to explain the anomaly of the Hall
conductivity. The inconsistency of the fluctuation-exchange approximation also
becomes clear.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04734</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04734</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fried</keyname><forenames>Stephen D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markland</keyname><forenames>Thomas E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Proton network flexibility enables robustness and large electric fields
  in the ketosteroid isomerase active site</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures (7 main text and 3 SI)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrogen bond networks play vital roles in biological functions ranging from
protein folding to enzyme catalysis. Here we combine electronic structure
calculations and ab initio path integral molecular dynamics simulations, which
incorporate both nuclear and electronic quantum effects, to show why the
network of short hydrogen bonds in the active site of ketosteroid isomerase is
remarkably robust to mutations along the network and how this gives rise to
large local electric fields. We demonstrate that these properties arise from
the network's ability to respond to a perturbation by shifting proton positions
and redistributing electronic charge density. This flexibility leads to small
changes in properties such as the partial ionization of residues and $pK_a$
isotope effects upon mutation of the residues, consistent with recent
experiments. This proton flexibility is further enhanced when an extended
hydrogen bond network forms in the presence of an intermediate analog, which
allows us to explain the chemical origins of the large electric fields in the
enzyme's active site observed in recent experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04752</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Quispe</keyname><forenames>H. Condori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bader</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chanana</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaudhuri</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nahata</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>H. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jena</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sensale-Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Terahertz spectroscopy of an electron-hole bilayer system in AlN/GaN/AlN
  quantum wells</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Applied Physics Letters</comments><journal-ref>APL 111(7), 073102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4996925</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe studies on the nanoscale transport dynamics of carriers in
strained AlN/GaN/AlN quantum wells: an electron-hole bilayer charge system with
large difference in transport properties between the two charge layers. From
electronic band diagram analysis, the presence of spatially separated
two-dimensional electron and hole charge layers is predicted at opposite
interfaces. Since these charge layers exhibit distinct spectral signatures at
terahertz frequencies, a combination of terahertz and far-infrared spectroscopy
enables us to extract (a) individual contributions to the total conductivity,
as well as (b) effective scattering rates for charge-carriers in each layer.
Furthermore, by comparing direct-current and terahertz extracted conductivity
levels, we are able to determine the extent to which structural defects affect
charge transport. Our results evidence that (i) a non-unity Hall-factor and
(ii) the considerable contribution of holes to the overall conductivity, lead
to a lower apparent mobility in Hall-effect measurements. Overall, our work
demonstrates that terahertz spectroscopy is a suitable technique for the study
of bilayer charge systems with large differences in transport properties
between layers, such as quantum wells in III-Nitride semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04761</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dao-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Xiang-hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xin-zhou</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive charged Dirac fields around Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om black holes:
  quasibound states and long-lived modes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in PRD</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The behavior of a massive charged test Dirac field in the background of a
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om black hole is investigated. Especially, we obtain the
frequencies of quasibound states by solving the Dirac equation numerically both
in time and frequency domain. Our results suggest that although the absence of
superradiance excludes the existence of stationary solutions for massive Dirac
fields, it is still possible to find arbitrarily long-lived solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04766</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Baojuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Teng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental Band Gap and Alignment of Two-Dimensional Semiconductors
  Explored by Machine Learning</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional (2D) semiconductors isoelectronic to phosphorene has been
drawing much attention recently due to their promising applications for
next-generation (opt)electronics. This family of 2D materials contains more
than 400 members, including (a) elemental group-V materials, (b) binary III-VII
and IV-VI compounds, (c) ternary III-VI-VII and IV-V-VII compounds, making
materials design with targeted functionality unprecedentedly rich and extremely
challenging. To shed light on rational functionality design with this family of
materials, we systemically explore their fundamental band gaps and alignments
using hybrid density functional theory (DFT) in combination with machine
learning. First, GGA-PBE and HSE calculations are performed as a reference. We
find this family of materials share similar crystalline structures, but possess
largely distributed band-gap values ranging approximately from 0 to 8 eV. Then,
we apply machine learning methods, including Linear Regression (LR), Random
Forest Regression (RFR), and Support Vector Machine Regression (SVR), to build
models for prediction of electronic properties. Among these models, SVR is
found to have the best performance, yielding the root mean square error (RMSE)
less than 0.15 eV for predicted band gaps, VBMs, and CBMs when both PBE results
and elemental information are used as features. Thus, we demonstrate machine
learning models are universally suitable for screening 2D isoelectronic systems
with targeted functionality and especially valuable for the design of alloys
and heterogeneous systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04769</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Sayan Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Aritra N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Biswajit</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum mechanics with space-time noncommutativity</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct an effective commutative Schr\&quot;odinger equation in Moyal
space-time in $(1+1)$-dimension where both $t$ and $x$ are operator-valued and
satisfy $\left[ \hat{t}, \hat{x} \right] = i \theta$. Beginning with a
time-reparametrised form of an action we identify the actions of various
space-time coordinates and their conjugate momenta on quantum states,
represented by Hilbert-Schmidt operators. Since time is also regarded as a
configuration space variable, we show how an `induced' inner product can be
extracted, so that an appropriate quantum mechanical interpretation is
obtained. We then discuss several other applications of the formalism developed
so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04786</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Sanjeeb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Suneel</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent Perfect Absorption: an electromagnetic perspective</title><categories>physics.optics physics.app-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple closed expression for determining the condition for
Coherent Perfect Absorption derived through electromagnetic wave treatment and
interface boundary conditions. Apart from providing physical insight this
expression can be used to estimate the values of various parameters required
for observation of coherent perfect absorption in a given medium characterized
by a complex dielectric constant. The results of the theoretical expression are
found to be in good agreement with those obtained through numerical
simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04810</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04810</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Vetere</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Namur</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgavi</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misiti</keyname><forenames>Valeria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mancinelli</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrelli</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauselli</keyname><forenames>Cristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perugini</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental constraints on the rheology, eruption and emplacement
  dynamics of analog lavas comparable to Mercury's northern volcanic plains</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Geophys. Res. Planets, 122, doi:10.1002/2016JE005181</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2016JE005181</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new viscosity measurements of a synthetic silicate system
considered an analogue for the lava erupted on the surface of Mercury. In
particular, we focus on the northern volcanic plains (NVP), which correspond to
the largest lava flows on Mercury and possibly in the Solar System.
High-temperature viscosity measurements were performed at both superliquidus
(up to 1736 K) and subliquidus conditions (1569-1502 K) to constrain the
viscosity variations as a function of crystallinity (from 0 to 28\%) and shear
rate (from 0.1 to 5 s 1). Melt viscosity shows moderate variations (4-16 Pa s)
in the temperature range of 1736-1600 K. Experiments performed below the
liquidus temperature show an increase in viscosity as shear rate decreases from
5 to 0.1 s 1, resulting in a shear thinning behavior, with a decrease in
viscosity of 1 log unit. The low viscosity of the studied composition may
explain the ability of NVP lavas to cover long distances, on the order of
hundreds of kilometers in a turbulent flow regime. Using our experimental data
we estimate that lava flows with thickness of 1, 5, and 10 m are likely to have
velocities of 4.8, 6.5, and 7.2 m/s, respectively, on a 5 degree ground slope.
Numerical modeling incorporating both the heat loss of the lavas and its
possible crystallization during emplacement allows us to infer that high
effusion rates (&gt;10,000 m3/s) are necessary to cover the large distances
indicated by satellite data from the MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment,
GEochemistry, and Ranging spacecraft.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04817</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balbo</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagiotou</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermi acceleration under control: $\eta$ Carinae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Proceedings of ICRC 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We used data from the Fermi Large Area Telescope obtained during the last 7
years and spanning two passages of $\eta$ Carinae at periastron and compared
them with the predictions of particle acceleration in hydrodynamic simulations.
Two emission components can be distinguished. The low-energy component cuts off
below 10 GeV and its flux, modulated by the orbital motion, varies by a factor
less than 2. Short-term variability occurs at periastron. The flux of the high
energy component varies by a factor 3-4 but differently during the two
periastrons. The variabilities observed at low-energy, including some details
of them, and these observed at high-energy during the first half of the
observations, do match the prediction of the simulation, assuming a surface
magnetic field in the range 0.4-1 kG. The high-energy component and the thermal
X-ray emission were weaker than expected around the second periastron
suggesting a modification of the wind density in the inner wind collision zone.
Diffuse shock acceleration in the complex geometry of the wind collision zone
of $\eta$ Carinae provides a convincing match to the observations and new
diagnostic tools to probe the geometry and energetics of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04825</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Leal</keyname><forenames>Allan M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulik</keyname><forenames>Dmitrii A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saar</keyname><forenames>Martin O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-Fast Reactive Transport Simulations When Chemical Reactions Meet
  Machine Learning: Chemical Equilibrium</title><categories>math.OC physics.chem-ph physics.flu-dyn stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During reactive transport modeling, the computational cost associated with
chemical reaction calculations is often 10-100 times higher than that of
transport calculations. Most of these costs results from chemical equilibrium
calculations that are performed at least once in every mesh cell and at every
time step of the simulation. Calculating chemical equilibrium is an iterative
process, where each iteration is in general so computationally expensive that
even if every calculation converged in a single iteration, the resulting
speedup would not be significant. Thus, rather than proposing a fast-converging
numerical method for solving chemical equilibrium equations, we present a
machine learning method that enables new equilibrium states to be quickly and
accurately estimated, whenever a previous equilibrium calculation with similar
input conditions has been performed. We demonstrate the use of this smart
chemical equilibrium method in a reactive transport modeling example and show
that, even at early simulation times, the majority of all equilibrium
calculations are quickly predicted and, after some time steps, the
machine-learning-accelerated chemical solver has been fully trained to rapidly
perform all subsequent equilibrium calculations, resulting in speedups of
almost two orders of magnitude. We remark that our new on-demand machine
learning method can be applied to any case in which a massive number of
sequential/parallel evaluations of a computationally expensive function $f$
needs to be done, $y=f(x)$. We remark, that, in contrast to traditional machine
learning algorithms, our on-demand training approach does not require a
statistics-based training phase before the actual simulation of interest
commences. The introduced on-demand training scheme requires, however, the
first-order derivatives $\partial f/\partial x$ for later smart predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04830</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gottowik</keyname><forenames>Marvin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glaser</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huege</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rautenberg</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling uncertainty of the radiation energy emitted by extensive air
  showers</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, ICRC2017 contribution</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the energy determination of extensive air showers using radio
emission has been shown to be both precise and accurate. In particular, radio
detection offers the opportunity for an independent measurement of the absolute
energy of cosmic rays, since the radiation energy (the energy radiated in the
form of radio signals) can be predicted using first-principle calculations
involving no free parameters, and the measurement of radio waves is not subject
to any significant absorption or scattering in the atmosphere. Here, we verify
the implementation of radiation-energy calculations from microscopic simulation
codes by comparing Monte Carlo simulations made with the two codes CoREAS and
ZHAireS. To isolate potential differences in the radio-emission calculation
from differences in the air-shower simulation, the simulations are performed
with equivalent settings, especially the same model for the hadronic
interactions and the description of the atmosphere. Comparing a large set of
simulations with different primary energies and shower directions we observe
differences amounting to a total of only 3.3 %. This corresponds to an
uncertainty of only 1.6 % in the determination of the absolute energy scale and
thus opens the potential of using the radiation energy as an accurate
calibration method for cosmic ray experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04839</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Arvapalli</keyname><forenames>Sai Srikanth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Talluri</keyname><forenames>Bhusankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anbalagan</keyname><forenames>Kousika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Tiju</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of pinning mechanism in co-precipitation derived cobalt rich,
  cobalt ferrite nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cobalt ferrite nanoparticles have been synthesized using a co-precipitation
approach. Co:Fe precursor ratio is varied over a certain window (1.05 to 1.2).
It is observed that the 1.15:2 precursor ratio gives better phase control but
poor coercivity. On the other hand, 1.05:2 precursor ratio results in
substantially better coercivity values (274kA/m; almost 300% the value reported
for co-precipitated cobalt ferrite by Praveena et al.), but moderate BH product
maximum (2.25 kJ/m3; ~ comparable to many reports on cobalt ferrite
nanoparticles so far). The nanoparticles with best coercivity are annealed at
873K for varying durations (2, 4, 6, 12 hrs). It is observed that the
coercivity drops drastically (almost by 80%) after annealing for 2 hours.
However thereafter coercivity and saturation magnetization improves marginally
with increasing duration of annealing. These studies, along with
thermogravimetric analysis, and infrared spectroscopic results indicate that a
hydroxide nanophase based flux pinning mechanism at the grain boundary plays an
important role in explaining the observed magnetic property trends. It is
believed that this result will be generically helpful in developing soft
chemically derived ferrites with higher coercivity and moderate (BH)max.
However to develop plausible applications using the reported ferrites that use
nanophase flux pinning, soft materials and device processing methods will need
to be explored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04842</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Morlino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blasi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Contribution to diffuse gamma-ray emission coming from self-confined CRs
  around their Galactic sources</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figs. Proceeding the 35th International Cosmic Ray
  Conference (ICRC2017), Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent observations of the diffuse Galactic gamma-ray emission by the
Fermi-LAT satellite have shown significant deviations from models which assume
the same diffusion properties for cosmic rays (CR) throughout the Galaxy. We
explore the possibility that a fraction of this diffuse Galactic emission could
be due to hadronic interactions of CRs self-confined in the region around their
sources. In fact, freshly accelerated CRs that diffuse away from the
acceleration region can trigger the streaming instability able to amplify
magnetic disturbance and to reduce the particle diffusion. When this happen,
CRs are trapped in the near source region for a time longer than expected and
an extended gamma-ray halo is produces around each source. Here we calculate
the contribution to the diffuse gamma-ray background due to the overlap along
lines of sight of several of these extended halos. We find that if the density
of neutrals is low, the halos can account for a substantial fraction of the
diffuse emission observed by Fermi-LAT, depending on the orientation of the
line of sight with respect to the direction of the galactic center.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04847</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>I.</keyname><forenames>Man'ko V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>A</keyname><forenames>Markovich L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unnormalized quasi-distributions and tomograms of quantum states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tomograms and quasi-distribution functions like Wigner, Glauber - Sudarshan
$P$- and Husimi $Q$- functions that violate the standard normalization
condition are considered. Conditions under which a reconstruction of the
density matrix using these tomograms and quasi-distribution functions is
possible are obtained. Three different examples of states like the de Broglie
plane wave, the Moschinsky shutter problem and the stationary state of the
charged particle in the uniform and constant electric field are studied. Their
tomograms and quasi-distribution functions expressed in terms of the Dirac
delta function, the Airy function and the Fresnel integrals are shown to
violate the standard normalization condition and thus the density matrix of the
state can not always be reconstructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04852</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Jakiela</keyname><forenames>Rafal</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex diffusion mechanism of Zn in InP</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Implantation and diffusion of Zn dopant into bulk InP:S were performed. Zn
concentration profiles were investigated by secondary ion mass spectrometry and
capacitance-voltage method. We find that thermodynamic conditions of annealing
influence diffusion mechanism of Zn atoms. Excess phosphorus vacancies
generation causes diffusion of Zn dopant by the complex [V_{P}-Zn_{In}-V_{P}]
producing characteristic diffusion profile with the sharp slope. Such
electrically inactive Zn configuration cause lower diffusion coefficient than
that in the generally known interstitial-substitutional mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04920</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Haibin</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical wave splitting due to transient energy convection between the
  pump and Stokes waves in stimulated Brillouin scattering</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>20 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we prove theoretically that both the stimulated Stokes
scattering and its reverse process can occur simultaneously for the light and
acoustic waves at different points of the medium, resulting in transient and
alternate energy flow between the pump and Stokes waves in the stimulated
Brillouin scattering. Furthermore, it is found that stimulated Stokes
scattering and its reverse process will dominate alternately on the whole
during the three-wave coupling, but the eventual net energy flow must be from
the pump wave to the Stokes wave as a result of the finite lifetime of
acoustical phonons. It is also deduced that direction of energy flow between
the pump and Stokes waves will turn to the opposite side once any one of the
three waves experiences a ${\pi}$-phase shift. Consequently, we present that
transient energy convection between the pump and Stokes waves can give rise to
optical wave splitting for the output pump and Stokes pulses, and is also
responsible for the generation of Brillouin solitons because energy reflux can
provide additional dissipation for the Stokes and acoustic waves to achieve the
gain-loss balance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04930</id><created>2017-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Weizhe Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hankiewicz</keyname><forenames>Ewelina M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Culcer</keyname><forenames>Dimitrie</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak Localization and Antilocalization in Topological Materials with
  Impurity Spin-Orbit Interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1705.07612</comments><journal-ref>Materials 10, 807 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/ma10070807</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological materials have attracted considerable experimental and
theoretical attention. They exhibit strong spin-orbit coupling both in the band
structure (intrinsic) and in the impurity potentials (extrinsic), although the
latter is often neglected. Here we discuss weak localization and
antilocalization of massless Dirac fermions in topological insulators and
massive Dirac fermions in Weyl semimetal thin films taking into account both
intrinsic and extrinsic spin-orbit interactions. The physics is governed by the
complex interplay of the chiral spin texture, quasiparticle mass, and scalar
and spin-orbit scattering. We demonstrate that terms linear in the extrinsic
spin-orbit scattering are generally present in the Bloch and momentum
relaxation times in all topological materials, and the correction to the
diffusion constant is linear in the strength of the extrinsic spin-orbit. In
TIs, which have zero quasiparticle mass, the terms linear in the impurity
spin-orbit coupling lead to an observable density dependence in the weak
antilocalization correction. They produce substantial qualitative modifications
to the magnetoconductivity, differing greatly from the conventional HLN formula
traditionally used in experimental fits, which predicts a crossover from weak
localization to antilocalization as a function of the extrinsic spin-orbit
strength. In contrast, our analysis reveals that topological insulators always
exhibit weak antilocalization. In WSM thin films having intermediate to large
values of the quasiparticle mass extrinsic spin-orbit scattering strongly
affects the boundary of the weak localization to antilocalization transition.
We produce a complete phase diagram for this transition as a function of the
mass and spin-orbit scattering strength. We discuss implications for
experiments and provide a brief comparison with transition metal
dichalcogenides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04940</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peeters</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Duppen</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-component plasmons in monolayer MoS$_2$ with circularly polarized
  optical pumping</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 085405 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.085405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By making use of circularly polarized light and electrostatic gating,
monolayer molybdenum disulfide (ML-MoS$_2$) can form a platform supporting
multiple types of charge carriers. They can be discriminated by their spin,
valley index or whether they're electrons or holes. We investigate the
collective properties of those charge carriers and are able to identify new
distinct plasmon modes. We analyze the corresponding dispersion relation,
lifetime and oscillator strength, and calculate the phase relation between the
oscillations in the different components of the plasmon modes. All platforms in
ML-MoS$_2$ support a long-wavelength $\sqrt{q}$ plasmon branch at zero Kelvin.
In addition to this, for an $n$-component system, $n-1$ distinct plasmon modes
appear as acoustic modes with linear dispersion in the long-wavelength limit.
These modes correspond to out-of-phase oscillations in the different Fermion
liquids and have, although being damped, a relatively long lifetime.
Additionally, we also find new distinct modes at large wave vector that are
stronger damped by intra-band processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04967</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kar</keyname><forenames>Payel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>The VERITAS</forenames></author></authors><title>VERITAS Observations of High-Mass X-Ray Binary SS 433</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, ICRC 2017 (Bexco, Busan, S Korea)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite decades of observations across all wavebands and dedicated
theoretical modelling, the SS 433 system still poses many questions, especially
in the high-energy range. SS 433 is a high-mass X-ray binary at a distance of
$\sim 5.5$ kpc, with a stellar mass black hole in a $13$ day orbit around a
supergiant $\sim$A7Ib star. SS 433 is unusual because it contains dual
relativistic jets with evidence of high-energy hadronic particles. X-ray
emission is seen from the central source as well as the jet termination
regions, where the eastern and western jets interact with the surrounding
interstellar medium. Very-high-energy gamma-ray emission is predicted both from
the central source and multiple smaller regions in the jets. This emission
could be detectable by current generation imaging atmospheric-Cherenkov
telescopes like VERITAS. VERITAS has observed the extended region around SS 433
for $\sim 70$ hours during 2009-2012. No significant emission was detected
either from the location of the black hole or the jet termination regions. We
report 99\% confidence level flux upper limits above 600 GeV for these regions
in the range $(1-10) \times 10^{-13} \mathrm{cm^{-2} \ s^{-1}}$. A phase
resolved analysis also does not reveal any significant emission from the
extended SS 433 region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04979</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Khrapak</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klumov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couedel</keyname><forenames>Lenaic</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective modes in simple melts: Transition from soft spheres to the
  hard sphere limit</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph physics.flu-dyn physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Full text access to the paper using the link: http://rdcu.be/uVRO</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 7985 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-08429-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study collective modes in a classical system of particles with repulsive
inverse-power-law (IPL) interactions in the fluid phase, near the fluid-solid
coexistence (IPL melts). The IPL exponent is varied from $n=10$ to $n=100$ to
mimic the transition from moderately soft to hard-sphere-like interactions. We
compare the longitudinal dispersion relations obtained using molecular dynamic
(MD) simulations with those calculated using the quasi-crystalline
approximation (QCA) and find that this simple theoretical approach becomes
grossly inaccurate for $n\gtrsim 20$. Similarly, conventional expressions for
high-frequency (instantaneous) elastic moduli, predicting their divergence as
$n$ increases, are meaningless in this regime. Relations of the longitudinal
and transverse elastic velocities of the QCA model to the adiabatic sound
velocity, measured in MD simulations, are discussed for the regime where QCA is
applicable. Two potentially useful freezing indicators for classical particle
systems with steep repulsive interactions are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04992</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Anguelova</keyname><forenames>Iana I.</forenames></author></authors><title>The two bosonizations of the CKP hierarchy: overview and character
  identities</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>25 pages. Contribution to the Proceedings of the AMS Special Session
  on Representations of Lie Algebras, Quantum Groups and Related Topics, edited
  by Kailash Misra and Naihuan Jing</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the Hirota bilinear equation for the CKP hierarchy introduced by
Date, Jimbo, Kashiwara and Miwa in J. Phys. Soc. Japan. 50(11), 3813-3818
(1981), and its algebraic properties. We review in parallel the two
bosonizations of the CKP hierarchy: one arising from a twisted Heisenberg
algebra (van de Leur, Orlov and Shiota, SIGMA 8, 28 (2012)), and the second
from an untwisted Heisenberg algebra (Anguelova, J. Math. Phys. 58(7), 071707
(2017)). In particular, we recount the decompositions into irreducible
Heisenberg modules and the (twisted) fermionic structures of the spaces spanned
by the highest weight vectors under the two Heisenberg actions. We show that
the two bosonizations give rise to four different diagonalizable grading
operators on the CKP Fock space, not all of them commuting among each other. We
compute the various graded dimensions related to these four grading operators.
We prove a sum-vs-product identity relating the bosonic vs fermionic
descriptions under the untwisted Heisenberg action, utilizing the charge and
the degree grading operators. As a corollary, the resulting identities relate
the CKP hierarchy, the Dyson crank of a partition and the Hammond-Lewis birank
of a distinct integer bipartition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04997</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciobanu</keyname><forenames>Tudor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear hydrodynamics, momentum relaxation, and the KSS bound</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>1 + 19 pages + references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate the behavior of the shear hydrodynamic response
functions in a simple holographic model exhibiting momentum relaxation. We
compute several stress tensor response functions in the transverse channel, and
from there derive the ratio of shear viscosity to entropy density, $\eta/s$,
using two different methods. The two values differ from each other, one which
satisfies the KSS bound $\eta/s \geq \frac{1}{4\pi}$ and one which does not,
and we discuss the causes and implications of this result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05000</id><created>2017-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Pekkola</keyname><forenames>Oili</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lungenschmied</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fejes</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Handreck</keyname><forenames>Anke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hermes</keyname><forenames>Wilfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irle</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lennartz</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schildknecht</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schillen</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindler</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Send</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valouch</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiel</keyname><forenames>Erwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruder</keyname><forenames>Ingmar</forenames></author></authors><title>Focus-Induced Photoresponse: a novel optoelectronic distance measurement
  technique</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the Focus-Induced Photoresponse (FIP) technique, a novel approach
to optical distance measurement. It takes advantage of a widely-observed
phenomenon in photodetector devices: a nonlinear, irradiance-dependent
photoresponse. This means that the output from a sensor is dependent on the
total number of photons incident and the size of the area in which they fall.
With a certain arrangement of sensor and lens, this phenomenon will cause the
output of the sensor to change based on how far in or out of focus an object
is. We call this the FIP effect. Here we demonstrate how to use the FIP effect
for distance measurements. We show that this technique works with different
sensor materials, device types, as well as visible and near infrared light. In
principle, any sensor exhibiting a photoresponse that depends nonlinearly on
irradiance could be used with the FIP technique. It is our belief that the FIP
technique can become an important method for measuring distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/9809023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/9809023</id><created>1998-09-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Holevo</keyname><forenames>Alexander S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coding Theorems for Quantum Channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, Latex, eps figure. Extended version of report appeared in
  &quot;Tamagawa University Research Review&quot;, no. 4, 1998</comments><journal-ref>Russian Math. Surveys, vol.53, no.6 (1998), 1295-1331</journal-ref><doi>10.1070/RM1998v053n06ABEH000091</doi><abstract>  The more than thirty years old issue of the (classical) information capacity
of quantum communication channels was dramatically clarified during the last
years, when a number of direct quantum coding theorems was discovered. The
present paper gives a self contained treatment of the subject, following as
much in parallel as possible with classical information theory and, on the
other side, stressing profound differences of the quantum case. An emphasis is
made on recent results, such as general quantum coding theorems including cases
of infinite (possibly continuous) alphabets and constrained inputs, reliability
function for pure state channels and quantum Gaussian channel. Several still
unsolved problems are briefly outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
