<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:43:23Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-08-28" from="2017-08-28" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.4705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.4705</id><created>2013-04-17</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>W-Y. Pauchy</forenames></author></authors><title>The Standard Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We declare that we live in the quantum 4-dimensional Minkowski space-time
with, via the gauge principle, the force-fields gauge-group structure, $SU_c(3)
\times SU_L(2) \times U(1)$ applied to the quark world or $SU_L(2) \times U(1)
\times SU_f(3)$ applied to the lepton world, built-in from the very beginning.
The quark world with the triplets from the &quot;quark&quot; group $SU_Q(3)$ (used to be
called &quot;flavor $SU(3)$ symmetry&quot;), which is of nuclear sizes and is protected
by $SU_c(3) \times SU_L(2) \times U(1)$ (i.e. the (123) symmetry), can be seen
by our world, while the lepton world, as of atomic sizes and protected by
$SU_L(2) \times U(1) \times SU_f(3)$ or another (123) symmetry, can also be
seen, as singlets of the quark group $SU_Q(3)$, by our world. Apart from the
&quot;ignition&quot; term, the entire Standard Model is dimensionless and massless in the
quantum 4-dimensional Minkowski space-time; that is, all couplings are
dimensionless and there are no mass terms in the quantum 4-dimensional
Minkowski space-time.
  Therefore, there exist the well-studied $3^\circ \,K$ cosmic microwave
background (CMB) and the now clustered neutrino halos formed from cosmic
background (CB) neutrinos (of three flavors, and antineutrinos), both present
in the overall background of our Universe. In theory, it yields neutrino
oscillations, as some lepton-flavor-violating processes, in a natural manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1075</id><created>2014-03-05</created><updated>2015-01-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frasca</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical proof of existence of fractional powers of Wiener processes</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures and source code. Changed the title for the sake
  of correctness</comments><journal-ref>Signal, Image and Video Processing, 11(7), 1365-1370 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11760-017-1094-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the Euler--Maruyama technique, we show that a class of Wiener processes
exist that are obtained by computing an arbitrary positive power of them. This
can be accomplished with a proper set of definitions that makes meaningful the
realization at discrete times of these processes and make them computable.
Standard results from It\=o calculus for integer powers hold as we are just
extending them. We provide the results from a Monte Carlo simulation with a
large number of samples. We yield evidence for the existence of these processes
by recovering from them the standard Brownian motion we started with after
power elevation. The perfect coincidence of the numerical results we obtained
is a clear evidence of existence of these processes. This could pave the way to
a generalization of the concepts of stochastic integral and relative process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.2602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.2602</id><created>2014-07-10</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weizman</keyname><forenames>Lior</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eldar</keyname><forenames>Yonina C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bashat</keyname><forenames>Dafna Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>Compressed sensing for longitudinal MRI: An adaptive-weighted approach</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.CV</categories><doi>10.1118/1.4928148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: Repeated brain MRI scans are performed in many clinical scenarios,
such as follow up of patients with tumors and therapy response assessment. In
this paper, the authors show an approach to utilize former scans of the patient
for the acceleration of repeated MRI scans.
  Methods: The proposed approach utilizes the possible similarity of the
repeated scans in longitudinal MRI studies. Since similarity is not guaranteed,
sampling and reconstruction are adjusted during acquisition to match the actual
similarity between the scans. The baseline MR scan is utilized both in the
sampling stage, via adaptive sampling, and in the reconstruction stage, with
weighted reconstruction. In adaptive sampling, k-space sampling locations are
optimized during acquisition. Weighted reconstruction uses the locations of the
nonzero coefficients in the sparse domains as a prior in the recovery process.
The approach was tested on 2D and 3D MRI scans of patients with brain tumors.
  Results: The longitudinal adaptive CS MRI (LACS-MRI) scheme provides
reconstruction quality which outperforms other CS-based approaches for rapid
MRI. Examples are shown on patients with brain tumors and demonstrate improved
spatial resolution. Compared with data sampled at Nyquist rate, LACS-MRI
exhibits Signal-to-Error Ratio (SER) of 24.8dB with undersampling factor of
16.6 in 3D MRI.
  Conclusions: The authors have presented a novel method for image
reconstruction utilizing similarity of scans in longitudinal MRI studies, where
possible. The proposed approach can play a major part and significantly reduce
scanning time in many applications that consist of disease follow-up and
monitoring of longitudinal changes in brain MRI.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.0998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.0998</id><created>2014-12-02</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Strambini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeret</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giazotto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mesoscopic Josephson junctions with switchable current-phase relation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4.5 pages, 5 color figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 112 (2015) 17013</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/112/17013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and analyze a mesoscopic Josephson junction consisting of two
ferromagnetic insulator-superconductors (FI-Ss) coupled through a normal metal
(N) layer. The Josephson current of the junction is non-trivially affected by
the spin-splitting field induced by the FIs in the two superconductors. In
particular, it shows sizeable enhancement by increasing the amplitude of the
exchange field ($h_{ex}$) and displays a switchable current-phase relation
which depends on the relative orientation of $h_{ex}$ in the FIs. In a
realistic EuS/Al-based setup this junction can be exploited as a
high-resolution threshold sensor for the magnetic field as well as an on-demand
tunable kinetic inductor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02775</id><created>2015-08-11</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weizman</keyname><forenames>Lior</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eldar</keyname><forenames>Yonina C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ben-Basaht</keyname><forenames>Dafna</forenames></author></authors><title>Reference-Based MRI</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><doi>10.1118/1.4962032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: In many clinical MRI scenarios, existing imaging information can be
used to significantly shorten acquisition time or to improve Signal to Noise
Ratio (SNR). In this paper the authors present a framework for fast MRI by
exploiting a reference image (FASTMER).
  Methods: The proposed approach utilizes the possible similarity of the
reference image that exists in many clinical MRI imaging scenarios. Such
scenarios include similarity between adjacent slices in high resolution MRI,
similarity between various contrasts in the same scan and similarity between
different scans of the same patient. The authors take into account that the
reference image may exhibit low similarity with the acquired image and develop
an iterative weighted approach for reconstruction, which tunes the weights
according to the degree of similarity.
  Results: Experimental results demonstrate the performance of the method in
three different clinical MRI scenarios: SNR improvement in high resolution
brain MRI, exploiting similarity between T2-weighted and fluid-attenuated
inversion recovery (FLAIR) for fast FLAIR scanning and utilizing similarity
between baseline and follow-up scans for fast follow-up. Results outperform
reconstruction results of existing state-of-the-art methods.
  Conclusions: The authors present a method for fast MRI by exploiting a
reference image. The method is based on an iterative reconstruction approach
that supports cases in which similarity to the reference scan is not
guaranteed, which enables the applicability of the method to a variety of MRI
applications. Thanks to the existence of reference images in various clinical
imaging scenarios, the proposed framework can play a major part in improving
reconstruction in many MR applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03678</id><created>2015-09-11</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roberto</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author></authors><title>The Spatial Proximity and Connectivity (SPC) Method for Measuring and
  Analyzing Residential Segregation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI stat.ME</categories><comments>32 pages, 12 figures, LaTeX</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, there has been increasing attention to the spatial
dimensions of residential segregation, such as the spatial arrangement of
segregated neighborhoods and the geographic scale or relative size of
segregated areas. However, the methods used to measure segregation do not
incorporate features of the built environment, such as the road connectivity
between locations or the physical barriers that divide groups. This article
introduces the Spatial Proximity and Connectivity (SPC) method for measuring
and analyzing segregation. The SPC method addresses the limitations of current
approaches by taking into account how the physical structure of the built
environment affects the proximity and connectivity of locations. In this
article, I describe the method and its application for studying segregation and
spatial inequality more broadly. I demonstrate one such application-analyzing
the impact of physical barriers on residential segregation-with a stylized
example and an empirical analysis of racial segregation in Pittsburgh, PA. The
SPC method contributes to scholarship on residential segregation by capturing
the effect of an important yet understudied mechanism of segregation-the
connectivity, or physical barriers, between locations-on the level and spatial
pattern of segregation, and enables further consideration of the role of the
built environment in segregation processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02624</id><created>2015-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Salikhov</keyname><forenames>Ruslan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichel</keyname><forenames>Ludwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zingsem</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;mer</keyname><forenames>Florian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abrudan</keyname><forenames>Radu-Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusz</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eriksson</keyname><forenames>Olle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schultz</keyname><forenames>Ludwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xe4;hler</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farle</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedwald</keyname><forenames>Ulf</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced and Tunable Spin-Orbit Coupling in Tetragonally Strained
  Fe-Co-B Films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter, Vol. 29, 27 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa7498</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have synthesized 20 nm thick films of tetragonally strained interstitial
Fe-Co-B alloys epitaxially grown on Au55Cu45 buffer layer. The strained axis is
perpendicular to the film plane and the corresponding lattice constant c is
enlarged with respect to the in-plane lattice parameter a. By adding the
interstitial boron with different concentrations 0, 4, and 10 at.% we were able
to stabilize the tetragonal strain in 20 nm Fe-Co films with different c/a
ratios of 1.013, 1.034 and 1.02, respectively. Using ferromagnetic resonance
(FMR) and x-ray magnetic circular dichroism (XMCD) we found that the orbital
magnetic moment increases with increasing the c/a ratio, pointing towards the
enhancement of spin-orbit coupling (SOC) at larger strain. Our results show
that careful doping of ferromagnetic films allows to control the SOC by
stabilizing anisotropic strain states. These findings are applicable in
material design for spintronics applications. We also discuss the influence of
B doping on the Fe-Co film microstructure, its magnetic properties and magnetic
relaxation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00001</id><created>2015-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Chunling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Anmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational time dilation induced decoherence during spontaneous
  emission</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7pages,4figures</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters B Vol. 31, No. 23 (2017) 1750214</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217984917502141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate decoherence of quantum superpositions induced by gravitational
time dilation and spontaneous emission between two atomic levels. It has been
shown that gravitational time dilation can be an universal decoherence source.
Here, we consider decoherence induced by gravitational time dilation only in
the situation of spontaneous emission. Then, we obtain that the coherence of
particle's position state depends on reference frame due to the time dilation
changing the distinguishability of emission photon from two positions of
particle. Changing the direction of light field can also result in the
difference about the coherence of quantum superpositions. For observing the
decoherence effect mainly due to gravitational time dilation, time-delayed
feedback can be utilized to increase the decoherence of particle's
superpositions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05738</id><created>2015-11-18</created><updated>2017-07-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Suen</keyname><forenames>Whei Yeap</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>Jayne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garner</keyname><forenames>Andrew J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedral</keyname><forenames>Vlatko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Mile</forenames></author></authors><title>The classical-quantum divergence of complexity in modelling spin chains</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.PR</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, comments are welcome</comments><doi>10.22331/q-2017-08-11-25</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The minimal memory required to model a given stochastic process - known as
the statistical complexity - is a widely adopted quantifier of structure in
complexity science. Here, we ask if quantum mechanics can fundamentally change
the qualitative behaviour of this measure. We study this question in the
context of the classical Ising spin chain. In this system, the statistical
complexity is known to grow monotonically with temperature. We evaluate the
spin chain's quantum mechanical statistical complexity by explicitly
constructing its provably simplest quantum model, and demonstrate that this
measure exhibits drastically different behaviour: it rises to a maximum at some
finite temperature then tends back towards zero for higher temperatures. This
demonstrates how complexity, as captured by the amount of memory required to
model a process, can exhibit radically different behaviour when quantum
processing is allowed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00582</id><created>2015-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yuntian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenderink</keyname><forenames>A. Femius</forenames></author></authors><title>General point dipole theory for periodic metasurfaces: magnetoelectric
  scattering lattices coupled to planar photonic structures</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figure</comments><journal-ref>Optics express 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.021358</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study semi-analytically the light emission and absorption properties of
arbitrary stratified photonic structures with embedded two-dimensional
magnetoelectric point scattering lattices, as used in recent plasmon-enhanced
LEDs and solar cells. By employing dyadic Green's function for the layered
structure in combination with Ewald lattice summation to deal with the particle
lattice, we develop an efficient method to study the coupling between planar 2D
scattering lattices of plasmonic, or metamaterial point particles, coupled to
layered structures. Using the `array scanning method' we deal with localized
sources. Firstly, we apply our method to light emission enhancement of dipole
emitters in slab waveguides, mediated by plasmonic lattices. We benchmark the
array scanning method against a reciprocity-based approach to find that the
calculated radiative rate enhancement in k-space below the light cone shows
excellent agreement. Secondly, we apply our method to study
absorption-enhancement in thin-film solar cells mediated by periodic Ag
nanoparticle arrays. Lastly, we study the emission distribution in k-space of a
coupled waveguide-lattice system. In particular, we explore the dark mode
excitation on the plasmonic lattice using the so-called Array Scanning Method.
Our method could be useful for simulating a broad range of complex nanophotonic
structures, i.e., metasurfaces, plasmon-enhanced light emitting systems and
photovoltaics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09130</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiodaroli</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunaydin</keyname><forenames>Murat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roiban</keyname><forenames>Radu</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete construction of magical, symmetric and homogeneous N=2
  supergravities as double copies of gauge theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, PDFLaTex, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 011603 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.011603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that scattering amplitudes in magical, symmetric or homogeneous N=2
Maxwell-Einstein supergravities can be obtained as double copies of two gauge
theories, using the framework of color/kinematics duality. The left-hand-copy
is N=2 super-Yang-Mills theory coupled to a hypermultiplet, whereas the
right-hand-copy is a non-supersymmetric theory that can be identified as the
dimensional reduction of a D-dimensional Yang-Mills theory coupled to P
fermions. For generic D and P, the double copy gives homogeneous
supergravities. For P=1 and D=7,8,10,14, it gives the magical supergravities.
We compute explicit amplitudes, discuss their soft limit and study the
UV-behavior at one loop.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08216</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-02-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malyshev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyakova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Very high energy Fermi/LAT detection of HESS J0632+057</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Typo corrected</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2173</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the results of ~7 yrs of the very-high energy (10-600 GeV)
observations of HESS J0632+057 with FERMI/LAT. In the highest energy band,
200-600 GeV, the source is clearly detected with the statistical significance
&gt;3.6sigma at orbital phases 0.2-0.4 and 0.6-0.8 at which HESS J0632+057 is
known to demonstrate enhanced emission in TeV energy band. The analysis did not
reveal the emission from HESS J0632+057 at lower energies and different orbital
phases. Using the upper limits on source's flux we locate the break of the
spectrum to &gt;80 GeV and low-energy slope &lt;2.0 (2sigma statistical
significance).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07968</id><created>2016-03-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Giakoumaki</keyname><forenames>Argyro N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenanakis</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klini</keyname><forenames>Argyro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viskadourakis</keyname><forenames>Zacharias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farsari</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selimis</keyname><forenames>Alexandros</forenames></author></authors><title>Architecting three-dimensional ZnO nanorods</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-02231-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fabrication of nanostructures with controlled assembly and architecture
is significant for the development of novel nanomaterials-based devices. In
this work we demonstrate that laser techniques coupled with low-temperature
hydrothermal growth enable complex three-dimensional ZnO nanorods patterning on
various types of substrates and geometries. The suggested methodology is based
on a procedure involving the 3D scaffold fabrication using Multi-Photon
Lithography of a photosensitive material, followed by Zn seeded Aqueous
Chemical Growth of ZnO nanorods. 3D, uniformly aligned ZnO nanorods are
produced, exhibiting electrical conductance and highly efficient photocatalytic
performance, providing a path to applications in a diverse field of
technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01587</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin-he</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular Momentum-Free of the Entropy Relations for Rotating Kaluza-Klein
  Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Final version, accepted for publication by International Journal of
  Theoretical Physics</comments><journal-ref>Int.J.Theor.Phys. 56 (2017) no.2, 437-449</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-016-3185-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on a mathematical lemma related to the Vandermonde determinant and two
theorems derived from the first law of black hole thermodynamics, we
investigate the angular momentum independence of the entropy sum as well as the
entropy product of general rotating Kaluza-Klein black holes in higher
dimensions. We show that for both non-charged rotating Kaluza-Klein black holes
and non-charged rotating Kaluza-Klein-AdS black holes, the angular momentum of
the black holes will not be present in entropy sum relation in dimensions
$d\geq4$, while the independence of angular momentum of the entropy product
holds provided that the black holes possess at least one zero rotation
parameter $a_j$ = 0 in higher dimensions $d\geq5$, which means that the
cosmological constant does not affect the angular momentum-free property of
entropy sum and entropy product under the circumstances that charge $\delta=0$.
For the reason that the entropy relations of charged rotating Kaluza-Klein
black holes as well as the non-charged rotating Kaluza-Klein black holes in
asymptotically flat spacetime act the same way, it is found that the charge has
no effect in the angular momentum-independence of entropy sum and product in
asymptotically flat spactime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04783</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>Li-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawamoto</keyname><forenames>Shoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Wen-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic uncertainty relation based on generalized uncertainty principle</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures; Ver 2, references and a new discussion based on
  an auxiliary momentum are added; Ver. 3, references updated. Final version to
  appear in Mod. Phys. Lett. A</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 28 (2017) 1750145</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317501450</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the modification of the entropic formulation of uncertainty
principle in quantum mechanics which measures the incompatibility of
measurements in terms of Shannon entropy. The deformation in question is the
type so called generalized uncertainty principle that is motivated by thought
experiments in quantum gravity and string theory and is characterized by a
parameter of Planck scale. The corrections are evaluated for small deformation
parameters by use of the Gaussian wave function and numerical calculation. As
the generalized uncertainty principle has proven to be useful in the study of
the quantum nature of black holes, this study would be a step toward
introducing an information theory viewpoint to black hole physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00919</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Raymond</keyname><forenames>Jack</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarkoni</keyname><forenames>Sheir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andriyash</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author></authors><title>Global warming: Temperature estimation in annealers</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech stat.AP</categories><comments>28 pages, 14 figures ; supplementary materials 18 pages, 5 figures
  [v4: updated supplementary material file correcting broken references]</comments><journal-ref>Frontiers in ICT 3 , 23 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3389/fict.2016.00023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sampling from a Boltzmann distribution is NP-hard and so requires heuristic
approaches. Quantum annealing is one promising candidate. The failure of
annealing dynamics to equilibrate on practical time scales is a well understood
limitation, but does not always prevent a heuristically useful distribution
from being generated. In this paper we evaluate several methods for determining
a useful operational temperature range for annealers. We show that, even where
distributions deviate from the Boltzmann distribution due to ergodicity
breaking, these estimates can be useful. We introduce the concepts of local and
global temperatures that are captured by different estimation methods. We argue
that for practical application it often makes sense to analyze annealers that
are subject to post-processing in order to isolate the macroscopic distribution
deviations that are a practical barrier to their application.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05020</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2017-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Farrell</keyname><forenames>Brian F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ioannou</keyname><forenames>Petros J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical state dynamics-based analysis of the physical mechanisms
  sustaining and regulating turbulence in Couette flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Fluids, 2(8), 084608, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.2.084608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes a study of the self-sustaining process in
wall-turbulence based on a second order statistical state dynamics (SSD) model
of Couette flow. SSD models with this form are referred to as S3T models and
self-sustain turbulence with a mean flow and second order perturbation
structure similar to that obtained by DNS. The use of a SSD model to study the
physical mechanisms underlying turbulence has advantages over the traditional
approach of studying the dynamics of individual realizations of turbulence. One
advantage is that the analytical structure of SSD isolates and directly
expresses the interaction between the coherent mean flow and the incoherent
perturbation components of the turbulence. Isolation of the interaction between
these components reveals how this interaction underlies both the maintenance of
the turbulence variance by transfer of energy from the externally driven flow
to the perturbation components as well as the enforcement of the observed
statistical mean turbulent state by feedback regulation between the mean and
perturbation fields. Another advantage of studying turbulence using SSD models
is that the analytical structure of S3T turbulence can be completely
characterized. For example, turbulence in the S3T system is maintained by a
parametric growth mechanism. Furthermore, the equilibrium statistical state of
the turbulence can be demonstrated to be enforced by feedback regulation in
which transient growth of the incoherent perturbations episodically suppresses
coherent streak growth preventing runaway parametric growth of the incoherent
turbulent component. Using S3T to isolate these parametric growth and feedback
regulation mechanisms allows a detailed characterization of the dynamics of the
self-sustaining process in S3T turbulence with compelling implications for
understanding the mechanism of wall-turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08808</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shuangxi</forenames></author></authors><title>A multi-parameter Lie transform method applied to the transform of the
  Lagrangian differential one-form</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, to fit the multi-scale perturbations, the single-parameter Lie
transform perturbation theory given in [Ann Phys, 151 1 (1983)] is generalized
to a multi-parameter case, which provides a formal solution of the new
Lagrangian differential 1-form transformed from the old one. In the new method,
the generators and their orders are appropriately chosen under the purpose of
reducing the fast variables from the new Lagrangian differential 1-form order
by order. As for the application, this multi-parameter Lie transform method is
applied to deriving the gyrokinetic model with the presentation of
low-frequency electrostatic perturbations. Compared with the conventional
model, the Finite Larmor Radius terms in the Lagrangian 1-form of the new model
are perfectly cancelled, without using any gauge function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06370</id><created>2016-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Chunling</forenames></author><author><keyname>wang</keyname><forenames>Anmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Michelson interferometer for measuring temperature</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8pages, 1figure</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 381 (2017) 3038</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.07.036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate that temperature can be measured by a modified Michelson
interferometer, where at least one reflected mirror is replaced by a
thermalized sample. Both of two mirrors replaced by the corresponding two
thermalized samples can help to approximatively improve the resolution of
temperature up to twice than only one mirror replaced by a thermalized sample.
For further improving the precision, a nonlinear medium can be employed. The
Michelson interferometer is embedded in a gas displaying Kerr nonlinearity. We
obtain the analytical equations and numerically calculate the precision with
parameters within the reach of current technology, proving that the precision
of temperature can be greatly enhanced by using a nonlinear medium. Our results
show that one can create an accurate thermometer by measuring the photons in
the Michelson interferometer, with no need for directly measuring the
population of thermalized sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01241</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gariel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>N. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Anzhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Observable acceleration of jets by a Kerr black hole</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>revtex4, two tables and six figures. Some typos are corrected. Gen.
  Relativit. Grav. 49 (2017) 43</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Relativit. Grav. 49 (2017) 43</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2208-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of a model based on the gravitational field of the Kerr
black hole, we turn to investigate the kinematic behavior of extragalactic
jets. We analytically calculate the observable velocities and accelerations
along any geodesic. Then, by numerical calculations, we apply our results to a
geodesic, typical of the M87 jet, and probe our results by confrontation to
recent observations. A transition from non-relativistic to ultrarelativistic
speeds at subparsec scale is highlighted. This transition comes sooner and more
abruptly than in models based on magnetic paradigm, which indicates that we
need a weaker magnetic field to explain observed synchrotron radiation. We
attribute the ejection phenomenon to the repulsive effect of the
gravitomagnetic Kerr field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01533</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ooguri</keyname><forenames>Hirosi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vafa</keyname><forenames>Cumrun</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-supersymmetric AdS and the Swampland</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><report-no>CALT-TH 2016-027, IPMU16-0139</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose to sharpen the weak gravity conjecture by the statement that,
except for BPS states in a supersymmetric theory, the gravitational force is
strictly weaker than any electric force and provide a number of evidences for
this statement. Our conjecture implies that any non-supersymmetric anti-de
Sitter vacuum supported by fluxes must be unstable, as is the case for all
known attempts at such holographic constructions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05907</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anantharaman</keyname><forenames>Nalini</forenames><affiliation>IRMA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sabri</keyname><forenames>Mostafa</forenames><affiliation>IRMA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Poisson kernel expansions for Schr\&quot;odinger operators on trees</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>To appear in Journal of Spectral Theory</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study Schr\&quot;odinger operators on trees and construct associated Poisson
kernels, in analogy to the laplacian on the unit disc. We show that in the
absolutely continuous spectrum, the generalized eigenfunctions of the operator
are generated by the Poisson kernel. We use this to define a &quot;Fourier
transform&quot;, giving a Fourier inversion formula and a Plancherel formula, where
the domain of integration runs over the energy parameter and the geometric
boundary of the tree.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01165</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fichet</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teles</keyname><forenames>Patricia Rebello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonero</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Sharpening the shape analysis for higher-dimensional operator searches</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures. v2: Minor corrections, references added, matches
  journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 036003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.036003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When the Standard Model is interpreted as the renormalizable sector of a
low-energy effective theory, the effects of new physics are encoded into a set
of higher dimensional operators. These operators potentially deform the shapes
of Standard Model differential distributions of final states observable at
colliders. We describe a simple and systematic method to obtain optimal
estimations of these deformations when using numerical tools, like Monte Carlo
simulations. A crucial aspect of this method is minimization of the estimation
uncertainty: we demonstrate how the operator coefficients have to be set in the
simulations in order to get optimal results. The uncertainty on the
interference term turns out to be the most difficult to control and grows very
quickly when the interference is suppressed. We exemplify our method by
computing the deformations induced by the ${\cal O}_{3W}$ operator in $W^+W^-$
production at the LHC, and by deriving a bound on ${\cal O}_{3W}$ using $8$ TeV
CMS data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03384</id><created>2016-11-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Tocci</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Chungwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkins</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roke</keyname><forenames>Sylvie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceriotti</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Second-Harmonic Scattering as a Probe of Structural Correlations in
  Liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 7 (21), 4311-4316 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b01851</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Second-harmonic scattering experiments of water and other bulk molecular
liquids have long been assumed to be insensitive to interactions between the
molecules. The measured intensity is generally thought to arise from incoherent
scattering due to individual molecules. We introduce a method to compute the
second-harmonic scattering pattern of molecular liquids directly from atomistic
computer simulations, which takes into account the coherent terms. We apply
this approach to large-scale molecular dynamics simulations of liquid water,
where we show that nanosecond second-harmonic scattering experiments contain a
coherent contribution arising from radial and angular correlations on a length
scale of &lt; 1 nm, much shorter than had been recently hypothesized (Shelton, D.
P. J. Chem. Phys. 2014, 141). By combining structural correlations from
simulations with experimental data (Shelton, D. P. J. Chem. Phys. 2014, 141),
we can also extract an effective molecular hyperpolarizability in the liquid
phase. This work demonstrates that second-harmonic scattering experiments and
atomistic simulations can be used in synergy to investigate the structure of
complex liquids, solutions, and biomembranes, including the intrinsic
intermolecular correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09285</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vischi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrega</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strambini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeret</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarov</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giazotto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent transport properties of a three-terminal hybrid superconducting
  interferometer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 054504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.054504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an exhaustive theoretical analysis of a double-loop Josephson
proximity interferometer, as the one recently realized by Strambini et al. for
the control of the Andreev spectrum via an external magnetic field. This
system, called $\omega$-SQUIPT, consists of a T-shaped diffusive normal metal
(N) attached to three superconductors (S) forming a double loop configuration.
By using the quasiclassical Green function formalism, we calculate the local
normalized density of states, the Josephson currents through the device and the
dependence of the former on the length of the junction arms, the applied
magnetic field and the S/N interface transparencies. We show that by tuning the
fluxes through the double loop, the system undergoes transitions from a gapped
to a gapless state. We also evaluate the Josephson currents flowing in the
different arms as a function of magnetic fluxes and explore the quasi-particle
transport, by considering a metallic probe tunnel-coupled to the Josephson
junction and calculating its I-V characteristics. Finally, we study the
performances of the $\omega$-SQUIPT and its potential applications, by
investigating its electrical and magnetometric properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07651</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spira</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs Boson Production and Decay at Hadron Colliders</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>87 pages, 47 figures, substantial update of arXiv:hep-ph/9705337; v2:
  version accepted by Progress in Particle and Nuclear Physics, references
  updated and text extended</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Part. Nucl. Phys. 95 (2017) 98</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ppnp.2017.04.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Higgs physics at hadron colliders as the LHC is reviewed within the Standard
Model (SM) and its minimal supersymmetric extension (MSSM) by summarizing the
present state-of-the-art of theoretical predictions for the production cross
sections and decay rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09491</id><created>2016-12-28</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaehler</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Massively Parallel Computation of Accurate Densities for N-body Dark
  Matter Simulations using the Phase-Space-Element Method</title><categories>physics.comp-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>accepted manuscript; code implementation available at
  https://github.com/kaehlerr/ADECO</comments><msc-class>85-08</msc-class><acm-class>B.4.2; D.1.3; I.3.5</acm-class><journal-ref>Astronomy and Computing, Volume 20, 2017, Pages 68-76</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2017.05.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents an accurate density computation approach for large dark
matter simulations, based on a recently introduced phase-space tessellation
technique and designed for massively parallel, heterogeneous cluster
architectures. We discuss a memory efficient construction of an oct-tree
structure to sample the mass densities with locally adaptive resolution,
according to the features of the underlying tetrahedral tessellation. We
propose an efficient GPU implementation for the computationally intensive
operation of intersecting the tetrahedra with the cubical cells of the deposit
grid, that achieves a speedup of almost an order of magnitude compared to an
optimized CPU version. We discuss two dynamic load balancing schemes - the
first exchanges particle data between cluster nodes and deposits all tetrahedra
for each block of the grid structure on single nodes, whereas the second
approach uses global reduction operations to obtain the total masses. We
demonstrate the scalability of our algorithms for up to 256 GPUs and TB-sized
simulation snapshots, resulting in tessellations with over 400 billion
tetrahedra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00858</id><created>2017-01-03</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lesieur</keyname><forenames>Thibault</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krzakala</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zdeborov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>Lenka</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained Low-rank Matrix Estimation: Phase Transitions, Approximate
  Message Passing and Applications</title><categories>math.ST cond-mat.stat-mech cs.IT math.IT stat.TH</categories><comments>64 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 7 (2017) 073403</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa7284</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article is an extended version of previous work of the authors [40, 41]
on low-rank matrix estimation in the presence of constraints on the factors
into which the matrix is factorized. Low-rank matrix factorization is one of
the basic methods used in data analysis for unsupervised learning of relevant
features and other types of dimensionality reduction. We present a framework to
study the constrained low-rank matrix estimation for a general prior on the
factors, and a general output channel through which the matrix is observed. We
draw a paralel with the study of vector-spin glass models - presenting a
unifying way to study a number of problems considered previously in separate
statistical physics works. We present a number of applications for the problem
in data analysis. We derive in detail a general form of the low-rank
approximate message passing (Low- RAMP) algorithm, that is known in statistical
physics as the TAP equations. We thus unify the derivation of the TAP equations
for models as different as the Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model, the restricted
Boltzmann machine, the Hopfield model or vector (xy, Heisenberg and other) spin
glasses. The state evolution of the Low-RAMP algorithm is also derived, and is
equivalent to the replica symmetric solution for the large class of vector-spin
glass models. In the section devoted to result we study in detail phase
diagrams and phase transitions for the Bayes-optimal inference in low-rank
matrix estimation. We present a typology of phase transitions and their
relation to performance of algorithms such as the Low-RAMP or commonly used
spectral methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01380</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Delavoipi&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Jessica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verneuil</keyname><forenames>Emilie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Yvette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chateauminois</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Poroelastic indentation of mechanically confined hydrogel layers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12 (2016) 8049-8058</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6sm01448h</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the poroelastic indentation response of hydrogel thin films
geometrically confined within contacts with rigid spherical probes of radii in
the millimeter range. Poly(PEGMA) (poly(ethylene glycol)) methyl ether
methacrylate), poly(DMA) (dimethylacrylamide) and poly(NIPAM)
(\textit{N}-isopropylacrylamide) gel films with thickness less than 15 $\mu$m
were grafted onto glass substrates using a thiol-ene click chemistry route.
Changes in the indentation depth under constant applied load were monitored
over time as a function of the film thickness and the radius of curvature of
the probe using an interferometric method. In addition, shear properties of the
indented films were measured using a lateral contact method. In the case of
poly(PEGMA) films, we show that poroelastic indentation behavior is adequately
described within the framework of an approximate contact model derived within
the limits of confined contact geometries. This model provides simple scaling
laws for the characteristic poroelastic time and the equilibrium indentation
depth. Conversely, deviations from this model are evidenced for poly(DMA) and
poly(NIPAM) films. From lateral contact experiments, these deviations are found
to result from strong changes in the shear properties as a result of glass
transition (poly(DMA)) or phase separation (poly(NIPAM)) phenomena induced by
the drainage of the confined films squeezed between the rigid substrates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01552</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yan-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Zi Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Spin Liquid with Symmetry-Protected Edge States</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures and 2tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological spin liquids are robust quantum states of matter with long-range
entanglement and possess many exotic properties such as the fractional
statistics of the elementary excitations. Yet these states, short of local
parameters like all topological states, are elusive for conventional
experimental probes. In this work, we combine theoretical analysis and quantum
Monte Carlo numerics on a frustrated spin model which hosts a $\mathbb Z_2$
topological spin liquid ground state, and demonstrate that the presence of
symmetry-protected gapless edge modes is a characteristic feature of the state,
originating from the nontrivial symmetry fractionalization of the elementary
excitations. Experimental observation of these modes on the edge would directly
indicate the existence of the topological spin liquids in the bulk, analogous
to the fact that the observation of Dirac edge states confirmed the existence
of topological insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02760</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Jennifer S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leppert</keyname><forenames>Ilana R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boudreau</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narayanan</keyname><forenames>Sridar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duval</keyname><forenames>Tanguy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen-Adad</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pike</keyname><forenames>G. Bruce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stikov</keyname><forenames>Nikola</forenames></author></authors><title>Promise and pitfalls of g-ratio estimation with MRI</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.bio-ph q-bio.QM</categories><comments>This is the accepted version, accepted by NeuroImage. It contains
  minor revisions suggested by reviewers</comments><doi>10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.08.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fiber g-ratio is the ratio of the inner to the outer diameter of the
myelin sheath of a myelinated axon. It has a limited dynamic range in healthy
white matter, as it is optimized for speed of signal conduction, cellular
energetics, and spatial constraints. In vivo imaging of the g-ratio in health
and disease would greatly increase our knowledge of the nervous system and our
ability to diagnose, monitor, and treat disease. MRI based g-ratio imaging was
first conceived in 2011, and expanded to be feasible in full brain with
preliminary results in 2013. This manuscript reviews the growing g-ratio
imaging literature and speculates on future applications. It details the
methodology for imaging the g-ratio with MRI, and describes the known pitfalls
and challenges in doing so.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07703</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abert</keyname><forenames>Claas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruckner</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groenefeld</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuschnigg</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teliban</keyname><forenames>Iulian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogler</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wautischer</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Windl</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suess</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>3D Printing of Polymer Bonded Rare-Earth Magnets With a Variable
  Magnetic Compound Density for a Predefined Stray Field</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph physics.pop-ph</categories><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-09864-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Additive manufacturing of polymer bonded magnets is a recently developed
technique, for single-unit production, and for structures that have been
impossible to manufacture previously. Also new possibilities to create a
specific stray field around the magnet are triggered. The current work presents
a method to 3D print polymer bonded magnets with a variable magnetic compound
density distribution. A low-cost, end-user 3D printer with a mixing extruder is
used to mix permanent magnetic filaments with pure PA12 filaments. The magnetic
filaments are compounded, extruded, and characterized for the printing process.
To deduce the quality of the manufactured magnets with a variable compound
density, an inverse stray field framework is used. The effectiveness of the
printing process and the simulation method is shown. It can also be used to
manufacture magnets that produce a predefined stray field in a given region.
Examples for sensor applications are presented. This setup and simulation
framework allows the design and manufacturing of polymer bonded permanent
magnets which are impossible to create with conventional methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08036</id><created>2017-01-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>D. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramakrishna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fretigny</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spencer</keyname><forenames>N. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chenadec</keyname><forenames>Y. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chateauminois</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Friction of rubber with surfaces patterned with rigid spherical
  asperities</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Tribology Letters 49 (2013) 135-144</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports on the frictional properties of smooth rubber substrates
sliding against rigid surfaces covered with various densities of colloidal
nano-particles (average diameter 77 nm). Friction experiments were carried out
using a transparent Poly(dimethyl siloxane) (PDMS) rubber contacting a silica
lens with silica nano-particles sintered onto its surface. Using a previously
described methodology (Nguyen \textit{et al.}, \textit{J. of Adhesion}
\textbf{87} (2011) 235-250 ), surface shear stress and contact-pressure
distribution within the contact were determined from a measurement of the
displacement field at the surface of the PDMS elastomer. Addition of silica
nano-particles results in a strong, pressure-independent enhancement of the
frictional shear stress as compared to the smooth lens. The contribution of
viscoelastic losses to these increased frictional properties is analyzed in the
light of a numerical model that solves the contact problem between the rubber
and the rough surface. An order-of-magnitude agreement is obtained between
experimental and theoretical results, the latter showing that the calculation
of viscoelastic dissipation within the contact is very sensitive to the details
of the topography of the rigid asperities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08741</id><created>2017-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Benjamin T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bate</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The dependence of protostar formation on the geometry and strength of
  the initial magnetic field</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS. 14 pages, 14 figures. Animations
  are other details can be found at
  http://www.astro.ex.ac.uk/people/blewis/research/outflows_weak_fields.html</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (June 1, 2017) 467 (3): 3324-3337</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report results from twelve simulations of the collapse of a molecular
cloud core to form one or more protostars, comprising three field strengths
(mass-to-flux ratios, {\mu}, of 5, 10, and 20) and four field geometries (with
values of the angle between the field and rotation axes, {\theta}, of 0{\deg},
20{\deg}, 45{\deg}, and 90{\deg}), using a smoothed particle
magnetohydrodynamics method. We find that the values of both parameters have a
strong effect on the resultant protostellar system and outflows. This ranges
from the formation of binary systems when {\mu} = 20 to strikingly differing
outflow structures for differing values of {\theta}, in particular highly
suppressed outflows when {\theta} = 90{\deg}. Misaligned magnetic fields can
also produce warped pseudo-discs where the outer regions align perpendicular to
the magnetic field but the innermost region re-orientates to be perpendicular
to the rotation axis. We follow the collapse to sizes comparable to those of
first cores and find that none of the outflow speeds exceed 8 km s$^{-1}$.
These results may place constraints on both observed protostellar outflows, and
also on which molecular cloud cores may eventually form either single stars and
binaries: a sufficiently weak magnetic field may allow for disc fragmentation,
whilst conversely the greater angular momentum transport of a strong field may
inhibit disc fragmentation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02956</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Titum</keyname><forenames>Paraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>Netanel H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Refael</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author></authors><title>Disorder induced transitions in resonantly driven Floquet Topological
  Insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 054207 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.054207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effects of disorder in Floquet topological insulators
(FTIs) occurring in semiconductor quantum wells. Such FTIs are induced by
resonantly driving a transition between the valence and conduction band. We
show that when disorder is added, the topological nature of such FTIs persists
as long as there is a mobility gap at the resonant quasi-energy. For strong
enough disorder, this gap closes and all the states become localized as the
system undergoes a transition to a trivial insulator. Interestingly, the
effects of disorder are not necessarily adverse: we show that in the same
quantum well, disorder can also induce a transition from a trivial to a
topological system, thereby establishing a Floquet Topological Anderson
Insulator (FTAI). We identify the conditions on the driving field necessary for
observing such a transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06004</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kono</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuyama</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tabuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamazaki</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usami</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshino</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonclassical photon number distribution in a superconducting cavity
  under a squeezed drive</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 023602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.023602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A superconducting qubit in the strong dispersive regime of a circuit quantum
electrodynamics system is a powerful probe for microwave photons in a cavity
mode. In this regime, a qubit spectrum is split into multiple peaks, with each
peak corresponding to an individual photon number in the cavity (discrete ac
Stark shift). Here, we measure the qubit spectrum in the cavity that is driven
continuously with a squeezed vacuum field generated by a Josephson parametric
amplifier. By fitting the qubit spectrum with a model which takes into account
the finite qubit excitation power, the photon number distribution, which is
dissimilar from the apparent peak area ratio in the spectrum, is determined.
The photon number distribution shows the even-odd photon number oscillation and
quantitatively fulfills Klyshko's criterion for the nonclassicality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07376</id><created>2017-02-23</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frouard</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efroimsky</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Tides in a body librating about a spin-orbit resonance. Generalisation
  of the Darwin-Kaula theory</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, Vol. 129, pp. 177 -
  214 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10569-017-9768-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Darwin-Kaula theory of bodily tides is intended for celestial bodies
rotating without libration. We demonstrate that this theory, in its customary
form, is inapplicable to a librating body. Specifically, in the presence of
libration in longitude, the actual spectrum of Fourier tidal modes differs from
the conventional spectrum rendered by the Darwin-Kaula theory for a
non-librating celestial object. This necessitates derivation of formulae for
the tidal torque and the tidal heating rate, that are applicable under
libration.
  We derive the tidal spectrum for longitudinal forced libration with one and
two main frequencies, generalisation to more main frequencies being
straightforward. (By main frequencies we understand those emerging due to the
triaxiality of the librating body.) Separately, we consider a case of free
libration at one frequency (once again, generalisation to more frequencies
being straightforward).
  We also calculate the tidal torque. This torque provides correction to the
triaxiality-caused physical libration. Our theory is not self-consistent: we
assume that the tidal torque is much smaller than the
permanent-triaxiality-caused torque; so the additional libration due to tides
is much weaker than the main libration due to the permanent triaxiality.
  Finally, we calculate the tidal dissipation rate in a body experiencing
forced libration at the main mode, or free libration at one frequency, or
superimposed forced and free librations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00508</id><created>2017-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Pattie</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Adamek</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brenner</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broussard</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Callahan</keyname><forenames>N. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clayton</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cude-Woods</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Currie</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geltonbort</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauer</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majewski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makela</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramsey</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvat</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saunders</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schroffenegger</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watkins</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeck</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluation of commercial nickel-phosphorus coating for ultracold neutron
  guides using a pinhole bottling method</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.07.051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the evaluation of commercial electroless nickel phosphorus (NiP)
coatings for ultracold neutron (UCN) transport and storage. The material
potential of 50~$\mu$m thick NiP coatings on stainless steel and aluminum
substrates was measured to be $V_F = 213(5.2)$~neV using the time-of-flight
spectrometer ASTERIX at the Lujan Center. The loss per bounce probability was
measured in pinhole bottling experiments carried out at ultracold neutron
sources at Los Alamos Neutron Science Center and the Institut Laue-Langevin.
For these tests a new guide coupling design was used to minimize gaps between
the guide sections. The observed UCN loss in the bottle was interpreted in
terms of an energy independent effective loss per bounce, which is the
appropriate model when gaps in the system and upscattering are the dominate
loss mechanisms, yielding a loss per bounce of $1.3(1) \times 10^{-4}$. We also
present a detailed discussion of the pinhole bottling methodology and an energy
dependent analysis of the experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00784</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenkins</keyname><forenames>Stewart D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bronstein</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruostekoski</keyname><forenames>Janne</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic electrodynamics simulations for collective atom response in
  optical cavities</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023855 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023855</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the collective optical response of an atomic ensemble confined
within a single-mode optical cavity by stochastic electrodynamics simulations
that include the effects of atomic position correlations, internal level
structure, and spatial variations in cavity coupling strength and atom density.
In the limit of low light intensity the simulations exactly reproduce the full
quantum field-theoretical description for cold stationary atoms and at higher
light intensities we introduce semiclassical approximations to atomic
saturation that we compare with the exact solution in the case of two atoms. We
find that collective subradiant modes of the atoms, with very narrow
linewidths, can be coupled to the cavity field by spatial variation of the
atomic transition frequency and resolved at low intensities, and show that they
can be specifically driven by tailored transverse pumping beams. We show that
the cavity optical response, in particular both the subradiant mode profile and
the resonance shift of the cavity mode, can be used as a diagnostic tool for
the position correlations of the atoms and hence the atomic quantum many-body
phase. The quantum effects are found to be most prominent close to the narrow
subradiant mode resonances at high light intensities. Although an optical
cavity can generally strongly enhance quantum fluctuations via light
confinement, we show that the semiclassical approximation to the stochastic
electrodynamics model provides at least a qualitative agreement with the exact
optical response outside the subradiant mode resonances even in the presence of
significant saturation of the atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06144</id><created>2017-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>Hamsa</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Information, the Cosmological Constant and the Amplitude of
  primordial perturbations</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages; 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Letts. B, 773 (2017) 81</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.07.066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A unique feature of gravity is its ability to control the information
accessible to any specific observer. We quantify the notion of cosmic
information ('CosmIn') for an eternal observer in the universe. Demanding the
finiteness of CosmIn requires the universe to have a late-time accelerated
expansion. Combining the introduction of CosmIn with generic features of the
quantum structure of spacetime (e.g., the holographic principle), we present a
holistic model for cosmology. We show that (i) the numerical value of the
cosmological constant, as well as (ii) the amplitude of the primordial, scale
invariant, perturbation spectrum can be determined in terms of a single free
parameter, which specifies the energy scale at which the universe makes a
transition from a pre-geometric phase to the classical phase. For a specific
value of the parameter, we obtain the correct results for both (i) and (ii).
This formalism also shows that the quantum gravitational information content of
spacetime can be tested using precision cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06374</id><created>2017-03-18</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rotondo</keyname><forenames>Marcello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nojiri</keyname><forenames>Shin'ichi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Toy Model of Discretized Gravity in Two Dimensions and its Extentions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>LaTeX 7 pages, version to appear in MPLA</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732317501498</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a toy model of quantum gravity in two dimensions with Euclidean
signature. The model is given by a kind of discretization which is different
from the dynamical triangulation. We show that there exists a continuum limit
and we can calculate some physical quantities such as the expectation value of
the area, that is, the volume of the two dimensional euclidean space-time. We
also consider the extensions of the model to higher dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08305</id><created>2017-03-24</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gisin</keyname><forenames>Boris V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Dirac equation and anomalous magnetic moment</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The idea of determining the magnetic resonance condition in a rotating frame
of reference is being studied. In this frame, the rotating magnetic field
should be at rest. The 3D transformation that determines the transition to the
frame is found. The Dirac equation in a rotating electromagnetic field after
such a transition is obtained. The magnetic resonance condition is determined
by the stationarity of solutions. The connection between g-factor in the
anomalous magnetic moment and a constant in 3D transformation is established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08993</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-06-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wakimoto</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketov</keyname><forenames>Sergei V.</forenames></author></authors><title>No inflation in type IIA strings on rigid CY spaces</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures, LaTeX2e; minor revision: section 3 expanded and
  a reference added. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1607.05293</comments><report-no>IPMU17-0029, NORDITA-2017-23</report-no><journal-ref>Progress of Theoretical and Experimental Physics, Volume 2017,
  Issue 8, 1 August 2017, 083E02</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx094</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate whether cosmological inflation is possible in a class of flux
compactifications of type IIA strings on rigid Calabi-Yau manifolds, when all
perturbative string corrections are taken into account. We confine ourselves to
the universal hypermultiplet and an abelian vector multiplet, representing
matter in four dimensions. Since all axions can be stabilized by D-instantons,
we choose dilaton and a K\&quot;ahler modulus as the only running scalars. Though
positivity of their scalar potential can be achieved, we find that there is no
slow roll ($\varepsilon &gt; 2$ and $\eta &gt;2$), and no Graceful Exit because the
scalar potential has the run-away behaviour resulting in decompactification. We
conclude that it is impossible to generate phenomenologically viable inflation
in the given class of flux compactifications of type IIA strings, without
explicit breaking of $N=2$ local supersymmetry of the low-energy effective
action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10587</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barghathi</keyname><forenames>Hatem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casiano-Diaz</keyname><forenames>Emanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Maestro</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle partition entanglement of one dimensional spinless fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 083108</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa819a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the scaling of the R\'{e}nyi entanglement entropies for a
particle bipartition of interacting spinless fermions in one spatial dimension.
In the Tomonaga-Luttinger liquid regime, we calculate the second R\'{e}nyi
entanglement entropy and show that the leading order finite-size scaling is
equal to a universal logarithm of the system size plus a non-universal
constant. Higher-order corrections decay as power-laws in the system size with
exponents that depend only on the Luttinger parameter. We confirm the
universality of our results by investigating the one dimensional $t-V$ model of
interacting spinless fermions via exact-diagonalization techniques. The
resulting sensitivity of the particle partition entanglement to boundary
conditions and statistics supports its utility as a probe of quantum liquids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10600</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baldenegro</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fichet</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Gersdorff</keyname><forenames>Gero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Royon</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the anomalous $\gamma\gamma\gamma Z$ coupling at the LHC with
  proton tagging</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures. v2 matches journal version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1706 (2017) 142</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensitivities to the anomalous quartic gauge boson coupling
$\gamma\gamma\gamma Z$ are estimated via $\gamma Z$ production with intact
protons in the forward region at the LHC. Proton tagging proves to be a
powerful tool to suppress the background, which allows consideration of the
hadronic decays of the $Z$ boson in addition to the leptonic ones. We discuss
the discovery potential for an integrated luminosity of $300\,\mathrm{fb}^{-1}$
and $3000\,\mathrm{fb}^{-1}$. The sensitivity we obtain at
$300\,\mathrm{fb}^{-1}$ goes beyond the one expected from LHC bounds on the
$Z\rightarrow \gamma\gamma\gamma$ decay by about three orders of magnitude. The
$\gamma Z$ channel provides important discriminatory information with respect
to the exclusive $\gamma\gamma$ channel, as many particles beyond the Standard
Model (such as a radion or Kaluza Klein gravitons) predict a signal in the
latter but not the former.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10777</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atluhanov</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burdakov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ushkova</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-resonant adiabatic photon trap</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>This article is translation from russian to english for full text of
  &quot;Nonresonance adiabatic photon trap&quot; arXiv:1606.03220. The text contans 6
  pages and 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper presents and experimentally investigates a concept of an efficient
radiation trap based on adiabatic photon confinement between curved mirrors.
Such a trap is free of restrictions typical to the Fabry-Perot cells, relating
to the confined radiation quality and accuracy and stabilization of optical
elements. Experiments have demonstrated high efficiency of confinement, which
depends mainly on the reflectivity of the mirrors and defects on their surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03274</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Yuxiang</forenames><affiliation>School of Physics, University of Melbourne</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mutch</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames><affiliation>School of Physics, University of Melbourne</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Duffy</keyname><forenames>Alan R.</forenames><affiliation>Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, Swinburne University of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames><affiliation>School of Physics, University of Melbourne</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>Gregory B.</forenames><affiliation>Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, Swinburne University of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mesinger</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames><affiliation>Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>J. Stuart B.</forenames><affiliation>School of Physics, University of Melbourne</affiliation></author></authors><title>Dark-ages Reionization and Galaxy Formation Simulation - XIII. AGN
  quenching of high-redshift star formation in ZF-COSMOS-20115</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures; Updated to match the published version. All
  results and conclusions remain unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 471 (4): 4345-4354</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1852</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive quiescent galaxies (MQGs) are thought to have formed stars rapidly at
early times followed by a long period of quiescence. The recent discovery of a
MQG, ZF-COSMOS-20115 at $z\sim4$, only 1.5 Gyr after the big bang, places new
constraints on galaxy growth and the role of feedback in early star formation.
Spectroscopic follow-up confirmed ZF-COSMOS-20115 as a MQG at $z=3.717$ with an
estimated stellar mass of ${\sim}10^{11}\mathrm{M}_\odot$, showing no evidence
of recent star formation. We use the Meraxes semi-analytic model to investigate
how ZF-COSMOS-20115 analogues build stellar mass, and why they become
quiescent. We identify three analogue galaxies with similar properties to
ZF-COSMOS-20115. We find that ZF-COSMOS-20115 is likely hosted by a massive
halo with virial mass of ${\sim}10^{13}\mathrm{M}_\odot$, having been through
significant mergers at early times. These merger events drove intense growth of
the nucleus, which later prevented cooling and quenched star formation.
ZF-COSMOS-20115 likely remained quiescent at $z&lt;3.7$. We find that the
analogues host the most massive black holes in our simulation and were luminous
quasars at $z\sim5$, indicating that ZF-COSMOS-20115 and other MQGs may be the
descendants of high-redshift quasars. In addition, the model suggests that
ZF-COSMOS-20115 formed in a region of intergalactic medium that was reionized
early.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03308</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Melendez</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wesolowski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furnstahl</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bayesian truncation errors in chiral effective field theory:
  nucleon-nucleon observables</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex physics.data-an</categories><comments>24 pages. Corresponds to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 96, 024003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.96.024003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chiral effective field theory (EFT) predictions are necessarily truncated at
some order in the EFT expansion, which induces an error that must be quantified
for robust statistical comparisons to experiment. In previous work, a Bayesian
model for truncation errors of perturbative expansions was adapted to EFTs. The
model yields posterior probability distribution functions (pdfs) for these
errors based on expectations of naturalness encoded in Bayesian priors and the
observed order-by-order convergence pattern of the EFT. A first application was
made to chiral EFT for neutron-proton scattering using the semi-local
potentials of Epelbaum, Krebs, and Mei{\ss}ner (EKM). Here we extend this
application to consider a larger set of regulator parameters, energies, and
observables as a general example of a statistical approach to truncation
errors. The Bayesian approach allows for statistical validations of the
assumptions and enables the calculation of posterior pdfs for the EFT breakdown
scale. The statistical model is validated for EKM potentials whose convergence
behavior is not distorted by regulator artifacts. For these cases, the
posterior for the breakdown scale is consistent with EKM assumptions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04363</id><created>2017-04-14</created><updated>2017-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin-He</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of dark energy on the efficiency of charged AdS black holes as
  heat engine</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>28 pages, 16 figures, refernces added, discussion and computation
  improved</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.8, 556</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5134-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the heat engine where charged AdS black holes
surrounded by dark energy is the working substance and the mechanical work is
done via $PdV$ term in the first law of black hole thermodynamics in the
extended phase space. We first investigate the effects of a kind of dark energy
(quintessence field in this paper) on the efficiency of the RN-AdS black holes
as heat engine defined as a rectangle closed path in the $P-V$ plane. We get
the exact efficiency formula and find that quintessence field can improve the
heat engine efficiency which will increase as the field density $\rho_q$ grows.
At some fixed parameters, we find that bigger volume difference between the
smaller black holes($V_1$) and the bigger black holes($V_2$ ) will lead to a
lower efficiency, while the bigger pressure difference $P_1-P_4$ will make the
efficiency higher but it is always smaller than 1 and will never be beyond
Carnot efficiency which is the maximum value of the efficiency constrained by
thermodynamics laws, this is consistent to the heat engine in traditional
thermodynamics. After making some special choices for thermodynamical
quantities, we find that the increase of electric charge $Q$ and normalization
factor $a$ can also promote heat engine efficiency which would infinitely
approach the Carnot limit when $Q$ or $a$ goes to infinity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05894</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bonder</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leon</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation as an amplifier: the case of Lorentz violation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 044036 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.044036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modified gravity theories are supposed to incorporate low-energy
quantum-gravity effects and, at the same time, they could shed light into the
dark matter and dark energy problems. Here we study a particular modification
of general relativity where local Lorentz invariance is spontaneously broken
and whose physical effects, despite a decade-long effort, were unknown. We show
that, during inflation, this modification produces anisotropies that would
generate measurable effects on the Cosmic Microwave Background. Then, by using
empirical constraints on the B-mode polarization spectrum, we can estimate that
the `coefficient' components absolute value have to be smaller than $10^{-43}$.
This is a remarkably strong limit, in fact, it is 29 orders of magnitude better
than the best constraints on similar coefficients. Thus, we propose that
inflation could stringently test other modified gravity theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07755</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-08-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Umucalilar</keyname><forenames>R. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iskin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>BCS theory of time-reversal-symmetric Hofstadter-Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages with 4 figures in the Main text, and 3 additional figures
  Online. To appear in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 085301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.085301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The competition between the length scales associated with the periodicity of
a lattice potential and the cyclotron radius of a uniform magnetic field is
known to have dramatic effects on the single-particle properties of a quantum
particle, e.g., the fractal spectrum is known as the Hofstadter butterfly.
Having this intricate competition in mind, we consider a two-component Fermi
gas on a square optical lattice with opposite synthetic magnetic fields for the
components, and study its effects on the many-body BCS-pairing phenomenon. By a
careful addressing of the distinct superfluid transitions from the semi-metal,
quantum spin-Hall insulator or normal phases, we explore the low-temperature
phase diagrams of the model, displaying lobe structures that are reminiscent of
the well-known Mott-insulator transitions of the Bose-Hubbard model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08550</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Frydendahl</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rep&#xe4;n</keyname><forenames>Taavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geisler</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>Sergey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beermann</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrinenko</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Sanshui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mortensen</keyname><forenames>N. Asger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenger</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical reconfiguration and polarization control in semi-continuous gold
  films close to the percolation threshold</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.other</categories><comments>Supplementary materials available upon request (chrfr@fotonik.dtu.dk)</comments><journal-ref>Nanoscale 9, 12014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7NR03378H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Controlling and confining light by exciting plasmons in resonant metallic
nanostructures is an essential aspect of many new emerging optical
technologies. Here we explore the possibility of controllably reconfiguring the
intrinsic optical properties of semi-continuous gold films, by inducing
permanent morphological changes with a femtosecond (fs)-pulsed laser above a
critical power. Optical transmission spectroscopy measurements show a
correlation between the spectra of the morphologically modified films and the
wavelength, polarization, and the intensity of the laser used for alteration.
In order to understand the modifications induced by the laser writing, we
explore the near-field properties of these films with electron energy-loss
spectroscopy (EELS). A comparison between our experimental data and full-wave
simulations on the exact film morphologies hints toward a restructuring of the
intrinsic plasmonic eigenmodes of the metallic film by photothermal effects. We
explain these optical changes with a simple model and demonstrate
experimentally that laser writing can be used to controllably modify the
optical properties of these semi-continuous films. These metal films offer an
easy-to-fabricate and scalable platform for technological applications such as
molecular sensing and ultra-dense data storage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03072</id><created>2017-05-08</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burnett</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chui</keyname><forenames>Chi On</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Benjamin S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density Matrix Modeling of Quantum Cascade Lasers without an
  Artificially Localized Basis: A Generalized Scattering Approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures, final version in Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 085308 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.085308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a density matrix (DM) theory for quantum cascade lasers (QCLs) that
describes the influence of scattering on coherences through a generalized
scattering superoperator. The theory enables quantitative modeling of QCLs,
including localization and tunneling effects, using the well-defined energy
eigenstates rather than the ad hoc localized basis states required by most
previous DM models. Our microscopic approach to scattering also eliminates the
need for phenomenological transition or dephasing rates. We discuss the
physical interpretation and numerical implementation of the theory, presenting
sets of both energy-resolved and thermally averaged equations which can be used
for detailed or compact device modeling. We illustrate the theory's
applications by simulating a high performance resonant-phonon terahertz (THz)
QCL design which cannot be easily or accurately modeled using conventional DM
methods. We show that the theory's inclusion of coherences is crucial for
describing localization and tunneling effects consistent with experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07973</id><created>2017-05-22</created><updated>2017-08-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tianjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maxin</keyname><forenames>James A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanopoulos</keyname><forenames>Dimitri V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the No-Scale ${\cal F}$-$SU(5)$ One-Parameter Model via Gluino
  Searches at the LHC2</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Physics Letters B version</comments><report-no>ACT-04-17, MI-TH-1755</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B773 (2017) 54-56</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.08.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our recent paper entitled &quot;The return of the King: No-Scale ${\cal
F}$-$SU(5)$&quot;, we showed that the model space supporting the most favorable
phenomenology should have been probed in 2016 at the LHC2, with an even further
reach into this region of the model in 2017-18. This ideal realm of the
one-parameter version of No-Scale ${\cal F}$-$SU(5)$ yields a 1.9-2.3 TeV
gluino mass at the very same point where the light Higgs boson mass enters its
rather narrow experimentally determined range of $m_h = 125.09 \pm 0.24$ GeV.
Given the recent results reported at Moriond 2017 for 36 ${\rm fb}^{-1}$ of
luminosity collected in 2016 at the 13 TeV LHC2, we now update the status of
the No-Scale ${\cal F}$-$SU(5)$ model space in light of the gluino mass
exclusion limits presented by the ATLAS and CMS Collaborations. We illustrate
that a resolution could be reached soon as to whether supersymmetry lives in
this most critical region of the model space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00196</id><created>2017-06-01</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bois</keyname><forenames>Juliana</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;rzd&#xf6;rfer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Size-dependence of non-empirically tuned DFT starting points for
  $G_0W_0$ applied to ${\pi}$-conjugated molecular chains</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $G_0W_0$ calculations for predicting vertical ionization potentials (IPs) and
electron affinities of molecules and clusters are known to show a significant
dependence on the density functional theory (DFT) starting point. A number of
non-empirical procedures to find an optimal starting point have been proposed,
typically based on tuning the amount of HF exchange in the underlying hybrid
functional specifically for the system at hand. For the case of
$\pi$-conjugated molecular chains, these approaches lead to a significantly
different amount of HF exchange for different oligomer sizes. In this study, we
analyze if and how strongly this size dependence affects the ability of
non-empirical tuning approaches to predict accurate IPs for $\pi$-conjugated
molecular chains of increasing chain length. To this end, we employ three
different non-empirical tuning procedures for the $G_0W_0$ starting point to
calculate the IP of polyene oligomers up to 22 repeat units and compare the
results to highly accurate coupled-cluster calculations. We find that, despite
its size dependence, using an IP-tuned hybrid functional as a starting point
for $G_0W_0$ yields excellent agreement with the reference data for all chain
lengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00730</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00730</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>Christiane S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>Erminia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Distinguishing between Neutrinos and time-varying Dark Energy through
  Cosmic Time</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, minor updates to match the version accepted by
  Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 043510 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.043510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the correlations between parameters characterizing neutrino physics
and the evolution of dark energy. Using a fluid approach, we show that
time-varying dark energy models exhibit degeneracies with the cosmic neutrino
background over extended periods of the cosmic history, leading to a degraded
estimation of the total mass and number of species of neutrinos. We investigate
how to break degeneracies and combine multiple probes across cosmic time to
anchor the behaviour of the two components. We use Planck CMB data and BAO
measurements from the BOSS, SDSS and 6dF surveys to present current limits on
the model parameters, and then forecast the future reach from the CMB Stage-4
and DESI experiments. We show that a multi-probe analysis of current data
provides only marginal improvement on the determination of the individual
parameters and no reduction of the correlations. Future observations will
better distinguish the neutrino mass and preserve the current sensitivity to
the number of species even in case of a time-varying dark energy component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01112</id><created>2017-06-04</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Richartz</keyname><forenames>Maur&#xed;cio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herdeiro</keyname><forenames>Carlos A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berti</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronous frequencies of extremal Kerr black holes: resonances,
  scattering and stability</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>v2: 10 pages, 2 figures, 1 table. Matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 044034 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.044034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The characteristic damping times of the natural oscillations of a Kerr black
hole become arbitrarily large as the extremal limit is approached. This
behavior is associated with the so-called zero damped modes (ZDMs), and
suggests that extremal black holes are characterized by quasinormal modes whose
frequencies are purely real. Since these frequencies correspond to oscillations
whose angular phase velocity matches the horizon angular velocity of the black
hole, they are sometimes called &quot;synchronous frequencies&quot;. Several authors have
studied the ZDMs for near-extremal black holes. Recently, their correspondence
to branch points of the Green's function of the wave equation was linked to the
Aretakis instability of extremal black holes. Here we investigate the existence
of ZDMs for extremal black holes, showing that these real-axis resonances of
the field are unphysical as natural black hole oscillations: the corresponding
frequency is always associated with a scattering mode. By analyzing the
behavior of these modes near the event horizon we obtain new insight into the
transition to extremality, including a simple way to understand the Aretakis
instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01342</id><created>2017-06-01</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Mingpu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shiwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical results on the short-range spin correlation functions in the
  ground state of the two-dimensional Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Published version, 8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075156 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075156</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical lattice experiments with ultracold fermion atoms and quantum gas
microscopy have recently realized direct measurements of magnetic correlations
at the site-resolved level. We calculate the short-range spin correlation
functions in the ground state of the two-dimensional repulsive Hubbard model
with the auxiliary-field Quantum Monte Carlo (AFQMC) method. The results are
numerically exact at half filling where the fermion sign problem is absent.
Away from half-filling, we employ the constrained path AFQMC approach to
eliminate the exponential computational scaling from the sign problem. The
constraint employs unrestricted Hartree-Fock trial wave-functions with an
effective interaction strength U , which is optimized self-consistently within
AFQMC. Large supercells are studied, with twist averaged boundary conditions as
needed, to reach the thermodynamic limit. We find that the nearest-neighbor
spin correlation always increases with the interaction strength U , contrary to
the finite-temperature behavior where a maximum is reached at a finite U value.
We also observe a change of sign in the next nearest neighbor spin correlation
with increasing density, which is a consequence of the buildup of the
long-range anti-ferromagnetic correlation. We expect the results presented in
this work to serve as a benchmark as lower temperatures are reached in
ultracold atom experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06862</id><created>2017-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Iubini</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepri</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Livi</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oppo</keyname><forenames>Gian-Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Politi</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>A Chain, a Bath, a Sink and a Wall</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Submitted to Entropy Special Issue &quot;Thermodynamics and Statistical
  Mechanics of Small Systems&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 2017, 19(9), 445</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19090445</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate out-of-equilibrium stationary processes emerging in a Discrete
Nonlinear Schroedinger chain in contact with a heat reservoir (a bath) at
temperature $T_L$ and a pure dissipator (a sink) acting on opposite edges. We
observe two different regimes. For small heat-bath temperatures $T_L$ and
chemical-potentials, temperature profiles across the chain display a
non-monotonous shape, remain remarkably smooth and even enter the region of
negative absolute temperatures. For larger temperatures $T_L$, the transport of
energy is strongly inhibited by the spontaneous emergence of discrete
breathers, which act as a thermal wall. A strongly intermittent energy flux is
also observed, due to the irregular birth and death events of the breathers.
The corresponding statistics exhibits the typical signature of rare events of
processes with large deviations. In particular, the breather lifetime is found
to be ruled by a stretched-exponential law.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08783</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pokorn&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>Vladislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17d;onda</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation effects in superconducting quantum dot systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, contribution to SCES 2017 Prague conference
  proceedings</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2017.08.059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of electron correlations on a system consisting of a
single-level quantum dot with local Coulomb interaction attached to two
superconducting leads. We use the single-impurity Anderson model with BCS
superconducting baths to study the interplay between the proximity induced
electron pairing and the local Coulomb interaction. We show how to solve the
model using the continuous-time hybridization-expansion quantum Monte Carlo
method. The results obtained for experimentally relevant parameters are
compared with results of self-consistent second order perturbation theory as
well as with the numerical renormalization group method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08825</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kantor</keyname><forenames>Yacov</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kardar</keyname><forenames>Mehran</forenames></author></authors><title>Attractive and repulsive polymer-mediated forces between scale-free
  surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>RevTeX, 10 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022148 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider forces acting on objects immersed in, or attached to, long
fluctuating polymers. The confinement of the polymer by the obstacles results
in polymer-mediated forces that can be repulsive (due to loss of entropy) or
attractive (if some or all surfaces are covered by adsorbing layers). The
strength and sign of the force in general depends on the detailed shape and
adsorption properties of the obstacles, but assumes simple universal forms if
characteristic length scales associated with the objects are large. This occurs
for scale-free shapes (such as a flat plate, straight wire, or cone), when the
polymer is repelled by the obstacles, or is marginally attracted to it (close
to the depinning transition where the absorption length is infinite). In such
cases, the separation $h$ between obstacles is the only relevant macroscopic
length scale, and the polymer mediated force equals ${\cal A} \, k_{B}T/h$,
where $T$ is temperature. The amplitude ${\cal A}$ is akin to a critical
exponent, depending only on geometry and universality of the polymer system.
The value of ${\cal A}$, which we compute for simple geometries and ideal
polymers, can be positive or negative. Remarkably, we find ${\cal A}=0$ for
ideal polymers at the adsorption transition point, irrespective of shapes of
the obstacles, i.e. at this special point there is no polymer-mediated force
between obstacles (scale-free or not).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09472</id><created>2017-06-28</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Busz</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaszewski</keyname><forenames>Damian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinek</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin correlation and entanglement detection in Cooper pair splitters by
  current measurements using magnetic detectors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064520</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze a model of double quantum dot Cooper pair splitter coupled to two
ferromagnetic detectors, and demonstrate the possibility of determination of
spin correlation by current measurements. We use perturbation theory taking
account of the exchange interaction with the detectors, which leads to complex
spin dynamics in the dots. This affects the measured spin and restricts the use
of ferromagnetic detectors to the nonlinear current-voltage characteristic
regime at current plateau, where the relevant spin projection is conserved, in
contrast to the linear current-voltage characteristic regime, in which the spin
information is distorted. Moreover, we show that for separable states the spin
correlation can only be determined in a limited parameter regime, much more
restricted than in the case of entangled states. We propose an entanglement
test based on the Bell inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09674</id><created>2017-06-29</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Sandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Abajo</keyname><forenames>F. Javier Garcia</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmon Generation through Electron Tunneling in Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures, 92 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The short wavelength of graphene plasmons relative to the light wavelength
makes them attractive for applications in optoelectronics and sensing. However,
this property limits their coupling to external light and our ability to create
and detect them. More efficient ways of generating plasmons are therefore
desirable. Here we demonstrate through realistic theoretical simulations that
graphene plasmons can be efficiently excited via electron tunneling in a
sandwich structure formed by two graphene monolayers separated by a few atomic
layers of hBN. We obtain plasmon generation rates of $\sim10^{12}-10^{14}/$s
over an area of the squared plasmon wavelength for realistic values of the
spacing and bias voltage, while the yield (plasmons per tunneled electron) has
unity order. Our results support electrical excitation of graphene plasmons in
tunneling devices as a viable mechanism for the development of optics-free
ultrathin plasmonic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09959</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Pacher</keyname><forenames>Ferdinand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayrhofer</keyname><forenames>Paul H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holec</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacancy-driven extended stability of cubic metastable Ta-Al-N and
  Nb-Al-N phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, submitted to S&amp;CT</comments><journal-ref>Surface and Coatings Technology Volume 326, 2017, Pages 37-44</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.surfcoat.2017.07.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum mechanical calculations had been previously applied to predict phase
stability in many ternary and multinary nitride systems. While the predictions
were very accurate for the Ti-Al-N system, some discrepancies between theory
and experiment were obtained in the case of other systems. Namely, in the case
of Ta-Al-N, the calculations tend to overestimate the minimum Al content
necessary to obtain a metastable solid solution with a cubic structure. In this
work, we present a comprehensive study of the impact of vacancies on the phase
fields in quasi-binary TaN-AlN and NbN-AlN systems. Our calculations clearly
show that presence of point defects strongly enlarges the cubic phase field in
the TaN-AlN system, while the effect is less pronounced in the NbN-AlN case.
The present phase stability predictions agree better with experimental
observations of physical vapour deposited thin films reported in the literature
than that based on perfect, non-defected structures. This study shows that a
representative structural model is crucial for a meaningful comparison with
experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01584</id><created>2017-07-05</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kontorovich</keyname><forenames>Victor M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trofymenko</keyname><forenames>Sergii V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the mystery of the interpulse shift in the Crab pulsar</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures; comparing to version 1, the abstract and the
  list of references are slightly modified, as well as the references in the
  captions of Fig.3,4,6 and denominations in formulae (12-14); the paper is
  accepted for publication in JPSA, Vol.7, no. 4, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new mechanism of radiation emission in the polar gap of a pulsar is
proposed. It is the curvature radiation which is emitted by returning positrons
moving toward the surface of the neutron star along field lines of the inclined
magnetic field and reflects from the surface. Such radiation interferes with
transition radiation emitted from the neutron star when positrons hit the
surface. It is shown that the proposed mechanism may be applicable for
explanation of the mystery of the interpulse shift in the Crab pulsar at high
frequencies discovered by Moffett and Hankins twenty years ago.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01686</id><created>2017-07-06</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Quesada</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sipe</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Why you should not use the electric field to quantize in nonlinear
  optics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>This version corrects a minor typo from the published version in
  Optics Letters. Eq. 22 should have an \epsilon_0 that is lacking in the OL
  version</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 42, 3443-3446 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.003443</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that using the electric field as a quantization variable in nonlinear
optics leads to incorrect expressions for the squeezing parameters in
spontaneous parametric down-conversion and conversion rates in frequency
conversion. This observation is related to the fact that if the electric field
is written as a linear combination of bosonic creation and annihilation
operators one cannot satisfy Maxwell's equations in a nonlinear dielectric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02289</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02289</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takaoka</keyname><forenames>Masanori</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrated analysis of energy transfers in elastic-wave turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96 (2017) 023106</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.023106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In elastic-wave turbulence, strong turbulence appears in small wave numbers
while weak turbulence does in large wave numbers. Energy transfers in the
coexistence of these turbulent states are numerically investigated in both of
the Fourier space and the real space. An analytical expression of a detailed
energy balance reveals from which mode to which mode energy is transferred in
the triad interaction. Stretching energy excited by external force is
transferred nonlocally and intermittently to large wave numbers as the kinetic
energy in the strong turbulence. In the weak turbulence, the resonant
interactions according to the weak turbulence theory produces cascading net
energy transfer to large wave numbers. Because the system's nonlinearity shows
strong temporal intermittency, the energy transfers are investigated at active
and moderate phases separately. The nonlocal interactions in the Fourier space
are characterized by the intermittent bundles of fibrous structures in the real
space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03613</id><created>2017-07-12</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bedington</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arrazola</keyname><forenames>Juan Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Progress in satellite quantum key distribution</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 3, Article number: 30 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0031-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum key distribution (QKD) is a family of protocols for growing a private
encryption key between two parties. Despite much progress, all ground-based QKD
approaches have a distance limit due to atmospheric losses or in-fibre
attenuation. These limitations make purely ground-based systems impractical for
a global distribution network. However, the range of communication may be
extended by employing satellites equipped with high-quality optical links. This
manuscript summarizes research and development which is beginning to enable QKD
with satellites. It includes a discussion of protocols, infrastructure, and the
technical challenges involved with implementing such systems, as well as a top
level summary of on-going satellite QKD initiatives around the world.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03847</id><created>2017-07-12</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goudfrooij</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames><affiliation>STScI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Girardi</keyname><forenames>Leo</forenames><affiliation>OAPD-INAF</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Correnti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames><affiliation>STScI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Extended Main Sequence Turnoffs in Intermediate-Age Star Clusters:
  Stellar Rotation diminishes, but does not eliminate, Age Spreads</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures, LaTeX version using emulateapj.cls</comments><journal-ref>Published in ApJ, 846, 22 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7fb7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extended main sequence turn-off (eMSTO) regions are a common feature in
color-magnitude diagrams of young and intermediate-age star clusters in the
Magellanic Clouds. The nature of eMSTOs remains debated in the literature. The
currently most popular scenarios are extended star formation activity and
ranges of stellar rotation rates. Here we study details of differences in MSTO
morphology expected from spreads in age versus spreads in rotation rates, using
Monte Carlo simulations with the Geneva SYCLIST isochrone models that include
the effects of stellar rotation. We confirm a recent finding of Niederhofer et
al. that a distribution of stellar rotation velocities yields an MSTO extent
that is proportional to the cluster age, as observed. However, we find that
stellar rotation yields MSTO crosscut widths that are generally smaller than
observed ones at a given age. We compare the simulations with high-quality
Hubble Space Telescope data of NGC 1987 and NGC 2249, which are the two only
relatively massive star clusters with an age of ~1 Gyr for which such data is
available. We find that the distribution of stars across the eMSTOs of these
clusters cannot be explained solely by a distribution of stellar rotation
velocities, unless the orientations of rapidly rotating stars are heavily
biased towards an equator-on configuration. Under the assumption of random
viewing angles, stellar rotation can account for ~60% and ~40% of the observed
FWHM widths of the eMSTOs of NGC 1987 and NGC 2249, respectively. In contrast,
a combination of distributions of stellar rotation velocities and stellar ages
fits the observed eMSTO morphologies very well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05496</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ronnet</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousis</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vernazza</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Pebble accretion at the origin of water in Europa</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa80e6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the fact that the observed gradient in water content among the
Galilean satellites is globally consistent with a formation in a circum-Jovian
disk on both sides of the snowline, the mechanisms that led to a low water mass
fraction in Europa ($\sim$$8\%$) are not yet understood. Here, we present new
modeling results of solids transport in the circum-Jovian disk accounting for
aerodynamic drag, turbulent diffusion, surface temperature evolution and
sublimation of water ice. We find that the water mass fraction of pebbles
(e.g., solids with sizes of 10$^{-2}$ -- 1 m) as they drift inward is globally
consistent with the current water content of the Galilean system. This opens
the possibility that each satellite could have formed through pebble accretion
within a delimited region whose boundaries were defined by the position of the
snowline. This further implies that the migration of the forming satellites was
tied to the evolution of the snowline so that Europa fully accreted from
partially dehydrated material in the region just inside of the snowline.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09749</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09749</id><created>2017-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Fornal</keyname><forenames>Bartosz</forenames></author></authors><title>Is There a Sign of New Physics in Beryllium Transitions?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages + references, 10 figures; Invited talk given at the American
  Physical Society April Meeting 2017, Washington, DC, January 28, 2017; based
  mainly on arXiv:1604.07411 [hep-ph] and arXiv:1608.03591 [hep-ph]</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 32 (2017) 1730020</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17300204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the current status of the anomaly in beryllium-8 nuclear
transitions recently reported in the angular distribution of internal
conversion electron-positron pairs. We present a phenomenological analysis of
the signal and review the models proposed to explain it, focusing on those
involving a new light protophobic vector gauge boson. We also elaborate on the
prospects of verifying the anomaly in present and future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02554</id><created>2017-08-08</created><updated>2017-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Daqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perc</keyname><forenames>Matjaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yangsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Dezhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency-difference-dependent stochastic resonance in neural systems</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>6 two-column pages, 7 figures; accepted for publication in Physical
  Review E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96 (2017) 022415</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biological neurons receive multiple noisy oscillatory signals, and their
dynamical response to the superposition of these signals is of fundamental
importance for information processing in the brain. Here we study the response
of neural systems to the weak envelope modulation signal, which is superimposed
by two periodic signals with different frequencies. We show that stochastic
resonance occurs at the beat frequency in neural systems at the single-neuron
as well as the population level. The performance of this
frequency-difference-dependent stochastic resonance is influenced by both the
beat frequency and the two forcing frequencies. Compared to a single neuron, a
population of neurons is more efficient in detecting the information carried by
the weak envelope modulation signal at the beat frequency. Furthermore, an
appropriate fine-tuning of the excitation-inhibition balance can further
optimize the response of a neural ensemble to the superimposed signal. Our
results thus introduce and provide insights into the generation and modulation
mechanism of the frequency-difference-dependent stochastic resonance in neural
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05705</id><created>2017-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Wardil</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaral</keyname><forenames>Marco A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooperation in public goods games: stay, but not for too long</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><doi>10.3390/g8030035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cooperation in repeated public goods game is hardly achieved, unless
contingent behavior is present. Surely, if mechanisms promoting positive
assortment between cooperators are present, then cooperators may beat
defectors, because cooperators would collect greater payoffs. In the context of
evolutionary game theory, individuals that always cooperate cannot win the
competition against defectors in well-mixed populations. Here, we study the
evolution of a population where fitness is obtained in repeated public goods
games and players have a fixed probability of playing the next round. As a
result, the group size decreases during the game. The population is well-mixed
and there are only two available strategies: always cooperate (ALLC) or always
defect (ALLD). Through numerical calculation and analytical approximations we
show that cooperation can emerge if the players stay playing the game, but not
for too long. The essential mechanism is the interaction between the transition
from strong to weak altruism, as the group size decreases, and the existence of
an upper limit to the number of rounds representing limited time availability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06849</id><created>2017-08-22</created><updated>2017-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brough</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croom</keyname><forenames>Scott M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Roger L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van de Sande</keyname><forenames>Jesse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>Joss</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bryant</keyname><forenames>Julia J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cortese</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Eugenio</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Federrath</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreras</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodwin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groves</keyname><forenames>Brent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konstantopoulos</keyname><forenames>Iraklis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawrence</keyname><forenames>Jon S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medling</keyname><forenames>Anne M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moffett</keyname><forenames>Amanda J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owers</keyname><forenames>Matt S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richards</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robotham</keyname><forenames>A. S. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonini</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Sukyoung K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The SAMI Galaxy Survey: Global stellar populations on the size-mass
  plane</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>25 pages, 18 figures, MNRAS in press Corrected typo in author list</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2166</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analysis of the global stellar populations of galaxies in the
SAMI Galaxy Survey. Our sample consists of 1319 galaxies spanning four orders
of magnitude in stellar mass and includes all morphologies and environments. We
derive luminosity-weighted, single stellar population equivalent stellar ages,
metallicities and alpha enhancements from spectra integrated within one
effective radius apertures. Variations in galaxy size explain the majority of
the scatter in the age--mass and metallicity--mass relations. Stellar
populations vary systematically in the plane of galaxy size and stellar mass,
such that galaxies with high stellar surface mass density are older, more
metal-rich and alpha-enhanced than less dense galaxies. Galaxies with high
surface mass densities have a very narrow range of metallicities, however, at
fixed mass, the spread in metallicity increases substantially with increasing
galaxy size (decreasing density). We identify residual correlations with
morphology and environment. At fixed mass and size, galaxies with late-type
morphologies, small bulges and low Sersic n are younger than early-type, high
n, high bulge-to-total galaxies. Age and metallicity both show small residual
correlations with environment; at fixed mass and size, galaxies in denser
environments or more massive halos are older and somewhat more metal rich than
those in less dense environments. We connect these trends to evolutionary
tracks within the size--mass plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07514</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Josiah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bildsten</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author></authors><title>The Importance of Urca-process Cooling in Accreting ONe White Dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>19 pages, 23 figures; Accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2169</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the evolution of accreting oxygen-neon (ONe) white dwarfs (WDs),
with a particular emphasis on the effects of the presence of the carbon-burning
products $\mathrm{^{23}Na}$ and $\mathrm{^{25}Mg}$. These isotopes lead to
substantial cooling of the WD via the $\mathrm{^{25}Mg}$-$\mathrm{^{25}Na}$,
$\mathrm{^{23}Na}$-$\mathrm{^{23}Ne}$, and
$\mathrm{^{25}Na}$-$\mathrm{^{25}Ne}$ Urca pairs. We derive an analytic formula
for the peak Urca-process cooling rate and use it to obtain a simple expression
for the temperature to which the Urca process cools the WD. Our estimates are
equally applicable to accreting carbon-oxygen WDs. We use the Modules for
Experiments in Stellar Astrophysics (MESA) stellar evolution code to evolve a
suite of models that confirm these analytic results and demonstrate that
Urca-process cooling substantially modifies the thermal evolution of accreting
ONe WDs. Most importantly, we show that MESA models with lower temperatures at
the onset of the $\mathrm{^{24}Mg}$ and $\mathrm{^{24}Na}$ electron captures
develop convectively unstable regions, even when using the Ledoux criterion. We
discuss the difficulties that we encounter in modeling these convective regions
and outline the potential effects of this convection on the subsequent WD
evolution. For models in which we do not allow convection to operate, we find
that oxygen ignites around a density of $\log(\rho_{\rm c}/\rm g\,cm^{-3})
\approx 9.95$, very similar to the value without Urca cooling. Nonetheless, the
inclusion of the effects of Urca-process cooling is an important step in
producing progenitor models with more realistic temperature and composition
profiles which are needed for the evolution of the subsequent oxygen
deflagration and hence for studies of the signature of accretion-induced
collapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07515</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Andriiashen</keyname><forenames>Vladyslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozhevnikov</keyname><forenames>Danila</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast optimal decomposed modification of FDK with potential decreasing of
  memory consuming</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new algorithm for 3D cone-beam tomography. The algorithm is
based on decomposition of the cone-beam backprojection operation and angular
decimation. It has computational complexity of $O(N^{3.5})$ and allows
considerable reduction of peak memory usage in comparison with conventional
algorithms. Tests with real data demonstrate the acceleration, achieved by
using our algorithm instead of FDK, with 20-fold speedup for a $2000 \times
2000 \times 720$ image. The algorithm is compared with other fast FDK
algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07519</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>d'Enterria</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snigirev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Double, triple, and $n$-parton scatterings in high-energy proton and
  nuclear collisions</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE hep-ex nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>33 pages, 9 figures. Review chapter in &quot;Multiple parton interactions
  at the LHC&quot;, Bartalini &amp; Gaunt eds., World Scientific</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The framework to compute the cross sections for the production of particles
with high mass and/or large transverse momentum in double- (DPS), triple-
(TPS), and in general $n$-parton scatterings, from the corresponding
single-parton ($\sigma_{\rm SPS}$) values in high-energy proton-proton,
proton-nucleus, and nucleus-nucleus is reviewed. The basic parameter of the
factorized $n$-parton scattering ansatz is an effective cross section
$\sigma_{\rm eff}$ encoding all unknowns about the underlying generalized
$n$-parton distribution in the proton (nucleon). In its simplest and most
economical form, the $\sigma_{\rm eff}$ parameter can be derived from the
transverse parton profile of the colliding protons and/or nucleus, using a
Glauber approach. Numerical examples for the cross sections and yields expected
for the concurrent DPS or TPS production of heavy-quarks, quarkonia, and/or
gauge bosons in proton and nuclear collisions at LHC and Future Circular
Collider (FCC) energies are provided. The obtained cross sections are based on
perturbative QCD predictions for $\sigma_{\rm SPS}$ at next-to-leading-order
(NLO) or next-to-NLO (NNLO) accuracy including, when needed, nuclear
modifications of the corresponding parton densities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07528</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Guerboukha</keyname><forenames>Hichem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nallappan</keyname><forenames>Kathirvel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skorobogatiy</keyname><forenames>Maksim</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploiting k-space - frequency duality in Fourier optics towards
  real-time compression-less terahertz imaging</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present theoretical formulation and experimental demonstration of a novel
technique for the fast compression-less terahertz imaging based on the
broadband Fourier optics. The technique exploits k-vector/frequency duality in
Fourier optics which allows using a single-pixel detector to perform angular
scan along a circular path, while the broadband spectrum is used to scan along
the radial dimension in Fourier domain. The proposed compression-less image
reconstruction technique (hybrid inverse transform) requires only a small
number of measurements that scales linearly with the image linear size, thus
promising real-time acquisition of high-resolution THz images. Additionally,
our imaging technique handles equally well and on the equal theoretical footing
the amplitude contrast and the phase contrast images, which makes this
technique useful for many practical applications. A detailed analysis of the
novel technique advantages and limitations is presented, as well as its place
among other existing THz imaging techniques is clearly identified
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07534</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolotova</keyname><forenames>Yuliya V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Safro</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting and monitoring foodborne illness outbreaks: Twitter
  communications and the 2015 U.S. Salmonella outbreak linked to imported
  cucumbers</title><categories>stat.AP cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This research uses Twitter, as a social media device, to track communications
related to the 2015 U.S. foodborne illness outbreak linked to Salmonella in
imported cucumbers from Mexico. The relevant Twitter data are analyzed in light
of the timeline of the official announcements made by the Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention (CDC). The largest number of registered tweets is
associated with the period immediately following the CDC initial announcement
and the official release of the first recall of cucumbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07537</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Freire</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author></authors><title>Memory matrix theory of the dc resistivity of a disordered
  antiferromagnetic metal with an effective composite operator</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 384, 142 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.07.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform the calculation of the dc resistivity as a function of temperature
of the &quot;strange-metal&quot; state that emerges in the vicinity of a
spin-density-wave phase transition in the presence of weak disorder. This
scenario is relevant to the phenomenology of many important correlated
materials, such as, e.g., the pnictides, the heavy-fermion compounds and the
cuprates. To accomplish this task, we implement the memory-matrix approach that
allows the calculation of the transport coefficients of the model beyond the
quasiparticle paradigm. Our computation is also inspired by the $\epsilon=3-d$
expansion in a hot-spot model embedded in $d$-space dimensions recently put
forth by Sur and Lee [Phys. Rev. B 91, 125136 (2015)], in which they find a new
low-energy non-Fermi liquid fixed point that is perturbatively accessible near
three dimensions. As a consequence, we are able to establish here the
temperature and doping dependence of the electrical resistivity at intermediate
temperatures of a two-dimensional disordered antiferromagnetic metallic model
with a composite operator that couples the order-parameter fluctuations to the
entire Fermi surface. We argue that our present theory provides a good basis in
order to unify the experimental transport data, e.g., in the cuprates and the
pnictide superconductors, within a wide range of doping regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07553</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldsmith</keyname><forenames>Paul F.</forenames><affiliation>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kauffmann</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institut f&#xfc;r Radioastronomie, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Electron Excitation of High Dipole Moment Molecules Reexamined</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 841, Issue 1, article id. 25, 11
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6f12</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Emission from high-dipole moment molecules such as HCN allows determination
of the density in molecular clouds, and is often considered to trace the
&quot;dense&quot; gas available for star formation. We assess the importance of electron
excitation in various environments. The ratio of the rate coefficients for
electrons and H$_2$ molecules, $\simeq$10$^5$ for HCN, yields the requirements
for electron excitation to be of practical importance if $n({\rm H}_2) \leq\
10^{5.5} ~ \rm cm^{-3}$ and $X({\rm e}^-) \geq\ 10^{-5}$, where the numerical
factors reflect critical values $n_{\rm{}c}({\rm H_2})$ and $X^*({\rm{}e}^-)$.
This indicates that in regions where a large fraction of carbon is ionized,
$X({\rm e}^-)$ will be large enough to make electron excitation significant.
The situation is in general similar for other &quot;high density tracers&quot;, including
HCO$^+$, CN, and CS. But there are significant differences in the critical
electron fractional abundance, $X^*({\rm e}^-)$, defined by the value required
for equal effect from collisions with H$_2$ and e$^-$. Electron excitation is,
for example, unimportant for CO and C$^+$. Electron excitation may be
responsible for the surprisingly large spatial extent of the emission from
dense gas tracers in some molecular clouds (Pety et al. 2017; Kauffmann,
Goldsmith et al. 2017). The enhanced estimates for HCN abundances and HCN/CO
and HCN/HCO$^+$ ratios observed in the nuclear regions of luminous galaxies may
be in part a result of electron excitation of high dipole moment tracers. The
importance of electron excitation will depend on detailed models of the
chemistry, which may well be non-steady state and non-static.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07564</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Delmastro</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>BMS in higher space-time dimensions and Non-relativistic BMS</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Master's thesis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Master's thesis. We present a study of the BMS Group is higher space-time
dimensions, and the extension of this group to non-relativistic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07574</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Escudero</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sourrouille</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ardenghi</keyname><forenames>Juan Sebasti&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jasen</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetization in pristine graphene with Zeeman splitting and variable
  spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Superlattices and Microstructures, 101, 537-546 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.spmi.2016.10.086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this work is to describe the spin magnetization of graphene with
Rashba spinorbit coupling and Zeeman effect. It is shown that the magnetization
depends critically on the spin-orbit coupling l that is controlled with an
external electric field. In turn, by manipulating the density of charge
carriers, it is shown that spin up and down Landau levels mix introducing jumps
in the spin magnetization. Two magnetic oscillations phases are described that
can be tunable through the applied external fields. The maximum and minimum of
the oscillations can be alternated by taking into account how the energy levels
are filled when the Rashba-spin-orbit coupling is turned on. The results
obtained are of importance to design superlattices with variable spin-orbit
coupling with different configurations in which spin oscillations and spin
filters can be developed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07577</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Dasarthy</keyname><forenames>Anirudh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isaacson</keyname><forenames>Joshua P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones-Smith</keyname><forenames>Katherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tabachnik</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathur</keyname><forenames>Harsh</forenames></author></authors><title>The particle in a box in PT quantum mechanics and an electromagnetic
  analog</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Published in 2013, previously unavailable on arxiv</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 87.6 (2013): 062111</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.87.062111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In PT quantum mechanics a fundamental principle of quantum mechanics, that
the Hamiltonian must be hermitian, is replaced by another set of requirements,
including notably symmetry under PT, where P denotes parity and T denotes time
reversal. Here we study the role of boundary conditions in PT quantum mechanics
by constructing a simple model that is the PT symmetric analog of a particle in
a box. The model has the usual particle in a box Hamiltonian but boundary
conditions that respect PT symmetry rather than hermiticity. We find that for a
broad class of PT-symmetric boundary conditions the model respects the
condition of unbroken PT-symmetry, namely that the Hamiltonian and the symmetry
operator PT have simultaneous eigenfunctions, implying that the energy
eigenvalues are real. We also find that the Hamiltonian is self-adjoint under
the PT inner product. Thus we obtain a simple soluble model that fulfils all
the requirements of PT quantum mechanics. In the second part of this paper we
formulate a variational principle for PT quantum mechanics that is the analog
of the textbook Rayleigh-Ritz principle. Finally we consider electromagnetic
analogs of the PT-symmetric particle in a box. We show that the isolated
particle in a box may be realized as a Fabry-Perot cavity between an absorbing
medium and its conjugate gain medium. Coupling the cavity to an external
continuum of incoming and outgoing states turns the energy levels of the box
into sharp resonances. Remarkably we find that the resonances have a
Breit-Wigner lineshape in transmission and a Fano lineshape in reflection; by
contrast in the corresponding hermitian case the lineshapes always have a
Breit-Wigner form in both transmission and reflection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07588</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Tison</keyname><forenames>Christopher C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneeloch</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alsing</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Central Moment Analogues to Linear Optically Generated Cluster States</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-mode squeezed states in the limit of small squeezing, Hong-Ou-Mandel
interference and post selection on coincidence counts are some of the staples
of linear quantum optics. We show that by using classical expectations on
central moments of intensities, we can remove the requirement of small
squeezing necessary for high fidelity coincidence detection. Utilizing existing
techniques to probabilistically generate a cluster state, we construct a
statistical analogue with deterministic generation at the cost of losing the
ability to feed forward and requiring statistical averaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07599</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Olinto</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aloisio</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anchordoqui</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergman</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertaina</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertone</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustamante</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christl</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csorna</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eser</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fenu</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;pin</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hays</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunter</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Judd</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jun</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotera</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krizmanic</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackovjak</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez-Sierra</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastafa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>J. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEnery</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neronov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otte</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parizot</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkins</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prevot</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reardon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reno</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarazin</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shinozaki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stecker</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Streitmatter</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venters</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiencke</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>POEMMA: Probe Of Extreme Multi-Messenger Astrophysics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, in the Proceedings of the 35th International Cosmic Ray
  Conference, ICRC217, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Probe Of Extreme Multi-Messenger Astrophysics (POEMMA) mission is being
designed to establish charged-particle astronomy with ultra-high energy cosmic
rays (UHECRs) and to observe cosmogenic tau neutrinos (CTNs). The study of
UHECRs and CTNs from space will yield orders-of-magnitude increase in
statistics of observed UHECRs at the highest energies, and the observation of
the cosmogenic flux of neutrinos for a range of UHECR models. These
observations should solve the long-standing puzzle of the origin of the highest
energy particles ever observed, providing a new window onto the most energetic
environments and events in the Universe, while studying particle interactions
well beyond accelerator energies. The discovery of CTNs will help solve the
puzzle of the origin of UHECRs and begin a new field of Astroparticle Physics
with the study of neutrino properties at ultra-high energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07613</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Julie V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gowrishankar</keyname><forenames>Thiruvallur R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Kyle C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weaver</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Broad pore lifetime distributions: A fundamental concept for cell
  electroporation</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Version01 August 24, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a concept that has the potential to change how we think about the
underlying mechanisms of cell membrane electroporation (EP). Prior
experimental, theoretical and modeling have emphasized a single pore lifetime
as adequate for particular conditions. Here we introduce a much more complex
response: The rapid creation of many types of pore structures, of which some
are traditional transient lipidic pores (TPs), but the great majority are
complex pores (CPs) based on both lipids and other molecules or molecular
segments. At the inner leaflet of the cell plasma membrane (PM) non-lipidic
molecules come from the over-crowded cytoplasm. At the outer leaflet they
originate from the extracellular medium and extracellular matrix. Some
partially or fully insert into TPs during or shortly after TP formation, or
bind to the membrane nearby. This process is complex, leading to mostly
short-lived structures, with relatively few lasting for long times. We
speculate that the characteristic pore lifetimes range from $\sim$100 ns to
1,000 s, based on implications from experiments. The frequency-of-occurrence
probably falls off extremely rapidly with increasing lifetime, $\tau_{CP}$,
which implies that most are inaccessible to traditional experimental methods.
It also suggests that unexpected behavior can occur early in pulsing, vanishing
before post-pulse observations begin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07623</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ambethkar</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kushawaha</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Simulations of 2-D Steady Free Convective flow with Heat and
  Mass Transfer in an Inclined Rectangular Domain</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.comp-ph</categories><msc-class>35Q307, 6D05, 76M20, 80A20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we have used the QUICK scheme of the finite volume method to
investigate the problem of steady 2-D free convective incompressible flow with
heat and mass transfer in an inclined rectangular domain at different Rayleigh
numbers in the range of $10^4 \le Ra \le 10^6$, for Prandtl number $Pr=7.2$,
and Lewis number $Le=1$. We have used no-slip wall boundary conditions for the
components of velocity and Neumann boundary conditions for temperature and
concentration. We have used the QUICK scheme to discretize the governing
equations along with the boundary conditions chosen in the present problem. The
SIMPLE algorithm is adopted to compute the numerical solutions of flow
variables, $U$-velocity, $V$-velocity, pressure, temperature, and concentration
as well as the local and average Nusselt and Sherwood numbers at different
Rayleigh numbers in the range mentioned above. Our numerical solutions for
$U$-velocity along the vertical line through the geometric center has been
compared with benchmark solutions available in the literature for
$\lambda=15^{\circ},\, Ra=10^4,\, Pr=7.2$, and $Le=1$ and it has been found
that it is in the good agreement. Pressure increases with increasing the angles
of inclination. When the angles of inclination increase from
$\lambda=15^{\circ}$ to $\lambda=45^{\circ}$, the intensity of streamlines
decreases near the center and secondary cells are formed at the top and bottom
of the center of the domain. As the Rayleigh number is increased from $10^4$ to
$10^6$, the average Nusselt number is decreased for $\lambda=15^{\circ}$, and
decreases and then increases for $\lambda=45^{\circ}$, whereas, the average
Sherwood number increases for $\lambda=15^{\circ}$ and decreases for
$\lambda=45^{\circ}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07631</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez</keyname><forenames>Leopoldo R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xe1;s A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Register</keyname><forenames>Richard A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vega</keyname><forenames>Daniel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pattern formation mechanisms in sphere-forming diblock copolymer thin
  films</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures, submitted to Papers in Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The order-disorder transition of a sphere-forming block copolymer thin film
was numerically studied through a Cahn-Hilliard model. Simulations show that
the fundamental mechanisms of pattern formation are spinodal decomposition and
nucleation and growth. The range of validity of each relaxation process is
controlled by the spinodal and order-disorder temperatures. The initial stages
of spinodal decomposition are well-approximated by a linear analysis of the
evolution equation of the system. In the metastable region, the critical size
for nucleation diverges upon approaching the order-disorder transition, and
reduces to the size of a single domain as the spinodal is approached. Grain
boundaries and topological defects inhibit the formation of superheated phases
above the order-disorder temperature. The numerical results are in good
qualitative agreement with experimental data on sphere-forming diblock
copolymer thin films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07635</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mass retention efficiencies of He accretion onto carbon-oxygen white
  dwarfs and type Ia supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables, published in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics
  (A&amp;A 604, A31, 2017)</comments><journal-ref>AA/2016/30099</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201630099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) play a crucial role in studying cosmology and
galactic chemical evolution. They are thought to be thermonuclear explosions of
carbon-oxygen white dwarfs (CO WDs) when their masses reach the Chandrasekar
mass limit in binaries. Previous studies have suggested that He novae may be
progenitor candidates of SNe Ia. However, the mass retention efficiencies
during He nova outbursts are still uncertain. In this article, we aim to study
the mass retention efficiencies of He nova outbursts and to investigate whether
SNe Ia can be produced through He nova outbursts. Using the stellar evolution
code Modules for Experiments in Stellar Astrophysics, we simulated a series of
multicycle He-layer flashes, in which the initial WD masses range from 0.7 to
1.35 Msun with various accretion rates. We obtained the mass retention
efficiencies of He nova outbursts for various initial WD masses, which can be
used in the binary population synthesis studies. In our simulations, He nova
outbursts can increase the mass of the WD to the Chandrasekar mass limit and
the explosive carbon burning can be triggered in the center of the WD; this
suggests that He nova outbursts can produce SNe Ia. Meanwhile, the mass
retention efficiencies in the present work are lower than those of previous
studies, which leads to a lower birthrates of SNe Ia through the WD + He star
channel. Furthermore, we obtained the elemental abundances distribution at the
moment of explosive carbon burning, which can be used as the initial input
parameters in studying explosion models of SNe Ia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07654</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Audo</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alouini</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author></authors><title>Intensity noise self-regulated solid-state laser at 1.5${\mu}$m using an
  ASHG based Buffer Reservoir</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An absorption mechanism based on second-harmonic generation (ASHG) is
successfully implemented as a buffer reservoir in a solid-state Er,Yb:Glass
laser emitting at telecom wavelength. We show that a slight ASHG rate
conversion of 0.016% using a BBO crystal enables to cancel out the excess
intensity noise at the relaxation oscillation frequency, i.e. 35 dB reduction,
as well as to cancel the amplified spontaneous emission beating at the free
spectral range resonances of the laser lying in the GHz range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07664</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Shoaib</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashif</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szucs-Csillik</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the planar central configurations of rhomboidal and triangular four-
  and five-body problems</title><categories>astro-ph.EP math.DS</categories><comments>22 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s10509-017-3161-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a symmetric five-body problem with three unequal collinear masses
on the axis of symmetry. The remaining two masses are symmetrically placed on
both sides of the axis of symmetry. Regions of possible central configurations
are derived for the four- and five-body problems. These regions are determined
analytically and explored numerically. The equations of motion are regularized
using Levi-Civita type transformations and then the phase space is investigated
for chaotic and periodic orbits by means of Poincar\'e surface of sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07666</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Haiyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yueling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Gongru</forenames></author></authors><title>$B^{\ast}$ ${\to}$ $\bar{D}D$ decays with perturbative QCD approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G. 44, 075007 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa7294</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The nonleptonic two-body $B^{\ast}$ ${\to}$ $\bar{D}D$ weak decays are
studied phenomenologically with the perturbative QCD factorization approach. It
is found that the $B_{s}^{{\ast}0}$ ${\to}$ $D_{s}^{-}D_{s}^{+}$,
$B_{d}^{{\ast}0}$ ${\to}$ $D_{d}^{-}D_{s}^{+}$, and $B_{u}^{{\ast}+}$ ${\to}$
$\bar{D}_{u}^{0}D_{s}^{+}$ decays have branching ratios ${\gtrsim}$ $10^{-9}$,
and might be promisingly measurable at the running LHC and forthcoming
SuperKEKB experiments in the future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07667</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Djuvsland</keyname><forenames>Julia Isabell</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the ATLAS Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Studying $WW\gamma$ and $WZ\gamma$ production in proton-proton
  collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV with the ATLAS experiment</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings of the Fifth AnnualLHCP</comments><report-no>ATL-PHYS-PROC-2017-095</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quartic gauge couplings are tested by this study of the production of
$WW\gamma$ and $WZ\gamma$ events in 20.2 fb$^{-1}$ of proton--proton collisions
at a centre-of-mass energy of $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV recorded with the ATLAS
detector at the LHC. The final state of $WW\gamma$ events containing an
electron, a muon and a photon is analysed as well as the final states of
$WW\gamma$ and $WZ\gamma$ production containing an electron or a muon, two jets
and a photon. For all final states two different fiducial regions are defined:
one yielding the best sensitivity to the production cross-section of the
process and one optimised for the detection of new physical phenomena. In the
former region, the $WW\gamma$ production cross-section is computed and in both
regions, upper limits on the $WW\gamma$ and $WZ\gamma$ production cross-section
are derived. The results obtained in the second phase space are combined for
the interpretation in the context of anomalous quartic gauge couplings using an
effective field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07668</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yueling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Gongru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jinshu</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the $\bar{B}_{q}^{\ast}$ ${\to}$ $DM$ decays with perturbative
  QCD approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>34 pages, 3 figures, revtex</comments><journal-ref>Phys Rev D 96, 036010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.036010</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The $\bar{B}_{q}^{\ast}$ ${\to}$ $DP$, $DV$ weak decays are studied with the
perturbative QCD approach, where $q$ $=$ $u$, $d$ and $s$; $P$ and $V$ denote
the ground $SU(3)$ pseudoscalar and vector meson nonet. It is found that the
branching ratios for the color-allowed $\bar{B}_{q}^{\ast}$ ${\to}$
$D_{q}{\rho}^{-}$ decays can reach up to $10^{-9}$ or more, and should be
promisingly measurable at the running LHC and forthcoming SuperKEKB experiments
in the near future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07672</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bella</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giunti</keyname><forenames>Arianna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Multipoles in Random media</title><categories>math.AP cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.PR</categories><comments>60 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a homogeneous medium, the far-field generated by a localized source can be
expanded in terms of multipoles; the coefficients are determined by the moments
of the localized charge distribution. We show that this structure survives to
some extent for a random medium in the sense of quantitative stochastic
homogenization: In three space dimensions, the effective dipole and quadrupole
- but not the octupole - can be inferred without knowing the realization of the
random medium far away from the (overall neutral) source and the point of
interest.
  Mathematically, this is achieved by using the two-scale expansion to higher
order to construct isomorphisms between the hetero- and homogeneous versions of
spaces of harmonic functions that grow at a certain rate, or decay at a certain
rate away from the singularity (near the origin); these isomorphisms crucially
respect the natural pairing between growing and decaying harmonic functions
given by the second Green's formula. This not only yields effective multipoles
(the quotient of the spaces of decaying functions) but also intrinsic moments
(taken with respect to the elements of the spaces of growing functions). The
construction of these rigid isomorphisms relies on a good (and
dimension-dependent) control on the higher-order correctors and their flux
potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07682</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oda</keyname><forenames>Kent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ono</keyname><forenames>Teruo</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin torque control of antiferromagnetic moments in NiO</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a long time, there have been no efficient ways of controlling
antiferromagnets. Quite a strong magnetic field was required to manipulate the
magnetic moments because of a high molecular field and a small magnetic
susceptibility. It was also difficult to detect the orientation of the magnetic
moments since the net magnetic moment is effectively zero. For these reasons,
research on antiferromagnets has not been progressed as drastically as that on
ferromagnets which are the main materials in modern spintronic devices. Here we
show that the magnetic moments in NiO, a typical natural antiferromagnet, can
indeed be controlled by the spin torque with a relatively small electric
current density (~5 x 10^7 A/cm^2) and their orientation is detected by the
transverse resistance resulting from the spin Hall magnetoresistance . The
demonstrated techniques of controlling and detecting antiferromagnets would
outstandingly promote the methodologies in the recently emerged
&quot;antiferromagnetic spintronics&quot;. Furthermore, our results essentially lead to a
spin torque antiferromagnetic memory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07684</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kondej</keyname><forenames>Sylwia</forenames></author></authors><title>Straight quantum layer with impurities inducing resonances</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>J.Phys.A: Math.Theor. vol. 50, No 31, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a straight three dimensional quantum layer with singular
potential supported on a straight wire which is localized perpendicularly to
the walls and connects them. We prove that the infinite number of embedded
eigenvalues appears in this system. Furthermore, we show that after introducing
a small surface impurity to the layer, the embedded eigenvalues turn to the
second sheet resolvent poles which state resonances. We discuss the asymptotics
of the imaginary component of the resolvent pole with respect to the surface
area.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07686</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Hands</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical study of the $2+1d$ Thirring model with U($2N$)-invariant
  fermions</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>talk at 35th International Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice
  2017), Granada, Spain</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2+1 dimensions the global U($2N$) symmetry associated with massless Dirac
fermions is broken to U($N)\otimes$U($N$) by a parity-invariant mass. I will
show how to adapt the domain wall formulation to recover the U($2N$)-invariant
limit in interacting fermion models as the domain wall separation is increased.
In particular, I will focus on the issue of potential dynamical mass generation
in the Thirring model, postulated to take place for $N$ less than some critical
$N_c$. I will present results of simulations of the model using both HMC
($N=2$) and RHMC ($N=1$) algorithms, and show that the outcome is very
different from previous numerical studies of the model made with staggered
fermions, where the corresponding pattern of symmetry breaking is distinct.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07688</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07688</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Amritendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Mainak</forenames></author><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Partha Sarathi</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase partitioning in a novel near equi-atomic AlCuFeMn alloy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel low cost, near equi-atomic alloy comprising of Al, Cu, Fe and Mn is
synthesized using arc-melting technique. The cast alloy possesses a dendritic
microstructure where the dendrites consist of disordered FCC and ordered FCC
phases. The inter-dendritic region is comprised of ordered FCC phase and
spinodally decomposed BCC phases. A Cu segregation is observed in the
inter-dendritic region while dendritic region is rich in Fe. The bulk hardness
of the alloy is ~ 380 HV, indicating significant yield strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07699</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicolleau</keyname><forenames>F. C. G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sung</keyname><forenames>K. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vassilicos</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vertical motions of heavy inertial particles smaller than the smallest
  scale of the turbulence in strongly stratified turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Keywords: Particle dispersion and Kinematic Simulation and Rapid
  Distortion \nd Stratified turbulence</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Flow, Turbulence and Combustion, Springer Verlag (Germany), 2013,
  91 (1), pp.79 - 103</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10494-013-9456-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the statistics of the vertical motion of inertial particles in
strongly stratified turbulence. We use Kinematic Simulation (KS) and Rapid
Distortion Theory (RDT) to study the mean position and the root mean square
(rms) of the position fluctuation in the vertical direction. We vary the
strength of the stratification and the particle inertial characteristic time.
The stratification is modelled using the Boussinesq equation and solved in the
limit of RDT. The validity of the approximations used here requires
that$\sqrt{{L}/{g}}&lt;{2\pi}/{\mathcal{N}}&lt;\tau\_{\eta}$,where $\tau\_{\eta}$ is
the Kolmogorov time scale, $g$ the gravitational acceleration, $L$ the
turbulence integral length scale and $\mathcal{N}$ the Brunt-V\&quot;ais\&quot;al\&quot;a
frequency. We introduce a drift Froude number$Fr\_{d} = \tau\_p g / \mathcal{N}
L$. When $Fr\_{d} &lt; 1$, the rms of the inertial particle displacement
fluctuation is the same as for fluid elements, i.e.$\langle(\zeta\_3 - \langle
\zeta\_3 \rangle)^2\rangle^{1/2} = 1.22\, u'/\mathcal{N} +
\mbox{oscillations}$. However, when $Fr\_{d} &gt; 1$,$\langle(\zeta\_3 - \langle
\zeta\_3 \rangle)^2\rangle^{1/2} = 267 \, u' \tau\_p$. That is the level of the
fluctuation is controlled by the particle inertia $\tau\_p$ andnot by the
buoyancy frequency $\mathcal{N}$. In other words it seems possible for inertial
particles to retain the vertical capping while loosing the memory of
theBrunt-V\&quot;ais\&quot;al\&quot;a frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07702</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Naumov</keyname><forenames>Pavel G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filsinger</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shylin</keyname><forenames>Sergii I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barkalov</keyname><forenames>Oleg I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ksenofontov</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yanpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palasyuk</keyname><forenames>Taras</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnelle</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medvedev</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenblatt</keyname><forenames>Martha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure-induced magnetic collapse and metallization of
  $\mathrm{TlF}{\mathrm{e}}_{1.6}\mathrm{S}{\mathrm{e}}_{2}$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 96, 064109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The crystal structure, magnetic ordering, and electrical resistivity of
TlFe1.6Se2 were studied at high pressures. Below ~7 GPa, TlFe1.6Se2 is an
antiferromagnetically ordered semiconductor with a ThCr2Si2-type structure. The
insulator-to-metal transformation observed at a pressure of ~ 7 GPa is
accompanied by a loss of magnetic ordering and an isostructural phase
transition. In the pressure range ~ 7.5 - 11 GPa a remarkable downturn in
resistivity, which resembles a superconducting transition, is observed below 15
K. We discuss this feature as the possible onset of superconductivity
originating from a phase separation in a small fraction of the sample in the
vicinity of the magnetic transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07707</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Amosov</keyname><forenames>G. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>On tomographic representation on the plane of the space of Schwartz
  operators and its dual</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><journal-ref>Lobachevskii J. Mathematics 38 (2017) 595-599</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that the set of optical quantum tomograms can be provided with
the topology of Frechet space. In such a case the conjugate space will consist
of symbols of quantum observables including all polynomials of the position and
momentum operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07710</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Amosov</keyname><forenames>Grigori G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dnestryan</keyname><forenames>Andrey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the entropy gain under the action of amplitude damping channel on
  qutrit</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Russian Laser Research 35 (2014) 291-294</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After realising qutrit in the form of bipartite system we estimate from below
the entropy gain under the action of the amplitude damping channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07712</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Buggy</keyname><forenames>Yvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;hberg</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>On the hydrodynamics of Bose-condensed fluids subject to
  density-dependent gauge potentials</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>13 pages. Comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When the energy functional of a Bose-condensed state of matter features an
effective gauge potential which depends on the density $\rho$ of the
condensate, the kinetic energy density of the matter field becomes nonlinear in
$\rho$ and additional flow-dependent terms enter the wave equation for the
phase of the condensate wavefunction. To begin with, we consider a certain
class of density-dependent `single-component' gauge potentials, and later
extend this class to encompass more general `multi-component' potentials. The
nonlinear flow terms are cast into the general form of an inner-product between
the velocity field of the fluid and the gauge potential. This is achieved by
introducing a coupling matrix of dimensionless functions $\gamma_{ij}\left(
\rho \right)$, which characterises the particular functional form of the gauge
potential and regulates the strengths of the nonlinear terms accordingly. In
the momentum-transport equation of the fluid, two non-trivial terms emerge due
to the density-dependent vector potential. A body-force of dilation appears as
a product of the gauge potential and the dilation rate of the fluid, while the
fluid stress tensor features a flow-dependent pressure contribution given by
the inner-product of the gauge potential and the current density of the fluid.
This explicit dependence of the fluid pressure on the flow highlights the lack
of Galilean invariance of the nonlinear fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07720</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Acerbi</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>Edwin J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bugs and features. A reply to Smaldino et al. (2017)</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-bio.QM</categories><comments>6 pages, 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide here a reply to: Smaldino, P. E., Aplin, L. M. &amp; Farine D. R., Do
Sigmoidal Acquisition Curves Indicate Conformity? bioRxiv 159038 (2017).
https://doi.org/10.1101/159038
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07724</id><created>2017-07-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xiaohua</forenames></author></authors><title>Discontinuity of curvature on axisymmetric Willmore surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The equilibrium shapes of vesicles are governed by the general shape equation
which is derived from the minimization of the Helfrich elastic free energy and
can be reduced to the Willmore equation in a special case. The general shape
equation is a high order nonlinear partial differential equation and it is very
difficult to find analytical solution even in axisymmetric case, which is
reduced to a seconder ordinary differential equation. Traditional axisymmetric
shape equation is with the turning radius as the variable. Here we study the
shape equation with the tangential angle as the variable. In this case, the
Willmore equation is reduced to the Bernoulli differential equation and the
general solution is obtained conveniently. We find that the curvature in this
solution is discontinuous in some cases, which was ignored by previous
researchers. This solution can satisfy the boundary conditions for open vesicle
with free edges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07728</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venturi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cassano</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunetti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dallacasa</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fanaroff</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugo</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makhatini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oozeer</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>O. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwart</keyname><forenames>J. T. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A MeerKAT view on galaxy clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures Accepted for publication, Proceedings of Science,
  Workshop on &quot;MeerKAT Science: On the Pathway to the SKA&quot;, held in
  Stellenbosch 25-27 May, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Almost two decades of observations of radio emission in galaxy clusters have
proven the existence of relativistic particles and magnetic fields that
generate extended synchrotron emission in the form of radio halos. In the
current scenario, radio halos are generated through re--acceleration of
relativistic electrons by turbulence generated by cluster mergers. Although
this theoretical framework has received increasingly supporting observational
evidence over the last ten years, observations of statistically complete
samples are needed in order to fundamentally test model predictions. In this
paper we briefly review our 7--element Karoo Radio Telescope observations of a
sample of nearby clusters aimed to test the predictions of the turbulent
re--acceleration model in small systems ($M_{500} &gt; 4 \times 10^{14}$
M$_{\odot}$). We conclude by presenting two galaxy cluster surveys to be
carried out with MeerKAT in order to provide crucial test of models of radio
halo formation in nearby ($z &lt; 0.1$) and high redshift ($z &gt; 0.4$) systems
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07736</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Gulevich</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yudin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skryabin</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iorsh</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelykh</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Edge Solitons in Polaritonic Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study discrete nonlinear edge excitations of polaritonic kagome lattice.
We show that when nontrivial topological phase of polaritons is realized, the
kagome lattice permits propagation of bright solitons formed from topological
edge states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07744</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahnert</keyname><forenames>Sebastian E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>William P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickard</keyname><forenames>Chris J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Revealing and exploiting hierarchical material structure through complex
  atomic networks</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures, data available from
  https://figshare.com/articles/Complex_atomic_networks_Ahnert_Grant_and_Pickard_2017/4780456,
  code available from https://www.mtg.msm.cam.ac.uk/Codes/AIRSS (see
  airss/examples/2.3 and 2.4)</comments><journal-ref>npj Computational Materials 3, Article number: 35 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41524-017-0035-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the great challenges of modern science is to faithfully model, and
understand, matter at a wide range of scales. Starting with atoms, the vastness
of the space of possible configurations poses a formidable challenge to any
simulation of complex atomic and molecular systems. We introduce a
computational method to reduce the complexity of atomic configuration space by
systematically recognising hierarchical levels of atomic structure, and
identifying the individual components. Given a list of atomic coordinates, a
network is generated based on the distances between the atoms. Using the
technique of modularity optimisation, the network is decomposed into modules.
This procedure can be performed at different resolution levels, leading to a
decomposition of the system at different scales, from which hierarchical
structure can be identified. By considering the amount of information required
to represent a given modular decomposition we can furthermore find the most
succinct descriptions of a given atomic ensemble. Our straightforward,
automatic and general approach is applied to complex crystal structures. We
show that modular decomposition of these structures considerably simplifies
configuration space, which in turn can be used in discovery of novel crystal
structures, and opens up a pathway towards accelerated molecular dynamics of
complex atomic ensembles. The power of this approach is demonstrated by the
identification of a possible allotrope of boron containing 56 atoms in the
primitive unit cell, which we uncover using an accelerated structure search,
based on a modular decomposition of a known dense phase of boron,
$\gamma$-B$_{28}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07750</id><created>2017-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Deng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin-He</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved constraints on the dark energy equation of state using Gaussian
  processes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 023508 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.023508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a comprehensive study of the dark energy equation of state (EoS)
utilizing the model-independent Gaussian processes (GP). Using a combination of
the Union 2.1 data set, the 30 newly added H(z) cosmic chronometer data points
and Planck's shift parameter, we modify the usual GaPP code and provide a
tighter constraint on the dark energy EoS than the previous literature about GP
reconstructions. Subsequently, we take the &quot;controlling variable method&quot; to
investigate directly the effects of variable matter density parameter
$\Omega_{m0}$, variable cosmic curvature $\Omega_{k0}$ and variable Hubble
constant $H_0$ on the dark energy EoS, respectively. We find that too small or
large $\Omega_{m0}$, $\Omega_{k0}$ and $H_0$ are all disfavored by our GP
reconstructions based on current cosmological observations. Subsequently, we
find that variable $\Omega_{m0}$ and $\Omega_{k0}$ affect the reconstructions
of the dark energy EoS, but affect hardly the reconstructions of the normalized
comoving distance $D(z)$ and its derivatives $D'(z)$ and $D&quot;(z)$. However,
variable $H_0$ affects the reconstructions of the dark energy EoS by affecting
obviously those of $D(z), D'(z)$ and $D&quot;(z)$. Furthermore, we find that the
results of our reconstructions support substantially the recent local
measurement of $H_0$ reported by Riess et al.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07759</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>David-Barrett</keyname><forenames>Tamas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotkirch</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Asim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Kunal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monsivais</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behncke</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kertesz</keyname><forenames>Janos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaski</keyname><forenames>Kimmo</forenames></author></authors><title>Peer relations with mobile phone data: Best friends and family formation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Earlier attempts to investigate the changes of the role of friendship in
different life stages have failed due to lack of data. We close this gap by
using a large data set of mobile phone calls from a European country in 2007,
to study how the people's call patterns to their close social contacts are
associated with age and gender of the callers. We hypothesize that (i)
communication with peers, defined as callers of similar age, will be most
important during the period of family formation and that (ii) the importance of
best friends defined as same-sex callers of exactly the same age, will be
stronger for women than for men. Results show that the frequency of phone calls
with the same-sex peers in this population turns out to be relatively stable
through life for both men and women. In line with the first hypothesis, there
was a significant increase in the length of the phone calls for callers between
ages 30 to 40 years. Partly in line with the second hypothesis, the increase in
phone calls turned out to be particularly pronounced among females, although
there were only minor gender differences in call frequencies. Furthermore,
women tended to have long phone conversations with their same-age female
friend, and also with somewhat older peers. In sum, we provide evidence from
big data for the adult life stages at which peers are most important, and
suggest that best friends appear to have a niche of their own in human
sociality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07765</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Haas</keyname><forenames>Pierre A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;hn</keyname><forenames>Stephanie S. M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honerkamp-Smith</keyname><forenames>Aurelia R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirkegaard</keyname><forenames>Julius B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Raymond E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanics and Variability of Cell Sheet Folding in the Embryonic
  Inversion of $Volvox$</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph q-bio.TO</categories><comments>37 pages, 26 figures, videos available on request</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Many embryonic deformations during development are the global result of local
cell shape changes and other local active cell sheet deformations.
Morphogenesis does not only therefore rely on the ability of the tissue to
produce these active deformations, but also on the ability to regulate them in
such a way as to overcome the intrinsic variability of and geometric
constraints on the tissue. Here, we explore the interplay of regulation and
variability in the green alga $Volvox$, whose spherical embryos turn themselves
inside out to enable motility. Through a combination of light sheet microscopy
and theoretical analysis, we quantify the variability of this inversion and
analyse its mechanics in detail to show how shape variability arises from a
combination of geometry, mechanics, and active regulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07774</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuperman</keyname><forenames>Marcelo N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laguna</keyname><forenames>Fabiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramson</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanata</keyname><forenames>Adrian Monjeau. Jose Luis</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillations from satiation of predators</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a mathematical model of extinction and coexistence in a generic
predator-prey ecosystem composed of two herbivores in asymmetrical competition
and a hunter exerting a predatory pressure on both species. With the aim of
representing the satiety of hunters when preys are overabundant, we introduce
for the predation behavior a dependence on preys density. Specifically,
predation is modeled as growing proportionally to the presence of herbivores at
low density, and saturating when the total population of prey is sufficiently
large. The model predicts the existence of different regimes depending on the
parameters considered: survival of a single species, coexistence of two species
and extinction of the third one, and coexistence of the three species. But more
interestingly, in some regions parameters space the solutions oscillate in
time, both as a transient phenomena and as persistent oscillations of constant
amplitude. The phenomenon is not present for the more idealized linear
predation model, suggesting that it can be the source of real ecosystems
oscillations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07778</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Materlik</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;nneth</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikolajick</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kersch</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author></authors><title>The impact of charge compensated and uncompensated strontium defects on
  the stabilization of the ferroelectric phase in HfO$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett., vol. 111, no. 8, p. 82902, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Different dopants with their specific dopant concentration can be utilized to
produce ferroelectric HfO$_2$ thin films. In this work it is explored for the
example of Sr in a comprehensive first-principles study. Density functional
calculations reveal structure, formation energy and total energy of the Sr
related defects in HfO$_2$. We found the charge compensated defect including an
associated oxygen vacancy Sr$_\text{Hf}$V$_\text{O}$ to strongly favour the
non-ferroelectric, tetragonal P4$_\text{2}$/mnc phase energetically. In
contrast, the uncompensated defect without oxygen vacancy Sr$_\text{Hf}$
favours the ferroelectric, orthorhombic Pca2$_\text{1}$ phase. According to the
formation energy the uncompensated defect can form easily under oxygen rich
conditions in the production process. Low oxygen partial pressure existing over
the lifetime promotes the loss of oxygen leading to V$_\text{O}$ and, thus, the
destabilization of the ferroelectric, orthorhombic Pca2$_\text{1}$ phase
accompanied by an increase of the leakage current. This study attempts to
fundamentally explain the stabilization of the ferroelectric, orthorhombic
Pca2$_\text{1}$ phase by doping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07779</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>JPAC Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Mathieu</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nys</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pilloni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackura</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhasenko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauk</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczepaniak</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fox</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analyticity Constraints for Hadron Amplitudes: Going High to Heal Low
  Energy Issues</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>JLAB-THY-17-2539</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analyticity constitutes a rigid constraint on hadron scattering amplitudes.
This property is used to relate models in different energy regimes. Using meson
photoproduction as a benchmark, we show how to test contemporary low energy
models directly against high energy data. This method pinpoints deficiencies of
the models and treads a path to further improvement. The implementation of this
technique enables one to produce more stable and reliable partial waves for
future use in hadron spectroscopy and new physics searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07793</id><created>2017-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirzaee</keyname><forenames>Somayeh M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rangan</keyname><forenames>Chitra</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Dynamics of a Two-level System Near a Gold Nanoparticle</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to prepare desired states without allowing time for the atomic
system to spontaneously decay to the ground state is limited by the fact that
Hamiltonian controls cannot affect the purity of the state in question. In this
paper, we discuss how a continuous off-resonant electromagnetic wave can be
used to prepare a desired final quantum state. With the aid of plasmonic
surface-enhancement, by placing a two-level atomic system near a gold
nanoparticle, preparation is accomplished in a reduced period of time and with
lower electric field intensity while the system purity is improved when
compared to an isolated system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
