<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T12:32:50Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-12-25" from="2017-12-25" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0902.0053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0902.0053</id><created>2009-01-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Veres</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagoly</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelemen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horvath</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balazs</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meszaros</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tusnady</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Combined Swift BAT-XRT Lightcurves</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>2008 NANJING GAMMA-RAY BURST CONFERENCE. AIP Conference Proceedings,
  Volume 1065, pp. 35-38 (2008)</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf.Proc.1065:35-38,2008</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.3027947</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we make an attempt to combine the two kinds of data from the
Swift-XRT instrument (windowed timing and photon counting modes) and the from
BAT. A thorough desription of the applied procedure will be given. We apply
various binning techniques to the different data: Bayes blocks, exponential
binning and signal-to-noise type of binning. We present a handful of
lightcurves and some possible applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1105.3785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1105.3785</id><created>2011-05-18</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Rakesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Brijesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Triplon mean-field analysis of an antiferromagnet with degenerate
  Shastry-Sutherland ground states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Commun. 1, 055020 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2399-6528/aa9b0a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We look into the quantum phase diagram of a spin-$\frac{1}{2}$
antiferromagnet on the square lattice with degenerate Shastry-Sutherland ground
states, for which only a schematic phase diagram is known so far. Many exotic
phases were proposed in the schematic phase diagram by the use of exact
diagonalization on very small system sizes. In our present work, an important
extension of this antiferromagnet is introduced and investigated in the
thermodynamic limit using triplon mean-field theory. Remarkably, this
antiferromagnet shows a stable plaquette spin-gapped phase like the original
Shastry-Sutherland antiferromagnet, although both of these antiferromagnets
differ in the Hamiltonian construction and ground state degeneracy. We propose
a sublattice columnar dimer phase which is stabilized by the second and third
neighbor antiferromagnetic Heisenberg exchange interactions. There are also
some commensurate and incommensurate magnetically ordered phases, and other
spin-gapped phases which find their places in the quantum phase diagram.
Mean-field results suggest that there is always a level-crossing phase
transition between two spin gapped phases, whereas in other situations, either
a level-crossing or a continuous phase transition happens.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05838</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parvan</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite size effects in the thermodynamics of a free neutral scalar field</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>9 figures, accepted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Physica A, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exact analytical lattice results for the partition function of the free
neutral scalar field in one spatial dimension in both the configuration and the
momentum space were obtained in the framework of the path integral method. The
symmetric square matrices of the bilinear forms on the vector space of fields
in both configuration space and momentum space were found explicitly. The exact
lattice results for the partition function were generalized to the
three-dimensional spatial momentum space and the main thermodynamic quantities
were derived both on the lattice and in the continuum limit. The thermodynamic
properties and the finite volume corrections to the thermodynamic quantities of
the free real scalar field were studied. We found that on the finite lattice
the exact lattice results for the free massive neutral scalar field agree with
the continuum limit only in the region of small values of temperature and
volume. However, at these temperatures and volumes the continuum physical
quantities for both massive and massless scalar field deviate essentially from
their thermodynamic limit values and recover them only at high temperatures
or/and large volumes in the thermodynamic limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03926</id><created>2015-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hazra</keyname><forenames>Dhiraj Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafieloo</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for a direction in the forest of Lyman-$\alpha$</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 11 (2015) 012</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/11/012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the first test of isotropy of the Universe in the matter dominated
epoch using the Lyman-$\alpha$ forest data from the high redshift quasars
($z&gt;2$) from SDSS-III BOSS-DR9 datasets. Using some specified data cuts, we
obtain the probability distribution function (PDF) of the Lyman-$\alpha$ forest
transmitted flux and use the statistical moments of the PDF to address the
isotropy of the Universe. In an isotropic Universe one would expect the
transmitted flux to have consistent statistical characteristics in different
parts of the sky. We trisect the total survey area of 3275 ${\rm deg}^2$ along
the galactic latitude and using quadrant convention. We also make three
subdivisions in the data for three different signal-to-noise-ratios (SNR).
Finally we obtain and compare the statistical moments in the mean redshifts of
2.3, 2.6 and 2.9. We find, that the moments from all patches agree at all
redshifts and at all SNRs, within 3$\sigma$ uncertainties. Since Lyman-$\alpha$
transmitted flux directly maps the neutral hydrogen distribution in the inter
galactic medium (IGM), our results indicate, within the limited survey area and
sensitivity of the data, the distribution of the neutral hydrogen in the
Universe is consistent with isotropic distribution. We should mention that we
report few deviations from isotropy in the data with low statistical
significance. Increase in survey area and larger amount of data are needed to
make any strong conclusion about these deviations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04793</id><created>2015-06-15</created><updated>2015-10-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;ster</keyname><forenames>Gerta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bungartz</keyname><forenames>Hans-Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Model Construction with Closed Observables</title><categories>math.NA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, 19 figures</comments><msc-class>70-08</msc-class><acm-class>I.6.6; G.1.0</acm-class><doi>10.1137/15M1043613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Performing analysis, optimization and control using simulations of
many-particle systems is computationally demanding when no macroscopic model
for the dynamics of the variables of interest is available. In case
observations on the macroscopic scale can only be produced via legacy simulator
code or live experiments, finding a model for these macroscopic variables is
challenging.
  In this paper, we employ time-lagged embedding theory to construct
macroscopic numerical models from output data of a black box, such as a
simulator or live experiments. Since the state space variables of the
constructed, coarse model are dynamically closed and observable by an
observation function, we call these variables closed observables. The approach
is an online-offline procedure, as model construction from observation data is
performed offline and the new model can then be used in an online phase,
independent of the original. We illustrate the theoretical findings with
numerical models constructed from time series of a two-dimensional ordinary
differential equation system, and from the density evolution of a
transport-diffusion system. Applicability is demonstrated in a real-world
example, where passengers leave a train and the macroscopic model for the
density flow onto the platform is constructed with our approach. If only the
macroscopic variables are of interest, simulation runtimes with the numerical
model are three orders of magnitude lower compared to simulations with the
original fine scale model. We conclude with a brief discussion of possibilities
of numerical model construction in systematic upscaling, network optimization
and uncertainty quantification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04680</id><created>2015-11-15</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hong-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pen</keyname><forenames>Ue-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Er</keyname><forenames>Xinzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xuelei</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic tidal reconstruction</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 103504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.103504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gravitational coupling of a long-wavelength tidal field with small-scale
density fluctuations leads to anisotropic distortions of the locally measured
small-scale matter correlation function. Since the local correlation function
is known to be statistically isotropic in the absence of such tidal
interactions, the tidal distortions can be used to reconstruct the
long-wavelength tidal field and large-scale density field in analogy with the
cosmic microwave background lensing reconstruction. In this paper we present
the theoretical framework of cosmic tidal reconstruction and test the
reconstruction in numerical simulations. We find that the density field on
large scales can be reconstructed with good accuracy and the cross-correlation
coefficient between the reconstructed density field and the original density
field is greater than 0.9 on large scales $(k\lesssim0.1\ h/\mathrm{Mpc})$,
with the filter scale $\sim1.25\ \mathrm{Mpc}/h$. This is useful in the 21cm
intensity mapping survey, where the long-wavelength radial modes are lost due
to a foreground subtraction process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08977</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Appleby</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Jinn-Ouk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hazra</keyname><forenames>Dhiraj Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafieloo</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sypsas</keyname><forenames>Spyros</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct search for features in the primordial bispectrum</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>(v1) 6 pages, 4 figures; (v2) improved results but conclusions not
  changed, to appear in Physics Letters B</comments><report-no>APCTP-Pre2015-027</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 760 (2016) 297-301</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study features in the bispectrum of the primordial curvature perturbation
correlated with the reconstructed primordial power spectrum from the observed
cosmic microwave background temperature data. We first show how the bispectrum
can be completely specified in terms of the power spectrum and its first two
derivatives, valid for any configuration of interest. Then using a
model-independent reconstruction of the primordial power spectrum from the
Planck angular power spectrum of temperature anisotropies, we compute the
bispectrum in different triangular configurations. We find that in the squeezed
limit at k ~ 0.06/Mpc and k ~ 0.014/Mpc there are marginal 2sigma deviations
from the standard featureless bispectrum, which meanwhile is consistent with
the reconstructed bispectrum in the equilateral configuration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01811</id><created>2016-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Agarwalla</keyname><forenames>Bijay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukamel</keyname><forenames>Shaul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable photonic cavity coupled to a voltage-biased double quantum dot
  system: Diagrammatic NEGF approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 035434 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.035434</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate gain in microwave photonic cavities coupled to voltage-biased
double quantum dot systems with an arbitrary strong dot-lead coupling and with
a Holstein-like light-matter interaction, by adapting the diagrammatic Keldysh
nonequilibrium Green's function approach. We compute out-of-equilibrium
properties of the cavity : its transmission, phase response, mean photon
number, power spectrum, and spectral function. We show that by the careful
engineering of these hybrid light-matter systems, one can achieve a significant
amplification of the optical signal with the voltage-biased electronic system
serving as a gain medium. We also study the steady state current across the
device, identifying elastic and inelastic tunnelling processes which involve
the cavity mode. Our results show how recent advances in quantum electronics
can be exploited to build hybrid light-matter systems that behave as
single-atom amplifiers and photon source devices. The diagrammatic Keldysh
approach is primarily discussed for a cavity-coupled double quantum dot
architecture, but it is generalizable to other hybrid light-matter systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01922</id><created>2016-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Agarwalla</keyname><forenames>Bijay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukamel</keyname><forenames>Shaul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant photon gain in large-scale quantum dot circuit-QED systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 121305(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.121305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experiments on the generation of coherent light in
engineered hybrid quantum systems, we investigate gain in a microwave photonic
cavity coupled to quantum dot structures, and develop concrete directions for
achieving a giant amplification in photon transmission. We propose two
architectures for scaling up the electronic gain medium: (i) $N$ double quantum
dot systems (N-DQD), (ii) $M$ quantum dots arranged in series akin to a quantum
cascade laser setup. In both setups, the fermionic reservoirs are voltage
biased, and the quantum dots are coupled to a single-mode cavity. Optical
amplification is explained based on a sum rule for the transmission function,
and it is determined by an intricate competition between two different
processes: charge density response in the gain medium, and cavity losses to
input and output ports. The same design principle is also responsible for the
corresponding giant amplification in other photonic observables, mean photon
number and emission spectrum, thereby realizing a quantum device that behaves
as a giant microwave amplifier.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06309</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06309</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brdar</keyname><forenames>Vedran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopp</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Antineutrino monitoring of spent nuclear fuel</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, matches published version. Antineutrino fluxes
  provided in the supplementary material</comments><report-no>MITP/16-058</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 8, 054050 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.8.054050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Military and civilian applications of nuclear energy have left a significant
amount of spent nuclear fuel over the past 70 years. Currently, in many
countries world wide, the use of nuclear energy is on the rise. Therefore, the
management of highly radioactive nuclear waste is a pressing issue. In this
letter, we explore antineutrino detectors as a tool for monitoring and
safeguarding nuclear waste material. We compute the flux and spectrum of
antineutrinos emitted by spent nuclear fuel elements as a function of time, and
we illustrate the usefulness of antineutrino detectors in several benchmark
scenarios. In particular, we demonstrate how a measurement of the antineutrino
flux can help to re-verify the contents of a dry storage cask in case the
monitoring chain by conventional means gets disrupted. We then comment on the
usefulness of antineutrino detectors at long-term storage facilities such as
Yucca mountain. Finally, we put forward antineutrino detection as a tool in
locating underground &quot;hot spots&quot; in contaminated areas such as the Hanford site
in Washington state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08618</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nie</keyname><forenames>Wenxing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Deping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic ground state of SU(3) Hubbard model on the Lieb lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 053616 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.053616</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the magnetic properties of a repulsive fermionic SU($3$)
Hubbard model on the Lieb lattice from weak to strong interaction by means of
the mean-field approximation. To validate the method we employed, we first
discuss the SU($2$) Hubbard model at the mean-field level, and find that our
results are consistent with known rigorous theorems. We then extend the
calculation to the case of SU($3$) symmetry. We find that, at $4/9$ filling,
the SU$(3)$ symmetry spontaneously breaks into the SU$(2)\times$U$(1)$ symmetry
in the ground state, leading to a staggered ferromagnetic state for any
repulsive $U$ at zero temperature. We then investigate the stability of the
ferromagnetic state by relaxing the filling away from $4/9$, and conclude that
the ferromagnetic state is sensitive but robust to fillings, as it can persist
within a certain filling regime. We also apply the mean-field approximation to
finite temperature to calculate the critical temperature and the critical
entropy of the ferromagnetic state. As the resulting critical entropy per
particle is significantly greater than that can be realized in experiments, we
expect some quasi-long-range-ordered features of such a ferromagnetic state can
be realized and observed with fermionic alkaline-earth-metal(-like) atoms
loaded into optical lattices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01227</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Levitt</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guta</keyname><forenames>Madalin</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification of single-input-single-output quantum linear systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 033825 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.033825</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to investigate system identification for
single-input-single-output general (active or passive) quantum linear systems.
For a given input we address the following questions: (1) Which parameters can
be identified by measuring the output? (2) How can we construct a system
realization from sufficient input-output data? We show that for time-dependent
inputs, the systems which cannot be distinguished are related by symplectic
transformations acting on the space of system modes. This complements a
previous result for passive linear systems. In the regime of stationary quantum
noise input, the output is completely determined by the power spectrum. We
define the notion of global minimality for a given power spectrum, and
characterize globally minimal systems as those with a fully mixed stationary
state. We show that in the case of systems with a cascade realization, the
power spectrum completely fixes the transfer function, so the system can be
identified up to a symplectic transformation. We give a method for constructing
a globally minimal subsystem direct from the power spectrum. Restricting to
passive systems the analysis simplifies so that identifiability may be
completely understood from the eigenvalues of a particular system matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03460</id><created>2016-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Guo Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhen Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of the strong coupling form factors of $\Sigma_bNB$ and
  $\Sigma_c ND$ in QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin.Phys.C 41(8) (2017)083104</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/8/083104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study the strong interaction of the vertexes $\Sigma_bNB$
and $\Sigma_c ND$ using the three-point QCD sum rules under two different dirac
structures. Considering the contributions of the vacuum condensates up to
dimension $5$ in the operation product expansion, the form factors of these
vertexes are calculated. Then, we fit the form factors into analytical
functions and extrapolate them into time-like regions, which giving the
coupling constant. Our analysis indicates that the coupling constant for these
two vertexes are $G_{\Sigma_bNB}=0.43\pm0.01GeV^{-1}$ and
$G_{\Sigma_cND}=3.76\pm0.05GeV^{-1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03756</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leo</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karsai</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarraute</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleury</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlations of consumption patterns in social-economic networks</title><categories>cs.SI cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><acm-class>J.4; H.2.8</acm-class><journal-ref>IEEE/ACM ASONAM p. 500-507, San Francisco CA, August 18-21 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze a coupled anonymized dataset collecting the mobile phone
communication and bank transactions history of a large number of individuals.
After mapping the social structure and introducing indicators of socioeconomic
status, demographic features, and purchasing habits of individuals we show that
typical consumption patterns are strongly correlated with identified
socioeconomic classes leading to patterns of stratification in the social
structure. In addition we measure correlations between merchant categories and
introduce a correlation network, which emerges with a meaningful community
structure. We detect multivariate relations between merchant categories and
show correlations in purchasing habits of individuals. Our work provides novel
and detailed insight into the relations between social and consuming behaviour
with potential applications in recommendation system design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07402</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shafieloo</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hazra</keyname><forenames>Dhiraj Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Consistency of the Planck CMB data and $\Lambda$CDM cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures, analysis and discussions extended including TE
  data, main results unchanged, matches the final version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 04 (2017) 012</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/04/012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We test the consistency between Planck temperature and polarization power
spectra and the concordance model of $\Lambda$ Cold Dark Matter cosmology
($\Lambda$CDM) within the framework of Crossing statistics. We find that Planck
TT best fit $\Lambda$CDM power spectrum is completely consistent with EE power
spectrum data while EE best fit $\Lambda$CDM power spectrum is not consistent
with TT data. However, this does not point to any systematic or model-data
discrepancy since in the Planck EE data, uncertainties are much larger compared
to the TT data. We also investigate the possibility of any deviation from
$\Lambda$CDM model analyzing the Planck 2015 data. Results from TT, TE and EE
data analysis indicate that no deviation is required beyond the flexibility of
the concordance $\Lambda$CDM model. Our analysis thus rules out any strong
evidence for beyond the concordance model in the Planck spectra data. We also
report a mild amplitude difference comparing temperature and polarization data,
where temperature data seems to have slightly lower amplitude than expected
(consistently at all multiples), as we assume both temperature and polarization
data are realizations of the same underlying cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00443</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Biddle</keyname><forenames>John W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Rakesh S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparano</keyname><forenames>Evan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valeriani</keyname><forenames>Chantal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abascal</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debenedetti</keyname><forenames>Pablo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anisimov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caupin</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-structure thermodynamics for the TIP4P/2005 model of water covering
  supercooled and deeply stretched regions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures. Supplementary Materials (2 pages, 2 figures) in
  anc subdirectory. Changes from previous version: Corrected misprint of values
  of S1 and S2 in Table I. Results unchanged. Supersedes arXiv:1605.05993</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics, 146 (2017) 034502</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973546</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most promising frameworks for understanding the anomalies of cold
and supercooled water postulates the existence of two competing,
interconvertible local structures. If the non-ideality in the Gibbs energy of
mixing overcomes the ideal entropy of mixing of these two structures, a
liquid-liquid phase transition, terminated at a liquid-liquid critical point,
is predicted. Various versions of the &quot;two-structure equation of state&quot; (TSEOS)
based on this concept have shown remarkable agreement with both experimental
data for metastable, deeply supercooled water and simulations of molecular
water models. However, existing TSEOSs were not designed to describe the
negative pressure region and do not account for the stability limit of the
liquid state with respect to the vapor. While experimental data on supercooled
water at negative pressures may shed additional light on the source of the
anomalies of water, such data are very limited. To fill this gap, we have
analyzed simulation results for TIP4P/2005, one of the most accurate classical
water models available. We have used recently published simulation data, and
performed additional simulations, over a broad range of positive and negative
pressures, from ambient temperature to deeply supercooled conditions. We show
that, by explicitly incorporating the liquid-vapor spinodal into a TSEOS, we
are able to match the simulation data for TIP4P/2005 with remarkable accuracy.
In particular, this equation of state quantitatively reproduces the lines of
extrema in density, isothermal compressibility, and isobaric heat capacity.
Contrary to an explanation of the thermodynamic anomalies of water based on a
&quot;retracing spinodal&quot;, the liquid-vapor spinodal in the present TSEOS continues
monotonically to lower pressures upon cooling, influencing but not giving rise
to density extrema and other thermodynamic anomalies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09638</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hong-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pen</keyname><forenames>Ue-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xuelei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Hao-Ran</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear reconstruction</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 123502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.123502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a direct approach to nonparametrically reconstruct the linear
density field from an observed nonlinear map. We solve for the unique
displacement potential consistent with the nonlinear density and positive
definite coordinate transformation using a multigrid algorithm. We show that we
recover the linear initial conditions up to the nonlinear scale
($r_{\delta_r\delta_L}&gt;0.5$ for $k\lesssim1\ h/\mathrm{Mpc}$) with minimal
computational cost. This reconstruction approach generalizes the linear
displacement theory to fully nonlinear fields, potentially substantially
expanding the baryon acoustic oscillations and redshift space distortions
information content of dense large scale structure surveys, including for
example SDSS main sample and 21cm intensity mapping initiatives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01008</id><created>2016-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Agarwalla</keyname><forenames>Bijay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy current and its statistics in the nonequilibrium spin-boson
  model: Majorana fermion representation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 043030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6657</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the statistics of thermal energy transfer in the nonequilibrium
(two-bath) spin-boson model. This quantum many-body impurity system serves as a
canonical model for quantum energy transport. Our method makes use of the
Majorana fermion representation for the spin operators, in combination with the
Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's function approach. We derive an analytical
expression for the cumulant generating function of the model in the steady
state limit, and show that it satisfies the Gallavotti-Cohen fluctuation
symmetry. We obtain analytical expressions for the heat current and its noise,
valid beyond the sequential and the co-tunnelling regimes. Our results satisfy
the quantum mechanical bound for heat current in interacting nanojunctions.
Results are compared with other approximate theories, as well as with a
non-interacting model, a fully harmonic thermal junction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02806</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02806</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-02-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum autoencoders for efficient compression of quantum data</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Now published in 2017 Quantum Sci. Technol. 2 045001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa8072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical autoencoders are neural networks that can learn efficient low
dimensional representations of data in higher dimensional space. The task of an
autoencoder is, given an input $x$, is to map $x$ to a lower dimensional point
$y$ such that $x$ can likely be recovered from $y$. The structure of the
underlying autoencoder network can be chosen to represent the data on a smaller
dimension, effectively compressing the input. Inspired by this idea, we
introduce the model of a quantum autoencoder to perform similar tasks on
quantum data. The quantum autoencoder is trained to compress a particular
dataset of quantum states, where a classical compression algorithm cannot be
employed. The parameters of the quantum autoencoder are trained using classical
optimization algorithms. We show an example of a simple programmable circuit
that can be trained as an efficient autoencoder. We apply our model in the
context of quantum simulation to compress ground states of the Hubbard model
and molecular Hamiltonians.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05583</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-07-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Renes</keyname><forenames>Joseph M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Duality of channels and codes</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>v2: 22 pages. fixed idempotency of duality for symmetric channels and
  added a statement about binary-input channels; v1: 23 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Information Theory 64, 577 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2017.2754921</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For any given channel $W$ with classical inputs and possibly quantum outputs,
a dual classical-input channel $W^\perp$ can be defined by embedding the
original into a channel $\mathcal N$ with quantum inputs and outputs. Here we
give new uncertainty relations for a general class of entropies that lead to
very close relationships between the original channel and its dual. Moreover,
we show that channel duality can be combined with duality of linear codes,
whereupon the uncertainty relations imply that the performance of a given code
over a given channel is entirely characterized by the performance of the dual
code on the dual channel. This has several applications. In the context of
polar codes, it implies that the rates of polarization to ideal and useless
channels must be identical. Duality also relates the tasks of channel coding
and privacy amplification, implying that the finite blocklength performance of
extractors and codes is precisely linked, and that optimal rate extractors can
be transformed into capacity-achieving codes, and vice versa. Finally, duality
also extends to the EXIT function of any channel and code. Here it implies that
for any channel family, if the EXIT function for a fixed code has a sharp
transition, then it must be such that the rate of the code equals the capacity
at the transition. This may give a different route to proving a code family
achieves capacity by establishing sharp EXIT function transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08909</id><created>2017-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyehwang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling charge transport mechanisms in molecular junctions:
  Distilling thermally-induced hopping from coherent-resonant conduction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 164702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electrical conductance of molecular junctions may strongly depend on the
temperature, and weakly on molecular length, under two distinct mechanisms:
phase-coherent resonant conduction, with charges proceeding via delocalized
molecular orbitals, and incoherent thermally-assisted multi-step hopping. While
in the case of coherent conduction the temperature dependence arises from the
broadening of the Fermi distribution in the metal electrodes, in the latter
case it corresponds to electron-vibration interaction effects on the junction.
With the objective to distill the thermally-activated hopping component, thus
expose intrinsic electron-vibration interaction phenomena on the junction, we
suggest the design of molecular junctions with &quot;spacers&quot;, extended anchoring
groups that act to filter out phase-coherent resonant electrons. Specifically,
we study the electrical conductance of fixed-gap and variable-gap junctions
that include a tunneling block, with spacers at the boundaries. Using numerical
simulations and analytical considerations, we demonstrate that in our design,
resonant conduction is suppressed. As a result, the electrical conductance is
dominated by two (rather than three) mechanisms: superexchange (deep
tunneling), and multi-step thermally-induced hopping. We further exemplify our
analysis on DNA junctions with an A:T block serving as a tunneling barrier.
Here, we show that the electrical conductance is insensitive to the number of
G:C base-pairs at the boundaries. This indicates that the tunneling-to-hopping
crossover revealed in such sequences truly corresponds to the properties of the
A:T barrier.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07927</id><created>2017-03-23</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baillie</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blakie</keyname><forenames>P. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective excitations of self-bound droplets of a dipolar quantum fluid</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 255302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.255302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the collective excitations of a dipolar Bose-Einstein condensate
in the regime where it self-binds into droplets stabilized by quantum
fluctuations. We show that the filament-shaped droplets act as a
quasi-one-dimensional waveguide along which low angular momentum phonons
propagate. The evaporation (unbinding) threshold occurring as the atom number
$N$ is reduced to the critical value $N_c$ is associated with a monopole-like
excitation going soft as $\epsilon_0\sim(N-N_c)^{1/4}$. Considering the system
in the presence of a trapping potential, we quantify the crossover from a
trap-bound condensate to a self-bound droplet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00121</id><created>2017-04-01</created><updated>2017-04-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agarwalla</keyname><forenames>Bijay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>The Anderson impurity model out of equilibrium: Assessing the accuracy
  of simulation techniques with an exact current-occupation relation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>JCP 147, 054104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4996562</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interacting, symmetrically coupled single impurity Anderson
model. By employing the nonequilibrium Green's function formalism, we establish
an exact relationship between the steady-state charge current flowing through
the impurity (dot) and its occupation. We argue that the steady state
current-occupation relation can be used to assess the consistency of simulation
techniques, and identify spurious transport phenomena. We test this relation in
two different model variants: First, we study the Anderson-Holstein model in
the strong electron-vibration coupling limit using the polaronic quantum master
equation method. We find that the current-occupation relation is violated
numerically in standard calculations, with simulations bringing up incorrect
transport effects. Using a numerical procedure, we resolve the problem
efficiently. Second, we simulate the Anderson model with electron-electron
interaction on the dot using a deterministic numerically-exact time-evolution
scheme. Here, we observe that the current-occupation relation is satisfied in
the steady-state limit---even before results converge to the exact limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02149</id><created>2017-04-07</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kahlhoefer</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt-Hoberg</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wild</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter self-interactions from a general spin-0 mediator</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures + appendices. v2: Matches published version. v3:
  fixed typographical mistake in eq. (2.8). v4: fixed typographical mistake in
  eq. (C.4)</comments><report-no>DESY-17-052</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP08(2017)003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/08/003</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter particles interacting via the exchange of very light spin-0
mediators can have large self-interaction rates and obtain their relic
abundance from thermal freeze-out. At the same time, these models face strong
bounds from direct and indirect probes of dark matter as well as a number of
constraints on the properties of the mediator. We investigate whether these
constraints can be consistent with having observable effects from dark matter
self-interactions in astrophysical systems. For the case of a mediator with
purely scalar couplings we point out the highly relevant impact of
low-threshold direct detection experiments like CRESST-II, which essentially
rule out the simplest realization of this model. These constraints can be
significantly relaxed if the mediator has CP-violating couplings, but then the
model faces strong constraints from CMB measurements, which can only be avoided
in special regions of parameter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08206</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dawid</keyname><forenames>Sebastian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonsior</keyname><forenames>Rafa&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwapisz</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serafin</keyname><forenames>Kamil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobolski</keyname><forenames>Mariusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#x142;azek</keyname><forenames>Stanis&#x142;aw D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization group procedure for potential $-g/r^2$</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 777 (2018) 260</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.12.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Schr\&quot;odinger equation with potential $-g/r^2$ exhibits a limit cycle,
described in the literature in a broad range of contexts using various
regularizations of the singularity at $r=0$. Instead, we use the
renormalization group transformation based on Gaussian elimination, from the
Hamiltonian eigenvalue problem, of high momentum modes above a finite, floating
cutoff scale. The procedure identifies a richer structure than the one we found
in the literature. Namely, it directly yields an equation that determines the
renormalized Hamiltonians as functions of the floating cutoff: solutions to
this equation exhibit, in addition to the limit-cycle, also the
asymptotic-freedom, triviality, and fixed-point behaviors, the latter in
vicinity of infinitely many separate pairs of fixed points in different partial
waves for different values of $g$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00271</id><created>2017-04-30</created><updated>2017-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Azuma</keyname><forenames>Hiroo</forenames></author></authors><title>An entangling-probe attack on Shor's algorithm for factorization</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>v1: 11 pages, latex2e; v2: 14 pages, 2 eps figures, the previous
  version has been completely rewritten with a new title; v3: minor
  corrections; v4: minor corrections; v5: a typographical error is corrected</comments><journal-ref>J. Mod. Opt. 65, 415-422 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2017.1397221</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate how to attack Shor's quantum algorithm for factorization with
an entangling probe. We show that an attacker can steal an exact solution of
Shor's algorithm outside an institute where the quantum computer is installed
if he replaces its initialized quantum register with entangled qubits, namely
the entangling probe. He can apply arbitrary local operations to his own probe.
Moreover, we assume that there is an unauthorized person who helps the attacker
to commit a crime inside the institute. He tells garbage data obtained from
measurements of the quantum register to the attacker secretly behind a
legitimate user's back. If the attacker succeeds in cracking Shor's algorithm,
the legitimate user obtains a random answer and does not notice the attacker's
illegal acts. We discuss how to detect the attacker. Finally we estimate a
probability that the quantum algorithm inevitably makes an error, of which the
attacker can take advantage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00598</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kallweit</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindert</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pozzorini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schonherr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>NLO QCD+EW predictions for $2\ell2\nu$ diboson signatures at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>25 pages + appendices, 22 figures</comments><report-no>IPPP/17/32, MCNET--17--05, CERN-TH-2017-097, ZU-TH 09/17</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1711 (2017) 120</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2017)120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present next-to-leading order (NLO) calculations including QCD and
electroweak (EW) corrections for $2\ell2\nu$ diboson signatures with two
opposite-charge leptons and two neutrinos. Specifically, we study the processes
$pp\to e^+ \mu^- \nu_{e}\bar\nu_{\mu}$ and $pp\to e^+ e^-\nu\bar\nu$, including
all relevant off-shell diboson channels, $W^+W^-$, $ZZ$, $\gamma Z$, as well as
non-resonant contributions. Photon-induced processes are computed at NLO EW,
and we discuss subtle differences related to the definition and the
renormalisation of the coupling $\alpha$ for processes with initial- and
final-state photons. All calculations are performed within the automated
Munich/Sherpa+OpenLoops frameworks, and we provide numerical predictions for
the LHC at 13 TeV. The behaviour of the corrections is investigated with
emphasis on the high-energy regime, where NLO EW effects can amount to tens of
percent due to large Sudakov logarithms. The interplay between $WW$ and $ZZ$
contributions to the same-flavour channel, $pp\to e^+ e^-\nu\bar\nu$, is
discussed in detail, and a quantitative analysis of photon-induced
contributions is presented. Finally, we consider approximations that account
for all sources of large logarithms, at high and low energy, by combining
virtual EW corrections with a YFS soft-photon resummation or a QED parton
shower.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00686</id><created>2017-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Neville</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparrow</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clifford</keyname><forenames>Rapha&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birchall</keyname><forenames>Patrick M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montanaro</keyname><forenames>Ashley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laing</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author></authors><title>No imminent quantum supremacy by boson sampling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 9 figures. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 13, 1153-1157 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys4270</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is predicted that quantum computers will dramatically outperform their
conventional counterparts. However, large-scale universal quantum computers are
yet to be built. Boson sampling is a rudimentary quantum algorithm tailored to
the platform of photons in linear optics, which has sparked interest as a rapid
way to demonstrate this quantum supremacy. Photon statistics are governed by
intractable matrix functions known as permanents, which suggests that sampling
from the distribution obtained by injecting photons into a linear-optical
network could be solved more quickly by a photonic experiment than by a
classical computer. The contrast between the apparently awesome challenge faced
by any classical sampling algorithm and the apparently near-term experimental
resources required for a large boson sampling experiment has raised
expectations that quantum supremacy by boson sampling is on the horizon. Here
we present classical boson sampling algorithms and theoretical analyses of
prospects for scaling boson sampling experiments, showing that near-term
quantum supremacy via boson sampling is unlikely. While the largest boson
sampling experiments reported so far are with 5 photons, our classical
algorithm, based on Metropolised independence sampling (MIS), allowed the boson
sampling problem to be solved for 30 photons with standard computing hardware.
We argue that the impact of experimental photon losses means that demonstrating
quantum supremacy by boson sampling would require a step change in technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01018</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kalinichenko</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazinski</keyname><forenames>P. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-temperature expansion of the one-loop effective action induced by
  scalar and Dirac particles</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pp; correct normalization condition used, some misprints corrected</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 880 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5450-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The complete nonperturbative expressions for the high-temperature expansion
of the one-loop effective action induced by the charged scalar and the charged
Dirac particles both at zero and finite temperatures are derived with account
for possible nontrivial boundary conditions. The background electromagnetic
field is assumed to be stationary and such that the corresponding Klein-Gordon
operator or the Dirac Hamiltonian are self-adjoint. The contributions of
particles and antiparticles are obtained separately. The explicit expressions
for the $C$-symmetric and the non $C$-symmetric vacuum energies of the Dirac
fermions are derived. The leading corrections to the high-temperature expansion
due to the nontrivial boundary conditions are explicitly found. The corrections
to the logarithmic divergence of the effective action that come from the
boundary conditions are derived. The high-temperature expansion of the naive
one-loop effective action induced by charged fermions turns out to be divergent
in the limit of a zero fermion mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03229</id><created>2017-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Guo Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhen Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of the strong vertexes of $\Sigma_c^{*} ND$ and
  $\Sigma_b^{*}NB$ in QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 32, 1750203 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17502037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we analyze the strong vertexes $\Sigma_{c}^{*}ND$ and
$\Sigma_{b}^{*}NB$ using the three-point QCD sum rules under the Dirac
structure of $q\!\!\!/p\!\!\!/\gamma_{\mu}$. We perform our analysis by
considering the contributions of the perturbative part and the condensate terms
of $&lt;\overline{q}q&gt;$ and $&lt;\frac{\alpha_{s}}{\pi}GG&gt;$. After the form factors
are calculated, they are then fitted into analytical functions which are used
to get the strong coupling constants for these two vertexes. The final results
are $g_{\Sigma_{c}^{*}ND}=7.19^{+8.49}_{-3.11}\pm1.76$ and
$g_{\Sigma_{b}^{*}NB}=10.54^{+15.59}_{-5.23}\pm1.82$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05234</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aghamousa</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamann</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafieloo</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author></authors><title>A non-parametric consistency test of the $\Lambda$CDM model with Planck
  CMB data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures; v2: matches version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 09 (2017) 031</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/09/031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-parametric reconstruction methods, such as Gaussian process (GP)
regression, provide a model-independent way of estimating an underlying
function and its uncertainty from noisy data. We demonstrate how
GP-reconstruction can be used as a consistency test between a given data set
and a specific model by looking for structures in the residuals of the data
with respect to the model's best-fit. Applying this formalism to the Planck
temperature and polarisation power spectrum measurements, we test their global
consistency with the predictions of the base $\Lambda$CDM model. Our results do
not show any serious inconsistencies, lending further support to the
interpretation of the base $\Lambda$CDM model as cosmology's gold standard.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07816</id><created>2017-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Haqq-Misra</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopparapu</keyname><forenames>Ravi Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>The Drake Equation as a Function of Spectral Type and Time</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>To be published in Habitability of the Universe Before Earth, R.
  Gordon and A. Sharov (Eds.), Elsevier</comments><journal-ref>Habitability of the Universe Before Earth, R. Gordon and A. Sharov
  (Eds.), Elsevier, pp 307-319, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/B978-0-12-811940-2.00013-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This chapter draws upon astronomical observations and modeling to constrain
the prevalence of communicative civilizations in the galaxy. We discuss the
dependence of the Drake equation parameters on the spectral type of the host
star and the time since the galaxy formed, which allow us to examine
trajectories for the emergence of communicative civilizations over the history
of the galaxy. We suggest that the maximum lifetime of communicative
civilizations depends on the spectral type of the host star, which implies that
F- and G-dwarf stars are the best places to search for signs of technological
intelligence today.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01200</id><created>2017-06-05</created><updated>2017-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sekine</keyname><forenames>Akihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Culcer</keyname><forenames>Dimitrie</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacDonald</keyname><forenames>Allan H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Kinetic Theory of the Chiral Anomaly</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 235134 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.235134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a general quantum kinetic theory of low-field magnetotransport in
weakly disordered crystals that accounts fully for the interplay between
electric-field induced interband coherence, Bloch-state scattering, and an
external magnetic field. The quantum kinetic equation we derive for the
Bloch-state density matrix naturally incorporates the momentum-space Berry
phase effects whose influence on Bloch-state wavepacket dynamics is normally
incorporated into transport theory in an ad hoc manner. The Berry phase
correction to the momentum-space density of states in the presence of an
external magnetic field implied by semiclassical wavepacket dynamics is
captured by our theory as an intrinsic density-matrix response to a magnetic
field. We propose a simple and general procedure for expanding the linear
response of the Bloch-state density matrix to an electric field in powers of
magnetic field. As an illustration, we apply our theory to magnetotransport in
Weyl semimetals. We show that the chiral anomaly (positive magnetoconductivity
quadratic in magnetic field) that appears when separate Fermi surface pockets
surround distinct Weyl points survives only when intervalley scattering is very
weak compared to intravalley scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03556</id><created>2017-06-12</created><updated>2017-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ripa</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafieloo</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing Isotropic Universe Using the Gamma-Ray Burst Data of Fermi / GBM</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>17 pages, 10 figures, 4 tables, accepted for publication in The
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 851 (2017) 1, 15</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa9708</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sky distribution of Gamma-Ray Bursts (GRBs) has been intensively studied
by various groups for more than two decades. Most of these studies test the
isotropy of GRBs based on their sky number density distribution. In this work
we propose an approach to test the isotropy of the Universe through inspecting
the isotropy of the properties of GRBs such as their duration, fluences and
peak fluxes at various energy bands and different time scales. We apply this
method on the {\em Fermi} / Gamma-ray Burst Monitor (GBM) data sample
containing 1591 GRBs. The most noticeable feature we found is near the Galactic
coordinates $l\approx 30^\circ$, $b\approx 15^\circ$ and radius $r\approx
20^\circ-40^\circ$. The inferred probability for the occurrence of such an
anisotropic signal (in a random isotropic sample) is derived to be less than a
percent in some of the tests while the other tests give results consistent with
isotropy. These are based on the comparison of the results from the real data
with the randomly shuffled data samples. Considering large number of statistics
we used in this work (which some of them are correlated to each other) we can
anticipate that the detected feature could be result of statistical
fluctuations. Moreover, we noticed a considerably low number of GRBs in this
particular patch which might be due to some instrumentation or observational
effects that can consequently affect our statistics through some systematics.
Further investigation is highly desirable in order clarify about this result,
e.g. utilizing a larger future {\em Fermi} / GBM data sample as well as data
samples of other GRB missions and also looking for possible systematics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04434</id><created>2017-06-13</created><updated>2017-11-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heydarzade</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corda</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darabi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Braneworld Black Holes and Entropy Bounds</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, accepted for publication in Physics Letters B</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 776, 457 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.11.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Bousso's D-bound entropy for the various possible black hole solutions on
a 4-dimensional brane is checked. It is found that the D-bound entropy here is
apparently different from that of obtained for the 4-dimensional black hole
solutions. This difference is interpreted as the extra loss of information,
associated to the extra dimension, when an extra-dimensional black hole is
moved outward the observer's cosmological horizon. Also, it is discussed that
N-bound entropy is hold for the possible solutions here. Finally, by adopting
the recent Bohr-like approach to black hole quantum physics for the excited
black holes, the obtained results are written also in terms of the black hole
excited states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04474</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04474</id><created>2017-06-14</created><updated>2017-11-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>F. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ficek</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Q. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Q. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase control of entanglement and quantum steering in a three-mode
  optomechanical system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 123039 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa9c9a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theory of phase control of coherence, entanglement and quantum steering
is developed for an optomechanical system composed of a single mode cavity
containing a partially transmitting dielectric membrane and driven by short
laser pulses. The closed loop in the coupling creates interfering channels
which depend on the relative phase of the coupling strengths of the field modes
to the mechanical mode. We show several interesting phase dependent effects
such as reversible population transfer from one field mode to the other,
creation of collective modes, and induced coherence without induced emission.
These effects result from perfect mutual coherence between the field modes
which is preserved even if one of the modes is not populated. Depending on the
phase, the field modes can act on the mechanical mode collectively or
individually resulting, respectively, in tripartite or bipartite entanglement.
In addition, we examine the phase sensitivity of quantum steering of the
mechanical mode by the field modes is investigated. Deterministic phase
transfer of the steering from bipartite to collective is predicted and optimum
steering corresponding to perfect EPR state can be achieved. These different
types of quantum steering can be distinguished experimentally by measuring the
coincidence rate between two detectors adjusted to collect photons of the
output cavity modes. In particular, we find that the minima of the interference
pattern of the coincidence rate signal the bipartite steering, while the maxima
signal the collective steering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04794</id><created>2017-06-15</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kummer</keyname><forenames>Janis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kahlhoefer</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt-Hoberg</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective description of dark matter self-interactions in small dark
  matter haloes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures; v2: minor changes; v3: matches version published
  in MNRAS</comments><report-no>DESY-17-089</report-no><journal-ref>Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 474 (2018) no.1, 388-399</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2715</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Self-interacting dark matter may have striking astrophysical signatures, such
as observable offsets between galaxies and dark matter in merging galaxy
clusters. Numerical N-body simulations used to predict such observables
typically treat the galaxies as collisionless test particles, a questionable
assumption given that each galaxy is embedded in its own dark matter halo. To
enable a more accurate treatment we develop an effective description of small
dark matter haloes taking into account the two major effects due to dark matter
self-scatterings: deceleration and evaporation. We point out that
self-scatterings can have a sizeable impact on the trajectories of galaxies,
diminishing the separation between galaxies and dark matter in merging
clusters. This effect depends sensitively on the underlying particle physics,
in particular the angular dependence of the self-scattering cross section, and
cannot be predicted from the momentum transfer cross section alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06769</id><created>2017-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Pauw</keyname><forenames>Brian R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snow</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terrill</keyname><forenames>Nick J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Th&#xfc;nemann</keyname><forenames>Andreas F.</forenames></author></authors><title>The modular SAXS data correction sequence for solids and dispersions</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>22 pages, four figures, laboratory note</comments><journal-ref>https://journals.iucr.org/j/issues/2017/06/00/vg5075/</journal-ref><doi>10.1107/S1600576717015096</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Data correction is probably the least favourite activity amongst users
experimenting with small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS): if it is not done
sufficiently well, this may become evident during the data analysis stage,
necessitating the repetition of the data corrections from scratch. A
recommended, comprehensive sequence of elementary data correction steps is
presented here to alleviate the difficulties associated with data correction.
When applied in the proposed order, the resulting data will provide a high
degree of accuracy for both solid samples and dispersions. The solution here
can be applied without modification to any pinhole-collimated instruments with
photon-counting, direct detection area detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08388</id><created>2017-06-26</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brubaker</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamoreaux</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lehnert</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Bibber</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The HAYSTAC Axion Search Analysis Procedure</title><categories>astro-ph.IM hep-ex</categories><comments>33 pages, 10 figures; added changes made in review process</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 123008 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.123008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe in detail the analysis procedure used to derive the first limits
from the Haloscope at Yale Sensitive to Axion CDM (HAYSTAC), a microwave cavity
search for cold dark matter (CDM) axions with masses above $20\ \mu\text{eV}$.
We have introduced several significant innovations to the axion search analysis
pioneered by the Axion Dark Matter eXperiment (ADMX), including optimal
filtering of the individual power spectra that constitute the axion search
dataset and a consistent maximum likelihood procedure for combining and
rebinning these spectra. These innovations enable us to obtain the axion-photon
coupling $|g_\gamma|$ excluded at any desired confidence level directly from
the statistics of the combined data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04911</id><created>2017-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Soohyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paik</keyname><forenames>Kyungrock</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGrath</keyname><forenames>Gavan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urich</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruger</keyname><forenames>Elisabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Praveen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>P. Suresh C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing Topology of Engineered and Natural Drainage Networks</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Water Resources Research 53 (2017) 8966-8979</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2017WR021555</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigated the scaling and topology of engineered urban drainage
networks (UDNs) in two cities, and further examined UDN evolution over decades.
UDN scaling was analyzed using two power-law characteristics widely employed
for river networks: (1) Hack's law of length ($L$)-area ($A$) scaling [$L
\propto A^{h}$], and (2) exceedance probability distribution of upstream
contributing area $(\delta)$ [$P(A\geq \delta) \sim a \delta^{-\epsilon}$]. For
the smallest UDNs ($&lt;2 \&gt;\text{km}^2$), length-area scales linearly ($h\sim
1$), but power-law scaling emerges as the UDNs grow. While $P(A\geq \delta)$
plots for river networks are abruptly truncated, those for UDNs display
exponential tempering [$P(A\geq \delta) \&gt;\text{=}\&gt; a
\delta^{-\epsilon}\exp(-c\delta)$]. The tempering parameter $c$ decreases as
the UDNs grow, implying that the distribution evolves in time to resemble those
for river networks. However, the power-law exponent $\epsilon$ for large UDNs
tends to be slightly larger than the range reported for river networks.
Differences in generative processes and engineering design constraints
contribute to observed differences in the evolution of UDNs and river networks,
including subnet heterogeneity and non-random branching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05343</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05343</id><created>2017-07-17</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>The xFitter Developers Team</keyname></author><author><keyname>Bertone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britzger</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camarda</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper-Sarkar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geiser</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godat</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luszczak</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyonnet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olness</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Placakyte</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radescu</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schienbein</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenaiev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of the heavy quark matching scales in PDF fits</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 12 figures. Updated to match published version</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5407-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the impact of displaced heavy quark matching scales in a
global fit. The heavy quark matching scale $\mu_{m}$ determines at which energy
scale $\mu$ the QCD theory transitions from $N_{F}$ to $N_{F}+1$ in the
Variable Flavor Number Scheme (VFNS) for the evolution of the Parton
Distribution Functions (PDFs) and strong coupling $\alpha_S(\mu)$. We study the
variation of the matching scales, and their impact on a global PDF fit of the
combined HERA data. As the choice of the matching scale $\mu_{m}$ effectively
is a choice of scheme, this represents a theoretical uncertainty; ideally, we
would like to see minimal dependence on this parameter. For the transition
across the charm quark (from $N_{F}=3$ to $4$), we find a large $\mu_m=\mu_{c}$
dependence of the global fit $\chi^2$ at NLO, but this is significantly reduced
at NNLO. For the transition across the bottom quark (from $N_{F}=4$ to $5$), we
have a reduced $\mu_{m}=\mu_b$ dependence of the $\chi^2$ at both NLO and NNLO
as compared to the charm. This feature is now implemented in xFitter 2.0.0, an
open source QCD fit framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05408</id><created>2017-07-17</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anchordoqui</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barger</keyname><forenames>Vernon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiler</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Mass Spectrometer</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To be published in JHEAp</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that if ultrahigh-energy (E &gt; 10^10 GeV) cosmic rays are heavy
nuclei (as indicated by existing data), then the pointing of cosmic rays to
their nearest extragalactic sources is expected for 10^10.6 &lt; E/GeV &lt; 10^11.
This is because for a nucleus of charge Ze and baryon number A, the bending of
the cosmic ray decreases as Z/E with rising energy, so that pointing to nearby
sources becomes possible at highest energies. In addition, the maximum energy
of acceleration capability of the sources grows linearly in Z, while the energy
loss per distance traveled decreases with increasing A. Each of these two
points tend to favor heavy nuclei at the highest energies. The traditional
bi-dimensional analyses, which simultaneously reproduce Auger data on the
spectrum and nuclear composition, may not be capable of incorporating the
relative importance of these phenomena. In this paper we propose a
multi-dimensional reconstruction of the individual emission spectra (in E,
direction, and cross-correlation with nearby putative sources) to study the
hypothesis that primaries are heavy nuclei subject to GZK photo-disintegration,
and to determine the nature of the extragalactic sources. More specifically, we
propose to combine information on nuclear composition and arrival direction to
associate a potential clustering of events with a 3-dimensional position in the
sky. Actually, both the source distance and maximum emission energy can be
obtained through a multi-parameter likelihood analysis to accommodate the
observed nuclear composition of each individual event in the cluster. We show
that nucleus-emitting-sources exhibit a cepa stratis structure on Earth which
could be pealed off by future space-missions, such as POEMMA. We also show that
metal-rich starburst galaxies are highly-plausible candidate sources, and we
use them as an explicit example of our proposed multi-dimensional analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05626</id><created>2017-07-18</created><updated>2017-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Weidong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Sixia</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of State-independent Proofs for Quantum Contextuality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>A revised viseion with supplemental materials. 10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 062126 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.062126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the enlightening proofs of quantum contextuality first established by
Kochen and Specker, and also by Bell, various simplified proofs have been
constructed to exclude the non-contextual hidden variable theory of our nature
at the microscopic scale. The conflict between the non-contextual hidden
variable theory and quantum mechanics is commonly revealed by Kochen-Specker
(KS) sets of yes-no tests, represented by projectors (or rays), via either
logical contradictions or noncontextuality inequalities in a
state-(in)dependent manner. Here we first propose a systematic and programmable
construction of a state-independent proof from a given set of nonspecific rays
in $\mC^3$ according to their Gram matrix. This approach brings us a greater
convenience in the experimental arrangements. Besides, our proofs in $\mC^3$
can also be generalized to any higher dimensional systems by a recursive
method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06044</id><created>2017-07-19</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jun-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Qiu-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zangi</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Cong-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental investigation of multi-observable uncertainty relations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>slightly extended. To appear in PRA</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 062123 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.062123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The uncertainty relation is a distinguishing feature of quantum theory,
characterizing the incompatibility of noncommuting observables in the
preparation of quantum states. Recently, many uncertainty relations were
proposed with improved lower bounds and were deemed capable of incorporating
multiple observables. Here we report an experimental verification of seven
uncertainty relations of this type with single-photon measurements. The
results, while confirming these uncertainty relations, show as well the
relative stringency of various uncertainty lower bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09296</id><created>2017-07-28</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poncelet</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruelle</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipoint correlators in the Abelian sandpile model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>60 pages, 21 figures. v2: reformulation of the grove theorem, minor
  corrections</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa9a59</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the calculation of height correlations in the two-dimensional
Abelian sandpile model by taking advantage of a technique developed recently by
Kenyon and Wilson. The formalism requires to equip the usual graph Laplacian,
ubiquitous in the context of cycle-rooted spanning forests, with a complex
connection. In the case at hand, the connection is constant and localized along
a semi-infinite defect line (zipper). In the appropriate limit of a trivial
connection, it allows one to count spanning forests whose components contain
prescribed sites, which are of direct relevance for height correlations in the
sandpile model. Using this technique, we first rederive known 1- and 2-site
lattice correlators on the plane and upper half-plane, more efficiently than
what has been done so far. We also compute explicitly the (new) next-to-leading
order in the distances ($r^{-4}$ for 1-site on the upper half-plane, $r^{-6}$
for 2-site on the plane). We extend these results by computing new correlators
involving one arbitrary height and a few heights 1 on the plane and upper
half-plane, for the open and closed boundary conditions. We examine our lattice
results from the conformal point of view, and confirm the full consistency with
the specific features currently conjectured to be present in the associated
logarithmic conformal field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09426</id><created>2017-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hong-Hsi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fieremans</keyname><forenames>Els</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry S.</forenames></author></authors><title>What dominates the time dependence of diffusion transverse to axons:
  Intra- or extra-axonal water?</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.med-ph q-bio.NC</categories><doi>10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.12.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Brownian motion of water molecules provides an essential length scale, the
diffusion length, commensurate with cell dimensions in biological tissues.
Measuring the diffusion coefficient as a function of diffusion time makes in
vivo diffusion MRI uniquely sensitive to the cellular features about three
orders of magnitude below imaging resolution. However, there is a longstanding
debate, regarding which contribution --- intra- or extra-cellular --- is more
relevant in the overall time-dependence of the diffusion metrics. Here we
resolve this debate in the human brain white matter. By varying not just the
diffusion time, but also the gradient pulse duration of a standard diffusion
pulse sequence, we identify a functional form of the measured time-dependent
diffusion coefficient transverse to white matter tracts in 5 healthy
volunteers. This specific functional form is shown to originate from the
extra-axonal space, and provides estimates of the fiber packing correlation
length for axons in a bundle. Our results offer a metric for the outer axonal
diameter, a promising candidate marker for demyelination in neurodegenerative
diseases. From the methodological perspective, our analysis demonstrates how
competing models, which describe different physics yet interpolate standard
measurements equally well, can be distinguished based on their prediction for
an independent &quot;orthogonal&quot; measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09797</id><created>2017-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Duc Tam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Sung Youb</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic Rippling Enhances Static Non-Reciprocity in Graphene
  Metamaterials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nanoscale 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7NR07651G</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In mechanical systems, Maxwell-Betti reciprocity means that the displacement
at point B in response to a force at point A is the same as the displacement at
point A in response to the same force applied at point B. Because the notion of
reciprocity is general, fundamental, and is operant for other physical systems
like electromagnetics, acoustics, and optics, there is significant interest in
understanding systems that are not reciprocal, or exhibit non-reciprocity.
However, most studies of non-reciprocity have occurred in bulk-scale structures
for dynamic problems involving time reversal symmetry. As a result, little is
known about the mechanisms governing static non-reciprocal responses,
particularly in atomically-thin two-dimensional materials like graphene. Here,
we use classical atomistic simulations to demonstrate that out of plane
ripples, which are intrinsic to graphene, enable significant, multiple orders
of magnitude enhancements in the statically non-reciprocal response of graphene
metamaterials. Specifically, we find that a striking interplay between the
ripples and the stress fields that are induced in the metamaterials due to
their geometry impact the displacements that are transmitted by the
metamaterial, thus leading to a significantly enhanced static non-reciprocal
response. This study thus demonstrates the potential of two-dimensional
mechanical metamaterials for symmetry-breaking applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02161</id><created>2017-08-07</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yu-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanazawa</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yau</keyname><forenames>Shing-Tung</forenames></author></authors><title>Weil-Petersson geometry on the space of Bridgeland stability conditions</title><categories>math.AG hep-th math.DG</categories><comments>v3. 19 pages. Comments are welcome!</comments><msc-class>53D37, 14J33, 14J32, 18E30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by mirror symmetry, we investigate some differential geometric
aspects of the space of Bridgeland stability conditions on a Calabi-Yau
triangulated category. The aim is to develop theory of Weil-Petersson geometry
on the stringy K\&quot;ahler moduli space. A few basic examples are studied. In
particular, we identify our Weil-Petersson metric with the Bergman metric on a
Siegel modular variety in the case of the self-product of an elliptic curve.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03966</id><created>2017-08-13</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gould</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pittalis</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>'Hartree-exchange' in ensemble density functional theory: Avoiding the
  non-uniqueness disaster</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Includes supplementary material. The copy here is the authors'
  preferred version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 243001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.243001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ensemble density functional theory is a promising method for the efficient
and accurate calculation of excitations of quantum systems, at least if useful
functionals can be developed to broaden its domain of practical applicability.
Here, we introduce a guaranteed single-valued 'Hartree-exchange' ensemble
density functional, $E_{Hx}[n]$, in terms of the right derivative of the
universal ensemble density functional with respect to the coupling constant at
vanishing interaction. We show that $E_{Hx}[n]$ is straightforwardly
expressible using block eigenvalues of a simple matrix [equation (14)].
Specialized expressions for $E_{Hx}[n]$ from the literature, including those
involving superpositions of Slater determinants, can now be regarded as
originating from the unifying picture presented here. We thus establish a clear
and practical description for Hartree-exchange in ensemble systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05090</id><created>2017-08-16</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Feng-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jia-ju</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissimilarities of reduced density matrices and eigenstate
  thermalization hypothesis</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>V1, 34 pages, 5 figures, see collection of complete results in the
  attached Mathematica notebook; V2, 38 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1712 (2017) 073</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2017)073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate various quantities that characterize the dissimilarity of
reduced density matrices for a short interval of length $\ell$ in a
two-dimensional (2D) large central charge conformal field theory (CFT). These
quantities include the R\'enyi entropy, entanglement entropy, relative entropy,
Jensen-Shannon divergence, as well as the Schatten 2-norm and 4-norm. We adopt
the method of operator product expansion of twist operators, and calculate the
short interval expansion of these quantities up to order of $\ell^9$ for the
contributions from the vacuum conformal family. The formal forms of these
dissimilarity measures and the derived Fisher information metric from
contributions of general operators are also given. As an application of the
results, we use these dissimilarity measures to compare the excited and thermal
states, and examine the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis (ETH) by showing
how they behave in high temperature limit. This would help to understand how
ETH in 2D CFT can be defined more precisely. We discuss the possibility that
all the dissimilarity measures considered here vanish when comparing the
reduced density matrices of an excited state and a generalized Gibbs ensemble
thermal state. We also discuss ETH for a microcanonical ensemble thermal state
in a 2D large central charge CFT, and find that it is approximately satisfied
for a small subsystem and violated for a large subsystem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06531</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Peng-Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Qiao-He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Tian-Long</forenames></author></authors><title>Magneto-transport and Electronic Structures of BaZnBi$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 123044 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa95e7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the magneto-transport properties and electronic structures of
BaZnBi$_2$. BaZnBi$_2$ is a quasi-two-dimensional (2D) material with metallic
behavior. The transverse magnetoresistance (MR) depends on magnetic field
linearly and exhibits Shubnikov-de Haas (SdH) oscillation at low temperature
and high field. The observed linear MR may originate from the disorder in
samples or the edge conductivity in compensated two-component systems. The
first-principles calculations reveal the absence of stable gapless Dirac
fermion. Combining with the trivial Berry phase extracted from SdH oscillation,
BaZnBi$_2$ is suggested to be a topologically trivial semimetal. Nearly
compensated electron-like Fermi surfaces (FSs) and hole-like FSs coexist in
BaZnBi$_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.09844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.09844</id><created>2017-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Eigen</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glidden</keyname><forenames>Jake A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navon</keyname><forenames>Nir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadzibabic</keyname><forenames>Zoran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Robert P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Scaling Laws in the Dynamics of a Homogeneous Unitary Bose Gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 250404 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.250404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of an initially degenerate homogeneous Bose gas after
an interaction quench to the unitary regime at a magnetic Feshbach resonance.
As the cloud decays and heats, it exhibits a crossover from degenerate- to
thermal-gas behaviour, both of which are characterised by universal scaling
laws linking the particle-loss rate to the total atom number $N$. In the
degenerate and thermal regimes the per-particle loss rate is $\propto N^{2/3}$
and $N^{26/9}$, respectively. The crossover occurs at a universal kinetic
energy per particle and at a universal time after the quench, in units of
energy and time set by the gas density. By slowly sweeping the magnetic field
away from the resonance and creating a mixture of atoms and molecules, we also
map out the dynamics of correlations in the unitary gas, which display a
universal temporal scaling with the gas density, and reach a steady state while
the gas is still degenerate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.00879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.00879</id><created>2017-09-04</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sombun</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinheimer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herold</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limphirat</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleicher</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher order net-proton number cumulants dependence on the centrality
  definition and other spurious effects</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages 13 figures, version accepted by JPG</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G 45 025101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa9c6c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dependence of the normalized moments of the net-proton
multiplicity distributions on the definition of centrality in relativistic
nuclear collisions at a beam energy of $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}= 7.7$ GeV. Using
the UrQMD model as event generator we find that the centrality definition has a
large effect on the extracted cumulant ratios. Furthermore we find that the
finite efficiency for the determination of the centrality introduces an
additional systematic uncertainty. Finally, we quantitatively investigate the
effects of event-pile up and other possible spurious effects which may change
the measured proton number. We find that pile-up alone is not sufficient to
describe the data and show that a random double counting of events, adding
significantly to the measured proton number, affects mainly the higher order
cumulants in most central collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.01090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.01090</id><created>2017-09-04</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoof</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaeckel</keyname><forenames>Joerg</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD axions and axionlike particles in a two-inflation scenario</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>24 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 115016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.115016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the phenomenology of QCD axions and axionlike particles in a
scenario with two eras of inflation. In particular, we describe the possible
solutions for the QCD axion field equation after the second inflation and
reheating. We calculate the dilution numerically for QCD axions and give an
analytic approximation for axionlike particles. While it has been realised
before that such a scenario can dilute the axion energy density and open up the
parameter space for the axion decay constant $f_A$, we find that even a small
increase in the relative QCD axion energy density is possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.01246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.01246</id><created>2017-09-05</created><updated>2017-12-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Fuminori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>Kazunori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terada</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitino Problem in Inflation Driven by Inflaton-Polonyi K\&quot;ahler
  Coupling</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages; accepted by PLB, title and abstract changed to clarify the
  topic, conclusion not changed, references added</comments><report-no>IPMU17-0116, UT-17-28, KEK-TH-1992, KEK-Cosmo-210</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 777 (2018) 270-274</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.12.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the cosmological gravitino problem in inflation models in which
the inflaton potential is constructed from K\&quot;ahler potential rather than
superpotential: a representative model is $\overline{\text{D}3}$-induced
geometric inflation. A critical ingredient in this type of models is the
coupling of the inflaton and Polonyi (supersymmetry-breaking) field in the
K\&quot;ahler potential, which is needed to build the inflaton potential. We point
out the same coupling let the inflaton dominantly decay into a pair of
inflatino and gravitino causing the gravitino problem. We propose some possible
solutions to this problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.03569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.03569</id><created>2017-09-11</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aguilera-Damia</keyname><forenames>Jerem&#xed;as</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>Diego H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fucito</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giraldo-Rivera</keyname><forenames>Victor I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Jose F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zayas</keyname><forenames>Leopoldo A. Pando</forenames></author></authors><title>Strings in Bubbling Geometries and Dual Wilson Loop Correlators</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>40 pages + appendices, 9 figures, A new discussion of WL correlators
  using the product of characters formula, two new figures added. Typos fixed.
  Version that matches the published article</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2017)109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a fundamental string in a bubbling geometry of arbitrary genus
dual to a half-supersymmetric Wilson loop in a general large representation
$\mathbf{R}$ of the $SU(N)$ gauge group in ${\cal N}=4$ Supersymmetric
Yang-Mills. We demonstrate, under some mild conditions, that the minimum value
of the string classical action for a bubbling geometry of arbitrary genus
precisely matches the correlator of a Wilson loop in the fundamental
representation and one in a general large representation. We work out the case
in which the large representation is given by a rectangular Young Tableau,
corresponding to a genus one bubbling geometry, explicitly. We also present
explicit results in the field theory for a correlator of two Wilson loops: a
large one in an arbitrary representation and a &quot;small&quot; one in the fundamental,
totally symmetric or totally antisymmetric representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.04040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.04040</id><created>2017-09-12</created><updated>2017-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roman-Taboada</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumis</keyname><forenames>Gerardo G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phase-diagram of time-periodically rippled zigzag graphene
  nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 2 appendices. Some issues with the text were
  corrected. Additional information about the experimental realization of our
  model and two figures were included for the sake of clarity. Comments and
  suggestions are welcome. The manuscript is to appear on Journal of Physics
  Communications</comments><doi>10.1088/2399-6528/aa98fd</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topological properties of electronic edge states in time-periodically
driven spatially-periodic corrugated zigzag graphene nanoribbons are studied.
An effective one-dimensional Hamiltonian is used to describe the electronic
properties of graphene and the time-dependence is studied within the Floquet
formalism. Then the quasienergy spectrum of the evolution operator is obtained
using analytical and numeric calculations, both in excellent agreement.
Depending on the external parameters of the time-driving, two different kinds
(type I and type II) of touching band points are found, which have a Dirac-like
nature at both zero and $\pm\pi$ quasienergy. These touching band points are
able to host topologically protected edge states for a finite size system. The
topological nature of such edge states was confirmed by an explicit evaluation
of the Berry phase in the neighborhood of type I touching band points and by
obtaining the winding number of the effective Hamiltonian for type II touching
band points. Additionally, the topological phase diagram in terms of the
driving parameters of the system was built.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05260</id><created>2017-09-15</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>J/$\psi$ elliptic flow in Pb-Pb collisions at $\mathbf{\sqrt{s_{\rm
  NN}}}$ = 5.02 TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 captioned figures, 1 table, authors from page 12,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/3831</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-EP-2017-237</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 242301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.242301</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We report a precise measurement of the J/$\psi$ elliptic flow in Pb-Pb
collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}} = 5.02$ TeV with the ALICE detector at the
LHC. The J/$\psi$ mesons are reconstructed at mid-rapidity ($|y| &lt; 0.9$) in the
dielectron decay channel and at forward rapidity ($2.5&lt;y&lt;4.0$) in the dimuon
channel, both down to zero transverse momentum. At forward rapidity, the
elliptic flow $v_2$ of the J/$\psi$ is studied as a function of transverse
momentum and centrality. A positive $v_2$ is observed in the transverse
momentum range $2 &lt; p_{\rm T} &lt; 8$ GeV/$c$ in the three centrality classes
studied and confirms with higher statistics our earlier results at
$\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}} = 2.76$ TeV in semi-central collisions. At mid-rapidity, the
J/$\psi$ $v_2$ is investigated as a function of transverse momentum in
semi-central collisions and found to be in agreement with the measurements at
forward rapidity. These results are compared to transport model calculations.
The comparison supports the idea that at low $p_{\rm T}$ the elliptic flow of
the J/$\psi$ originates from the thermalization of charm quarks in the
deconfined medium, but suggests that additional mechanisms might be missing in
the models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.07815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.07815</id><created>2017-09-22</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Esmail</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferguson</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooper pair tunnelling and quasiparticle poisoning in a galvanically
  isolated superconducting double dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 111, 252602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.5009079</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We increase the isolation of a superconducting double dot from its
environment by galvanically isolating it from any electrodes. We probe it using
high frequency reflectometry techniques, find 2e-periodic behaviour, and
characterise the energy structure of its charge states. By modelling the
response of the device, we determine the quasiparticle poisoning rate to be
significantly worse than that of a unisolated double dot, and conclude that
quasiparticle exchange between the dot and the leads is an important relaxation
mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08217</id><created>2017-09-24</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Neelesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhir</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimates of W-exchange contributions to $\Xi_{cc}$ decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 113006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.113006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Encouraged by recent discovery of $\Xi_{cc}^{++}$ baryon, we investigate two
body non-leptonic weak decays of doubly charmed, $\Xi_{cc}$, baryons. We
calculate the branching ratios for CKM-favored and suppressed modes in
factorization and pole model approach. We give the first estimates of
nonfactorizable W-exchange contributions using pole model. We find that
W-exchange contributions to $\Xi_{cc}$ decays being sizable can not be ignored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.10073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.10073</id><created>2017-09-28</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsang</keyname><forenames>Mankei</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum limits on the time-bandwidth product of an optical resonator</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. v2: expanded and submitted; v3: updated and
  published. Copyright 2018 Optical Society of America. One print or electronic
  copy may be made for personal use only. Systematic reproduction and
  distribution, duplication of any material in this paper for a fee or for
  commercial purposes, or modifications of the content of this paper are
  prohibited</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 43, 150-153 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.43.000150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A thought-provoking proposal by Tsakmakidis et al. [Science 356, 1260 (2017)]
suggests that nonreciprocal optics can break a time-bandwidth limit to passive
resonators. Here I quantize their resonator model and show that quantum
mechanics does impose a limit, or requires extra noise to be added in the same
fashion as amplified spontaneous emission in an active resonator. I also use
thermodynamics to argue that extra dissipation or noise must be present in
their proposed device.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04891</id><created>2017-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Koo</keyname><forenames>Bonho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bader</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkhard</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baenitz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gille</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sichelschmidt</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin dynamics of FeGa$_{3-x}$Ge$_x$ studied by Electron Spin Resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Condens. Matter 30, 045601 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aaa18a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The intermetallic semiconductor FeGa$_{3}$ acquires itinerant ferromagnetism
upon electron doping by a partial replacement of Ga with Ge. We studied the
electron spin resonance (ESR) of high-quality single crystals of
FeGa$_{3-x}$Ge$_x$ for $x$ from 0 up to 0.162 where ferromagnetic order is
observed. For $x = 0$ we observed a well-defined ESR signal, indicating the
presence of pre-formed magnetic moments in the semiconducting phase. Upon Ge
doping the occurrence of itinerant magnetism clearly affects the ESR properties
below $\approx 40$~K whereas at higher temperatures an ESR signal as seen in
FeGa$_{3}$ prevails independent on the Ge-content. The present results show
that the ESR of FeGa$_{3-x}$Ge$_x$ is an appropriate and direct tool to
investigate the evolution of 3d-based itinerant magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.05909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.05909</id><created>2017-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Fargion</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khlopov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Could GRB170817A be really correlated to a NS-NS merging?</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D, 4 December, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271818410018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exciting development of gravitational wave (GW) astronomy in the
correlation of LIGO and VIRGO detection of GW signals makes possible to expect
registration of effects of not only Binary Black Hole (BH) coalescence, but
also Binary Neutron Star (NS) merging accompanied by electromagnetic (GRB)
signal. Here we consider the possibility that a Neutron Star (NS), merging in a
NS-NS or NS-BH system might be (soon) observed in correlation with any
LIGO-VIRGO Gravitational Waves detection. We analyze as an example the recent
case of the short GRB 170817A observed by Fermi and Integral. The associated
Optical transient OT source in NGC4993 imply a rare near source, a consequent
averaged large rate of such events (almost) compatible with expected NS NS
merging rate. However the expected beamed GRB (or Short GRB) may be mostly
aligned to a different direction than our. Therefore even soft GRB photons,
more spread than hard ones, might be hardly able to shower to us. Nevertheless
a prompt spiraling electron turbine jet in largest magnetic fields, at the base
of the NS-NS collapse, might shine by its tangential synchrotron radiation in
spread way with its skimming photons shining in large open disk. The consequent
solid angle for such soft disk gamma radiation may be large enough to be
nevertheless often observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.06978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.06978</id><created>2017-10-18</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hayano</keyname><forenames>Ryugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyazaki</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of the UNSCEAR isodose maps for annual external exposure in
  Fukushima with those obtained based on the airborne monitoring surveys</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2016, UNSCEAR published an attachment to its Fukushima 2015 White Paper,
entitled &quot;Development of isodose maps representing annual external exposure in
Japan as a function of time,&quot; in which the committee presented annual
additional 1 mSv effective dose ab extra isodose lines for 1, 3, 5, 10, 30, 50
years after the accident, based on the soil deposition data of radionuclides
within 100 km from FDNPP. Meanwhile, the median of the ratio, c, between the
external effective dose rates and the ambient dose equivalent rates at 1 m
above the ground obtained by the airborne monitoring has been established to be
c~0.15. We here compare the UNSCEAR predictions with respect to estimates based
on the airborne monitoring. Although both methods and data used in the two
approaches are di erent, the resultant contours show relatively good agreement.
However, to improve the accuracy of long-term annual effective isodose lines,
feedback from continuous measurements such as airborne monitoring is important.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.10157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.10157</id><created>2017-10-24</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fitzgerald</keyname><forenames>Jamie M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giannini</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Battling Retardation And Nonlocality: The hunt For The Ultimate
  Plasmonic Cascade Nanolens</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a study of the achievable field enhancement of plasmonic cascade
nanolenses in the quantum and classical regimes, and explore the limits
enforced at larger sizes by retardation and at smaller sizes by nonlocality and
other quantum effects. We compare the near field response of a sodium nanolens
within a local and nonlocal formalism and find that the increased electron-
surface scattering decreases the field enhancements by over an order of
magnitude. The large parameter space is explored, within the local
approximation, for a number of plasmonic metals as well as the polar dielectric
SiC. Using localised surface phonon polaritons, which can be excited in polar
dielectrics, is an effective strategy for overcoming retardation due to the
lower energy phonon frequency. Finally, we compare the nanolens against the
more usual dimer configuration, we find that the superior geometry depends
crucially on the material used, with noble metal nanolenses unlikely to offer
better performance to equivalent dimers. Interestingly SiC nanolenses can offer
a larger maximum field enhancement compared to the corresponding dimer
configuration, suggesting that future endeavours in constructing a nanolens
should be based on polar dielectrics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.03780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.03780</id><created>2017-11-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haverkort</keyname><forenames>Maurits W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-perturbative series expansion of Green's functions: The Anatomy of
  Resonant Inelastic X-Ray Scattering in Doped Hubbard Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6+6 pages; 4+9 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.256401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a non-perturbative, divergence-free series expansion of Green's
functions using effective operators. The method is especially suited for
computing correlators of complex operators as a series of correlation functions
of simpler forms. We apply the method to study low-energy excitations in
resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS) in doped one- and two-dimensional
single-band Hubbard models. The RIXS operator is expanded into polynomials of
spin, density, and current operators weighted by fundamental x-ray spectral
functions. These operators couple to different polarization channels resulting
in simple selection rules. The incident photon energy dependent coefficients
help to pinpoint main RIXS contributions from different degrees of freedom. We
show in particular that, with parameters pertaining to cuprate superconductors,
local spin excitation dominates the RIXS spectral weight over a wide doping
range in the cross-polarization channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.04072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.04072</id><created>2017-11-10</created><updated>2017-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rachh</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serkh</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author></authors><title>On the solution of Stokes equation on regions with corners</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><report-no>YALE/DCS/TR1536</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Stokes flow, the stream function associated with the velocity of the fluid
satisfies the biharmonic equation. The detailed behavior of solutions to the
biharmonic equation on regions with corners has been historically difficult to
characterize. The problem was first examined by Lord Rayleigh in 1920; in 1973,
the existence of infinite oscillations in the domain Green's function was
proven in the case of the right angle by S.~Osher. In this paper, we observe
that, when the biharmonic equation is formulated as a boundary integral
equation, the solutions are representable by rapidly convergent series of the
form $\sum_{j} ( c_{j} t^{\mu_{j}} \sin{(\beta_{j} \log{(t)})} + d_{j}
t^{\mu_{j}} \cos{(\beta_{j} \log{(t)})} )$, where $t$ is the distance from the
corner and the parameters $\mu_{j},\beta_{j}$ are real, and are determined via
an explicit formula depending on the angle at the corner. In addition to being
analytically perspicuous, these representations lend themselves to the
construction of highly accurate and efficient numerical discretizations,
significantly reducing the number of degrees of freedom required for the
solution of the corresponding integral equations. The results are illustrated
by several numerical examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06545</id><created>2017-11-07</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiarelli</keyname><forenames>Piero</forenames></author></authors><title>The quantum hydrodynamic representation in curved space: An adequate
  gravity equation for quantum fields</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>The work has been revised following the adivices and the observations
  of a referee of Physical review D</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work the scalar free Klein-Gordon field coupled to the quantum
mechanical gravity equation (QMGE), that takes into account the quantum
property of matter, is quantized. The model has been developed at the first
order in the metric tensor with a self-consistent analytical dependence of the
energy impulse tensor by the quantum field. The quantum behavior, due to the
quantum potential energy, in the gravity equation (GE) has been investigated by
studying the energy-impulse tensor density generated the quantum field. The
outputs of the theory show that the vacuum energy density of the zero point is
effective for the cosmological constant only in the volume of space where the
mass is localized in particles or in high gravity bodies, leading to a
cosmological effect on the motion of the galaxies that is compatible with the
astronomical observations. The paper shows that the energy-impulse tensor
density makes the QMGE, in the quasi-Euclidean limit, physically independent by
the level of the zero-point energy density of the vacuum, and possibly
compatible with the renormalization techniques of the quantum field theory
(QFT). Finally, the coupling of the QGE to the quantum Dirac field has been
preliminary outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.02946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.02946</id><created>2017-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Yifei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Incorporation of Velocity-dependent Restitution Coefficient and Particle
  Surface Friction into Kinetic Theory for Modeling Granular Flow Cooling</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted for Physical Review E</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.062907</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kinetic theory (KT) has been successfully used to model rapid granular flows
in which particle interactions are frictionless and near elastic. However, it
fails when particle interactions become frictional and inelastic. For example,
the KT is not able to accurately predict the free cooling process of a vibrated
granular medium that consists of inelastic frictional particles under
microgravity. The main reason that the classical KT fails to model these flows
is due to its inability to account for the particle surface friction and its
inelastic behavior, which are the two most important factors that need be
considered in modeling collisional granular flows. In this study, we have
modified the KT model that is able to incorporate these two factors. The
inelasticity of a particle is considered by establishing a velocity-dependent
expression for the restitution coefficient based on many experimental studies
found in the literature, and the particle friction effect is included by using
a tangential restitution coefficient that is related to the particle friction
coefficient. Theoretical predictions of the free cooling process by the
classical KT and the improved KT are compared with the experimental results
from a study conducted on an airplane undergoing parabolic flights without the
influence of gravity [Y. Grasselli, G. Bossis, and G. Goutallier, EPL
(Europhysics Letters) 86, 60007 (2009)]. Our results show that both the
velocity- dependent restitution coefficient and the particle surface friction
are important in predicting the free cooling process of granular flows; the
modified KT model that integrates these two factors is able to improve the
simulation results and led to a better agreement with the experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.04977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.04977</id><created>2017-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Klimchitskaya</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostepanenko</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conductivity of graphene in the framework of Dirac model: Interplay
  between nonzero mass gap and chemical potential</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 5 figures; accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B, v.96, 235432-(1-14) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.235432</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The complete theory of electrical conductivity of graphene at arbitrary
temperature is developed with taken into account mass-gap parameter and
chemical potential. Both the in-plane and out-of-plane conductivities of
graphene are expressed via the components of the polarization tensor in
(2+1)-dimensional space-time analytically continued to the real frequency axis.
Simple analytic expressions for both the real and imaginary parts of the
conductivity of graphene are obtained at zero and nonzero temperature. They
demonstrate an interesting interplay depending on the values of mass gap and
chemical potential. In the local limit, several results obtained earlier using
various approximate and phenomenological approaches are reproduced, refined and
generalized. The numerical computations of both the real and imaginary parts of
the conductivity of graphene are performed to illustrate the obtained results.
The analytic expressions for the conductivity of graphene obtained in this
paper can serve as a guide in the comparison between different theoretical
approaches and between experiment and theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.07762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.07762</id><created>2017-12-20</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jovanovic</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guyon</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotani</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawahara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lozi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Males</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mawet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leon-Saval</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betters</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuthill</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Developing post-coronagraphic, high-resolution spectroscopy for
  terrestrial planet characterization on ELTs</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, AO4ELTs4 conference held in Tenerife</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spectroscopic observations are extremely important for determining the
composition, structure, and surface gravity of exoplanetary atmospheres. High
resolution spectroscopy of the planet itself has only been demonstrated a
handful of times. By using advanced high contrast imagers, it is possible to
conduct high resolution spectroscopy on imageable exoplanets, after the star
light is first suppressed with an advanced coronagraph. Because the planet is
spatially separated in the focal plane, a single mode fiber could be used to
collect the light from the planet alone, reducing the photon noise by orders of
magnitude. In addition, speckle control applied to the location where an
exoplanet is known to exist, can be used to preferentially reject the stellar
flux from the fiber further.
  In this paper we will present the plans for conducting high resolution
spectroscopic studies of this nature with the combination of SCExAO and IRD in
the H-band on the Subaru Telescope. This technique will be critical to the
characterization of terrestrial planets on ELTs and future space missions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.07956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.07956</id><created>2017-12-21</created><updated>2017-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Zhongyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caciagli</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Tianyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoev</keyname><forenames>Iliya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zupkauskas</keyname><forenames>Mykolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Neill</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wenzel</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamboll</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dongsheg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eiser</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author></authors><title>Microrheology of DNA Hydrogels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A key objective in DNA-based material science is understanding and precisely
controlling the mechanical properties of DNA hydrogels. We perform
microrheology measurements using diffusing-wave spectroscopy (DWS) to
investigate the viscoelastic behavior of a hydrogel made of Y-shaped DNA
nano-stars over a wide range of frequencies and temperatures. Results show a
clear liquid-to-equilibrium-gel transition as the temperature cycles up and
down across the melting-temperature region for which the Y-DNA bind to each
other. These first measurements reveal the crossover of the elastic
G'({\omega}) and loss modulus G'({\omega}) when the DNA-hydrogel formed at low
temperatures is heated to a fluid phase of DNA nano-stars well above the melt
temperature Tm. We show that the crossover relates to the life-time of the
DNA-bond and also that percolation coincides with the systems' Tm. The approach
demonstrated here can be easily extended to more complicated DNA hydrogel
systems and provides guidance for the future design of such transient,
semi-flexible networks that can be adapted to the application of molecular
sensing and controlled release.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08162</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Bertone</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botje</keyname><forenames>Michiel</forenames></author></authors><title>A C++ interface to QCDNUM</title><categories>hep-ph cs.MS</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this document we report on the recent development of a C++ interface to
the FORTRAN-based evolution program QCDNUM. A short description of the
interface is given with a few basic examples of its usage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08178</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Bezuidenhout</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venter</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seyffert</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harding</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calibration of statistical methods used to constrain pulsar geometries
  via multiband light curve modelling</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since its launch in 2008, the Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT) has detected
over 200 -ray pulsars above 100 MeV. This population of pulsars is
characterised by a rich diversity of light curve morphologies. Researchers have
been using both the radio and -ray light curves to constrain the inclination
and observer angles for each of these pulsars. At first, this was done using a
by-eye technique and later via statistical approaches. We have also developed
two novel statistical approaches that place the radio and -ray data on equal
footing despite their disparate relative flux errors. We chose eleven pulsars
from the Second Fermi Pulsar Catalog, both old and young, and applied these new
techniques as well as the by-eye technique to constrain their geometric
parameters using standard pulsar models. We present first results on our
comparison of the best-fit parameters yielded by each of the aforementioned
techniques. This will assist us in determining the utility of our new
statistical approaches, and gauge the overlap of the best-fit parameters (plus
errors) from each of the different methods. Such a statistical fitting approach
will provide the means for further pulsar magnetospheric model development
using light curve data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08183</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Hiromichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisarski</keyname><forenames>Robert D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skokov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible higher order phase transition in large-$N$ gauge theory at
  finite temperature</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, conference proceeding for Critical Point and
  Onset of Deconfinement - CPOD2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the phase structure of $SU(\infty)$ gauge theory at finite
temperature using matrix models. Our basic assumption is that the effective
potential is dominated by double-trace terms for the Polyakov loops. As a
function of the temperature, a background field for the Polyakov loop, and a
quartic coupling, it exhibits a universal structure: in the large portion of
the parameter space, there is a continuous phase transition analogous to the
third-order phase transition of Gross, Witten and Wadia, but the order of phase
transition can be higher than third. We show that different confining
potentials give rise to drastically different behavior of the eigenvalue
density and the free energy. Therefore lattice simulations at large $N$ could
probe the order of phase transition and test our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08187</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Elvati</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turrentine</keyname><forenames>Kirk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Violi</keyname><forenames>Angela</forenames></author></authors><title>The Role of Molecular Properties on the Dimerization of Aromatic
  Compounds</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Preprint submitted to Proceedings of the Combustion Institute</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent results have shown the presence and importance of oxygen chemistry
during the growth of aromatic compounds, leading to the formation of oxygenated
structures that have been identified in various environments. Since the
formation of polycyclic aromatic compounds (PAC) bridge the formation of
gas-phase species with particle inception, in this work we report a detailed
analysis of the effects of molecular characteristics on physical growth of PAC
via dimerization. We have included oxygen content, mass, type of bonds (rigid
versus rotatable), and shape as main properties of the molecules and studied
their effect on the propensity of these structures to form homo-molecular and
hetero-molecular dimers. Using enhanced sampling molecular dynamics techniques,
we have computed the free energy of dimerization in the temperature range
$500-1680$~K. Initial structures used in this study were obtained from
experimental data. The results show that although the effects of shape,
presence of oxygen, mass, and internal bonds are tightly intertwined, and their
relative importance changes with temperature. In general, mass and the presence
of rotatable bonds are the best indicators. The results provide knowledge on
the inception step and the role that particle characteristics play during
inception. In addition, our study highlights the fact that current models that
use stabilomers as monomers for physical aggregation are overestimating the
importance of this process during particle nucleation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08188</id><created>2017-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Sidhaarth</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suriyanarayanan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srigovindan</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiruvengadathan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Holistic Approach to Evaluate EMI Shielding Characteristics of Carbon
  Nanotube-based Polymer Composites</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted at IEEE-Nanotechnology Materials and Devices Conference
  (NMDC-2017), Singapore. 2 Pages, 2 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The work presents a comprehensive methodology to determine the Shielding
Effectiveness (SE) of single-walled carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs)/polymer
nanocomposites. Here, an algorithm based on Ant Colony Optimization (ACO) was
employed to determine the electrical conductivity ({\sigma}) of these
nanocomposites as a function of SWCNT concentration. Then, these {\sigma}
values were used to compute the SE values as a function of frequency and
concentration. Specifically, a pseudo three-dimensional (3D) percolation model
was developed to study the effects of random connectivity of SWCNTs to one
another on the {\sigma} values of the nanocomposites. Both intrinsic and
tunneling resistances were taken into account. The consequences of the presence
of both well-exfoliated and aggregated SWCNTs with varying lengths distributed
inhomogeneously on {\sigma} and SE values were investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08199</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godat</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jezo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keppel</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovarik</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyonnet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morfin</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olness</keyname><forenames>F. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owens</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schienbein</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>LHC data and its impact on nCTEQ15 PDFs</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures. 25th International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic
  Scattering and Related Topics (DIS 2017). PoS(DIS2017)204</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LHC heavy ion data for W/Z production can provide new incisive
information on the PDFs. This data is sensitive to the heavier quark flavors
(strange and charm) in a high energy kinematic region; this can facilitate the
determination of PDFs in the small x region where previous data was limited. At
present, the flavor separation of the proton PDFs is dependent on DIS data from
nuclear targets. Therefore, improved nuclear corrections can also yield
enhanced flavor determination of both the proton and nuclear PDFs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08202</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Minn</keyname><forenames>Khant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anopchenko</keyname><forenames>Aleksei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jingyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ho Wai Howard</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation of epsilon-near-zero resonance in ultra-thin indium tin oxide
  shell embedded nanostructured optical fiber</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a novel optical waveguide design of a hollow step index fiber
modified with a thin layer of indium tin oxide (ITO). We show an excitation of
highly confined waveguide mode in the proposed fiber near the wavelength where
permittivity of ITO approaches zero. Due to the high field confinement within
thin ITO shell inside the fiber, the epsilon-near-zero (ENZ) mode can be
characterized by a peak in modal loss of the hybrid waveguide. Our results show
that such in-fiber excitation of ENZ mode is due to the coupling of the guided
core mode to the thin-film ENZ mode. We also show that the phase matching
wavelength, where the coupling takes place, varies depending on the refractive
index of the constituents inside the central bore of the fiber. These ENZ
nanostructured optical fibers have many potential applications, for example, in
ENZ nonlinear and magneto-optics, as in-fiber wavelength-dependent filters, and
as subwavelength fluid channel for optical and bio-photonic sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08204</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Huajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen</keyname><forenames>Sampo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dijken</keyname><forenames>Sebastiaan</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchange-torque-induced excitation of perpendicular standing spin waves
  in nanometer-thick YIG films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin waves in ferrimagnetic yttrium iron garnet (YIG) films with ultralow
magnetic damping are relevant for magnon-based spintronics and low-power
wave-like computing. The excitation frequency of spin waves in YIG is rather
low in weak external magnetic fields because of its small saturation
magnetization, which limits the potential of YIG films for high-frequency
applications. Here, we demonstrate how exchange-coupling to a CoFeB film
enables efficient excitation of high-frequency perpendicular standing spin
waves (PSSWs) in nanometer-thick (80 nm and 295 nm) YIG films using uniform
microwave magnetic fields. In the 295-nm-thick YIG film, we measure intense
PSSW modes up to 10th order. Strong hybridization between the PSSW modes and
the ferromagnetic resonance mode of CoFeB leads to characteristic anti-crossing
behavior in broadband spin-wave spectra. A dynamic exchange torque at the
YIG/CoFeB interface explains the excitation of PSSWs. The localized torque
originates from exchange coupling between two dissimilar magnetization
precessions in the YIG and CoFeB layers. As a consequence, spin waves are
emitted from the YIG/CoFeB interface and PSSWs form when their wave vector
matches the perpendicular confinement condition. PSSWs are not excited when the
exchange coupling between YIG and CoFeB is suppressed by a Ta spacer layer.
Micromagnetic simulations confirm the exchange-torque mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08206</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Zurlo</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truskinovsky</keyname><forenames>Lev</forenames></author></authors><title>Inelastic Surface Growth</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inelastic surface growth associated with continuous creation of
incompatibility on the boundary of an evolving body is behind a variety of
natural and technological processes, including embryonic development and 3D
printing. In this paper we extend the recently proposed stress-space-centered
theory of surface growth (PRL 119, 048001, 2017) by shifting the focus towards
growth induced strains. To illustrate the new development we present several
analytically tractable examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08219</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>Sankha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enomoto</keyname><forenames>Seishi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Yaqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikivie</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todarello</keyname><forenames>Elisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Duration of Classicality of Homogeneous Condensates with Attractive
  Interactions</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages, no figures, contributed to the 13th Patras Workshop on
  Axions, WIMPs and WISPs, Thessaloniki, May 15 to 19, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter axions and other highly degenerate bosonic fluids are commonly
described by classical field equations. In a recent paper \cite{BECprop} we
calculated the duration of classicality of homogeneous condensates with
attractive contact interactions and of self-gravitating homogeneous condensates
in critical expansion. According to their classical equations of motion, such
condensates persist forever. In their quantum evolution parametric resonance
causes quanta to jump in pairs out of the condensate into all modes with
wavevector less than some critical value. We estimated in each case the time
scale over which the condensate is depleted and after which a classical
description is invalid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08220</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>F&#xfc;l&#xf6;p</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matolcsi</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s</forenames></author></authors><title>Probability current in zero-spin relativistic quantum mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages, no figures; material presented at the Zim\'anyi School,
  December 7-11, 2015, Budapest, Hungary</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the antisymmetric spinor tensor representation of spin-0
relativistic quantum mechanics provides a conserved current with positive
definite timelike component, interpretable as probability density. The
construction runs in complete analogy to the spin-1/2 case, and provides an
analogously natural one-particle Hilbert space description for spin 0. Except
for the free particle, the obtained formulation proves to be inequivalent to
the one based on the Klein--Gordon equation. The second quantized version may
lead to new field theoretical interaction terms for zero-spin particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08224</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Cintio</keyname><forenames>Pierfrancesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Shamik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casetti</keyname><forenames>Lapo</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-thermal states in models of filaments: a dynamical study</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>To appear in the proceedings of the international conference
  &quot;Francesco's legacy - Star Formation in Space and Time&quot; Firenze, Italy June
  5-9 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the origin of the non-thermal profiles observed in filamentary
structures in galactic molecular clouds by means of numerical dynamical
simulations. We find that such profiles are intrinsic features of the end
products of dissipationless collapse in cylindrical symmetry. Moreover, for
sufficiently cold initial conditions, we obtain end states characterized by
markedly anticorrelated radial density and temperature profiles. Gravitational,
dissipationless dynamics alone is thus sufficient to reproduce, at least
qualitatively, many of the properties of the observed non-thermal structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08233</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senkovskiy</keyname><forenames>B. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haberer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>F. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meerholz</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xfc;neis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindfors</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic enhancement of aligned semiconducting graphene nanoribbons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We couple photoluminescent semiconducting 7-atom wide armchair edge graphene
nanoribbons to plasmonic nanoantenna arrays and demonstrate an enhancement of
the photoluminescence and Raman scattering intensity of the nanoribbons by more
than one order of magnitude. The increase in signal allows us to study Raman
spectra with high signal-to-noise ratio. Using plasmonic enhancement we are
able to detect the off-resonant Raman signals from the modified radial
breathing-like mode (RBLM) due to physisorbed molecules, the 3rd order RBLM,
and C-H vibrations. We find excellent agreement between data and simulations
describing the spectral dependence of the enhancement and modifications of the
polarization anisotropy. The strong field gradients in the optical near-field
further allow us to probe the subwavelength coherence properties of the phonon
modes in the nanoribbons. We theoretically model this considering a finite
coherence length along the GNR direction. Our results allow estimating the
coherence length in graphene nanoribbons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08234</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Ebel</keyname><forenames>Denton S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>Sarah T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Elusive Origin of Mercury</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>To appear in &quot;Mercury: The View after MESSENGER&quot; edited by Solomon,
  Nittler &amp; Anderson (www.cambridge.org/9781107154452). This version is free to
  view and download for personal use only. Not for re-distribution, re-sale or
  use in derivative works. 37 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The MESSENGER mission sought to discover what physical processes determined
Mercury's high metal to silicate ratio. Instead, the mission has discovered
multiple anomalous characteristics about our innermost planet. The lack of FeO
and the reduced oxidation state of Mercury's crust and mantle are more extreme
than nearly all other known materials in the solar system. In contrast,
moderately volatile elements are present in abundances comparable to the other
terrestrial planets. No single process during Mercury's formation is able to
explain all of these observations. Here, we review the current ideas for the
origin of Mercury's unique features. Gaps in understanding the innermost
regions of the solar nebula limit testing different hypotheses. Even so, all
proposed models are incomplete and need further development in order to unravel
Mercury's remaining secrets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08249</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Mengxiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zongyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Liyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author></authors><title>Graph Clustering with Dynamic Embedding</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graph clustering (or community detection) has long drawn enormous attention
from the research on web mining and information networks. Recent literature on
this topic has reached a consensus that node contents and link structures
should be integrated for reliable graph clustering, especially in an
unsupervised setting. However, existing methods based on shallow models often
suffer from content noise and sparsity. In this work, we propose to utilize
deep embedding for graph clustering, motivated by the well-recognized power of
neural networks in learning intrinsic content representations. Upon that, we
capture the dynamic nature of networks through the principle of influence
propagation and calculate the dynamic network embedding. Network clusters are
then detected based on the stable state of such an embedding. Unlike most
existing embedding methods that are task-agnostic, we simultaneously solve for
the underlying node representations and the optimal clustering assignments in
an end-to-end manner. To provide more insight, we theoretically analyze our
interpretation of network clusters and find its underlying connections with two
widely applied approaches for network modeling. Extensive experimental results
on six real-world datasets including both social networks and citation networks
demonstrate the superiority of our proposed model over the state-of-the-art.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08253</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08253</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horowitz</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Zidu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couch</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author></authors><title>Core-Collapse Supernova Simulations including Neutrino Interactions from
  the Virial EOS</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, appears in Proc. IAU Symposium 331, SN 1987A, 30
  years later - Cosmic Rays and Nuclei from Supernovae and Their Aftermaths</comments><journal-ref>Supernova 1987A:30 years later - Cosmic Rays and Nuclei from
  Supernovae and their aftermaths, Proceedings of the International
  Astronomical Union, IAU Symposium, Volume 331, pp. 107-112</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1743921317004586</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Core-collapse supernova explosions are driven by a central engine that
converts a small fraction of the gravitational binding energy released during
core collapse to outgoing kinetic energy. The suspected mode for this energy
conversion is the neutrino mechanism, where a fraction of the neutrinos emitted
from the newly formed protoneutron star are absorbed by and heat the matter
behind the supernova shock. Accurate neutrino-matter interaction terms are
crucial for simulating these explosions. In this proceedings for IAUS 331, SN
1987A, 30 years later, we explore several corrections to the neutrino-nucleon
scattering opacity and demonstrate the effect on the dynamics of the
core-collapse supernova central engine via two dimensional
neutrino-radiation-hydrodynamics simulations. Our results reveal that the
explosion properties are sensitive to corrections to the neutral-current
scattering cross section at the 10-20% level, but only for densities at or
above $\sim 10^{12}$ g cm$^{-3}$
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08278</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Palmer</keyname><forenames>Jeremy C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haji-Akbari</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Rakesh S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martelli</keyname><forenames>Fausto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Car</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagiotopoulos</keyname><forenames>Athanassios Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debenedetti</keyname><forenames>Pablo G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on the Hybrid Monte Carlo Method</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the detailed balance condition for hybrid Monte Carlo method
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08293</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Albisetti</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petti</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sala</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silvani</keyname><forenames>Raffaele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacchi</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finizio</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wintz</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cal&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Xiaorui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raabe</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riedo</keyname><forenames>Elisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertacco</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanomagnonic waveguides based on reconfigurable spin-textures for spin
  computing</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnonics is gaining momentum as an emerging technology for information
processing. The wave character and Joule heating-free propagation of spin-waves
hold promises for highly efficient analog computing platforms, based on
integrated magnonic circuits. Miniaturization is a key issue but, so far, only
few examples of manipulation of spin-waves in nanostructures have been
demonstrated, due to the difficulty of tailoring the nanoscopic magnetic
properties with conventional fabrication techniques. In this Letter, we
demonstrate an unprecedented degree of control in the manipulation of
spin-waves at the nanoscale by using patterned reconfigurable spin-textures. By
space and time-resolved scanning transmission X-ray microscopy imaging, we
provide direct evidence for the channeling and steering of propagating
spin-waves in arbitrarily shaped nanomagnonic waveguides based on patterned
domain walls, with no need for external magnetic fields or currents.
Furthermore, we demonstrate a prototypic nanomagnonic circuit based on two
converging waveguides, allowing for the tunable spatial superposition and
interaction of confined spin-waves modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08298</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Abdel-Waged</keyname><forenames>Khaled</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felemban</keyname><forenames>Nuha</forenames></author></authors><title>Nucleon shadowing effects in $Cu+Cu$ and $Au+Au$ collisions at RHIC
  within the HIJING code</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Abdel-Waged et al 2017 J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aaa101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The centrality dependence of pseudorapidity density of charged particles ($
dN_{ch}/d\eta $) in $Cu+Cu$ ($Au+Au$) collisions at RHIC energy of $
\sqrt{s_{_{\rm NN}}}=22.4$ , $62.4 $ and $200$ ($19.6$, $62.4$ and $200$) GeV,
is investigated within an improved HIJING code. The standard HIJING model is
enhanced by a prescription for collective nucleon-nucleon ($NN$) interactions
and more modern parton distribution functions. The collective $NN$-interactions
are used to induce both cascade and nucleon shadowing effects. We find
collective cascade broadens the pseudorapidity distributions in the tails (at $
|\eta|&gt; y_{\rm beam} $) above $25-30\%$ collision centrality to be consistent
with the $ dN_{ch}/d\eta $ data at $ \sqrt{s_{_{\rm NN}}}=19.6$, $22.4$, $62.4
$ GeV. The overall contribution of nucleon shadowing is shown to depress the
whole shape of $ dN_{ch}/d\eta$ in the primary interaction region (at $ |\eta|&lt;
y_{\rm beam} $) for semiperipheral ($ 20-25 $ \%) and peripheral ($\ge
35-40$\%) $Cu+Cu$ ($Au+Au$) interactions at $ \sqrt{s_{_{\rm NN}}}=200$ GeV, in
accordance with the PHOBOS data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08323</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Osipov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mending $\rho\pi\pi$ vertex through the $\pi a_1$ diagonalization</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of the strong momentum dependence of the $\rho\pi\pi$-vertex in
the extended Nambu -- Jona-Lasinio model is solved by an appropriate choice of
fields for spin-1 particles. A corresponding phenomenological Lagrangian is
derived. As straightforward applications, the decay widths of $\rho\to\pi\pi$,
and $a_1\to\rho\pi$ transitions are calculated and compared with known
empirical data and previous theoretical estimates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08332</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Navamani</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pati</keyname><forenames>Swapan K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Charge Energy Rate for Organic Solids and Biomolecular
  Aggregates Through Drift-Diffusion and Hopping Transport Equations: A Unified
  Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive generalized charge energy rate equations for organic solids and
biomolecular aggregates, even when these are dynamically disordered. These
equations suggest that the transport in such cases rely on both drift and
diffusion phenomena. The presence of disorder and field effects makes the
equations nonlinear and together with cooperativity, these enhance the charge
and energy transport. The generalized drift diffusion expression connects the
adiabatic band and nonadiabatic hopping transport mechanisms, well suited for
any complex organic semiconductors or assemblies of bio molecular systems. Here
we have proposed donor-acceptor (DA) reaction state model, which examines the
probability of charge transfer and the rate between two distinct transition
state identities. From our analytical equations, we suggest that charge and
energy transport property in DA states can be tuned by only a single parameter,
i.e., the chemical potential. Importantly, we find the non-equilibrium assisted
drift-diffusion transport at non- steady state regime in 2D and 3D
semiconducting devices. The numerical results clearly support our unified
analytical equations, which goes beyond Einstein's diffusion law even in quasi-
equilibrium cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08336</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Nag</keyname><forenames>Sayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanyal</keyname><forenames>Shankha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Archi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sengupta</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Dipak</forenames></author></authors><title>Music of Brain and Music on Brain: A Novel EEG Sonification approach</title><categories>q-bio.NC cs.SD eess.AS physics.data-an</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures; Presented in the International Symposium on
  Frontiers of Research in speech and Music (FRSM)-2017, held at NIT, Rourkela
  in 15-16 December 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Can we hear the sound of our brain? Is there any technique which can enable
us to hear the neuro-electrical impulses originating from the different lobes
of brain? The answer to all these questions is YES. In this paper we present a
novel method with which we can sonify the Electroencephalogram (EEG) data
recorded in rest state as well as under the influence of a simplest acoustical
stimuli - a tanpura drone. The tanpura drone has a very simple yet very complex
acoustic features, which is generally used for creation of an ambiance during a
musical performance. Hence, for this pilot project we chose to study the
correlation between a simple acoustic stimuli (tanpura drone) and sonified EEG
data. Till date, there have been no study which deals with the direct
correlation between a bio-signal and its acoustic counterpart and how that
correlation varies under the influence of different types of stimuli. This is
the first of its kind study which bridges this gap and looks for a direct
correlation between music signal and EEG data using a robust mathematical
microscope called Multifractal Detrended Cross Correlation Analysis (MFDXA).
For this, we took EEG data of 10 participants in 2 min 'rest state' (i.e. with
white noise) and in 2 min 'tanpura drone' (musical stimulus) listening
condition. Next, the EEG signals from different electrodes were sonified and
MFDXA technique was used to assess the degree of correlation (or the cross
correlation coefficient) between tanpura signal and EEG signals. The variation
of {\gamma}x for different lobes during the course of the experiment also
provides major interesting new information. Only music stimuli has the ability
to engage several areas of the brain significantly unlike other stimuli (which
engages specific domains only).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08344</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Benquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yebing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jianxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shougang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jiguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploration of the magnetic-field-induced
  $5s5p$~$^3P_0$~-~$5s^2$~$^1S_0$ forbidden transition in bosonic Sr atom</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures, 055017</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics Communications 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2399-6528/aa9da5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We presented experimental and theoretical studies of the effect of an
external magnetic field on the forbidden transition in the bosonic Sr atom. In
our ultra-cold atomic system, the excitation fraction of
$5s5p$~$^3P_0$~-~$5s^2$~$^1S_0$ forbidden transition was measured under the
circumstance of the different magnetic field strengths by using the normalized
detection method. Based on perturbation theory, we calculated the
magnetic-field-induced $5s5p$~$^3P_0$~-~$5s^2$~$^1S_0$ transition rate. The
excitation fraction as a function of the magnetic field strength was deduced
according to the calculated results. A good agreement was found between the
experimental measurements and the calculations. This study should be helpful in
evaluating the magnetic field effects on the forbidden transition rate with
higher accuracy. Moreover, it can help to understand the ultra-cold atomic
interaction in the external magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08372</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Delagrange</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weil</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasumov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchiat</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deblock</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>0-Pi quantum transition in a carbon nanotube Josephson junction:
  Universal phase dependence and orbital degeneracy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Proceedings SCES 2017, accepted for publication in Physica B</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2017.09.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a quantum dot hybrid superconducting junction, the behavior of the
supercurrent is dominated by Coulomb blockade physics, which determines the
magnetic state of the dot. In particular, in a single level quantum dot singly
occupied, the sign of the supercurrent can be reversed, giving rise to a
pi-junction. This 0-pi transition, corresponding to a singlet-doublet
transition, is then driven by the gate voltage or by the superconducting phase
in the case of strong competition between the superconducting proximity effect
and Kondo correlations. In a two-level quantum dot, such as a clean carbon
nanotube, 0-pi transitions exist as well but, because more cotunneling
processes are allowed, are not necessarily associated to a magnetic state
transition of the dot. In this proceeding, after a review of 0-pi transitions
in Josephson junctions, we present measurements of current-phase relation in a
clean carbon nanotube quantum dot, in the single and two-level regimes. In the
single level regime, close to orbital degeneracy and in a regime of strong
competition between local electronic correlations and superconducting proximity
effect, we find that the phase diagram of the phase-dependent transition is a
universal characteristic of a discontinuous level-crossing quantum transition
at zero temperature. In the case where the two levels are involved, the
nanotube Josephson current exhibits a continuous 0-pi transition, independent
of the superconducting phase, revealing a different physical mechanism of the
transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08384</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rcio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Provid&#xea;ncia</keyname><forenames>Constan&#xe7;a</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetized QCD phase diagram</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the International Meeting &quot;Excited QCD&quot;, Sintra,
  Portugal, 07-13 May 2017</comments><journal-ref>Acta Phys.Polon.Supp. 10 (2017) no.4, 1197-1202</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolBSupp.10.1197</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the 2+1 flavor Nambu--Jona-Lasinio (NJL) model with the Polyakov loop,
we determine the structure of the QCD phase diagram in an external magnetic
field. Beyond the usual NJL model with constant couplings, we also consider a
variant with a magnetic field dependent scalar coupling, which reproduces the
Inverse Magnetic Catalysis (IMC) at zero chemical potential. We conclude that
the IMC affects the location of the Critical End Point, and found indications
that, for high enough magnetic fields, the chiral phase transition at zero
chemical potential might change from an analytic to a first-order phase
transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08390</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Da-jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Covariant hodograph transformations between nonlocal short pulse models
  and AKNS$(-1)$ system</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper presents hodograph transformation between nonlocal short pulse
models and the first member in the AKNS negative hierarchy (AKNS($-1$)). We
consider real and complex multi-component cases. It is shown that the
independent variables of the short pulse models and AKNS($-1$) that are
connected via hodograph transformation are covariant in nonlocal reductions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08396</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuchumov</keyname><forenames>Nikolai</forenames></author></authors><title>Limit shapes for the dimer model</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>33 pages, 26 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the existence of a limit shape for the dimer model on planar
periodic bipartite graphs with an arbitrary fundamental domain and arbitrary
periodic weights. This proof is based on a variational principle that uses the
locality of the model and the compactness of the space of states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08397</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Arnlind</keyname><forenames>Joakim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Shujary</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author></authors><title>K\&quot;ahler-Poisson algebras</title><categories>math.RA math-ph math.AC math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce K\&quot;ahler-Poisson algebras as analogues of algebras of smooth
functions on K\&quot;ahler manifolds, and prove that they share several properties
with their classical counterparts on an algebraic level. For instance, the
module of inner derivations of a K\&quot;ahler-Poisson algebra is a finitely
generated projective module, and allows for a unique metric and torsion-free
connection whose curvature enjoys all the classical symmetries. Moreover,
starting from a large class of Poisson algebras, we show that every algebra has
an associated K\&quot;ahler-Poisson algebra constructed as a localization. At the
end, detailed examples are provided in order to illustrate the novel concepts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08413</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Rosenblatt</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lafont</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levkivskyi</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabo</keyname><forenames>Ron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurman</keyname><forenames>Itamar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banitt</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heiblum</keyname><forenames>Moty</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umansky</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Transmission of heat modes across a potential barrier</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Published in Nature Communications 8, 2251 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-02433-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Controlling the transmission of electrical current using a quantum point
contact constriction paved a way to a large variety of experiments in
mesoscopic physics. The increasing interest in heat transfer in such systems
fosters questions about possible manipulations of quantum heat modes that do
not carry net charge(neutral modes). Here, we study the transmission of
upstream neutral modes through a quantum point contact in fractional
hole-conjugate quantum Hall states. Employing two different measurement
techniques, we were able to render the relative spatial distribution of these
chargeless modes with their charged counter-parts. In these states, which were
found to harbor more than one downstream charge mode, the upstream neutral
modes are found to flow with the inner charge mode - as theoretically
predicted. These results unveil a universal upstream heat current structure and
open the path for more complex engineering of heat flows and cooling mechanisms
in quantum nano-electronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08421</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Nokkala</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maniscalco</keyname><forenames>Sabrina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piilo</keyname><forenames>Jyrki</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovianity over ensemble averages in quantum complex networks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 4 figures. A contribution in the special issue &quot;40 years of
  the GKLS equation&quot; of &quot;Open Systems and Information Dynamics&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Open Systems &amp; Information Dynamics Vol. 24, No. 4 (2017) 1740018</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S1230161217400182</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider bosonic quantum complex networks as structured finite
environments for a quantum harmonic oscillator and investigate the interplay
between the network structure and its spectral density, excitation transport
properties and non-Markovianity. After a review of the formalism used, we
demonstrate how even small changes to the network structure can have a large
impact on the transport of excitations. We then consider the non-Markovianity
over ensemble averages of several different types of random networks of
identical oscillators and uniform coupling strength. Our results show that
increasing the number of interactions in the network tends to suppress the
average non-Markovianity. This suggests that tree networks are the random
networks optimizing this quantity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08424</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiang-qun</keyname><forenames>Fu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan-su</keyname><forenames>Bao</forenames></author><author><keyname>He-liang</keyname><forenames>Huang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jian-hong</keyname><forenames>Shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Wang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuo</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng-guang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author></authors><title>Realization of t-bit semiclassical quantum Fourier transform on IBM's
  quantum cloud computer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To overcome the difficulty of realizing large-scale quantum Fourier transform
(QFT) within existing technology, this paper presents a resource-saving method,
namely t-bit semiclassical QFT over (Z_(2^n)), which could realize large-scale
QFT using arbitrary-scale quantum register. Using our method, the scale of
quantum register can be determined flexibility according to the scale of
quantum system, enabling the quantum resource and speed of realizing QFT to be
optimal. By developing a feasible method to realize the control quantum gate
R_k, we experimentally demonstrate the 2-bit semiclassical QFT over (Z_(2^3))
on IBM's quantum cloud computer, showing the feasibility of our proposed
method. Then, we compare the actual performance of 2-bit semiclassical QFT and
standard QFT in the experiments. Experimental data show that the fidelity of
the result of 2-bit semiclassical QFT is higher than that of standard QFT,
which is mainly due to less two-qubit controlled gates are required in the
semiclassical QFT. Furthermore, based on the proposed method, we successfully
implement the Shor's algorithm to factorize N=15.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08426</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Greveling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Laan</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jagers</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Oosten</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization of a Bose-Einstein Condensate of Photons in a Dye-Filled
  Microcavity</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measure the polarization of a photon gas in a dye-filled microcavity. The
polarization is obtained by a single-shot measurement of the Stokes parameters.
We find that the polarization of both the thermal cloud and the Bose-Einstein
condensate of photons (phBEC) does not differ from shot to shot. In the case of
the phBEC, we find that the polarization correlates with the polarization of
the pump pulse. The polarization of the thermal cloud is independent of
parameters varied in the experiment and is governed by a hidden anisotropy in
the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08436</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Payez</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple and effective parametrisation for Earth-impacting orbits</title><categories>astro-ph.EP math.OC physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Technical Report, European Space Agency - Mission Analysis Section,
  ESOC, 2017. 28 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents a new parametrisation suitable for parameter-space studies
of heliocentric Earth-impacting orbits. Originally motivated by the issue of
potentially hazardous asteroids (PHAs) and the mitigation of such a risk, we
show that the simultaneous analysis of all the conceivable impacting elliptical
orbits is greatly facilitated by the use of a parametrisation that involves
only the true anomaly at impact, the eccentricity and the inclination.
  While the new parametrisation is presented from an explicit planetary-defence
perspective, it is general enough to be useful in analogous studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08456</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Lev</keyname><forenames>B. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zagorodny</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective diffusion of a colloidal particles in a liquid crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7pages, 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The collective diffusion effects in system of a colloidal particles in a
liquid crystal has been proposed. In this article described peculiarity of
collective diffusion colloidal particles in a liquid crystal, which can be
observe experimentally. The diffusion coefficient should be crucial dependence
from temperature and concentration of particles. In system colloidal particles
arise from the elastic distortion of the elastic director field the
inter-particle interaction. These interaction can cause nontrivial collective
behavior, as the results the non-monotonic dependence collective diffusion. Are
predicted a nontrivial behavior collective diffusion of colloidal particles in
a liquid crystal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08463</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Pi&#xf1;eirua</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiria</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godoy-Diana</keyname><forenames>Ramiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling of an actuated elastic swimmer</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>20 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Fluid Mech. (2017), vol. 829, pp. 731-750</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.570</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the force production dynamics of undulating elastic plates as a
model for fish-like inertial swimmers. Using a beam model coupled with
Lighthill's large-amplitude elongated-body theory, we explore different
localised actuations at one extremity of the plate (heaving, pitching, and a
combination of both) in order to quantify the reactive and resistive
contributions to the thrust. The latter has the form of a quadratic drag in
large Reynolds number swimmers and has recently been pointed out as a crucial
element in the thrust force balance. We validate the output of a weakly
nonlinear solution to the fluid--structure model using thrust force
measurements from an experiment with flexible plates subjected to the three
different actuation types. The model is subsequently used in a self-propelled
configuration ---with a skin friction model that balances thrust to produce a
constant cruising speed--- to map the reactive versus resistive thrust
production in a parameter space defined by the aspect ratio and the actuation
frequency. We show that this balance is modified as the frequency of excitation
changes and the response of the elastic plate shifts between different resonant
modes, the pure heaving case being the most sensitive to the modal response
with drastic changes in the reactive/resistive contribution ratio along the
frequency axis. We analyse also the role of the phase lag between the heaving
and pitching components in the case of combined actuation, showing in
particular a non-trivial effect on the propulsive efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08465</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>de Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano Sassoli</forenames></author></authors><title>On the quantum &quot;self-teleportation&quot; probability of a human body</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The probability of quantum relocation of a human body, at a given distance,
is estimated using two different methods, giving comparable results. Not only
the obtained values for the probabilities are inconceivably small, but
assumptions of a sci-fi nature are also necessary to ensure that they are not
identical to zero. The notions of 'non-spatiality' and 'superselection rule'
are also briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08472</id><created>2017-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Laforest</keyname><forenames>Timoth&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carpentras</keyname><forenames>Dino</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;nzi</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalczuk</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behar-Cohen</keyname><forenames>Francine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moser</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>A new microscopy for imaging retinal cells</title><categories>physics.optics physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 12 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1701.08854</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evaluation and monitoring of cells health in the human retina is crucial
and follow time course of retinal diseases, detect lesions before irreversible
visual loss and to evaluate treatment effects. Towards this goal, a major
challenge is to image and quantify retinal cells in human eyes in a
non-invasive manner. Despite the phenomenal advances in Optical Coherence
Tomography (OCT) and Adaptive Optics systems, in vivo imaging of many of these
cells is limited by the fact that cell contrast in reflection is extremely low.
Here, we report on a major advance by proposing and demonstrating a radically
different method compared with OCT to visualize retinal cells with high
contrast, resolution and an acquisition time suitable for clinical use. The
method uses a transscleral illumination which provides a high numerical
aperture in a dark field configuration. The light backscattered by the Retinal
Pigment Epithelium (RPE) and the choroid provides a forward illumination for
the upper layer of the retina, thus providing a transmission illumination
condition. By collecting the scattered light through the pupil, the partially
coherent illumination produces dark field images, which are combined to
reconstruct a quasi-quantitative phase image with twice the numerical aperture
given by the eye's pupil. The retrieved quasi-quantitative phase images (QPI)
of cells in ex vivo human and pig's eyes are validated with those taken with a
standard QPI system. We then apply the technique in vivo on human eye, without
pupil dilation, we demonstrated the feasibility to image retinal cells up to
the retinal pigment epithelium within a few seconds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08473</id><created>2017-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mashkin</keyname><forenames>Timur</forenames></author></authors><title>Solitons in the Presence of a Small, Slowly Varying Electric Field</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1705.05713</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the perturbed sine-Gordon equation $\theta_{tt}-\theta_{xx}+\sin
\theta=
  \varepsilon^2 f(\varepsilon x)$, where the external perturbation
$\varepsilon^2 f(\varepsilon x)$ corresponds to a small, slowly varying
electric field. We show that the initial value problem with an appropriate
initial state close enough to the solitary manifold has a unique solution,
which follows up to time $1/{\varepsilon}$ and errors of order $\varepsilon^{
3/4}$ a trajectory on the solitary manifold. The trajectory on the solitary
manifold is described by ODEs, which agree approximately up to errors of order
$\varepsilon^3$ with Hamilton equations for the restricted to the solitary
manifold sine-Gordon Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08476</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Gui</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobczak</keyname><forenames>Zuzanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Cai-Zhuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimczuk</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Kai-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Ternary Bismuthide SrPtBi2: Computation and Experiment in Synergism to
  Explore Solid-State Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A combination of theoretical calculation and the experimental synthesis to
explore the new ternary compound is demonstrated in the Sr-Pt-Bi system. Since
Pt-Bi is considered as a new critical charge-transfer pair for
superconductivity, it inspired us to investigate the Sr-Pt-Bi system. With a
thorough calculation of all the known stable/metastable compounds in the
Sr-Pt-Bi system and crystal structure predictions, the thermodynamic stability
of hypothetical stoichiometry, SrPtBi2, is determined. Followed by the
high-temperature synthesis and crystallographic analysis, the first ternary
bismuthide in Sr-Pt-Bi, SrPtBi2 was prepared and the stoichiometry was
confirmed experimentally. SrPtBi2 crystallizes in the space group Pnma (S.G.
62, Pearson Symbol oP48), which matches well with theoretical prediction using
an adaptive genetic algorithm (AGA). Using first-principles calculations, we
demonstrate that the orthorhombic structure has lower formation energies than
other 112 structure types, such as tetragonal BaMnBi2 (CuSmP2) and LaAuBi2
(CuHfSi2) structure types. The bonding analysis indicates the Pt-Bi
interactions play a critical role in structural stability. The physical
properties measurements show the metallic properties with low electron-phonon
interactions at the low temperature, which agrees with the electronic structure
assessment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08483</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Elise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rastegari</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Chengyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mongin</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamer</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasparian</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arissian</keyname><forenames>Ladan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diels</keyname><forenames>Jean-Claude</forenames></author></authors><title>HV discharge acceleration by sequences of UV laser filaments with
  visible and near-infrared pulses</title><categories>physics.optics physics.app-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 123040 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa9b76</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the triggering and guiding of DC high-voltage discharges over
a distance of 37 cm by filaments produced by ultraviolet (266 nm) laser pulses
of 200 ps duration. The latter reduce the breakdown electric field by half and
allow up to 80% discharge probability in an electric field of 920 kV/m. This
high efficiency is not further increased by adding nanosecond pulses in the
Joule range at 532 nm and 1064 nm. However, the latter statistically increases
the guiding length, thereby accelerating the discharge by a factor of 2. This
effect is due both to photodetachment and to the heating of the plasma channel,
that increases the efficiency of avalanche ionization and reduces electron
attachment and recombination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08484</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Gustin</keyname><forenames>Lea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Lingyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Max T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Rongying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron Counts, Structural Stability, and Magnetism in
  BaCuSn$_2$-CeNi$_1$$_-$$_x$Si$_2$-type YT$_x$Ge$_2$ (T= Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, and
  Ni)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Results of crystallographic refinement, the relationship between electron
counts and structural stability, and magnetic characterization of YT$_x$Ge$_2$
(T= Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) prepared using the arc melting method are
presented. These YT$_x$Ge$_2$ compounds crystallize in the
BaCuSn$_2$-CeNi$_1$$_-$$_x$Si$_2$-type structure with space group Cmcm, and the
site occupancies of 3d transition metals range from x = 0.22(1) for Cr to x =
0.66(1) for Ni. Based on a combination of single crystal and powder X-ray
diffraction and scanning electron microscopy, the trends are clearly
established that the smaller transition metal atoms exhibit larger occupancies
on T (Cu) site. Our investigation into the relationship between electron count
and site defect reveals that a stable configuration is obtained when reaching
10.3e- per transition metal (Y+T), which strongly correlates with the defect
observed in the case of T metals. Magnetic properties measurements indicate
paramagnetism for T = Cr, Fe, and Co, but ferromagnetism for T = Mn with a
Curie temperature at 293 K and effective moment ~ 3.6 uB/Mn. The absence of
superconductivity in this series is surprising because they consist of similar
building blocks and electron counts to superconducting
YGe$_1$$_.$$_5$$_+$$_d$Si$_2$ except for 3d transition metals. Introducing 3d
transition metals into the system plays a critical role in suppressing
superconductivity, offering new insights into the interplay between
superconductivity and magnetism in layered intermetallics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08488</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Tikhonov</keyname><forenames>Aleksey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asadchikov</keyname><forenames>Viktor E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Yurii O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roshchin</keyname><forenames>Boris S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ermakov</keyname><forenames>Yurii A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of DMPS Monolayers on a Water Substrate with Laboratory X-ray
  Reflectometer</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 pictures</comments><journal-ref>JETP 125, 1051 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776117120093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The molecular structure of dimyristoyl phosphatidylserine (DMPS) monolayers
on a water substrate in different phase states has been investigated under
normal conditions by X-ray reflectometry with a photon energy of ~ 8 keV.
According to the experimental data, the transition from a two-dimensional
expanded liquid state to a solid gel state (liquid crystal) accompanied by the
ordering of the hydrocarbon tails of the DMPS molecule occurs in the monolayer
as the surface pressure rises. The monolayer thickness is (20 +/- 3) Angstrom
and (28 +/- 2) Angstrom in the liquid and solid phases, respectively, with the
deflection angle of the molecular tail axis from the normal to the surface in
the gel phase being (26 +/- 8) deg. At least a twofold decrease in the degree
of hydration of the polar lipid groups also occurs under two-dimensional
monolayer compression. The reflectometry data have been analyzed using two
approaches: under the assumption about the presence of two layers with
different electron densities in the monolayer and without any assumptions about
the transverse surface structure. Both approaches demonstrate satisfactory
agreement between themselves in describing the experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08490</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>De Vecchi</keyname><forenames>Francesco C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite dimensional solutions to SPDEs and the geometry of infinite jet
  bundles</title><categories>math.PR nlin.SI</categories><msc-class>60H15, 35A30, 35B06</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Finite dimensional solutions to a class of stochastic partial differential
equations are obtained extending the differential constraints method for
deterministic PDE to the stochastic framework. A geometrical reformulation of
the stochastic problem using the concept of infinite jet bundles is provided
and a practical algorithm for explicitly computing these finite dimensional
solutions is developed. This method, covering the majority of the current
literature, is applied to a set of new SPDEs admitting finite dimensional
solutions taken from Heath-Jarrow-Morton framework, stochastic hydrodynamics
and filtering theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08495</id><created>2017-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Yamaleev</keyname><forenames>Robert M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Concept of semi-velocity and related wave equation</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The semi-velocity is defined as an exponential function of the rapidity.
Physically the semi-velocity is interpreted as the relativistic analogue of the
phase velocity, a geometrical interpretation done within the framework of
Beltrami-Klein and Poincar\'e models. A kinematical wave equation related with
the Fermat principle and the concept of the semi-velocity is derived.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08503</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>M. L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>D. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasconcellos</keyname><forenames>C. A. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadjimichef</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fine-tuning in scalar meson decay with bound-state corrections</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The glueball-quarkonia mixture decay amplitude has been evaluated, in the
literature, by diagrammatic techniques for drawing quark lines and the
quark-gluon vertex. In this paper we use an alternative approach which consists
in a mapping technique, the Fock-Tani formalism, in order to obtain an
effective Hamiltonian starting from microscopic interactions. An extra effect
is present in this formalism associated to the extended nature of mesons:
bound-state corrections, which introduces an additional decay amplitude and
sets a fine-tuning procedure for general meson decay calculations. The
$f_0(1500) \to \pi \pi$ channel shall be considered as numerical example of the
procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08504</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaoran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Yanwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Middey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kareev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haskel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arenholz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakhalian</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis and electronic properties of Ruddlesden-Popper strontium
  iridate epitaxial thin films stabilized by control of growth kinetics</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review MATERIALS 1, 075004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.075004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the selective fabrication of high-quality Sr$_2$IrO$_4$ and
SrIrO$_3$ epitaxial thin films from a single polycrystalline Sr$_2$IrO$_4$
target by pulsed laser deposition. Using a combination of X-ray diffraction and
photoemission spectroscopy characterizations, we discover that within a
relatively narrow range of substrate temperature, the oxygen partial pressure
plays a critical role in the cation stoichiometric ratio of the films, and
triggers the stabilization of different Ruddlesden-Popper (RP) phases. Resonant
X-ray absorption spectroscopy measurements taken at the Ir $L$-edge and the O
$K$-edge demonstrate the presence of strong spin-orbit coupling, and reveal the
electronic and orbital structures of both compounds. These results suggest that
in addition to the conventional thermodynamics consideration, higher members of
the Sr$_{n+1}$Ir$_n$O$_{3n+1}$ series can possibly be achieved by kinetic
control away from the thermodynamic limit. These findings offer a new approach
to the synthesis of ultra-thin films of the RP series of iridates and can be
extended to other complex oxides with layered structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08506</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact values of quantum violations in low-dimensional Bell correlation
  inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The famous Clauser-Horne-Shimony-Holt (CHSH) inequality certifies a quantum
violation, by a factor $\sqrt{2}$, of correlations predicted by the classical
view of the world in the simplest possible nontrivial measurement setup (two
systems with two dichotomic measurements each). In such setting, this is the
largest possible violation, which is known as the \emph{Tsirelson bound}. In
this paper we calculate the exact values of quantum violations for the other
Bell correlation inequalities that appear in the setups involving up to four
measurements; they are all smaller than $\sqrt{2}$. While various authors
investigated these inequalities via numerical methods, our approach is
analytic. We also include tables summarizing facial structure of Bell polytopes
in low dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08510</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Dedovets</keyname><forenames>Dmytro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monteux</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;cile</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author></authors><title>A temperature-controlled stage for laser scanning confocal microscopy
  and case studies in chemistry of materials</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>31 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If confocal microscopy is an ubiquitous tool in life science, its
applications in chemistry and materials science are still, in comparison, very
limited. Of particular interest in these domains is the use of confocal
microscopy to investigate temperature-dependent phenomena such as
self-assembly, diffusio- or thermophoresis, or crystal growth. Several hurdles
must be solved to develop a temperature-controlled stage for laser scanning
confocal microscopy, in particular regarding the influence of an elevated
temperature gradient close to the microscope objective, which most people try
very hard to avoid. Here we report the design of a temperature-controlled stage
able to generate stable temperature gradients in both positive and negative
temperature range and does not require use of liquid nitrogen. Our setup
provides an excellent control of the temperature gradient, which can be coupled
with a controlled displacement of the sample, making it useful in particular
for a variety of solidification, chemistry, and interfacial problems. We
illustrate the benefits of our setup with several case studies of interest in
chemistry and materials science: the 3D real-time imaging of ice growth, the
segregation of hard particles by growing crystals, the freezing behaviour of
single emulsions, the self-shaping of oil droplets upon cooling, and the
self-assembly of amphiphile molecules into helical structures. These results
show how confocal microscopy coupled with a temperature-controlled stage is a
welcome addition to the toolkit of chemists and materials scientists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08515</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Korol</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Dvira</forenames></author></authors><title>From exhaustive simulations to key principles in DNA nanoelectronics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Charge transfer can take place along double helical DNA over distances as
long as 30 nanometers. However, given the active role of the thermal
environment surrounding charge carriers in DNA, physical mechanisms driving the
transfer process are highly debated. Moreover, the overall potential of DNA to
act as a conducting material in nanoelectronic circuits is questionable. Here,
we identify key principles in DNA nanoelectronics by performing an exhaustive
computational study. The electronic structure of double-stranded DNA is
described with a coarse-grained model. The dynamics of the molecular system and
its environment is taken into account using a quantum scattering method,
mimicking incoherent, elastic and inelastic effects. By analyzing all possible
sequences with 3 to 7 base pairs, we identify fundamental principles in DNA
nanoelectronics: The environment crucially influences the electrical
conductance of DNA, and the majority of sequences conduct via a mixed,
coherent-incoherent mechanism. Likewise, the metal-molecule coupling and the
gateway states play significant roles in the transport behavior. While most
sequences analyzed here are exposed to be rather poor electrical conductors, we
identify exceptional DNA molecules, which we predict to be excellent and robust
conductors of electric current over a wide range of physical conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08517</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Althammer</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goennenwein</keyname><forenames>Sebastian T. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetically Ordered Insulators for Advanced Spintronics</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetically ordered, electrically insulating materials pave the way towards
novel spintronic devices. In these materials the flow of magnetic excitations
such as magnons results in pure spin currents. These spin currents can be
driven by gradients of the spin chemical potential and/or temperature such that
they can play the same role in novel spintronic devices as charge currents in
traditional electronic circuits. Connecting spin current based and charge
current based devices requires spin to charge interconversion. This has been
achieved by the spin Hall effect with an efficiency of several 10%. The recent
progress in materials development and understanding of pure spin current
physics opens up a plethora of novel device concepts and opportunities for
fundamental studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08527</id><created>2017-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Hadjesfandiari</keyname><forenames>Ali R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hajesfandiari</keyname><forenames>Arezoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Haoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dargush</keyname><forenames>Gary F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Size-dependent couple stress Timoshenko beam theory</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>48 pages, 12 figures, 60 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a new size-dependent Timoshenko beam model is developed based
on the consistent couple stress theory. In the present formulation, the
governing equations and corresponding boundary conditions are obtained.
Afterwards, this formulation is used to investigate size-dependency for several
elementary beam problems. Analytical solutions are obtained for pure bending of
a beam and for a cantilever beam with partially and fully clamped boundary
conditions. These analytical results are then compared to the numerical results
from a two-dimensional finite element formulation for the corresponding couple
stress continuum problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08531</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Levitt</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#x163;&#x103;</keyname><forenames>M&#x103;d&#x103;lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kypraios</keyname><forenames>Theodore</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification and Estimation of Quantum Linear Input-Output Systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Matthew Levitt PhD Thesis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The system identification problem is to estimate dynamical parameters from
the output data, obtained by performing measurements on the output fields. We
investigate system identification for quantum linear systems. Our main
objectives are to address the following general problems: (1) Which parameters
can be identified by measuring the output? (2) How can we construct a system
realisation from sufficient input-output data? (3) How well can we estimate the
parameters governing the dynamics? We investigate these problems in two
contrasting approaches; using time-dependent inputs or time-stationary (quantum
noise) inputs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08535</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Shivam</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coldea</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moessner</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McClarty</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron Scattering Signatures of Magnon Weyl Points</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the inelastic neutron scattering cross section in the vicinity of
touching points in magnon bands. Among the possible touching points are magnon
Weyl points in three dimensional ordered magnets with significant spin-orbit
coupling that are characterized by a linear dispersion in their vicinity. A
Weyl point is topologically protected by its net chirality and here we show
that this leads to a characteristic form for the dynamical structure factor. To
address this question, we show that scattering intensities in the vicinity of
arbitrary magnon two-band touching points are identical to expectation values
of the pseudospin polarization along some direction $\hat{\boldsymbol{n}}$ in
momentum space fixed by the magnetic Hamiltonian. This approach applied to Weyl
points shows that they are singular points in the intensity of the form
$\hat{\boldsymbol{n}}\cdot \delta\hat{\boldsymbol{k}}$ regardless of the
magnetic ground state. We make specific predictions for the experimental
signatures of such intensity singularities in several spin models hosting Weyl
magnons applicable to candidate materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08541</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ablinger</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blumlein</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Round</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Special functions, transcendentals and their numerics</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cyclotomic polylogarithms are reviewed and new results concerning the special
constants that occur are presented. This also allows some comments on previous
literature results using PSLQ.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08542</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williamson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation Reaction in the Plasma-Based High-Energy Accelerators</title><categories>physics.acc-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasma-based accelerators have achieved tremendous progress in the past few
decades, thanks to the advances of high power lasers and the availability of
high-energy and relativistic particle beams. However, the electrons (or
positrons) accelerated in the plasma wakefields are subject to radiation
losses, which generally suppress the final energy gains of the beams. In this
paper, radiation reaction in plasma-based high-energy accelerators is
investigated using test particle approach. Energy-frontier TeV colliders based
on a multiple stage laser-driven plasma wakefield accelerator and a
single-staged proton-driven plasma wakefield accelerator are studied in detail.
The results show that the higher axial and transverse field gradients seen by
an off-axis injected witness beam result in a stronger damping force on the
accelerated particles. Proton-driven plasma wakefield accelerated electrons are
shown to lose less energy compared to those accelerated in a multi-staged
laser-driven plasma wakefield accelerator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08579</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Boughn</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reginatto</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author></authors><title>Another look through Heisenberg's microscope</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 1 figure European Journal of Physics (in press)</comments><doi>10.1088/1361-6404/aaa33f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heisenberg introduced his famous uncertainty relations in a seminal 1927
paper entitled &quot;The Physical Content of Quantum Kinematics and Mechanics&quot;. He
motivated his arguments with a gedanken experiment, a gamma ray microscope to
measure the position of a particle. A primary result was that, due to the
quantum nature of light, there is an inherent uncertainty in the determinations
of the particle's position and momentum dictated by an indeterminacy relation,
$\delta q \delta p \sim h$. Heisenberg offered this demonstration as &quot;a direct
physical interpretation of the [quantum mechanical] equation $\textbf{pq} -
\textbf{qp} = -i\hbar$&quot; but considered the indeterminacy relation to be much
more than this. He also argued that it implies limitations on the very meanings
of position and momentum and emphasized that these limitations are the source
of the statistical character of quantum mechanics. In addition, Heisenberg
hoped but was unable to demonstrate that the laws of quantum mechanics could be
derived directly from the uncertainty relation. In this paper, we revisit
Heisenberg's microscope and argue that the Schr\&quot;odinger equation for a free
particle does indeed follow from the indeterminacy relation together with
reasonable statistical assumptions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08584</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Jovanovic</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guyon</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lozi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuthill</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huby</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacour</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchis</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchene</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauchet</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feger</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rains</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bento</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coutts</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cvetojevic</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arriola</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagadec</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goebel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazin</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massie</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groff</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chilcote</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasdin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loomis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galvin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotani</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawahara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinache</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Males</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pioneering high contrast science instruments for planet characterization
  on giant segmented mirror telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, AO4ELTs4 conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A suite of science instruments is critical to any high contrast imaging
facility, as it defines the science capabilities and observing modes available.
SCExAO uses a modular approach which allows for state-of-the-art visitor
modules to be tested within an observatory environment on an 8-m class
telescope. This allows for rapid prototyping of new and innovative imaging
techniques that otherwise take much longer in traditional instrument design.
With the aim of maturing science modules for an advanced high contrast imager
on an giant segmented mirror telescopes (GSMTs) that will be capable of imaging
terrestrial planets, we offer an overview and status update on the various
science modules currently under test within the SCExAO instrument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.08600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1712.08600</id><created>2017-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Gianoli</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Risler</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlov</keyname><forenames>Andrei S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lipid bilayer mediates ion-channel cooperativity in a model of hair-cell
  mechanotransduction</title><categories>q-bio.SC physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>The Supporting Information is attached at the end as an included
  image</comments><journal-ref>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 114:E11010--E11019 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1713135114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mechanoelectrical transduction in the inner ear is a biophysical process
underlying the senses of hearing and balance. The key players involved in this
process are mechanosensitive ion channels. They are located in the stereocilia
of hair cells and opened by the tension in specialized molecular springs, the
tip links, connecting adjacent stereocilia. When channels open, the tip links
relax, reducing the hair-bundle stiffness. This gating compliance makes hair
cells especially sensitive to small stimuli. The classical explanation for the
gating compliance is that the conformational rearrangement of a single channel
directly shortens the tip link. However, to reconcile theoretical models based
on this mechanism with experimental data, an unrealistically large structural
change of the channel is required. Experimental evidence indicates that each
tip link is a dimeric molecule, associated on average with two channels at its
lower end. It also indicates that the lipid bilayer modulates channel gating,
although it is not clear how. Here, we design and analyze a model of
mechanotransduction where each tip link attaches to two channels, mobile within
the membrane. Their states and positions are coupled by membrane-mediated
elastic forces arising from the interaction between the channels' hydrophobic
cores and that of the lipid bilayer. This coupling induces cooperative opening
and closing of the channels. The model reproduces the main properties of
hair-cell mechanotransduction using only realistic parameters constrained by
experimental evidence. This work provides an insight into the fundamental role
that membrane-mediated ion-channel cooperativity can play in sensory
physiology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
