<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:42:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-08-24" from="2017-08-24" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0905.0078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0905.0078</id><created>2009-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>P. H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulenburg</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The DSUB$m$ Approximation Scheme for the Coupled Cluster Method and
  Applications to Quantum Magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Condensed Matter Physics, 12, No 3, 479 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.5488/CMP.12.3.479</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new approximate scheme, DSUB$m$, is described for the coupled cluster
method. We then apply it to two well-studied (spin-1/2 Heisenberg
antiferromagnet) spin-lattice models, namely: the $XXZ$ and the $XY$ models on
the square lattice in two dimensions. Results are obtained in each case for the
ground-state energy, the sublattice magnetization and the quantum critical
point. They are in good agreement with those from such alternative methods as
spin-wave theory, series expansions, quantum Monte Carlo methods and those from
the CCM using the LSUB$m$ scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.3971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.3971</id><created>2013-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Moch&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>W. Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez-Sol&#xed;s</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effectiveness of the GT200 Molecular Detector: A Double-Blind Test</title><categories>physics.soc-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables, additional data files attached</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Technology and Society Magazine {\bf 36} No. 2, 76-82 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/MTS.2017.2696601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The GT200 is a device that has been extensively used by the Mexican armed
forces to remotely detect and identify substances such as drugs and explosives.
A double blind experiment has been performed to test its effectivity. In
seventeen out of twenty attempts, the GT200 failed in the hands of certified
operators to find more than 1600 amphetamine pills and four bullets hidden in a
randomly chosen cardboard box out of eight identical boxes distributed within a
90m$\times$20m ballroom. This result is compatible with the 1/8 probability
expected for a completely ineffectual device, and is incompatible with even a
moderately effective working one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1302.5666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1302.5666</id><created>2013-01-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Kapur</keyname><forenames>Tina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egger</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damato</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Ehud J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viswanathan</keyname><forenames>Akila N.</forenames></author></authors><title>3T MR-Guided Brachytherapy for Gynecologic Malignancies</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.GR</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures, 41 references. Epub 2012 Aug 13</comments><journal-ref>Magn Reson Imaging, 2012, 30(9):1279-90</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mri.2012.06.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gynecologic malignancies are a leading cause of death in women worldwide.
Standard treatment for many primary and recurrent gynecologic cancer cases
includes a combination of external beam radiation, followed by brachytherapy.
Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is benefitial in diagnostic evaluation, in
mapping the tumor location to tailor radiation dose, and in monitoring the
tumor response to treatment. Initial studies of MR-guidance in gynecologic
brachtherapy demonstrate the ability to optimize tumor coverage and reduce
radiation dose to normal tissues, resulting in improved outcomes for patients.
In this article we describe a methodology to aid applicator placement and
treatment planning for 3 Tesla (3T) MR-guided brachytherapy that was developed
specifically for gynecologic cancers. This has been used in 18 cases to date in
the Advanced Multimodality Image Guided Operating suite at Brigham and Women's
Hospital. It is comprised of state of the art methods for MR imaging, image
analysis, and treatment planning. An MR sequence using 3D-balanced steady state
free precession in a 3T MR scan was identified as the best sequence for
catheter identification with ballooning artifact at the tip. 3D treatment
planning was performed using MR images. Item in development include a software
module designed to support virtual needle trajectory planning that includes
probabilistic bias correction, graph based segmentation, and image registration
algorithms. The results demonstrate that 3T MR has a role in gynecologic
brachytherapy. These novel developments improve targeted treatment to the tumor
while sparing the normal tissues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.5069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.5069</id><created>2013-11-20</created><updated>2015-05-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lovas</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andai</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author></authors><title>Refinement of Robertson-type uncertainty principles with geometric
  interpretation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><msc-class>62B10, 94A17</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Quantum Inf., 14(2):1650013, 15, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generalisation of the classical covariance for quantum mechanical
observables has previously been presented by Gibilisco, Hiai and Petz.
Gibilisco and Isola has proved that the usual quantum covariance gives the
sharpest inequalities for the determinants of covariance matrices. We introduce
a new generalisation of the classical covariance which gives better
inequalities than the classical one furthermore it has a direct geometric
interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.4049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.4049</id><created>2014-10-15</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krajniak</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banaszak</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Monte Carlo Study of Patchy Nanostructures Self-Assembled from a Single
  Multiblock Chain</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cs.CE</categories><journal-ref>Computational Methods in Science and Technology, 19(3) 137-143,
  2013</journal-ref><doi>10.12921/cmst.2013.19.03.137-143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a lattice Monte Carlo simulation for a multiblock copolymer chain
of length N=240 and microarchitecture $(10-10)_{12}$.The simulation was
performed using the Monte Carlo method with the Metropolis algorithm. We
measured average energy, heat capacity, the mean squared radius of gyration,
and the histogram of cluster count distribution. Those quantities were
investigated as a function of temperature and incompatibility between segments,
quantified by parameter {\omega}. We determined the temperature of the
coil-globule transition and constructed the phase diagram exhibiting a variety
of patchy nanostructures. The presented results yield a qualitative agreement
with those of the off-lattice Monte Carlo method reported earlier, with a
significant exception for small incompatibilities,{\omega}, and low
temperatures, where 3-cluster patchy nanostructures are observed in contrast to
the 2-cluster structures observed for the off-lattice $(10-10)_{12}$ chain. We
attribute this difference to a considerable stiffness of lattice chains in
comparison to that of the off-lattice chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.2078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.2078</id><created>2014-11-07</created><updated>2017-03-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Yefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Ramanujan Identities and Quasi-Modularity in Gromov-Witten Theory</title><categories>math.AG hep-th math.NT</categories><comments>Version 3 (journal version): typos corrected, shortened. See version
  2 for complete discussions. Mathematica Notebook files as an aid in doing
  computations are available upon request</comments><msc-class>14N35, 11Fxx</msc-class><journal-ref>Communications in Number Theory and Physics, vol 11. no. 2,
  405-452, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/CNTP.2017.v11.n2.a5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the ancestor Gromov-Witten correlation functions of
one-dimensional compact Calabi-Yau orbifolds are quasi-modular forms. This
includes the pillowcase orbifold which can not yet be handled by using
Milanov-Ruan's B-model technique. We first show that genus zero modularity is
obtained from the phenomenon that the system of WDVV equations is essentially
equivalent to the set of Ramanujan identities satisfied by the generators of
the ring of quasi-modular forms for a certain modular group associated to the
orbifold curve. Higher genus modularity then follows by using tautological
relations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.5632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.5632</id><created>2014-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Labouvie</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Bodhaditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heun</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wimberger</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Herwig</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative differential conductivity in an interacting quantum gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 050601 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.050601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Negative differential conductivity (NDC) is a widely exploited effect in
modern electronic components. Here, a proof-of-principle is given for the
observation of NDC in a quantum transport device for neutral atoms employing a
multi-mode tunneling junction. The transport of the many-body quantum system is
governed by the interplay between the tunnel coupling, the interaction energy
and the thermodynamics of intrinsic collisions, which turn the coherent
coupling into a hopping process. The resulting current voltage characteristics
exhibit NDC, for which we identify a new microscopic physical mechanism. Our
study opens new ways for the future implementation and control of complex
neutral atom quantum circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05338</id><created>2015-02-18</created><updated>2017-02-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Fadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Jinwu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wu-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum incommensurate Skyrmion crystals and Commensurate to
  In-commensurate transitions in cold atoms and materials with spin orbit
  couplings in a Zeeman field</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>21 pages, 7 figures, Revtex 4</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 083015 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study strongly interacting spinor atoms in a lattice subject
to a 2 dimensional (2d) anisotropic Rashba type of spin orbital coupling (SOC)
and an Zeeman field. We find the interplay between the Zeeman field and the SOC
provides a new platform to host rich and novel classes of quantum commensurate
and in-commensurate phases, excitations and phase transitions. These
commensurate phases include two collinear states at low and high Zeeman field,
two co-planar canted states at Mirror reflected SOC parameters respectively.
Most importantly, there are non-coplanar incommensurate Skyrmion (IC-SkX)
crystal phases surrounded by the 4 commensurate phases. New excitation spectra
above all the 5 phases, especially on the IC-SKX phase are computed. Three
different classes of quantum commensurate to in-commensurate transitions from
the IC-SKX to its 4 neighboring commensurate phases are identified. Finite
temperature behaviors and transitions are discussed. The critical temperatures
of all the phases can be raised above that reachable by current cold atom
cooling techniques simply by tuning the number of atoms $ N $ per site. In view
of recent impressive experimental advances in generating 2d SOC for cold atoms
in optical lattices, these new many-body phenomena can be explored in the
current and near future cold atom experiments. Applications to various
materials such as MnSi, Fe$_{0.5}$Co$_{0.5}$Si, especially the complex
incommensurate magnetic ordering in Li$_2$IrO$_3$ are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.06415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.06415</id><created>2015-02-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Joshua C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fok</keyname><forenames>Pak-Wing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Bayesian field theoretic reconstruction of bond potential and bond
  mobility in single molecule force spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.data-an cond-mat.stat-mech math.OC q-bio.QM</categories><comments>In review - Python source code available on github. Abridged abstract
  on arXiv</comments><journal-ref>Biophysical journal 109.5 (2015): 966-974</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.bpj.2015.07.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantifying the forces between and within macromolecules is a necessary first
step in understanding the mechanics of molecular structure, protein folding,
and enzyme function and performance. In such macromolecular settings, dynamic
single-molecule force spectroscopy (DFS) has been used to distort bonds. The
resulting responses, in the form of rupture forces, work applied, and
trajectories of displacements, have been used to reconstruct bond potentials.
Such approaches often rely on simple parameterizations of one-dimensional bond
potentials, assumptions on equilibrium starting states, and/or large amounts of
trajectory data. Parametric approaches typically fail at inferring
complex-shaped bond potentials with multiple minima, while piecewise estimation
may not guarantee smooth results with the appropriate behavior at large
distances. Existing techniques, particularly those based on work theorems, also
do not address spatial variations in the diffusivity that may arise from
spatially inhomogeneous coupling to other degrees of freedom in the
macromolecule, thereby presenting an incomplete picture of the overall bond
dynamics. To solve these challenges, we have developed a comprehensive
empirical Bayesian approach that incorporates data and regularization terms
directly into a path integral. All experiemental and statistical parameters in
our method are estimated empirically directly from the data. Upon testing our
method on simulated data, our regularized approach requires fewer data and
allows simultaneous inference of both complex bond potentials and diffusivity
profiles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.01586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.01586</id><created>2015-03-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Niederpr&#xfc;m</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manthey</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Tobias M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Herwig</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant cross section for molecular ion formation in ultracold Rydberg
  gases</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.chem-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 013003 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.013003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the associative ionization of a Rydberg atom and a ground
state atom in an ultracold Rydberg gas. The measured scattering cross section
is three orders of magnitude larger than the geometrical size of the produced
molecule. This giant enhancement of the reaction kinetics is due to an
efficient directed mass transport which is mediated by the Rydberg electron. We
also find that the total inelastic scattering cross section is given by the
geometrical size of the Rydberg electron's wavefunction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05007</id><created>2015-07-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Labouvie</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Bodhaditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heun</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Herwig</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium steady-states in a driven-dissipative superfluid</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 235302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.235302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally study a driven-dissipative Josephson junction array,
realized with a weakly interacting Bose Einstein condensate residing in a
one-dimensional optical lattice. Engineered losses on one site act as a local
dissipative process, while tunneling from the neighboring sites constitutes the
driving force. We characterize the emerging steady-states of this atomtronic
device. With increasing dissipation strength $\gamma$ the system crosses from a
superfluid state, characterized by a coherent Josephson current into the lossy
site to a resistive state, characterized by an incoherent hopping transport.
For intermediate values of $\gamma$, the system exhibits bistability, where a
superfluid and a resistive branch coexist. We also study the relaxation
dynamics towards the steady-state, where we find a critical slowing down,
indicating the presence of a non-equilibrium phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04329</id><created>2015-08-18</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Falciano</keyname><forenames>F. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadovski</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreiro</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaz</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology from a gauge induced gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Gen.Rel.Grav. 49 (2017) no.9, 118</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2282-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main goal of the present work is to analyze the cosmological scenario of
the induced gravity theory developed in previous works. Such a theory consists
on a Yang-Mills theory in a four-dimensional Euclidian spacetime with $SO(m,n)$
such that $m+n=5$ and $m\in\{0,1,2\}$ as its gauge group. This theory undergoes
a dynamical gauge symmetry breaking via an In\&quot;on\&quot;u-Wigner contraction in its
infrared sector. As a consequence, the $SO(m,n)$ algebra is deformed into a
Lorentz algebra with the emergency of the local Lorentz symmetries and the
gauge fields being identified with a vierbein and a spin connection. As a
result, gravity is described as an effective Einstein-Cartan-like theory with
ultraviolet correction terms and a propagating torsion field. We show that the
cosmological model associated with this effective theory has three different
regimes. In particular, the high curvature regime presents a de Sitter phase
which tends towards a $\Lambda$CDM model. We argue that $SO(m,n)$ induced
gravities are promising effective theories to describe the early phase of the
universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00063</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ta</keyname><forenames>Ton Viet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Linh Thi Hoai</forenames></author></authors><title>A stochastic differential equation model for foraging behavior of fish
  schools</title><categories>math.PR nlin.AO</categories><comments>26 pages, 14 figures</comments><msc-class>92A18, 60H10, 35R60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel model of stochastic differential equations for foraging
behavior of fish schools in space including obstacles. We then study the model
numerically. Three configurations of space with different locations of food
resource are considered. In the first configuration, fish move in free but
limited space. All individuals can find food almost surely. In the second and
third configurations, fish move in limited space with one or two obstacles. Our
results reveal that on one hand, when school size increases, so does the
probability of foraging success. On the other hand, when it exceeds an optimal
value, the probability decreases. In all configurations, fish always keep a
school structure through the process of foraging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04883</id><created>2015-09-16</created><updated>2016-04-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rozikov</keyname><forenames>U. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haydarov</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Four Competing interactions for models with uncountable set of spin
  values on a Cayley Tree</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we consider four competing interactions (external field,
nearest neighbor, second neighbors and triples of neighbors) of models with
uncountable (i.e. $[0,1]$) set of spin values on the Cayley tree of order two.
We reduce the problem of describing the &quot;splitting Gibbs measures&quot; of the model
to the analysis of solutions to some nonlinear integral equation and study some
particular cases for Ising and Potts models. Also we show that periodic Gibbs
measures for given models are either translation-invariant or periodic with
period two and we give examples of the non-uniqueness of translation-invariant
Gibbs measures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09293</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buzna</keyname><forenames>Lubos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling congestion on complex networks: fairness, efficiency and
  network structure</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.NI math.OC</categories><comments>published</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 9152 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-09524-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider two elementary (max-flow and uniform-flow) and two realistic
(max-min fairness and proportional fairness) congestion control schemes, and
analyse how the algorithms and network structure affect throughput, the
fairness of flow allocation, and the location of bottleneck edges. The more
realistic proportional fairness and max-min fairness algorithms have similar
throughput, but path flow allocations are more unequal in scale-free than in
random regular networks. Scale-free networks have lower throughput than their
random regular counterparts in the uniform-flow algorithm, which is favoured in
the complex networks literature. We show, however, that this relation is
reversed on all other congestion control algorithms for a region of the
parameter space given by the degree exponent $\gamma$ and average degree ${k}$.
Moreover, the uniform-flow algorithm severely underestimates the network
throughput of congested networks, and a rich phenomenology of path flow
allocations is only present in the more realistic $\alpha$-fair family of
algorithms. Finally, we show that the number of paths passing through an edge
characterises the location of a wide range of bottleneck edges in these
algorithms. Such identification of bottlenecks could provide a bridge between
the two fields of complex networks and congestion control.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01609</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Deshui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valado</keyname><forenames>Maria Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hufnagel</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwek</keyname><forenames>Leong Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amico</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumke</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge Qubit-Atom Hybrid</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>accepted for publication in Physical Review A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042329 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042329</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a novel hybrid system of a superconducting charge qubit
interacting directly with a single neutral atom via electric dipole coupling.
Interfacing of the macroscopic superconducting circuit with the microscopic
atomic system is accomplished by varying the gate capacitance of the charge
qubit. To achieve strong interaction, we employ two Rydberg states with an
electric-dipole allowed transition, which alters the polarizability of the
dielectric medium of the gate capacitor. Sweeping the gate voltage with
different rates leads to a precise control of hybrid quantum states.
Furthermore, we show a possible implementation of a universal two-qubit gate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02114</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Todeschini</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miscouridou</keyname><forenames>Xenia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caron</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchangeable Random Measures for Sparse and Modular Graphs with
  Overlapping Communities</title><categories>stat.ME cs.SI physics.soc-ph stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel statistical model for sparse networks with overlapping
community structure. The model is based on representing the graph as an
exchangeable point process, and naturally generalizes existing probabilistic
models with overlapping block-structure to the sparse regime. Our construction
builds on vectors of completely random measures, and has interpretable
parameters, each node being assigned a vector representing its level of
affiliation to some latent communities. We develop methods for simulating this
class of random graphs, as well as to perform posterior inference. We show that
the proposed approach can recover interpretable structure from two real-world
networks and can handle graphs with thousands of nodes and tens of thousands of
edges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08400</id><created>2016-02-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Niederpr&#xfc;m</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichert</keyname><forenames>Tanita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippe</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-R&#xed;os</keyname><forenames>Jes&#xfa;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Chris H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Herwig</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of pendular butterfly Rydberg molecules</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures; Supplementary Material included</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12820 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12820</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Obtaining full control over the internal and external quantum states of
molecules is the central goal of ultracold chemistry and allows for the study
of coherent molecular dynamics, collisions and tests of fundamental laws of
physics. When the molecules additionally have a permanent electric dipole
moment, the study of dipolar quantum gases and spin-systems with long-range
interactions as well as applications in quantum information processing are
possible. Rydberg molecules constitute a class of exotic molecules, which are
bound by the interaction between the Rydberg electron and the ground state
atom. They exhibit extreme bond lengths of hundreds of Bohr radii and giant
permanent dipole moments in the kilo-Debye range. A special type with
exceptional properties are the so-called butterfly molecules, whose electron
density resembles the shape of a butterfly. Here, we report on the
photoassociation of butterfly Rydberg molecules and their orientation in a weak
electric field. Starting from a Bose-Einstein condensate of rubidium atoms, we
fully control the external degrees of freedom and spectroscopically resolve the
rotational structure and the emerging pendular states in an external electric
field. This not only allows us to extract the bond length, the dipole moment
and the angular momentum of the molecule but also to deterministically create
molecules with a tunable bond length and orientation. We anticipate direct
applications in quantum chemistry, many-body quantum physics and quantum
information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.09034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.09034</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-11-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Dung Trung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svensson</keyname><forenames>Gunnar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tai</keyname><forenames>Cheuk-Wai</forenames></author></authors><title>SUePDF: a program to obtain quantitative pair distribution function from
  electron diffraction data</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other physics.comp-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Cryst. 50 (2017) 304-312</journal-ref><doi>10.1107/S160057671601863X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SUePDF is a graphic-user-interface program written in MATLAB to achieve
quantitative pair distribution functions (PDF) from electron diffraction data.
The program facilitates the structural studies of amorphous materials and small
nanoparticles based on electron diffraction data from transmission electron
microscopes (TEMs). It is based on the physics of electron scattering as well
as the total scattering methodology. A method of background modelling is
introduced to treat the intensity tail of the direct beam, inelastic scattering
and incoherent multiple scattering. Kinematical electron scattering intensity
is scaled using the electron scattering factors. The PDFs obtained after
Fourier transforms are normalized with respect to number density, nanoparticle
form factor, and the non-negativity of probability density. SUePDF is
distributed as free software for academic users.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02934</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Topological cell clustering in the ATLAS calorimeters and its
  performance in LHC Run 1</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>83 pages plus author list (100 pages in total), 44 figures, 3 tables,
  final version published in EPJC. All figures including auxiliary figures are
  available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/PERF-2014-07/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-304</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 490</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5004-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reconstruction of the signal from hadrons and jets emerging from the
proton-proton collisions at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) and entering the
ATLAS calorimeters is based on a three-dimensional topological clustering of
individual calorimeter cell signals. The cluster formation follows cell
signal-significance patterns generated by electromagnetic and hadronic showers.
In this, the clustering algorithm implicitly performs a topological noise
suppression by removing cells with insignificant signals which are not in close
proximity to cells with significant signals. The resulting topological cell
clusters have shape and location information, which is exploited to apply a
local energy calibration and corrections depending on the nature of the
cluster. Topological cell clustering is established as a well-performing
calorimeter signal definition for jet and missing transverse momentum
reconstruction in ATLAS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07973</id><created>2016-03-25</created><updated>2016-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kirkpatrick</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belitz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>The quantum ferromagnetic transition in a clean Kondo lattice is
  discontinuous</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8pp., 2 figs., contribution to FQMT'15</comments><journal-ref>Fortschr. Phys. 65, 1600028 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201600028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kondo-lattice model, which couples a lattice of localized magnetic
moments to conduction electrons, is often used to describe heavy-fermion
systems. Because of the interplay between Kondo physics and magnetic order it
displays very complex behavior and is notoriously hard to solve. The
ferromagnetic Kondo-lattice model, with a ferromagnetic coupling between the
local moments, describes a phase transition from a paramagnetic phase to a
ferromagnetic one as a function of either temperature or the ferromagnetic
local-moment coupling. At zero temperature, this is a quantum phase transition
that has received considerable attention. It has been theoretically described
to be continuous, or second order. Here we show that this belief is mistaken;
in the absence of quenched disorder the quantum phase transition is first
order, in agreement with experiments, as is the corresponding transition in
other metallic ferromagnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06683</id><created>2016-04-22</created><updated>2017-08-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Sudipto Singha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>Himadri Shekhar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakshit</keyname><forenames>Debraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Aditi Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Ujjwal</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical recursive method to ascertain multisite entanglement in doped
  quantum spin ladders</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, RevTex 4-1, accepted in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075143 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate an analytical recursive method to generate the wave function of
doped short-range resonating valence bond (RVB) states as a tool to efficiently
estimate multisite entanglement as well as other physical quantities in doped
quantum spin ladders. We prove that doped RVB ladder states are always genuine
multipartite entangled. Importantly, our results show that within specific
doping concentration and model parameter regimes, the doped RVB state
essentially characterizes the trends of genuine multiparty entanglement in the
exact ground states of the Hubbard model with large onsite interactions, in the
limit which yields the $t$-$J$ Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06742</id><created>2016-04-22</created><updated>2016-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Niederpr&#xfc;m</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichert</keyname><forenames>Tanita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Herwig</forenames></author></authors><title>Rydberg molecule-induced remote spin-flips</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 123002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.123002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed high resolution photoassociation spectroscopy of rubidium
ultra long-range Rydberg molecules in the vicinity of the 25$P$ state. Due to
the hyperfine interaction in the ground state perturber atom, the emerging
mixed singlet-triplet potentials contain contributions from both hyperfine
states. We show that this can be used to induce remote spin-flips in the
perturber atom upon excitation of a Rydberg molecule. When furthermore the
spin-orbit splitting of the Rydberg state is comparable to the hyperfine
splitting in the ground state, the orbital angular momentum of the Rydberg
electron is entangled with the nuclear spin of the perturber atom. Our results
open new possibilities for the implementation of spin-dependent interactions
for ultracold atoms in bulk systems and in optical lattices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07348</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2017-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Accioly</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacchini</keyname><forenames>Breno L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Ilya L.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the gravitational seesaw in higher-derivative gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages. Improved version with discussions substantially modified
  and partially interchanged material with arXiv:1610.05260. Fits the
  manuscript accepted in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017), 540</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5117-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Local gravitational theories with more than four derivatives are
superrenormalizable, and also may be unitary in the Lee-Wick sense. Thus, it is
relevant to study the low-energy properties of these theories, especially to
identify observables which might be useful for experimental detection of higher
derivatives. Using an analogy with the neutrino Physics, we explore the
possibility of a gravitational seesaw mechanism, in which several dimensional
parameters of the same order of magnitude produce a hierarchy in the masses of
propagating particles. Such a mechanism could make a relatively light degree of
freedom detectable in low-energy laboratory and astrophysical observations,
such as torsion balance experiments and the bending of light. We demonstrate
that such a seesaw mechanism in the six- and more-derivative theories is unable
to reduce the lightest mass more than in the simplest four-derivative model.
Adding more derivatives to the four-derivative action of gravity makes heavier
masses even greater, while the lightest massive ghost is not strongly affected.
This fact is favorable for protecting the theory from instabilities, but makes
the experimental detection of higher derivatives more difficult.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03379</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fouvry</keyname><forenames>Jean-Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pichon</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chavanis</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Henri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monk</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant thickening of self-gravitating discs: imposed or self-induced
  orbital diffusion in the tightly wound limit</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>31 pages, 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 471 (3): 2642-2673</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1625</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The secular thickening of a self-gravitating stellar galactic disc is
investigated using the dressed collisionless Fokker-Planck equation and the
inhomogeneous multicomponent Balescu-Lenard equation. The thick WKB limits for
the diffusion fluxes are found using the epicyclic approximation, while
assuming that only radially tightly wound transient spirals are sustained by
the disc. This yields simple quadratures for the drift and diffusion
coefficients, providing a clear understanding of the positions of maximum
vertical orbital diffusion within the disc, induced by fluctuations either
external or due to the finite number of particles. These thick limits also
offer a consistent derivation of a thick disc Toomre parameter, which is shown
to be exponentially boosted by the ratio of the vertical to radial scale
heights. Dressed potential fluctuations within the disc statistically induce a
vertical bending of a subset of resonant orbits, triggering the corresponding
increase in vertical velocity dispersion. When applied to a tepid stable
tapered disc perturbed by shot noise, these two frameworks reproduce
qualitatively the formation of ridges of resonant orbits towards larger
vertical actions, as found in direct numerical simulations, but overestimates
the time-scale involved in their appearance. Swing amplification is likely
needed to resolve this discrepancy, as demonstrated in the case of razor-thin
discs. Other sources of thickening are also investigated, such as fading
sequences of slowing bars, or the joint evolution of a population of giant
molecular clouds within the disc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08508</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Vikas</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic factor strengths using $ab ~ initio$ approaches</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C 94, 064306 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.064306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated the spectroscopic factor strengths for the one-proton and
one-neutron pick-up reactions $^{27}$Al($d$,$^{3}$He)$^{26}$Mg and
$^{27}$Al($d$,$t$)$^{26}$Al within the framework of the shell model. We
employed two different $ab ~ initio$ approaches : an in-medium similarity
renormalization targeted for a particular nucleus, and the coupled- cluster
effective interaction. We also compared our results with recently determined
experimental spectroscopic factors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02716</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carmona</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goertz</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papaefstathiou</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncovering the relation of a scalar resonance to the Higgs boson</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 29 figures. Version matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 095022 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.095022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the associated production of a scalar resonance with the standard
model Higgs boson. We demonstrate via a realistic phenomenological analysis
that couplings of such a resonance to the Higgs boson can be constrained in a
meaningful way in future runs of the LHC, providing insights on its origin and
its relation to the electroweak symmetry breaking sector. Moreover, the final
state can provide a direct way to determine whether the new resonance is
produced predominantly in gluon fusion or quark-anti-quark annihilation. The
analysis focusses on a resonance coming from a scalar field with vanishing
vacuum expectation value and its decay to a photon pair. It can however be
straightforwardly generalised to other scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00956</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kolchinsky</keyname><forenames>Artemy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolpert</keyname><forenames>David H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dependence of dissipation on the initial distribution over states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cs.ET</categories><msc-class>82C05</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 083202</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa7ee1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze how the amount of work dissipated by a fixed nonequilibrium
process depends on the initial distribution over states. Specifically, we
compare the amount of dissipation when the process is used with some specified
initial distribution to the minimal amount of dissipation possible for any
initial distribution. We show that the difference between those two amounts of
dissipation is given by a simple information-theoretic function that depends
only on the initial and final state distributions. Crucially, this difference
is independent of the details of the process relating those distributions. We
then consider how dissipation depends on the initial distribution for a
'computer', i.e., a nonequilibrium process whose dynamics over coarse-grained
macrostates implement some desired input-output map. We show that our results
still apply when stated in terms of distributions over the computer's
coarse-grained macrostates. This can be viewed as a novel thermodynamic cost of
computation, reflecting changes in the distribution over inputs rather than the
logical dynamics of the computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01699</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>Eric D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Paul R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Einhorn</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hicks</keyname><forenames>Bradley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundeen</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Future singularities if the universe underwent Starobinsky inflation in
  the past</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Two references and minor changes added to the PRD version, 45 pages,
  5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 044012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.044012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects which quantum fields and an $\alpha_0 R^2$ term in the
gravitational Lagrangian have on future singularities are investigated. While
all values of $\alpha_0$ are considered, an emphasis is placed on those values
which are compatible with the universe having undergone Starobinsky inflation
in the past. These are also values which lead to stable solutions to the
semiclassical backreaction equations in the present universe. The dark energy
is modeled as a perfect fluid, and the focus is on type I-IV singularities and
little rips which result when the classical Einstein equations are solved with
various types of dark energy as a source. First, evidence is provided that the
energy densities of massive conformally coupled scalar fields approach that of
the conformally invariant scalar field as a type III singularity is approached.
Then, solutions to the semiclassical backreaction equations are investigated
when conformally invariant fields and the $ \alpha_0 R^2$ term in the
gravitational Lagrangian are present. General proofs regarding the behaviors of
the solutions are given. The proofs are illustrated by analytic and numerical
calculations in specific cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01938</id><created>2016-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>Malik Muhammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurek</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Son</keyname><forenames>Sang-Kil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of x-ray scattering patterns from nanocrystals at high x-ray
  intensity</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>Structural Dynamics 3, 054101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4958887</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a generalized method to describe the x-ray scattering intensity of
the Bragg spots in a diffraction pattern from nanocrystals exposed to intense
x-ray pulses. Our method involves the subdivision of a crystal into smaller
units. In order to calculate the dynamics within every unit we employ a
Monte-Carlo (MC)-molecular dynamics (MD)-ab-initio hybrid framework using real
space periodic boundary conditions. By combining all the units we simulate the
diffraction pattern of a crystal larger than the transverse x-ray beam profile,
a situation commonly encountered in femtosecond nanocrystallography experiments
with focused x-ray free-electron laser radiation. Radiation damage is not
spatially uniform and depends on the fluence associated with each specific
region inside the crystal. To investigate the effects of uniform and
non-uniform fluence distribution we have used two different spatial beam
profiles, gaussian and flattop.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03643</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Mingzhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Huaqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kenan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Eryin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Guoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arita</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Haitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Shoushan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Shuyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz-violating type-II Dirac fermions in transition metal
  dichalcogenide PtTe$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 257 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-00280-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological semimetals have recently attracted extensive research interests
as host materials to condensed matter physics counterparts of Dirac and Weyl
fermions originally proposed in high energy physics. These fermions with linear
dispersions near the Dirac or Weyl points obey Lorentz invariance, and the
chiral anomaly leads to novel quantum phenomena such as negative
magnetoresistance. The Lorentz invariance is, however, not necessarily
respected in condensed matter physics, and thus Lorentz-violating type-II Dirac
fermions with strongly tilted cones can be realized in topological semimetals.
Here, we report the first experimental evidence of type-II Dirac fermions in
bulk stoichiometric PtTe$_2$ single crystal. Angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy (ARPES) measurements and first-principles calculations reveal a
pair of strongly tilted Dirac cones along the $\Gamma$-A direction under the
symmetry protection, confirming PtTe$_2$ as a type-II Dirac semimetal. The
realization of type-II Dirac fermions opens a new door for exotic physical
properties distinguished from type-I Dirac fermions in condensed matter
materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07376</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2017-01-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rakov</keyname><forenames>Mykhailo V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weyrauch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Bilinear-biquadratic spin-1 rings: an SU(2)-symmetric MPS algorithm for
  periodic boundary conditions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables, improved numbers, new references added</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Commun. 1, 015007 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2399-6528/aa7470</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An efficient algorithm for SU(2) symmetric matrix product states (MPS) with
periodic boundary conditions (PBC) is proposed and implemented. It is applied
to a study of the spectrum and correlation properties of the spin-1
bilinear-biquadratic Heisenberg model. We characterize the various phases of
this model by the lowest states of the spectrum with angular momentum J = 0, 1,
2 for systems of up to 100 spins. Furthermore, we provide precision results for
the dimerization correlator as well as the string correlator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02095</id><created>2016-08-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tener</keyname><forenames>James E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of the unitary free fermion Segal CFT</title><categories>math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>42 pages</comments><msc-class>81T40, 47C99, 30F99</msc-class><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys., 355 (2017), no. 2, 463-518</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2959-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we provide a detailed construction and analysis of the
mathematical conformal field theory of the free fermion, defined in the sense
of Graeme Segal. We verify directly that the operators assigned to disks with
two disks removed correspond to vertex operators, and use this to deduce
analytic properties of the vertex operators. One of the main tools used in the
construction is the Cauchy transform for Riemann surfaces, for which we
establish several properties analogous to those of the classical Cauchy
transform in the complex plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03760</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>H&#xfc;gel</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strand</keyname><forenames>Hugo U. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollet</keyname><forenames>Lode</forenames></author></authors><title>The anisotropic Harper-Hofstadter-Mott model: competition between
  condensation and magnetic fields</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 054431 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.054431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the reciprocal cluster mean-field method to study the
strongly-interacting bosonic Harper-Hofstadter-Mott model. The system exhibits
a rich phase diagram featuring band insulating, striped superfluid, and
supersolid phases. Furthermore, for finite hopping anisotropy we observe
gapless uncondensed liquid phases at integer fillings, which are analyzed by
exact diagonalization. The liquid phases at fillings 1 and 3 exhibit the same
band fillings as the fermionic integer quantum Hall effect, while the phase at
filling 2 is CT-symmetric with zero charge response. We discuss how these
phases become gapped on a quasi-one-dimensional cylinder, leading to a
quantized Hall response, which we characterize by introducing a suitable
measure for non-trivial many-body topological properties. Incompressible
metastable states at fractional filling are also observed, indicating competing
fractional quantum Hall phases. The combination of reciprocal cluster
mean-field and exact diagonalization yields a promising method to analyze the
properties of bosonic lattice systems with non-trivial unit cells in the
thermodynamic limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09834</id><created>2016-09-30</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borsato</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wulff</keyname><forenames>Linus</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable deformations of T-dual $\sigma$ models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages. References added. Projector reinstated in eq. (3). Claims on
  DTD with degenerate cocycle corrected</comments><report-no>Imperial-TP-RB-2016-06</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 251602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.251602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method to deform (generically non-abelian) T duals of
two-dimensional $\sigma$ models, which preserves classical integrability. The
deformed models are identified by a linear operator $\omega$ on the dualised
subalgebra, which satisfies the 2-cocycle condition. We prove that the
so-called homogeneous Yang-Baxter deformations are equivalent, via a field
redefinition, to our deformed models when $\omega$ is invertible. We explain
the details for deformations of T duals of Principal Chiral Models, and present
the corresponding generalisation to the case of supercoset models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01410</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2017-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lovas</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andai</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author></authors><title>Invariance of separability probability over reduced states in 4x4
  bipartite systems</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>81P16, 81P40, 81P45</msc-class><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7176</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The geometric separability probability of composite quantum systems is
extensively studied in the last decades. One of most simple but strikingly
difficult problem is to compute the separability probability of qubit-qubit and
rebit-rebit quantum states with respect to the Hilbert-Schmidt measure. A lot
of numerical simulations confirm the P(rebit-rebit)=29/64 and
P(qubit-qubit)=8/33 conjectured probabilities. Milz and Strunz studied the
separability probability with respect to given subsystems. They conjectured
that the separability probability of qubit-qubit (and qubit-qutrit) depends on
sum of single qubit subsystems (D), moreover it depends just on the Bloch radii
(r) of D and it is constant in r. Using the Peres-Horodecki criterion for
separability we give mathematical proof for the P(rebit-rebit)=29/64
probability and we present an integral formula for the complex case which
hopefully will help to prove the P(qubit-qubit)=8/33 probability too. We prove
Milz and Strunz's conjecture for rebit-rebit and qubit-qubit states. The case,
when the state space is endowed with the volume form generated by the operator
monotone function f(x)=sqrt(x) is studied too in detail. We show, that even in
this setting the Milz and Strunz's conjecture holds and we give an integral
formula for separability probability according to this measure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06176</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pollina</keyname><forenames>Giorgia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamaus</keyname><forenames>Nico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolag</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weller</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldi</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moscardini</keyname><forenames>Lauro</forenames></author></authors><title>On the linearity of tracer bias around voids</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, MNRAS published</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, Volume 469, Issue 1, 21 July 2017, Pages 787-799</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx785</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The large-scale structure of the universe can only be observed via luminous
tracers of the dark matter. However, the clustering statistics of tracers are
biased and depend on various properties, such as their host-halo mass and
assembly history. On very large scales this tracer bias results in a constant
offset in the clustering amplitude, known as linear bias. Towards smaller
nonlinear scales, this is no longer the case and tracer bias becomes a
complicated function of scale and time. We focus on tracer bias centred on
cosmic voids, depressions of the density field that spatially dominate the
universe. We consider three types of tracers: galaxies, galaxy clusters and
AGN, extracted from the hydrodynamical simulation Magneticum Pathfinder. In
contrast to common clustering statistics that focus on auto-correlations of
tracers, we find that void-tracer cross-correlations are successfully described
by a linear-bias relation. The tracer-density profile of voids can thus be
related to their matter-density profile by a single number. We show that it
coincides with the linear tracer bias extracted from the large-scale
auto-correlation function and expectations from theory, if sufficiently large
voids are considered. For smaller voids we observe a shift towards higher
values. This has important consequences on cosmological parameter inference, as
the problem of unknown tracer bias is alleviated up to a constant number. The
smallest scales in existing datasets become accessible to simpler models,
providing numerous modes of the density field that have been disregarded so
far, but may help to further reduce statistical errors in constraining
cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00100</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiaochuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-Mechanical Inertia in Antiferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 054409 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.054409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Angular momentum conservation has served as a guiding principle in the
interplay between spin dynamics and mechanical rotations. However, in an
antiferromagnet with vanishing magnetization, new fundamental rules are
required to properly describe spin-mechanical phenomena. Here we show that the
N\'eel order dynamics affects the mechanical motion of a rigid body by
modifying its inertia tensor in the presence of strong magnetocrystalline
anisotropy. This effect depends on temperature when magnon excitations are
considered. Such a spin-mechanical inertia can produce measurable consequences
at small scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02940</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scherzinger</keyname><forenames>Julius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jebali</keyname><forenames>Ramsey Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Annand</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fissum</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall-Wilton</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauritzson</keyname><forenames>Nicholai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrey</keyname><forenames>Hanno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rofors</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author></authors><title>Tagging fast neutrons from a 252Cf fission-fragment source</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures, to be submitted to Applied Radiation and
  Isotopes</comments><journal-ref>Applied Radiation and Isotopes 127 (2017) 270-274</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.apradiso.2017.05.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coincidence and time-of-flight measurement techniques are employed to tag
fission neutrons emitted from a 252Cf source sealed on one side with a very
thin layer of Au. The source is positioned within a gaseous 4He scintillator
detector. Together with alpha particles, both light and heavy fission fragments
pass through the thin layer of Au and are detected. The fragments enable the
corresponding fission neutrons, which are detected in a NE-213
liquid-scintillator detector, to be tagged. The resulting continuous
polychromatic beam of tagged neutrons has an energy dependence that agrees
qualitatively with expectations. We anticipate that this technique will provide
a cost-effective means for the characterization of neutron-detector efficiency
in the energy range 1 - 6 MeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03152</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Deshui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valado</keyname><forenames>Maria Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hufnagel</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwek</keyname><forenames>Leong Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amico</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumke</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum State Transmission in a Superconducting Charge Qubit-Atom Hybrid</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>3 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 38356 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep38356</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hybrids consisting of macroscopic superconducting circuits and microscopic
components, such as atoms and spins, have the potential of transmitting an
arbitrary state between different quantum species, leading to the prospective
of high-speed operation and long-time storage of quantum information. Here we
propose a novel hybrid structure, where a neutral-atom qubit directly
interfaces with a superconducting charge qubit, to implement the qubit-state
transmission. The highly-excited Rydberg atom located inside the gate capacitor
strongly affects the behavior of Cooper pairs in the box while the atom in the
ground state hardly interferes with the superconducting device. In addition,
the DC Stark shift of the atomic states significantly depends on the
charge-qubit states. By means of the standard spectroscopic techniques and
sweeping the gate voltage bias, we show how to transfer an arbitrary quantum
state from the superconducting device to the atom and vice versa.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04438</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;mpfer</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Afterglow of the dynamical Schwinger process: soft photons amass</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 125007 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.125007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the conversion of an electric field into photons as a secondary
probe of the dynamical Schwinger process. In spatially homogeneous electric
fields, quantum fluctuations of electron-positron ($e^+e^-$) pairs are lifted
on the mass shell leaving asymptotically a small finite pair density. The
$e^+e^-$ dynamics in turn couples to the quantized photon field and drives its
on-shell mode occupation. The spectral properties of the emerging asymptotic
photons accompanying the Schwinger process are calculated in lowest-order
perturbation theory. Soft photons in the optical range are produced amass in
the sub critical region, thus providing a promising discovery avenue, e.g. for
laser parameters of the Extreme Light Initiative (ELI-NP) to be put in
operation soon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05156</id><created>2016-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Deshui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landra</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valado</keyname><forenames>Maria Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hufnagel</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwek</keyname><forenames>Leong Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amico</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumke</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting Resonator-Rydberg Atom Hybrid in the Strong Coupling
  Regime</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 062301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.062301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a promising hybrid quantum system, where a highly-excited atom
strongly interacts with a superconducting LC oscillator via the electric field
of capacitor. An external electrostatic field is applied to tune the energy
spectrum of atom. The atomic qubit is implemented by two eigenstates near an
avoided-level crossing in the DC Stark map of Rydberg atom. Varying the
electrostatic field brings the atomic-qubit transition on- or off-resonance to
the microwave resonator, leading to a strong atom-resonator coupling with an
extremely large cooperativity. Like the nonlinearity induced by Josephson
junctions in superconducting circuits, the large atom-resonator interface
disturbs the harmonic potential of resonator, resulting in an artificial
two-level particle. Different universal two-qubit logic gates can also be
performed on our hybrid system within the space where an atomic qubit couples
to a single photon with an interaction strength much larger than any relaxation
rates, opening the door to the cavity-mediated state transmission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05809</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-02-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaspard</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical contribution to the heat conductivity in stochastic energy
  exchanges of locally confined gases</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>33 pages, minor revisions</comments><journal-ref>J Stat Mech (2017) 043210</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa60ce</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a systematic computation of the heat conductivity of the Markov
jump process modeling the energy exchanges in an array of locally confined hard
spheres at the conduction threshold. Based on a variational formula [Sasada M.
2016, {\it Thermal conductivity for stochastic energy exchange models},
arXiv:1611.08866], explicit upper bounds on the conductivity are derived, which
exhibit a rapid power-law convergence towards an asymptotic value. We thereby
conclude that the ratio of the heat conductivity to the energy exchange
frequency deviates from its static contribution by a small negative correction,
its dynamic contribution, evaluated to be $-0.000\,373$ in dimensionless units.
This prediction is corroborated by kinetic Monte Carlo simulations which were
substantially improved compared to earlier results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07288</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Logemann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudenko</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirilyuk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchange interactions in transition metal oxides: The role of oxygen
  spin polarization</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 335801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa7b00</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetism of transition metal (TM) oxides is usually described in terms of
the Heisenberg model, with orientation-independent interactions between the
spins. However, the applicability of such a model is not fully justified for TM
oxides because spin polarization of oxygen is usually ignored. In the
conventional model based on the Anderson principle, oxygen effects are
considered as a property of the TM ion and only TM interactions are relevant.
Here, we perform a systematic comparison between two approaches for spin
polarization on oxygen in typical TM oxides. To this end, we calculate the
exchange interactions in NiO, MnO, and hematite (Fe2O3) for different magnetic
configurations using the magnetic force theorem. We consider the full spin
Hamiltonian including oxygen sites, and also derive an effective model where
the spin polarization on oxygen renormalizes the exchange interactions between
TM sites. Surprisingly, the exchange interactions in NiO depend on the magnetic
state if spin polarization on oxygen is neglected, resulting in non-Heisenberg
behavior. In contrast, the inclusion of spin polarization in NiO makes the
Heisenberg model more applicable. Just the opposite, MnO behaves as a
Heisenberg magnet when oxygen spin polarization is neglected, but shows strong
non-Heisenberg effects when spin polarization on oxygen is included. In
hematite, both models result in non-Heisenberg behavior. General applicability
of the magnetic force theorem as well as the Heisenberg model to TM oxides is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00345</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Miao</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Dark Energy</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>98 pages, 21 figures, 10 tables. Accepted for Publication in Physics
  Reports</comments><journal-ref>Physics Reports 696 (2017) 1-57</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2017.06.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the paradigm of holographic dark energy (HDE), which arises from a
theoretical attempt of applying the holographic principle (HP) to the dark
energy (DE) problem. Making use of the HP and the dimensional analysis, we
derive the general formula of the energy density of HDE. Then, we describe the
properties of HDE model, in which the future event horizon is chosen as the
characteristic length scale. We also introduce the theoretical explorations and
the observational constraints for this model. Next, in the framework of HDE, we
discuss various topics, such as spatial curvature, neutrino, instability of
perturbation, time-varying gravitational constant, inflation, black hole and
big rip singularity. In addition, from both the theoretical and the
observational aspects, we introduce the interacting holographic dark energy
scenario, where the interaction between dark matter and HDE is taken into
account. Furthermore, we discuss the HDE scenario in various modified gravity
(MG) theories, such as Brans-Dicke theory, braneworld theory, scalar-tensor
theory, Horava-Lifshitz theory, and so on. Besides, we introduce the attempts
of reconstructing various scalar-field DE and MG models from HDE. Moreover, we
introduce other DE models inspired by the HP, in which different characteristic
length scales are chosen. Finally, we make comparisons among various
HP-inspired DE models, by using cosmological observations and diagnostic tools.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06333</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Beekveld</keyname><forenames>Melissa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beenakker</keyname><forenames>Wim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caron</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peeters</keyname><forenames>Ruud</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Austri</keyname><forenames>Roberto Ruiz</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetry with Dark Matter is still natural</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 035015 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.035015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We identify the parameter regions of the phenomenological minimal
supersymmetric standard model (pMSSM) with the minimal possible fine-tuning. We
show that the fine-tuning of the pMSSM is not large, nor under pressure by LHC
searches. Low sbottom, stop and gluino masses turn out to be less relevant for
low fine-tuning than commonly assumed. We show a link between low fine-tuning
and the dark matter relic density. Fine-tuning arguments point to models with a
dark matter candidate yielding the correct dark matter relic density: a
bino-higgsino particle with a mass of $35-155$ GeV. Some of these candidates
are compatible with recent hints seen in astrophysics experiments such as
Fermi-LAT and AMS-02. We argue that upcoming direct search experiments, such as
XENON1T, will test all of the most natural solutions in the next few years due
to the sensitivity of these experiments on the spin-dependent WIMP-nucleon
cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08577</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dom&#xed;nguez</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arrazola</keyname><forenames>&#xcd;&#xf1;igo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dom&#xe9;nech</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedernales</keyname><forenames>Julen Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamata</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>A Single-Ion Reservoir as a High-Sensitive Sensor of Electric Signals</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 8336 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-08782-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A single-ion reservoir has been tested, and characterized in order to be used
as a highly sensitive optical detector of electric signals arriving at the
trapping electrodes. Our system consists of a single laser-cooled $^{40}$Ca$^+$
ion stored in a Paul trap with rotational symmetry. The performance is observed
through the axial motion of the ion, which is equivalent to an underdamped and
forced oscillator. Thus, the results can be projected also to Penning traps. We
have found that, for an ion oscillator temperature $T_{\scriptsize{\rm
axial}}\lesssim 10$~mK in the forced-frequency range $\omega_z =2\pi \times
(80,200$~kHz), the reservoir is sensitive to a time-varying electric field
equivalent to an electric force of $5.3(2)$~neV/$\mu $m, for a measured quality
factor $Q=3875(45)$, and a decay time constant $\gamma_z=88(2)$~s$^{-1}$. This
method can be applied to measure optically the strength of an oscillating field
or induced (driven) charge in this frequency range within times of tens of
milliseconds. Furthermore the ion reservoir has been proven to be sensitive to
electrostatic forces by measuring the ion displacement. Since the heating rate
is below $0.3$~$\mu$eV/s, this reservoir might be used as optical detector for
any ion or bunch of charged particles stored in an adjacent trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09511</id><created>2016-12-30</created><updated>2017-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Date</keyname><forenames>Ghanashyam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoque</keyname><forenames>Sk Jahanur</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Horizon and the Quadrupole Formula in de Sitter Background</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Version accepted for publication in phys. rev. D. This version is
  slightly shortened, presentation is improved and 3 new references are added.
  Results and conclusions are unchanged. 34 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>IMSc/2016/12/07</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 044026 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.044026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An important class of observables for gravitational waves consists of the
fluxes of energy, momentum and angular momentum carried away by them and are
well understood for weak gravitational waves in Minkowski background. In de
Sitter background, the future null infinity, $\mathcal{J}^+$, is space-like
which makes the meaning of these observables subtle. A spatially compact source
in de Sitter background also provides a distinguished null hypersurface, its
{\em cosmological horizon}, $\mathcal{H}^+$. For sources supporting the short
wavelength approximation, we adopt the Isaacson prescription to define an
effective gravitational stress tensor. We show that the fluxes computed using
this effective stress tensor can be evaluated at $\mathcal{H}^+$, match with
those computed at $\mathcal{J}^+$ and also match with those given by Ashtekar
et al at $\mathcal{J}^+$ {{\em at a coarse grained level}}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07596</id><created>2017-01-26</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandy</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Diptiman</forenames></author></authors><title>Aperiodically driven integrable systems and their emergent steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>v3; 18 pages, 12 figures, version accepted for publication in Phys.
  Rev. X</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 031034 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.031034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Does a closed quantum many-body system that is continually driven with a
time-dependent Hamiltonian finally reach a steady state? This question has only
recently been answered for driving protocols that are periodic in time, where
the long time behavior of the local properties synchronize with the drive and
can be described by an appropriate periodic ensemble. Here, we explore the
consequences of breaking the time-periodic structure of the drive with
additional aperiodic noise in a class of integrable systems. We show that the
resulting unitary dynamics leads to new emergent steady states in at least two
cases. While any typical realization of random noise causes eventual heating to
an infinite temperature ensemble for all local properties in spite of the
system being integrable, noise which is self-similar in time leads to an
entirely different steady state, which we dub as &quot;geometric generalized Gibbs
ensemble&quot;, that emerges only after an astronomically large time scale. To
understand the approach to steady state, we study the temporal behavior of
certain coarse-grained quantities in momentum space that fully determine the
reduced density matrix for a subsystem with size much smaller than the total
system. Such quantities provide a concise description for any drive protocol in
integrable systems that are reducible to a free fermion representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00368</id><created>2017-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Al-Badawi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owaidat</keyname><forenames>M. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Dirac equation in Schwarzschild mass coupled to a Stationary
  Electromagnetic Field</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2017) 49: 110</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2279-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Dirac equation in a spacetime that represents the nonlinear
superposition of the Schwarzchild solution to an external, stationary
electromagnetic Berttoti-Robinson solution. We separate the Dirac equation into
radial and angular equations using Newman--Penrose formalism. We obtain exact
analytical solutions of the angular equations. We manage to obtain the radial
wave equations with effective potentials. Finally, we study the potentials by
plotting them as a function of radial distance and examine the effect of the
twisting parameter and the frequencies on the potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00701</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Contreras</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelinovsky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plum</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbital Stability of Domain Walls in Coupled Gross-Pitaevskii Systems</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP nlin.PS</categories><comments>25 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Domain walls are minimizers of energy for coupled one-dimensional
Gross--Pitaevskii systems with nontrivial boundary conditions at infinity. It
has been shown that these solutions are orbitally stable in the space of
complex $\dot{H}^1$ functions with the same limits at infinity. In the present
work we adopt a new weighted $H^1$ space to control perturbations of the domain
walls and thus to obtain an improved orbital stability result. A major
difficulty arises from the degeneracy of linearized operators at the domain
walls and the lack of coercivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01968</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abert</keyname><forenames>Claas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruckner</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groenefeld</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teliban</keyname><forenames>Iulian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogler</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suess</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology Optimized and 3D Printed Polymer Bonded Permanent Magnets for a
  Predefined External Field</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4997441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topology optimization offers great opportunities to design permanent magnetic
systems that have specific external field characteristics. Additive
manufacturing of polymer bonded magnets with an end-user 3D printer can be used
to manufacture permanent magnets with structures that have been difficult or
impossible to manufacture previously. This work combines these two powerful
methods to design and manufacture permanent magnetic system with specific
properties. The topology optimization framework is simple, fast, and accurate.
It can be also used for reverse engineering of permanent magnets in order to
find the topology from field measurements. Furthermore, a magnetic system that
generate a linear external field above the magnet is presented. With a volume
constraint the amount of magnetic material can be minimized without losing
performance. Simulations and measurements of the printed system show a very
good agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02084</id><created>2017-02-07</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arruda</keyname><forenames>L. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenells</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-time asymptotics for the derivative nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger
  equation on the half-line</title><categories>nlin.SI math.AP</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><msc-class>35Q55, 35Q15, 41A60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive asymptotic formulas for the solution of the derivative nonlinear
Schr\&quot;odinger equation on the half-line under the assumption that the initial
and boundary values lie in the Schwartz class. The formulas clearly show the
effect of the boundary on the solution. The approach is based on a nonlinear
steepest descent analysis of an associated Riemann-Hilbert problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02688</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02688</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aguilar-Arevalo</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Backfish</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bashyal</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batell</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carr</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>deNiverville</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dharmapalan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djurcic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garvey</keyname><forenames>G. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grange</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huelsnitz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Astiz</keyname><forenames>I. L. de Icaza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karagiorgi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katori</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketchum</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobilarcik</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louis</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mills</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirabal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nienaber</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlovic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perevalov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roe</keyname><forenames>B. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaevitz</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shahsavarani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stancu</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tayloe</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thornton</keyname><forenames>R. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Water</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wester</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter Search in a Proton Beam Dump with MiniBooNE</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures, Version consistent with final PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 221803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.221803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The MiniBooNE-DM collaboration searched for vector-boson mediated production
of dark matter using the Fermilab 8 GeV Booster proton beam in a dedicated run
with $1.86 \times 10^{20}$ protons delivered to a steel beam dump. The
MiniBooNE detector, 490~m downstream, is sensitive to dark matter via elastic
scattering with nucleons in the detector mineral oil. Analysis methods
developed for previous MiniBooNE scattering results were employed, and several
constraining data sets were simultaneously analyzed to minimize systematic
errors from neutrino flux and interaction rates. No excess of events over
background was observed, leading to a 90\% confidence limit on the dark-matter
cross section parameter, $Y=\epsilon^2\alpha_D(m_\chi/m_V)^4 \lesssim10^{-8}$,
for $\alpha_D=0.5$ and for dark-matter masses of $0.01&lt;m_\chi&lt;0.3~\mathrm{GeV}$
in a vector portal model of dark matter. This is the best limit from a
dedicated proton beam dump search in this mass and coupling range and extends
below the mass range of direct dark matter searches. These results demonstrate
a novel and powerful approach to dark matter searches with beam dump
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04602</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dickinson</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forshaw</keyname><forenames>Jeff</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millington</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Working directly with probabilities in quantum field theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures. Prepared for the proceedings of the 8th
  International Workshop DICE2016 Spacetime - Matter - Quantum Mechanics, 12-16
  September 2016, Castiglioncello, Italy, to appear in the Journal of Physics:
  Conference Series (JPCS). Presented by P. Millington</comments><report-no>MAN/HEP/2017/04</report-no><journal-ref>2017 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 880 012041</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/880/1/012041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel approach to computing transition probabilities in quantum
field theory, which allows them to be written directly in terms of expectation
values of nested commutators and anti-commutators of field operators, rather
than squared matrix elements. We show that this leads to a diagrammatic
expansion in which the retarded propagator plays a dominant role. As a result,
one is able to see clearly how faster-than-light signalling is prevented
between sources and detectors. Finally, we comment on potential implications of
this approach for dealing with infra-red divergences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07675</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petrillo</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tortora</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vernardos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koopmans</keyname><forenames>L. V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleijn</keyname><forenames>G. Verdoes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Napolitano</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Covone</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grado</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finding Strong Gravitational Lenses in the Kilo Degree Survey with
  Convolutional Neural Networks</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>24 pages, 17 figures. Published in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The volume of data that will be produced by new-generation surveys requires
automatic classification methods to select and analyze sources. Indeed, this is
the case for the search for strong gravitational lenses, where the population
of the detectable lensed sources is only a very small fraction of the full
source population. We apply for the first time a morphological classification
method based on a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for recognizing strong
gravitational lenses in $255$ square degrees of the Kilo Degree Survey (KiDS),
one of the current-generation optical wide surveys. The CNN is currently
optimized to recognize lenses with Einstein radii $\gtrsim 1.4$ arcsec, about
twice the $r$-band seeing in KiDS. In a sample of $21789$ colour-magnitude
selected Luminous Red Galaxies (LRG), of which three are known lenses, the CNN
retrieves 761 strong-lens candidates and correctly classifies two out of three
of the known lenses. The misclassified lens has an Einstein radius below the
range on which the algorithm is trained. We down-select the most reliable 56
candidates by a joint visual inspection. This final sample is presented and
discussed. A conservative estimate based on our results shows that with our
proposed method it should be possible to find $\sim100$ massive LRG-galaxy
lenses at $z\lsim 0.4$ in KiDS when completed. In the most optimistic scenario
this number can grow considerably (to maximally $\sim$2400 lenses), when
widening the colour-magnitude selection and training the CNN to recognize
smaller image-separation lens systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01240</id><created>2017-03-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat conduction and the nonequilibrium stationary states of stochastic
  energy exchange processes</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>26 pages</comments><journal-ref>J Stat Mech (2017) 083205</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa78b0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I revisit the exactly solvable Kipnis--Marchioro--Presutti model of heat
conduction [J. Stat. Phys. 27 65 (1982)] and describe, for one-dimensional
systems of arbitrary sizes whose ends are in contact with thermal baths at
different temperatures, a systematic characterization of their non-equilibrium
stationary states. These arguments avoid resorting to the analysis of a dual
process and yield a straightforward derivation of Fourier's law, as well as
higher-order static correlations, such as the covariant matrix. The
transposition of these results to families of gradient models generalizing the
KMP model is established and specific cases are examined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02875</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armata</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butera</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiscelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Incardone</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Notararigo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palacino</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passante</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzuto</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spagnolo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of boundaries on vacuum field fluctuations and radiation-mediated
  interactions between atoms</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, Proceedings of the Eighth International Workshop
  DICE 2016 Spacetime - Matter - Quantum Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conf. Series 880, 012064 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/880/1/012064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss and review several aspects of the effect of boundary
conditions and structured environments on dispersion and resonance interactions
involving atoms or molecules, as well as on vacuum field fluctuations. We first
consider the case of a perfect mirror, which is free to move around an
equilibrium position and whose mechanical degrees of freedom are treated
quantum mechanically. We investigate how the quantum fluctuations of the
mirror's position affect vacuum field fluctuations for both a one-dimensional
scalar and electromagnetic field, showing that the effect is particularly
significant in the proximity of the moving mirror. This result can be also
relevant for possible gravitational effects, since the field energy density
couples to gravity. We stress that this interaction-induced modification of the
vacuum field fluctuations can be probed through the Casimir-Polder interaction
with a polarizable body, thus allowing to detect the effect of the mirror's
quantum position fluctuations. We then consider the effect of an environment
such as an isotropic photonic crystal or a metallic waveguide, on the resonance
interaction between two entangled identical atoms, one excited and the other in
the ground state. We discuss the strong dependence of the resonance interaction
with the relative position of the atomic transition frequency with the gap of
the photonic crystal in the former case, and with the cut-off frequency of
waveguide in the latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02880</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lattuca</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passante</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzuto</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spagnolo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Van der Waals and resonance interactions between accelerated atoms in
  vacuum and the Unruh effect</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, Proceedings of the Eighth International Workshop DICE 2016
  Spacetime - Matter - Quantum Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conf. Series 880, 012042 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/880/1/012042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss different physical effects related to the uniform acceleration of
atoms in vacuum, in the framework of quantum electrodynamics. We first
investigate the van der Waals/Casimir-Polder dispersion and resonance
interactions between two uniformly accelerated atoms in vacuum. We show that
the atomic acceleration significantly affects the van der Waals force, yielding
a different scaling of the interaction with the interatomic distance and an
explicit time dependence of the interaction energy. We argue how these results
could allow for an indirect detection of the Unruh effect through dispersion
interactions between atoms. We then consider the resonance interaction between
two accelerated atoms, prepared in a correlated Bell-type state, and
interacting with the electromagnetic field in the vacuum state, separating
vacuum fluctuations and radiation reaction contributions, both in the
free-space and in the presence of a perfectly reflecting plate. We show that
nonthermal effects of acceleration manifest in the resonance interaction,
yielding a change of the distance dependence of the resonance interaction
energy. This suggests that the equivalence between temperature and acceleration
does not apply to all radiative properties of accelerated atoms. To further
explore this aspect, we evaluate the resonance interaction between two atoms in
non inertial motion in the coaccelerated (Rindler) frame and show that in this
case the assumption of an Unruh temperature for the field is not required for a
complete equivalence of locally inertial and coaccelerated points of views.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05251</id><created>2017-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Alexandre</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>Carl M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millington</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Light neutrino masses from a non-Hermitian Yukawa theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure. Prepared for the proceedings of DISCRETE2016: the
  Fifth Symposium on Prospects in the Physics of Discrete Symmetries, 28
  November-3 December 2016, University of Warsaw, Poland, to appear in the
  Journal of Physics: Conference Series (JPCS). Presented by P. Millington</comments><report-no>KCL-PH-TH/2017-10</report-no><journal-ref>2017 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 873 012047</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/873/1/012047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Working within the context of PT-symmetric quantum mechanics, we begin by
describing a non-Hermitian extension of QED that is both Lorentz invariant and
consistent with unitarity. We show that the non-Hermitian Dirac mass matrix of
this theory exhibits an exceptional point, corresponding to an effectively
massless theory whose conserved current is either right- or left-chiral
dominated. With this inspiration, we are able to construct a non-Hermitian
model of light Dirac neutrino masses from Hermitian and anti-Hermitian Yukawa
couplings that are both of order unity. We finish by highlighting potential
phenomenological implications of this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05277</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimabukuro</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saalmann</keyname><forenames>Aaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelinovsky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The derivative NLS equation: global existence with solitons</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the global existence result for the derivative NLS equation to the
case when the initial datum includes a finite number of solitons. This is
achieved by an application of the B\&quot;acklund transformation that removes a
finite number of zeros of the scattering coefficient. By means of this
transformation, the Riemann--Hilbert problem for meromorphic functions can be
formulated as the one for analytic functions, the solvability of which was
obtained recently.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05325</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Behan</keyname><forenames>Connor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rastelli</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rychkov</keyname><forenames>Slava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zan</keyname><forenames>Bernardo</forenames></author></authors><title>A scaling theory for the long-range to short-range crossover and an
  infrared duality</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>57pp, detailed version of arXiv:1703.03430, v2: misprints corrected,
  v3: refs and discussion of log corrections at the crossover added, v4:
  published version plus extra comments in appendix A,B and an acknowledgement,
  v5: published version plus extra comments in appendix A,B and an
  acknowledgement (replacing the wrong tex file of v4)</comments><report-no>CERN PH-TH/2017-052, YITP-SB-17-13</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 354002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa8099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the second-order phase transition in the $d$-dimensional Ising model
with long-range interactions decreasing as a power of the distance $1/r^{d+s}$.
For $s$ below some known value $s_*$, the transition is described by a
conformal field theory without a local stress tensor operator, with critical
exponents varying continuously as functions of $s$. At $s=s_*$, the phase
transition crosses over to the short-range universality class. While the
location $s_*$ of this crossover has been known for 40 years, its physics has
not been fully understood, the main difficulty being that the standard
description of the long-range critical point is strongly coupled at the
crossover. In this paper we propose another field-theoretic description which,
on the contrary, is weakly coupled near the crossover. We use this description
to clarify the nature of the crossover and make predictions about the critical
exponents. That the same long-range critical point can be reached from two
different UV descriptions provides a new example of infrared duality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05417</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05417</id><created>2017-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Garbrecht</keyname><forenames>Bjorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millington</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-consistent radiative corrections to false vacuum decay</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures. Prepared for the proceedings of DISCRETE2016:
  the Fifth Symposium on Prospects in the Physics of Discrete Symmetries, 28
  November-3 December 2016, University of Warsaw, Poland, to appear in the
  Journal of Physics: Conference Series (JPCS). Presented by P. Millington</comments><report-no>TUM/HEP/1076/17</report-no><journal-ref>2017 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 873 012041</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/873/1/012041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the Higgs mass now measured at the sub-percent level, the potential
metastability of the electroweak vacuum of the Standard Model (SM) motivates
renewed study of false vacuum decay in quantum field theory. In this note, we
describe an approach to calculating quantum corrections to the decay rate of
false vacua that is able to account fully and self-consistently for the
underlying inhomogeneity of the solitonic tunneling configuration. We show that
this method can be applied both to theories in which the instability arises
already at the level of the classical potential and those in which the
instability arises entirely through radiative effects, as is the case for the
SM Higgs vacuum. We analyse two simple models in the thin-wall regime, and we
show that the modifications of the one-loop corrections from accounting fully
for the inhomogeneity can compete at the same level as the two-loop homogeneous
corrections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05726</id><created>2017-03-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Leonov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponomareva</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abrikosov</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure-induced spin-state transition of iron in magnesiow\&quot;ustite
  (Fe,Mg)O</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075136 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed theoretical study of the electronic, magnetic, and
structural properties of magnesiow\&quot;ustite Fe$_{1-x}$Mg$_x$O with $x$ in the
range between 0$-$0.875 using a fully charge self-consistent implementation of
the density functional theory plus dynamical mean-field theory (DFT+DMFT)
method. In particular, we compute the electronic structure and phase stability
of the rock-salt B1-structured (Fe,Mg)O at high pressures relevant for the
Earth's lower mantle. We obtain that upon compression paramagnetic (Fe,Mg)O
exhibits a spin-state transition of Fe$^{2+}$ ions from a high-spin to low-spin
(HS-LS) state which is accompanied by a collapse of local magnetic moments. The
HS-LS transition results in a substantial drop of the lattice volume by about
4$-$8 %, implying a complex interplay between electronic and lattice degrees of
freedom. Our results reveal a strong sensitivity of the calculated transition
pressure $P_{\rm tr.}$ upon addition of Mg. While for Fe-rich
magnesiow\&quot;ustite, Mg $x &lt; 0.5$, $P_{\rm tr.}$ exhibits a rather weak variation
at $\sim$80 GPa, for Fe-poor (Fe,Mg)O it drops, e.g., by about 35 % to 52 GPa
for Mg $x=0.75$. This behavior is accompanied by a substantial change of the
spin transition range from 50$-$140 GPa in FeO to 30$-$90 GPa for $x=0.75$. In
addition, the calculated bulk modulus (in the HS state) is found to increase by
$\sim$12 % from 142 GPa in FeO to 159 GPa in (Fe,Mg)O with Mg $x=0.875$. We
find that the pressure-induced HS-LS transition has different consequences for
the electronic properties of the Fe-rich and poor (Fe,Mg)O. For the Fe-rich
(Fe,Mg)O, the transition is found to be accompanied by a Mott insulator to
(semi-) metal phase transition. In contrast to that, for $x&gt;0.25$, (Fe,Mg)O
remains insulating up to the highest studied pressures, implying a Mott
insulator to band insulator phase transition at the HS-LS transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06506</id><created>2017-03-19</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghorbani</keyname><forenames>Parsa Hossein</forenames></author></authors><title>Electroweak Baryogenesis and Dark Matter via a Pseudoscalar vs. Scalar</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures. Fermi-LAT constraint on DM DM to b\bar, tau^+
  tau^- in the model was imposed. The range of the mediator mass was shown in a
  figure. Published in JHEP</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2017)058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the electroweak baryogenesis in a fermionic dark matter scenario
with a (pseudo)scalar being the mediator in the Higgs portal. It is discussed
that the electroweak phase transition turns to be first-order after taking into
account the role of the (pseudo)scalar in the thermal effective potential in
our extended standard model. Imposing the relic density constraint from the
WMAP/Planck and the bounds from the direct detection experiments XENON100/LUX,
we show that the dark matter scenario with a scalar mediator is hardly capable
of explaining the baryogenesis while the same model with a pseudoscalar
mediator is able to explain the baryon asymmetry. For the latter, we constrain
more the model with {\it Fermi}-LAT upper limit on dark matter annihilation
into $b\bar b$ and $\tau^+\tau^-$. The allowed dark matter mass that leads to
correct relic abundance, renders the electroweak phase transition strongly
first-order, and respects the {\it Fermi}-LAT limit, will be in the range
$110-320$ GeV. The exotic and invisible Higgs decay bounds and the mono-jet
search limit at the LHC do not affect the viable space of parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09110</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>Malik Muhammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anurag</keyname></author><author><keyname>Jurek</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Son</keyname><forenames>Sang-Kil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>A molecular-dynamics approach for studying the non-equilibrium behavior
  of x-ray-heated solid-density matter</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 023205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.023205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When matter is exposed to a high-intensity x-ray free-electron-laser pulse,
the x rays excite inner-shell electrons leading to the ionization of the
electrons through various atomic processes and creating high-energy-density
plasma, i.e., warm or hot dense matter. The resulting system consists of atoms
in various electronic configurations, thermalizing on sub-picosecond to
picosecond timescales after photoexcitation. We present a simulation study of
x-ray-heated solid-density matter. For this we use XMDYN, a Monte-Carlo
molecular-dynamics-based code with periodic boundary conditions, which allows
one to investigate non-equilibrium dynamics. XMDYN is capable of treating
systems containing light and heavy atomic species with full electronic
configuration space and 3D spatial inhomogeneity. For the validation of our
approach we compare for a model system the electron temperatures and the ion
charge-state distribution from XMDYN to results for the thermalized system
based on the average-atom model implemented in XATOM, an ab-initio x-ray atomic
physics toolkit extended to include a plasma environment. Further, we also
compare the average charge evolution of diamond with the predictions of a
Boltzmann continuum approach. We demonstrate that XMDYN results are in good
quantitative agreement with the above mentioned approaches, suggesting that the
current implementation of XMDYN is a viable approach to simulate the dynamics
of x-ray-driven non-equilibrium dynamics in solids. In order to illustrate the
potential of XMDYN for treating complex systems we present calculations on the
triiodo benzene derivative 5-amino-2,4,6-triiodoisophthalic acid (I3C), a
compound of relevance of biomolecular imaging, consisting of heavy and light
atomic species.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10038</id><created>2017-03-26</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alsaleh</keyname><forenames>Salwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Modlej</keyname><forenames>Abeer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Ahmed Farag</forenames></author></authors><title>Virtual Black Holes from Generalized Uncertainty Principle and Proton
  Decay</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 1 figure. Minor typos corrected. Published in EPL</comments><journal-ref>Euro Physics Letters (EPL), 118 (2017) 50008</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/50008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the formation of virtual black holes in the context of
generalized uncertainty principle (GUP), as a mediator for a proton decay
process which is forbidden by the standard model. Then, we calculate the lower
bounds of the GUP deformation parameter by the experimental bound on the half
life of the proton.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10686</id><created>2017-03-28</created><updated>2017-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zibang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Zichao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Kaikai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nambiar</keyname><forenames>Aparna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yutong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Shaowei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Jingang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choma</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Guoan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual-LED-based multichannel microscopy for whole-slide multiplane,
  multispectral, and phase imaging</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Biophotonics, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/jbio.201700075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the development of a multichannel microscopy for whole-slide
multiplane, multispectral, and phase imaging. We use trinocular heads to split
the beam path into 6 independent channels and employ a camera array for
parallel data acquisition, achieving a maximum data throughput of ~1 gigapixel
per second. To perform single-frame rapid autofocusing, we place two
near-infrared LEDs at the back focal plane of the condenser lens to illuminate
the sample from two different incident angles. A hot mirror is used to direct
the near-infrared light to an autofocusing camera. For multiplane whole slide
imaging (WSI), we acquire 6 different focal planes of a thick specimen
simultaneously. For multispectral WSI, we relay the 6 independent image planes
to the same focal position and simultaneously acquire information at 6 spectral
bands. For whole-slide phase imaging, we acquire images at 3 focal positions
simultaneously and use the transport-of-intensity equation to recover the phase
information. We also provide an open-source design to further increase the
number of channels from 6 to 15. The reported platform provides a simple
solution for multiplexed fluorescence imaging and multimodal WSI. Acquiring an
instant focal stack without z-scanning may also enable fast 3D dynamic tracking
of various biological samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00603</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xd6;vg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Ayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author></authors><title>Charged Thin-shell Gravastars in Noncommutative Geometry</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, twocolumn, Accepted in EPJC for publication</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77:566</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5139-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we construct a charged thin-shell gravastar model within the
context of noncommutative geometry. To do so, we choose the interior of the
nonsingular de Sitter spacetime with an exterior charged noncommutative
solution by cut-and-paste technique and apply the generalized junction
conditions. We then investigate the stability of a charged thin-shell gravastar
under linear perturbations around the static equilibrium solutions as well as
the thermodynamical stability of the charged gravastar. We find the stability
regions by choosing appropriate parameter values which is located sufficiently
close to the event horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04506</id><created>2017-04-14</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Boyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Tianjing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Argyropoulos</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced third harmonic generation with graphene metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Optics, vol. 19, No 9, pp. 094005, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8986/aa8280</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonlinear responses of different materials provide useful mechanisms for
optical switching, low noise amplification, and harmonic frequency generation.
However, the nonlinear processes usually have an extremely weak nature and
require high input power to be excited. To alleviate this severe limitation, we
propose new designs of ultrathin nonlinear metasurfaces composed of patterned
graphene micro-ribbons to significantly enhance third harmonic generation (THG)
at far-infrared and terahertz (THz) frequencies. The incident wave is tightly
confined and significantly boosted along the surface of graphene in these
configurations due to the excitation of highly localized plasmons. The
bandwidth of the resonant response becomes narrower due to the introduction of
a metallic substrate below the graphene micro-ribbons, which leads to zero
transmission and standing waves inside the intermediate dielectric spacer
layer. The enhancement of the incident field, combined with the large nonlinear
conductivity of graphene, can dramatically increase the THG conversion
efficiency by several orders of magnitude. In addition, the resonant frequency
of the metasurface can be adjusted by dynamically tuning the Fermi energy of
graphene via electrical or chemical doping. As a result, the third harmonic
generated wave can be optimized and tuned to be emitted at different
frequencies without the need to change the nonlinear metasurface geometry. The
proposed nonlinear metasurfaces provide a new way to realize compact and
efficient nonlinear sources at the far-infrared and THz frequency ranges, as
well as new frequency generation and wave mixing devices which are expected to
be useful for nonlinear THz spectroscopy and noninvasive THz imaging
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07419</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grumiller</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merbis</keyname><forenames>Wout</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riegler</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>Most general flat space boundary conditions in three-dimensional
  Einstein gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pp, invited for CQG BMS Focus Issue edited by Geoffrey Compere,
  v2: added minor clarifications and refs</comments><report-no>TUW-17-04</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 184001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa8004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the most general asymptotically flat boundary conditions in
three-dimensional Einstein gravity in the sense that we allow for the maximal
number of independent free functions in the metric, leading to six towers of
boundary charges and six associated chemical potentials. We find as associated
asymptotic symmetry algebra an isl(2)_k current algebra. Restricting the
charges and chemical potentials in various ways recovers previous cases, such
as BMS_3, Heisenberg or Detournay-Riegler, all of which can be obtained as
contractions of corresponding AdS_3 constructions. Finally, we show that a flat
space contraction can induce an additional Carrollian contraction. As examples
we provide two novel sets of boundary conditions for Carroll gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00402</id><created>2017-04-30</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Masaki J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A possibility on prohibition of Higgs mass by the extended Lorentz
  transformation in noncommutative geometry</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, substantially modified from the previous version</comments><report-no>STUPP-17-230</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we propose the extended Lorentz transformation in
noncommutative geometry, as a possibility on prohibition of the Higgs mass.
  Since it is difficult to build the symmetry between the connections $A_{\mu}$
and $H$, the transformation is defined for the differential two-forms. The
parameter of the transformation $\omega$ changes a two-form into other
two-forms. Comparing the coefficients of the two-forms, the transformations are
translated to those of the product fields $F_{\mu\nu}, D_{\mu} H$ and
$HH^{\dagger}$. It shows the invariance of the bosonic Lagrangian explicitly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00512</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alberti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wimberger</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum walk of a Bose-Einstein condensate in the Brillouin zone</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures; in the new version, added a discussion about
  decoherence in the appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023620 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a realistic scheme to implement discrete-time quantum walks in the
Brillouin zone (i.e., in quasimomentum space) with a spinor Bose-Einstein
condensate. Relying on a static optical lattice to suppress tunneling in real
space, the condensate is displaced in quasimomentum space in discrete steps
conditioned upon the internal state of the atoms, while short pulses
periodically couple the internal states. We show that tunable twisted boundary
conditions can be implemented in a fully natural way by exploiting the
periodicity of the Brillouin zone. The proposed setup does not suffer from
off-resonant scattering of photons and could allow a robust implementation of
quantum walks with several tens of steps at least. In addition, onsite
atom-atom interactions can be used to simulate interactions with infinitely
long range in the Brillouin zone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03168</id><created>2017-05-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Hatomura</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Shortcuts to adiabaticity in the infinite-range Ising model by
  mean-field counter-diabatic driving</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn., 86, 094002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.094002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strategy of shortcuts to adiabaticity enables us to realize adiabatic
dynamics in finite time. In the counter-diabatic driving approach, an auxiliary
Hamiltonian which is called the counter-diabatic Hamiltonian is appended to an
original Hamiltonian to cancel out diabatic transitions. The counter-diabatic
Hamiltonian is constructed by using the eigenstates of the original
Hamiltonian. Therefore, it is in general difficult to construct the
counter-diabatic Hamiltonian for quantum many-body systems. Even if the
counter-diabatic Hamiltonian for quantum many-body systems is obtained, it is
generally non-local and even diverges at critical points. We construct an
approximated counter-diabatic Hamiltonian for the infinite-range Ising model by
making use of the mean-field approximation. An advantage of this method is that
the mean-field counter-diabatic Hamiltonian is constructed by only local
operators. We numerically demonstrate the effectiveness of this method through
quantum annealing processes going the vicinity of the critical point. It is
also confirmed that the mean-field counter-diabatic Hamiltonian is still
well-defined in the limit to the critical point. The present method can take
higher order contributions into account and is consistent with the variational
approach for local counter-diabatic driving.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05423</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chepiga</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mila</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation spectrum and Density Matrix Renormalization Group iterations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 20 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 054425 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.054425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that, in certain circumstances, exact excitation energies appear as
locally site-independent (or flat) modes if one records the excitation spectrum
of the effective Hamiltonian while sweeping through the lattice in the
variational Matrix Product State formulation of the Density Matrix
Renormalization Group (DMRG), a remarkable property since the effective
Hamiltonian is only constructed to target the ground state. Conversely, modes
that are very flat over several consecutive iterations are systematically found
to correspond to faithful excitations. We suggest to use this property to
extract accurate information about excited states using the standard ground
state algorithm. The results are spectacular for critical systems, for which
the low-energy conformal tower of states can be obtained very accurately at
essentially no additional cost, as demonstrated by confirming the predictions
of boundary conformal field theory for two simple minimal models - the
transverse-field Ising model and the critical three-state Potts model. This
approach is also very efficient to detect the quasi-degenerate low-energy
excitations in topological phases, and to identify localized excitations in
systems with impurities. Finally, using the variance of the Hamiltonian as a
criterion, we assess the accuracy of the resulting Matrix Product State
representations of the excited states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05578</id><created>2017-05-16</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruognolo</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zhenyue</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Steven R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoudenmire</keyname><forenames>E. Miles</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix product state techniques for two-dimensional systems at finite
  temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>24 pages, 10 figures, v2: changed to SciPost layout, MPS codes
  publicly available at https://github.com/emstoudenmire/finiteTMPS/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The density matrix renormalization group is one of the most powerful
numerical methods for computing ground-state properties of two-dimensional (2D)
quantum lattice systems. Here we show its finite-temperature extensions are
also viable for 2D, using the following strategy: At high temperatures, we
combine density-matrix purification and numerical linked-cluster expansions to
extract static observables directly in the thermodynamic limit. At low
temperatures inaccessible to purification, we use the minimally entangled
typical thermal state (METTS) algorithm on cylinders. We consider the
triangular Heisenberg antiferromagnet as a first application, finding excellent
agreement with other state of the art methods. In addition, we present a
METTS-based approach that successfully extracts critical temperatures, and
apply it to a frustrated lattice model. On a technical level, we compare two
different schemes for performing imaginary-time evolution of 2D clusters,
finding that a Suzuki-Trotter decomposition with swap gates is currently the
most accurate and efficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08803</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hu Sung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Juho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsutsui</keyname><forenames>Makusu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawai</keyname><forenames>Tomoji</forenames></author></authors><title>Stretching-induced conductance variations as fingerprints of contact
  configurations in single-molecule junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures; to be published in J. Am. Chem. Soc</comments><journal-ref>J. Am. Chem. Soc. 139, 8286 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/jacs.7b03393</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecule-electrode contact atomic structures are a critical factor that
characterizes molecular devices, but their precise understanding and control
still remain elusive. Based on combined first-principles calculations and
single-molecule break junction experiments, we herein establish that the
conductance of alkanedithiolate junctions can both increase and decrease with
mechanical stretching and the specific trend is determined by the S-Au linkage
coordination number (CN) or the molecule-electrode contact atomic structure.
Specifically, we find that the mechanical pulling results in the conductance
increase for the junctions based on S-Au CN two and CN three contacts, while
the conductance is minimally affected by stretching for junctions with the CN
one contact and decreases upon the formation of Au monoatomic chains. Detailed
analysis unravels the mechanisms involving the competition between the
stretching-induced upshift of the highest occupied molecular orbital-related
states toward the Fermi level of electrodes and the deterioration of
molecule-electrode electronic couplings in different contact CN cases.
Moreover, we experimentally find a higher chance to observe the conductance
enhancement mode under a faster elongation speed, which is explained by ab
initio molecular dynamics simulations that reveal an important role of thermal
fluctuations in aiding deformations of contacts into low-coordination
configurations that include monoatomic Au chains. Pointing out the
insufficiency in previous notions of associating peak values in conductance
histograms with specific contact atomic structures, this work resolves the
controversy on the origins of ubiquitous multiple conductance peaks in
S-Au-based single-molecule junctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10605</id><created>2017-05-30</created><updated>2017-06-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grumiller</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tempo</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troncoso</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Log corrections to entropy of three dimensional black holes with soft
  hair</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures, v2: added ref</comments><report-no>CECS-PHY-17/03, TUW-17-03</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP08 (2017) 107</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2017)107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate log corrections to the entropy of three-dimensional black holes
with &quot;soft hairy&quot; boundary conditions. Their thermodynamics possesses some
special features that preclude a naive direct evaluation of these corrections,
so we follow two different approaches. The first one exploits that the BTZ
black hole belongs to the spectrum of Brown-Henneaux as well as soft hairy
boundary conditions, so that the respective log corrections are related through
a suitable change of the thermodynamic ensemble. In the second approach the
analogue of modular invariance is considered for dual theories with anisotropic
scaling of Lifshitz type with dynamical exponent z at the boundary. On the
gravity side such scalings arise for KdV-type boundary conditions, which
provide a specific 1-parameter family of multi-trace deformations of the usual
AdS3/CFT2 setup, with Brown-Henneaux corresponding to z=1 and soft hairy
boundary conditions to the limiting case z=0. Both approaches agree in the case
of BTZ black holes for any non-negative z. Finally, for soft hairy boundary
conditions we show that not only the leading term, but also the log corrections
to the entropy of black flowers endowed with affine u(1) soft hair charges
exclusively depend on the zero modes and hence coincide with the ones for BTZ
black holes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00881</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Senchyna</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stark</keyname><forenames>Daniel P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Alba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevallard</keyname><forenames>Jacopo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charlot</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainali</keyname><forenames>Ramesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Tucker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wofford</keyname><forenames>Aida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feltre</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutkin</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultraviolet spectra of extreme nearby star-forming regions ---
  approaching a local reference sample for JWST</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>27 pages, 13 figures, 11 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nearby dwarf galaxies provide a unique laboratory in which to test stellar
population models below $Z_\odot/2$. Such tests are particularly important for
interpreting the surprising high-ionization UV line emission detected at $z&gt;6$
in recent years. We present HST/COS ultraviolet spectra of ten nearby
metal-poor star-forming galaxies selected to show He II emission in SDSS
optical spectra. The targets span nearly a dex in gas-phase oxygen abundance
($7.8&lt;12+\log\mathrm{O/H}&lt;8.5$) and present uniformly large specific star
formation rates (sSFR $\sim 10^2$ $\mathrm{Gyr}^{-1}$). The UV spectra confirm
that metal-poor stellar populations can power extreme nebular emission in
high-ionization UV lines, reaching C III] equivalent widths comparable to those
seen in systems at $z\sim 6-7$. Our data reveal a marked transition in UV
spectral properties with decreasing metallicity, with systems below
$12+\log\mathrm{O/H}\lesssim 8.0$ ($Z/Z_\odot \lesssim 1/5$) presenting minimal
stellar wind features and prominent nebular emission in He II and C IV. This is
consistent with nearly an order of magnitude increase in ionizing photon
production beyond the $\mathrm{He^+}$-ionizing edge relative to H-ionizing flux
as metallicity decreases below a fifth solar, well in excess of standard
stellar population synthesis predictions. Our results suggest that often
neglected sources of energetic radiation such as stripped binary products and
very massive O-stars produce a sharper change in the ionizing spectrum with
decreasing metallicity than expected. Consequently, nebular emission in C IV
and He II powered by these stars may provide useful metallicity constraints in
the reionization era.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01547</id><created>2017-06-05</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacla</keyname><forenames>Alexandre B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caves</keyname><forenames>Carlton M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bosonic Particle-Correlated States: A Nonperturbative Treatment Beyond
  Mean Field</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023621 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023621</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many useful properties of dilute Bose gases at ultra-low temperature are
predicted precisely by the (mean-field) product-state Ansatz, in which all
particles are in the same quantum state. Yet, in situations where
particle-particle correlations become important, the product Ansatz fails. To
include correlations nonperturbatively, we consider a new set of states: the
particle-correlated state of $N=l\times n$ bosons is derived by symmetrizing
the $n$-fold product of an $l$-particle quantum state. The particle-correlated
states can be simulated efficiently for large $N$, because their parameter
spaces, which depend on $l$, do not grow with $n$. Here we formulate and
develop in great detail the pure-state case for $l=2$, where the many-body
state is constructed from a two-particle pure state. These paired wave
functions, which we call pair-correlated states (PCS), were introduced by A. J.
Leggett [Rev. Mod. Phys. ${\bf 73}$, 307 (2001)] as a
particle-number-conserving version of the Bogoliubov approximation. We present
an iterative algorithm that solves for the reduced (marginal) density matrices
(RDMs), i.e., the correlation functions, associated with PCS in time $O(N)$.
The RDMs can also be derived from the normalization factor of PCS, which is
derived analytically in the large-$N$ limit. To test the efficacy of PCS, we
analyze the ground state of the two-site Bose-Hubbard model by minimizing the
energy of the PCS~state, both in its exact form and in its large-$N$
approximate form, and comparing with the exact ground state. For $N=1\,000$,
the relative errors of the ground-state energy for both cases are within
$10^{-5}$ over the entire parameter region from a single condensate to a Mott
insulator. We present numerical results that suggest that PCS might be useful
for describing the dynamics in the strongly interacting regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01704</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mittag</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karalic</keyname><forenames>Matija</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Susanne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tschirky</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegscheider</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarenko</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalenko</keyname><forenames>Maksym V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ihn</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ensslin</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Passivation of Edge States in Etched InAs Sidewalls</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 111, 082101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4986614</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate different methods of passivating sidewalls of wet etched InAs
heterostructures in order to suppress inherent edge conduction that is presumed
to occur due to band bending at the surface leading to charge carrier
accumulation. Passivation techniques including sulfur, positively charged
compensation dopants and plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition of
$\mathrm{SiN}_{\mathrm{x}}$ do not show an improvement. Surprisingly, atomic
layer deposition of $\mathrm{Al}_{\mathrm{2}}\mathrm{O}_{\mathrm{3}}$ leads to
an increase in edge resistivity of more than an order of magnitude. While the
mechanism behind this change is not fully understood, possible reasons are
suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05491</id><created>2017-06-17</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kandel</keyname><forenames>Yadav Prasad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adhikari</keyname><forenames>Narayan Prasad</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion of Zwitterion Glycine, Diglycine, and Triglycine in Water</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diffusion, transport of mass in response to concentration and thermal energy
gradient, is an important transport property, vital in material science and
life science. In the present work classical molecular dynamics study of
diffusion of zwittterion glycine, zwitterion diglycine and zwitterion
triglycine in water have been carried out. Self and binary diffusion
coefficients of aqueous solution of these molecules have been calculated using
Einstein method. Our results agree with experimental data reported in
literatures. Temperature dependency of diffusion of glycine in water have been
explored using estimated values of self and binary diffusion coefficients at
four different temperatures. Effect of peptide bond formation in diffusion has
been studied using peptide chain composed of up to three monomers of glycine.
The structure of the system is analyzed using radial diestibution function of
different atom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09527</id><created>2017-06-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Deshui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwek</keyname><forenames>Leong Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amico</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumke</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting Qubit-Resonator-Atom Hybrid System</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Sci. Technol. 2, 035005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa7c50</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a hybrid quantum system, where an $LC$ resonator inductively
interacts with a flux qubit and is capacitively coupled to a Rydberg atom.
Varying the external magnetic flux bias controls the flux-qubit flipping and
the flux qubit-resonator interface. The atomic spectrum is tuned via an
electrostatic field, manipulating the qubit-state transition of atom and the
atom-resonator coupling. Different types of entanglement of superconducting,
photonic, and atomic qubits can be prepared via simply tuning the flux bias and
electrostatic field, leading to the implementation of three-qubit Toffoli logic
gate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09968</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willott</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carilli</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagg</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Galaxy Formation Through Filamentary Accretion at z=6.1</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 845, Issue 2, article id. 175, 8
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7d0d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present ALMA observations of the dust continuum and [C II] 158um line
emission from the z=6.0695 Lyman Break Galaxy WMH5. These observations at 0.3&quot;
spatial resolution show a compact (~3kpc) main galaxy in dust and [C II]
emission, with a 'tail' of emission extending to the east by about 5kpc (in
projection). The [C II] tail is comprised predominantly of two distinct
sub-components in velocity, separated from the core by ~100 and 250km/s, with
narrow intrinsic widths of about 80km/s, which we call 'sub-galaxies'. The
sub-galaxies themselves are extended east-west by about 3kpc in individual
channel images. The [C II] tail joins smoothly into the main galaxy velocity
field. The [C II] line to continuum ratios are comparable for the main and
sub-galaxy positions, within a factor 2. In addition, these ratios are
comparable to z~5.5 LBGs. We conjecture that the WMH5 system represents the
early formation of a galaxy through the accretion of smaller satellite
galaxies, embedded in a smoother gas distribution, along a possibly filamentary
structure. The results are consistent with current cosmological simulations of
early galaxy formation, and support the idea of very early enrichment with dust
and heavy elements of the accreting material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02697</id><created>2017-07-10</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gr&#xf8;nnow</keyname><forenames>Asger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tepper-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Thor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>Joss</forenames></author><author><keyname>McClure-Griffiths</keyname><forenames>Naomi</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetized High Velocity Clouds in the Galactic Halo: A New Distance
  Constraint</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 14 figures. Published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ.845.69(2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7ed2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High velocity gas that does not conform to Galactic rotation is observed
throughout the Galaxy's halo. One component of this gas, HI high velocity
clouds (HVCs), have attracted attention since their discovery in the 1960s and
remain controversial in terms of their origins, largely due to the lack of
reliable distance estimates. The recent discovery of enhanced magnetic fields
towards HVCs has encouraged us to explore their connection to cloud evolution,
kinematics, and survival as they fall through the magnetized Galactic halo. For
a reasonable model for the halo magnetic field, most infalling clouds see
transverse rather than radial field lines. We find that significant compression
(and thereby amplification) of the ambient magnetic field occurs in front of
the cloud and in the tail of material stripped from the cloud. The compressed
transverse field attenuates hydrodynamical instabilities. This delays cloud
destruction, though not indefinitely. The observed B-field compression is
related to the cloud's distance from the Galactic plane. As a result, the
observed rotation measure provides useful distance information on a cloud's
location.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.07014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.07014</id><created>2017-07-21</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ivrii</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotics of the ground state energy in the relativistic settings</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19pp</comments><msc-class>35P20</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to derive sharp asymptotics of the ground state
energy for the heavy atoms and molecules in the relativistic settings, and, in
particular, to derive relativistic Scott correction term and also Dirac,
Schwinger and relativistic correction terms. Also we will prove that
Thomas-Fermi density approximates the actual density of the ground state, which
opens the way to estimate the excessive negative and positive charges and the
ionization energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.07451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.07451</id><created>2017-07-24</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Choudhary</keyname><forenames>Priyanka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Subhayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babu</keyname><forenames>Sujin B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Locomotion of a flexible one-hinge swimmer in Stokes regime</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  E. M. Purcell showed that a body has to perform non-reciprocal motion in
order to propel itself in a highly viscous environment. The swimmer with one
degree of freedom is bound to do reciprocal motion, whereby the center of mass
of the swimmer will not be able to propel itself due to the Scallop theorem. In
the present study, we are proposing a new artificial swimmer called the one
hinge swimmer. Here we will show that flexibility plays a crucial role in the
breakdown of Scallop theorem in the case of one-hinge swimmer or
two-dimensional scallop at low Reynolds number. To model a one-hinge artificial
swimmer, we use bead spring model for two arms joined by a hinge with bending
potential for the arms in order to make them semi-flexible. The fluid is
simulated using a particle based mesoscopic simulation method called the
multi-particle collision dynamics with Anderson thermostat. Here we show that
when our swimmer has rigid arms, the center of mass of the swimmer is not able
to propel itself as expected from the Scallop theorem. When we introduce
flexibility in the arms, the time reversal symmetry breaks in the case of the
one-hinged swimmer without the presence of a head contrary to the one-armed
super paramagnetic swimmer which required a passive head in order to swim. The
reduced velocity of the swimmer is studied using a range of parameters like
flexibility, beating frequency and the amplitude of the beat, where we obtain
similar scaling as that of the one-armed super paramagnetic swimmer. We also
calculate the dimensionless Sperm number for the swimmer and we get the maximum
velocity when the Sperm number is around 1.7.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.00438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.00438</id><created>2017-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Pourhassan</keyname><forenames>Behnam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sudhaker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asfar</keyname><forenames>Lina Al</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Fluctuations in a Hyperscaling Violation Background</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77:555</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5125-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the effect of thermal fluctuations on the
thermodynamics of a black geometry with hyperscaling violation. These thermal
fluctuations in the thermodynamics of this system are produced from quantum
corrections of geometry describing this system. We discuss the stability of
this system using specific heat and the entire Hessian matrix of the free
energy. We will analyze the effects of thermal fluctuations on the stability of
this system. We also analyze the effects of thermal fluctuations on the
criticality of the Hyperscaling violation background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01373</id><created>2017-08-04</created><updated>2017-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bloomfield</keyname><forenames>Philip E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Schrodinger Equation weakly attractive 1/r^2 Potential Eigenfunctions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 1 figure, 17 references, 6 explanatory footnotes</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bound state solutions of the Schrodinger Equation for the $-a/r^2$ potential
have been presented recently for both the weak and strong coupling cases.
However, Shortley in 1931 and Landau and Lifshitz in 1958 claimed that no bound
state solutions exist for the weak coupling case when $0 &lt; 2ma/\hbar^2 &lt;= (l +
1/2)^2$. We demonstrate that one bound state solution can exist for each
angular momentum state l, and that a complete orthogonal set of continuum
eigenfunctions orthogonal to the bound state eigenfunction can be constructed
when $l(l+ 1) &lt; 2ma/\hbar^2 &lt;= (l + 1/2)^2$. We show that Shortley's argument
is spurious due to his neglecting a boundary term arising from the momentum
operator and that the Landau and Lifshitz claim is based on a restrictive
fitting of the exterior solution to an interior spherical well. Instead, to
each weak coupling, a, we find a unique interior well strength $V_{in} =
-a'/ro^2$ which yields a finite bound state. In particular for the l = 0 case
the well strength is given by: $2ma'/\hbar^2 = 1.3734 + 2.2265*(1/4 -
2ma'/\hbar^2)^{1/2}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04683</id><created>2017-08-15</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghaforyan</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghaffary</keyname><forenames>Tooraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pincak</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebrahimzadeh</keyname><forenames>Majid</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of ultrasound waves intensity on the removal of Congo red color
  from the textile industry wastewater by Fe3O4@TiO2 core-shell nanospheres</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>5 pages and 6 fiures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Environmental pollutants, such as colors from the textile industry, affect
water quality indicators like color, smell, and taste. These substances in the
water cause the obstruction of filters and membranes and thereby reduce the
efficiency of advanced water treatment processes. In addition, they are harmful
to human health because of reaction with disinfectants and production of
by-products. Iron oxide nanoparticles are considered effective absorbents for
the removal of pollutants from aqueous environments. In order to increase the
stability and dispersion, nanospheres with iron oxide core and titanium dioxide
coating were used in this research and their ability to absorb Congo red color
was evaluated. Iron oxide-titanium oxide nanospheres were prepared based on the
coprecipitation method and then their physical properties were determined using
a tunneling electron microscope (TEM) and an X-ray diffraction device.
Morphological investigation of the absorbent surface showed that iron
oxide-titanium oxide nanospheres sized about 5 to 10 nm. X-ray dispersion
survey also suggested the high purity of the sample. In addition, the
absorption rate was measured in the presence of ultrasound waves and the
results indicated that the capacity of the synthesized sample to absorb Congo
red is greatly dependent on the intensity power of ultrasound waves, as the
absorption rate reaches 100% at powers above 30 watts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05557</id><created>2017-08-18</created><updated>2017-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Egel</keyname><forenames>Amos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eremin</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wriedt</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theobald</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemmer</keyname><forenames>Uli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomard</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author></authors><title>Extending the applicability of the T-matrix method to light scattering
  by flat particles on a substrate via truncation of Sommerfeld integrals</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Accepted manuscript. \copyright 2017. This manuscript version is made
  available under the CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0 license,
  http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer 202C
  (2017) pp. 279-285</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jqsrt.2017.08.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The simulation of light scattering by particles on a substrate with the
$T$-matrix method relies on the expansion of the scattered field in spherical
waves, followed by a plane wave expansion to allow the evaluation of the
reflection from the substrate. In practice, the plane wave expansion (i.e., the
Sommerfeld integrals) needs to be truncated at a maximal in-plane wavenumber
$\kappa_\mathrm{max}$. An appropriate selection of $\kappa_\mathrm{max}$ is
essential: counter-intuitively, the overall accuracy can degrade significantly
if the integrals are truncated with a too large value. In this paper, we
propose an empirical formula for the selection of $\kappa_\mathrm{max}$ and
discuss its application using a number of example simulations with dielectric
and metallic oblate spheroids on dielectric and metallic substrates. The
computed differential scattering cross sections are compared to results
obtained from the discrete-sources method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06760</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Larkoski</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moult</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neill</keyname><forenames>Duff</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic Boosted Boson Discrimination at the Large Hadron Collider</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Jet substructure is playing a central role at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC)
probing the Standard Model in extreme regions of phase space and providing
innovative ways to search for new physics. Analytic calculations of
experimentally successful observables are a primary catalyst driving
developments in jet substructure, allowing for a deeper understanding of
observables and for the exploitation of increasingly subtle features of jets.
In this paper we present a field theoretic framework enabling systematically
improvable calculations of groomed multi-prong substructure observables, which
builds on recent developments in multi-scale effective theories. We use this
framework to compute for the first time the full spectrum for groomed tagging
observables at the LHC, carefully treating both perturbative and
non-perturbative contributions in all regions. Our analysis enables a precision
understanding which we hope will improve the reach and sophistication of jet
substructure techniques at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06762</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Koss</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glidden</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balokovic</keyname><forenames>Mislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamperti</keyname><forenames>Isabella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Assef</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Franz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballantyne</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boggs</keyname><forenames>Steven E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrah</keyname><forenames>Dancan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furst</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gandhi</keyname><forenames>Poshak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehrels</keyname><forenames>Neil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hailey</keyname><forenames>Charles J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Fiona A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markwardt</keyname><forenames>Craig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masini</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treister</keyname><forenames>Ezequiel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>Dominic J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author></authors><title>NuSTAR Resolves the First Dual AGN above 10 keV in SWIFT J2028.5+2543</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in ApJ, 7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 824, Issue 1, article
  id. L4, 7 pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/824/1/L4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have discovered heavy obscuration in the dual active galactic nucleus
(AGN) in the Swift/Burst Alert Telescope (BAT) source SWIFT J2028.5+2543 using
Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope Array (NuSTAR). While an early XMM-Newton study
suggested the emission was mainly from NGC 6921, the superior spatial
resolution of NuSTAR above 10 keV resolves the Swift/BAT emission into two
sources associated with the nearby galaxies MCG +04-48-002 and NGC 6921 (z =
0.014) with a projected separation of 25.3 kpc (91&quot;). NuSTAR's sensitivity
above 10 keV finds both are heavily obscured to Compton-thick levels (N
H=(1-2)x10^24 cm-2) and contribute equally to the BAT detection ({L}10-50
{keV}{{int}}= 6x10^42 erg s-1). The observed luminosity of both sources is
severely diminished in the 2-10 keV band, illustrating the importance of &gt;10
keV surveys like those with NuSTAR and Swift/BAT. Compared to archival X-ray
data, MCG +04-48-002 shows significant variability (&gt;3) between observations.
Despite being bright X-ray AGNs, they are difficult to detect using optical
emission-line diagnostics because MCG +04-48-002 is identified as a
starburst/composite because of the high rates of star formation from a luminous
infrared galaxy while NGC 6921 is only classified as a LINER using line
detection limits. SWIFT J2028.5+2543 is the first dual AGN resolved above 10
keV and is the second most heavily obscured dual AGN discovered to date in the
X-rays other than NGC 6240.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06765</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Paulos</keyname><forenames>Miguel F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penedones</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toledo</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Rees</keyname><forenames>Balt C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vieira</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>The S-matrix Bootstrap III: Higher Dimensional Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25+18 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider constraints on the S-matrix of any gapped, Lorentz invariant
quantum field theory in 3+1 dimensions due to crossing symmetry, analyticity
and unitarity. We extremize cubic couplings, quartic couplings and scattering
lengths relevant for the elastic scattering amplitude of two identical scalar
particles. In the cases where our results can be compared with the older
S-matrix literature they are in excellent agreement. We also extremize a cubic
coupling in 2+1 dimensions which we can directly compare to a universal bound
for a QFT in AdS. This paper generalizes our previous 1+1 dimensional results
of arXiv:1607.06109 and arXiv:1607.06110.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06788</id><created>2017-08-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Amiri</keyname><forenames>Iraj S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorger</keyname><forenames>Volker J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ariannejad</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghasemi</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yupapin</keyname><forenames>P</forenames></author></authors><title>Channel resolution enhancement through scalability of nano/micro-scale
  thickness and width of SU-8 polymer based optical channels using UV
  lithography</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports on an approach for fabrication of micro-channels with
nanometer thickness achieved by optimization of UV lithography processes.
Rectangular micro-channels with a staple edge are fabricated over the surface
of a silicon wafer substrate in which a sub-micron layer of diluted SU-8 thin
film has been coated. The optimization of the process parameters including the
duration of a two-step pre- and post-baking process, UV exposure dosage, and
finally chemical developing time with constant agitation produces
micro-channels with high contrast edges and thickness below 100 nm is achieved.
The dimensions achieved using this approach has potential applications in
sub-micron optical waveguides and nanoelectromechanical (NEMS) devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06792</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Campi</keyname><forenames>Mercedes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Due&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Volatility and Economic Growth in the Twentieth Century</title><categories>q-fin.GN physics.soc-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>25 pages, 6 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The twentieth century was a period of outstanding economic growth together
with an unequal income distribution. This paper analyses the international
distribution of growth rates and its dynamics during the twentieth century. We
show that the whole century is characterized by a high heterogeneity in the
distribution of GDP per capita growth rates, which is reflected in different
shapes and a persistent asymmetry of the distributions at the regional level
and for countries of different development levels. We find that in the context
of the global conflicts that characterized the first half of the twentieth
century and involved mainly large economies, the well-known negative scale
relation between volatility and size of countries is not significant. After the
year 1956, a redistribution of volatility leads to a significant negative
scale-relation, which has been recently considered as a robust feature of the
evolution of economic organizations. Our results contribute with more empirical
facts that call the attention to traditional macroeconomic theories to better
explain the underlying complexity of the growth process and sheds light on its
historical evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06808</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>Ellis R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Kinwah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surajbali</keyname><forenames>Pooja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobsen</keyname><forenames>Idunn B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic rays in early star-forming galaxies and their effects on the
  interstellar medium</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures; Proceedings of the 35th International Cosmic Ray
  Conference (ICRC2017), 10-20 July 2017, Bexco, Busan, Korea -
  PoS(ICRC2017)289</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galaxies at high redshifts with strong star formation are sources of
high-energy cosmic rays. These cosmic rays interact with the baryon and
radiation fields of the galactic environment via photo-pair, photo-pion and
proton-proton processes to produce charged and neutral pions, neutrons and
protons. The cosmic rays thereby deposit energy into the interstellar medium
(ISM) as they propagate. We show how energy transport and deposition by ultra
high-energy cosmic rays is regulated by the evolution of the galaxy, in
particular by the development of the galactic magnetic field. We show how the
particle-driven energy deposition can influence the thermal evolution of the
host and its surroundings. Using a parametric protogalaxy model, we calculate
the heating effect on the ISM as the cosmic rays are increasingly confined by
the magnetic evolution of the galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06818</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Rosiek</keyname><forenames>Janusz</forenames></author></authors><title>General Mass Insertion Expansion in Flavor Physics</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, to appear in proceedings of the The Fifth Annual
  Conference on Large Hadron Collider Physics, Shanghai, China, May 15-20, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Calculating amplitudes for the flavor changing transitions in terms of the
off-diagonal elements of mass matrices, so called &quot;Mass Insertions&quot; (MI) in the
theory defined in &quot;gauge basis&quot; (before mass matrix diagonalization) is the
common technique in analyzing the flavor structure of the New Physics models. I
present a general method allowing to expand any QFT amplitude calculated in the
mass-eigenstates (physical) basis into series in MI's, to any required order.
The technique is purely algebraic, translating an amplitude written in the mass
eigenbasis into MI series without performing diagrammatic calculations in the
gauge basis. It can be applied for all types of mass matrices - either
Hermitian (scalar or vector), general complex (Dirac fermions) or complex
symmetric (Majorana fermions). Proposed expansion has been also automatized in
the form of publicly available specialized Mathematica package, MassToMI, which
features I illustrate with the example of the Higgs boson decays in the MSSM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06823</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames><affiliation>Ural Physico-Technical Institute, Sverdlovsk</affiliation></author></authors><title>The application of the electrodynamics of Born to the theory of the
  propagation of light in electromagnetic fields [Engl. transl. of kand. diss.
  (Ph.D. thesis), 1936]</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>216 pages, translator: K. Scharnhorst (Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  English translation of a Russian Ph.D. thesis from 1936. No original
abstract, translator's abstract: The thesis consists of two chapters. In
chapter I, general requirements to be imposed on any nonlinear electrodynamics
and their implementation in the electrodynamics of Born and Infeld are
discussed. In chapter II, within the nonlinear electrodynamics of Born the
propagation of a light wave in the presence of a homogeneous electric or
magnetic field as well as the interaction of two plane light waves in vacuo are
studied. Source details: A. A. Smirnov: Primenenie elektrodinamiki Borna k
teorii rasprostraneniya sveta v elektromagnitnykh polyakh. Kandidatskaya
dissertatsiya (Ph.D. thesis), Moscow State University, Moscow, 1936, 67 pp..
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06841</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Helminck</keyname><forenames>Gerard</forenames></author></authors><title>The strict AKNS hierarchy: its structure and solutions</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><msc-class>22E65, 34A34, 35F99, 35Q53, 37K10, 37K30, 58B25</msc-class><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics, Volume 2016, Article ID 3649205</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/3649205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss an integrable hierarchy of compatible Lax equations
that is obtained by a wider deformation of a commutative algebra in the loop
space of ${\rm sl}_{2}$ than that in the AKNS-case and whose Lax equations are
based on a different decomposition of this loop space. We show the
compatibility of these Lax equations and that they are equivalent to a set of
zero curvature relations. We present a linearization of the system and conclude
by giving a wide construction of solutions of this hierarchy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06847</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Lieu</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Lingze</forenames></author></authors><title>Superluminal transmission of phase modulation information by a long
  macroscopic pulse propagating through interstellar space</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 21 equations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method of transmitting information in interstellar space at superluminal,
or $&gt; c$, speeds is proposed. The information is encoded as phase modulation of
an electromagnetic wave of constant intensity, i.e. fluctuations in the rate of
energy transport plays no role in the communication, and no energy is
transported at speed $&gt;$ c. Of course, such a constant wave can ultimately last
only the duration of its enveloping wave packet. However, as a unique feature
of this paper, we assume the source is sufficiently steady to be capable of
emitting wave packets, or pulses, of size much larger than the separation
between sender and receiver. Therefore, if a pre-existing and enduring wave
envelope already connects the two sides, the subluminal nature of the
envelope's group velocity will no longer slow down the communication, which is
now limited by the speed at which information encoded as phase modulation
propagates through the plasma, i.e. the phase velocity $v_p &gt; c$. The method
involves no sharp structure in either time or frequency. As a working example,
we considered two spaceships separated by 1 lt-s in the local hot bubble.
Provided the bandwidth of the extra Fourier modes generated by the phase
modulation is much smaller than the carrier wave frequency, the radio
communication of a message, encoded as a specific alignment between the carrier
wave phase and the anomalous (modulated) phase, can take place at a speed in
excess of light by a few parts in 10$^{11}$ at $\nu\approx 1$~GHz, and higher
at smaller $\nu$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06867</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06867</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Kishigi</keyname><forenames>Keita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Yasumasa</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-quarter Dirac points, Landau levels and magnetization in
  $\alpha$-(BEDT-TTF)$_2$I$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>25 pages, 31 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 96, 085430 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.085430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energies as a function of the magnetic field ($H$) and the pressure are
studied theoretically in the tight-binding model for the two-dimensional
organic conductor,
  $\alpha$-(BEDT-TTF)$_2$I$_3$, in which massless Dirac fermions are realized.
The effects of the uniaxial pressure ($P$) are studied by using the
pressure-dependent hopping parameters. The system is semi-metallic with the
same area of an electron pocket and a hole pocket at $P &lt; 3.0$~kbar, where the
energies $(\varepsilon_{\rm D}^0$) at the Dirac points locate below the Fermi
energy $(\varepsilon_{\rm F}^0$) when $H=0$. We find that at $P=2.3$~kbar the
Dirac cones are critically tilted. In that case a new type of band crossing
occurs at &quot;three-quarter&quot;-Dirac points, i.e., the dispersion is quadratic in
one direction and linear in the other three directions. We obtain new
magnetic-field-dependences of the Landau levels $(\varepsilon_n)$;
$\varepsilon_n-\varepsilon^0_{\textrm{D}} \propto (n H)^{4/5}$ at $P=2.3$~kbar
(&quot;three-quarter&quot;-Dirac points) and $|\varepsilon_n-\varepsilon_{\rm F}^0|
\propto (n H)^2$ at $P=3.0$~kbar (the critical pressure for the semi-metallic
state). We also study the magnetization as a function of the inverse magnetic
field. We obtain two types of quantum oscillations. One is the usual de Haas
van Alphen (dHvA) oscillation, and the other is the unusual dHvA-like
oscillation which is seen even in the system without the Fermi surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06871</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohishi</keyname><forenames>Masatoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Taiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirota</keyname><forenames>Tomoya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Masao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaifu</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of New Methylamine (CH$_3$NH$_2$) Sources: Candidates for
  Future Glycine Surveys</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>27 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables, submitted to the Publications of
  Astronomical Society of Japan (PASJ)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been a long-standing problem to detect interstellar glycine
(NH$_2$CH$_2$COOH), the simplest amino acid, in studying a possible relation
between the Universe and origin of life. In the last about 40 years all surveys
of glycine failed, and it would be an alternative strategy to search for
precursor(s) to glycine. Such studies of precursors would be crucial prior to
conducting sensitive surveys by ALMA.
  Laboratory studies have suggested that CH$_3$NH$_2$ is a possible precursor
to glycine. Further theoretical study also suggested that the CH$_2$NH$_2$
radical that can be formed from CH$_3$NH$_2$ through photodissociation can be a
good precursor to glycine. Thus we observed CH$_3$NH$_2$ towards several hot
core sources by using the Nobeyama 45m radio telescope, and succeeded in
finding a new CH$_3$NH$_2$ source, G10.47+0.03, with its fractional abundance
of 2.4+-0.6x10^{-8}; at the time of writing, this source is the most abundant
source of CH$_3$NH$_2$ ever known. We also found another new source of
CH$_3$NH$_2$, NGC6334F, however, the detection may be tentative since the
signal-to-noise ratios are not sufficient to claim secure detection. Detailed
analysis of the detected data revealed the detection of the hyperfine
components of CH$_3$NH$_2$ for the first time. We found that the observed
abundance of CH$_3$NH$_2$ agrees fairly well with the theoretically predicted
value by Garrod (2013). Detectability of interstellar glycine is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06923</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Arabnejad</keyname><forenames>Saeid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Nhan Tien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shim</keyname><forenames>VPW</forenames></author></authors><title>Deformation Behavior of multi-spherulitic nylon6/silica nanocomposites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, the deformation of nylon6/silica nanocomposite is investigated
by employing a multiscale computational approach to understand the influence of
nanoparticles. Initially, the upper and lower bounds for the elastic properties
of a combination of crystalline and amorphous lamella are predicted via Voigt
and Reuss model. Subsequently, these results are used in an FEM model for RVEs
representing the multi-spherulitic structure of nylon6 and a silica/nylon6
nanocomposite. Each spherulite in these models has directional mechanical
properties defined by spherical coordinates. Simulation of deformation applied
in orthogonal directions and the mechanical response of the pure polymer and
nanocomposite are examined. The results show that spherical nanoparticles have
a smaller potential for enhancement of mechanical response compared to
nanoparticles of other shapes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06927</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>SUSY strong production in leptonic final state with ATLAS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 17 figures, Proceedings of the LHCP2017, Shanghai, 15-20 May
  2017</comments><report-no>ATL-PHYS-PROC-2017-096</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetry is one of the most motivated scenarios for physics beyond the
Standard Model. This article summarizes recent ATLAS results on searches for
supersymmetry in proton-proton collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 13 TeV
at LHC, which target supersymmetric particles produced by strong interaction in
events with leptonic final states. No significant excess above the Standard
Model expectation is observed and exclusion limits have been set on squark and
gluino masses in various scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06944</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Villalba</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wissink</keyname><forenames>Jan G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodi</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of the approach boundary layer on the flow over an
  axisymmetric hill at a moderate Reynolds number</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Turbulence, 11, N8, 2010</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/14685241003702449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large Eddy Simulations of a flow at a moderate Reynolds number over and
around a three-dimensional hill have been performed. The main aim of the
simulations was to study the effects of various inflow conditions (boundary
layer thickness and laminar versus turbulent boundary layers) on the flow
behind the hill. The main features of the flow behind the hill are similar in
all simulations, however various differences are observed. The topology of the
streamlines (friction lines) on the surface adjacent to the lower wall was
found to be independent of the inflow conditions prescribed and comprised four
saddle points and four nodes (of which two are foci). In all simulations a
variety of vortical structures could be observed, ranging from a horseshoe
vortex - that was formed at the foot of the hill - to a train of large hairpin
vortices in the wake of the hill. In the simulation with a thick incoming
laminar boundary layer also secondary vortical structures (i.e. hairpin
vortices) were observed to be formed at either side of the hill, superposed on
the legs of the horseshoe vortex. Sufficiently far downstream of the hill, at
the symmetry plane the mean velocity and the rms of the velocity fluctuations
were found to become quasi-independent of the inflow conditions, while towards
the sides the influence of the hill decreases and the velocity profiles recover
the values prevailing at the inflow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06949</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Elipe</keyname><forenames>G. Torralba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazquez</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zas</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-messenger Astronomy: a Bayesian approach</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After the discovery of the gravitational waves and the observation of
neutrinos of cosmic origin, we have entered a new and exciting era where cosmic
rays, neutrinos, photons and gravitational waves will be used simultaneously to
study the highest energy phenomena in the Universe. Here we present a fully
Bayesian approach to the challenge of combining and comparing the wealth of
measurements from existing and upcoming experimental facilities. We discuss the
procedure from a theoretical point of view and using simulations, we also
demonstrate the feasibility of the method by incorporating the use of
information provided by different theoretical models and different experimental
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06952</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Treiber</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kesting</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author></authors><title>The Intelligent Driver Model with Stochasticity -- New Insights Into
  Traffic Flow Oscillations</title><categories>physics.soc-ph nlin.PS</categories><comments>presented at the conference ISTTT22 in Chicago (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Transportation Research Part B (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.trb.2017.08.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Traffic flow oscillations, including traffic waves, are a common yet
incompletely understood feature of congested traffic. Possible mechanisms
include traffic flow instabilities, indifference regions or finite human
perception thresholds (action points), and external acceleration noise.
However, the relative importance of these factors in a given situation remains
unclear. We bring light into this question by adding external noise and action
points to the Intelligent Driver Model and other car-following models thereby
obtaining a minimal model containing all three oscillation mechanisms. We show
analytically that even in the subcritical regime of linearly stable flow (order
parameter $\epsilon&lt;0$), external white noise leads to spatiotemporal speed
correlations &quot;anticipating&quot; the waves of the linearly unstable regime.
Sufficiently far away from the threshold, the amplitude scales with
$(-\epsilon)^{-0.5}$. By means of simulations and comparisons with experimental
car platoons and bicycle traffic, we show that external noise and indifference
regions with action points have essentially equivalent effects. Furthermore,
flow instabilities dominate the oscillations on freeways while external noise
or action points prevail at low desired speeds such as vehicular city or
bicycle traffic. For bicycle traffic, noise can lead to fully developed waves
even for single-file traffic in the subcritical regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06954</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Gerosa</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suarez</keyname><forenames>Felipe G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Domingues</keyname><forenames>Sergio H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Matos</keyname><forenames>Christiano J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>One-step deposition and in-situ reduction of graphene oxide in glass
  microcapillaries and application to photonics</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Films of graphene oxide (GO) were produced on the inner walls of glass
microcapillaries via insertion of a GO water suspension followed by quick
drying with a hot finger (no previous surface functionalization required).
Individual capillaries from an array could also be selectively GO coated. Raman
hyperspectral images revealed the films to be continuous along tens of
centimeters. Furthermore, the films could be thermally reduced through an
annealing process, which also decreased the concentration of defects. As a
proof of principle application, the microcapillaries of photonic crystal fibers
were covered with a GO film, leading to the demonstration of fiber polarizers
and mode lockers for pulsed fiber lasers. A comparison between GO- and reduced
GO-coated fibers revealed that shorter pulses are obtained with the latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06956</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Serry</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuffaha</keyname><forenames>Amjad</forenames></author></authors><title>Static Stability Analysis of a Thin Plate with a Fixed Trailing Edge in
  Axial Subsonic Flow: Possio Integral Equation Approach</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>76B07, 76B10, 45C05, 74G99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the static stability of plates with fixed trailing edges in
axial airflow is studied using the framework of Possio integral equation.
First, we introduce a new derivation of a Possio integral equation that relates
the pressure jump along thin plates to their downwash based on the
linearization of the governing equations of an ideal compressible fluid. The
steady state solution to the Possio equation is used to account for the
aerodynamic forces in the steady state plate governing equation resulting in a
singular differential-integral equation which is transformed to an integral
equation. Next, we verify the solvability of the integral equation based on the
Fredholm alternative for compact operators in Banach spaces and the contraction
mapping theorem. Then, we derive explicit formulas for the characteristic
equations of free-clamped and free-pinned plates. The minimum solutions to the
characteristic equations are the divergence speeds which indicate when static
instabilities start to occur. We show analytically that free-pinned plates are
statically unstable. After that, we move to derive analytically flow speed
intervals that correspond to static stability regions for free-clamped plates.
We also resort to numerical computations to obtain an explicit formula for the
divergence speed of free-clamped plates. Finally, we apply the obtained results
on piezoelectric plates and we show that free-clamped piezoelectric plates are
statically more stable than conventional free-clamped plates due to the
piezoelectric coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06957</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Siampour</keyname><forenames>Hamidreza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Shailesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanofabrication of Plasmonic Circuits Containing Single Photon Sources</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 4, 1879 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00374</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanofabrication of photonic components based on dielectric-loaded surface
plasmon-polariton waveguides (DLSPPWs) excited by single nitrogen vacancy (NV)
centers in nanodiamonds is demonstrated. DLSPPW circuits are built around NV
containing nanodiamonds, which are certified to be single-photon emitters,
using electron-beam lithography of hydrogen silsesquioxane (HSQ) resist on
silver-coated silicon substrates. A propagation length of ~20 {\mu}m for the NV
single-photon emission is measured with DLSPPWs. A 5-fold enhancement in the
total decay rate and up to 63% coupling efficiency to the DLSPPW mode is
achieved, indicating significant mode confinement. Finally, we demonstrate
routing of single plasmons with DLSPPW-based directional cou-plers, revealing
the potential of our approach for on-chip realization of quantum-optical
networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06970</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Saichev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sornette</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistics of seismic cluster durations</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>45 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the standard ETAS model of triggered seismicity, we present a rigorous
theoretical analysis of the main statistical properties of temporal clusters,
defined as the group of events triggered by a given main shock of fixed
magnitude m that occurred at the origin of time, at times larger than some
present time t. Using the technology of generating probability function (GPF),
we derive the explicit expressions for the GPF of the number of future
offsprings in a given temporal seismic cluster, defining, in particular, the
statistics of the cluster's duration and the cluster's offsprings maximal
magnitudes. We find the remarkable result that the magnitude difference between
the largest and second largest event in the future temporal cluster is
distributed according to the regular Gutenberg-Richer law that controls the
unconditional distribution of earthquake magnitudes. For earthquakes obeying
the Omori-Utsu law for the distribution of waiting times between triggering and
triggered events, we show that the distribution of the durations of temporal
clusters of events of magnitudes above some detection threshold \nu has a power
law tail that is fatter in the non-critical regime $n&lt;1$ than in the critical
case n=1. This paradoxical behavior can be rationalised from the fact that
generations of all orders cascade very fast in the critical regime and
accelerate the temporal decay of the cluster dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06986</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Marty</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cramer</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitagliano</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toth</keyname><forenames>Geza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plenio</keyname><forenames>Martin B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiparticle entanglement criteria for nonsymmetric collective
  variances</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a general scheme to detect various multiparticle entanglement
structures from global non-permutationally invariant observables. In
particular, we derive bounds on the variance of non-permutationally invariant
and collective operators for the verification of $k$-party entanglement. For a
family of observables related to the spin structure factor, we give
quantitative bounds on entanglement that are independent of the total number of
particles. We introduce highly non-symmetric states with genuine multipartite
entanglement that is verifiable with the presented technique and discuss how
they can be prepared with trapped ions exploiting the high degree of control in
these systems. As a special case, our framework provides an alternative
approach to obtain a tight relaxation of the entanglement criterion by S{\o}
rensen and M{\o} lmer [Phys. Rev. Lett. 86, 4431 (2001)] that is free from
technical assumptions and allows to calculate the bounds with an improved
scaling in the detectable depth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06991</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yanhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>A Mathematical Treatment to Determine Transient Growth Kinetics from a
  Given Size Distribution</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Particle coarsening and grain growth take place to minimize the total
interfacial energy. The classical mean-field treatments by Lifshitz, Slyozov,
[1] Wagner [2] and Hillert [3] predicted cubic growth law under bulk-diffusion
controlled precipitation coarsening and parabolic growth law under interface
controlled grain growth, as well as their steady-state size distribution. When
the size distribution is the steady-state one, the average grain size satisfies
the following dependence: under bulk-diffusion control and under interface
control, with correct slopes definitely given by the theory. However, when the
size distribution does not satisfy the steady-state one, the growth kinetics
would deviate from theoretical prediction. As is shown by numerical simulations
in Ref. 4 and 5, the deviation is less obvious in the growth law, but more
evident in the slope of the growth curve. Specifically, starting from a
non-steady-state size distribution, the parabolic/cubic growth law would be
recovered quickly, yet the convergence of the slope in the or curve is
extremely slow. Therefore, it would be interesting to know how to calculate the
instantaneous slope of the growth kinetics from an arbitrarily given size
distribution. As will be shown below, assuming a known growth law, the
analytical solution can be easily obtained and the exact solution can be
obtained by numerical integration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06993</id><created>2017-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>A smoothed dissipative particle dynamics methodology for wall-bounded
  domains</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>PhD thesis (2013), Mechanical Engineering, Worcester Polytechnic
  Institute</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents the mathematical and computational aspects of a smooth
dissipative particle dynamics with dynamic virtual particle allocation method
(SDPD-DV) for modeling and simulation of mesoscopic fluids in wall-bounded
domains. The SDPD-DV method is realized with fluid particles, boundary
particles and dynamically allocated virtual particles near solid boundaries.
The physical domain in SDPD-DV contains external and internal solid boundaries,
periodic inlets and outlets, and the fluid region. The solid boundaries of the
domain are represented with boundary particles which have an assigned position,
wall velocity, and temperature upon initialization. The fluid domain is
discretized with fluid particles placed in a global index. The algorithm for
nearest neighbor particle search is based on a combination of the linked-cell
and Verlet-list approaches and utilizes large rectangular cells for
computational efficiency. The density model of a fluid particle in the
proximity of a solid boundary includes the contribution from the virtual
particles in its truncated support domain. The thermodynamic properties of a
virtual particle are identical to those of the corresponding fluid particle.
Additional verification involves SDPD-DV simulations of transient, planar,
Couette liquid water flow. The top plate is moving at and separated by 10-3 m
from the bottom stationary plate. The numerical results are in very good
agreement with the analytical solutions. Additional SDPD-DV verification is
accomplished with the simulation of a body-force driven, low-Reynolds number
flow of water over a cylinder of radius . The SDPD-DV field velocity and
pressure are compared with those obtained by FLUENT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06996</id><created>2017-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Changshi</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author></authors><title>Extraction of Schottky barrier height insensitive to temperature via
  forward currentvoltage- temperature measurements</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, one Table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermal stability of most electronic and photo-electronic devices
strongly depends on the relationship between Schottky Barrier Height (SBH) and
temperature. In this paper, the possible of thermionic current depicted via
correct and reliability relationship between forward current and voltage is
consequently discussed, the intrinsic SBH insensitive to temperature can be
calculated by modification on Richardson- Dushman`s formula suggested in this
paper. The results of application on four hetero-junctions prove that the
method proposed is credible in this paper, this suggests that the I/V/T method
is a feasible alternative to characterize these heterojunctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07006</id><created>2017-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruglov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear electrodynamics and magnetic black holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Annalen Phys. 529 (2017) no.8, 1700073</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201700073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model of nonlinear electrodynamics with two parameters, coupled with
general relativity, is investigated. We study the magnetized black hole and
obtain solutions. The asymptotic of the metric and mass functions at
$r\rightarrow\infty$ and $r\rightarrow 0$, and corrections to the
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m solution are found. We investigate thermodynamics of
black holes and calculate the Hawking temperature and heat capacity of black
holes. It is shown that there are phase transitions and at some parameters of
the model black holes are stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07016</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Grebenev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames><affiliation>Space Research Institute, Russian Academy of Sciences</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chelovekov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames><affiliation>Space Research Institute, Russian Academy of Sciences</affiliation></author></authors><title>Multiple X-ray bursts and the model of a spreading layer of accreting
  matter over the neutron star surface</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, v. 43, n. 9, pp. 583-594 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S106377371709002X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the detection during the JEM-X/INTEGRAL observations of several
X-ray bursters of series of close type I X-ray bursts consisting of two or
three events with a recurrence time much shorter than the characteristic (at
the observed mean accretion rate) time of matter accumulation needed for a
thermonuclear explosion to be initiated on the neutron star surface. We show
that such series of bursts are naturally explained in the model of a spreading
layer of accreting matter over the neutron star surface in the case of a
sufficiently high ($\dot{M}\geq 1\times 10^{-9}\ M_{\odot}\ \mbox{yr}^{-1}$)
accretion rate (corresponding to a mean luminosity $L_{\rm tot}\geq 1\times
10^{37} \mbox{erg s}^{-1}$). The existence of triple bursts requires some
refinement of the model - the importance of a central ring zone is shown. In
the standard model of a spreading layer no infall of matter in this zone is
believed to occur.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07034</id><created>2017-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Madrazo</keyname><forenames>Celia Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cacha</keyname><forenames>Ignacio Heredia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iglesias</keyname><forenames>Lara Lloret</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Lucas</keyname><forenames>Jes&#xfa;s Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of a Convolutional Neural Network for image classification
  to the analysis of collisions in High Energy Physics</title><categories>cs.CV hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures, educational</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The application of deep learning techniques using convolutional neural
networks to the classification of particle collisions in High Energy Physics is
explored. An intuitive approach to transform physical variables, like momenta
of particles and jets, into a single image that captures the relevant
information, is proposed. The idea is tested using a well known deep learning
framework on a simulation dataset, including leptonic ttbar events and the
corresponding background at 7 TeV from the CMS experiment at LHC, available as
Open Data. This initial test shows competitive results when compared to more
classical approaches, like those using feedforward neural networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07098</id><created>2017-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Sudheer</keyname></author><author><keyname>Porwal</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhartiya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication of plasmonic surface relief gratings for the application of
  band-pass filter in UV-Visible spectral range</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>10 page</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The measured experimental results of optical diffraction of 10, 5 and 3.4
micrometer period plasmonic surface relief grating are presented for the
application of band-pass filter in visible spectral range. Conventional
scanning electron microscopic (SEM) is used to fabricate the grating structures
on the silver halide based film (substrate) by exposing the electron beam in
raster scan fashion. Morphological characterization of the gratings is
performed by atomic force microscopy (AFM) shows that the period, height and
profile depends on the line per frame, beam spot, single line dwell time, beam
current, and accelerating voltage of the electron beam. Optical transmission
spectra of 10 micrometer period grating shows a well-defined localized surface
plasmon resonance (LSPR) dip at ~366 nm wavelength corresponding to gelatin
embedded silver nanoparticles of the grating structure. As the period of the
grating reduces LSPR dip becomes prominent. The maximum first order diffraction
efficiency (DE) and bandwidth for 10 micrometer period grating are observed as
4% and 400 nm in 350 nm to 800 nm wavelength range respectively. The DE and
bandwidth are reduced up to 0.03% and 100 nm for 3.4 micrometer period grating.
The profile of DE is significantly flat within the diffraction bandwidth for
each of the gratings. An assessment of the particular role of LSPR absorption
and varied grating period in the development of the profile of first order DE
v/s wavelength are studied. Fabrication of such nano-scale structures in a
large area using conventional SEM and silver halide based films may provide the
simple and efficient technique for various optical devices applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07106</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Modeling of MEMS Fixed-Fixed beams</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>PhD thesis, Lehigh Univ, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This dissertation presents a new coupled electro-mechanical model that is an
improvement on the classical parallel-plate approximation. The model employs a
hyperbolic function to account for the beam deformed shape and electrostatic
field. Based on this, the model can accurately calculate the deflection of a
fixed-fixed beam subjected to an applied voltage and the switch
capacitance-voltage characteristics without using parallel-plate assumption.
For model validation, the model solutions are compared with ANSYS finite
element results and experimental data. It is found that the model works
especially well in residual stress dominant and stretching dominant cases. The
model shows that the nonlinear stretching can significantly increase the
pull-in voltage and extend the beam maximum travel range. Based on the model, a
graphene nanoelectromechanical systems (NEMS) resonator is simulated and the
agreement with the experimental data is excellent. The proposed coupled
hyperbolic model demonstrates its capacity to guide the design and optimization
of both RF microelectromechanical system (MEMS) capacitive switches and NEMS
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07109</id><created>2017-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kurdyubov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trifonov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerlovin</keyname><forenames>I. Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ignatiev</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavokin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impurity-induced modulation of terahertz waves in optically excited GaAs</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of the photoinduced absorption of terahertz (THz) radiation in a
semi-insulating GaAs crystal is studied by the pulsed THz transmission
spectroscopy. We found that a broad-band modulation of THz radiation may be
induced by a low-power optical excitation in the spectral range of the impurity
absorption band in GaAs. The measured modulation achieves 80\%. The amplitude
and frequency characteristics of the resulting THz modulator are critically
dependent on the carrier density and relaxation dynamics in the conduction band
of GaAs. In semi-insulating GaAs crystals, the carrier density created by the
impurity excitation is controlled by the rate of their relaxation to the
impurity centers. The relaxation rate and, consequently, the frequency
characteristics of the modulator can be optimized by an appropriate choice of
the impurities and their concentrations. The modulation parameters can be also
controlled by the crystal temperature and by the power and photon energy of the
optical excitation. These experiments pave the way to the low-power fast
optically-controlled THz modulation, imaging, and beam steering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0007059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0007059</id><created>2000-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Luhman</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames><affiliation>CfA</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Initial Mass Function of Low-Mass Stars and Brown Dwarfs in Taurus</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>to be published in The Astrophysical Journal, 24 pages, 6 figures,
  also found at http://cfa-www.harvard.edu/~kluhman/taurus/</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J.544:1044-1055,2000</journal-ref><doi>10.1086/317232</doi><abstract>  By combining deep optical imaging and infrared spectroscopy with data from
the Two-Micron All-Sky Survey (2MASS) and from previous studies (e.g., Briceno
et al.), I have measured the Initial Mass Function (IMF) for a
reddening-limited sample in four fields in the Taurus star forming region. This
IMF is representative of the young populations within these fields for masses
above 0.02 Msun. Relative to the similarly derived IMF for the Trapezium
Cluster (Luhman et al.), the IMF for Taurus exhibits a modest deficit of stars
above one solar mass (i.e., steeper slope), the same turnover mass (~0.8 Msun),
and a significant deficit of brown dwarfs. If the IMF in Taurus were the same
as that in the Trapezium, 12.8+/-1.8 brown dwarfs (&gt;0.02 Msun) are expected in
these Taurus fields where only one brown dwarf candidate is found. These
results are used to test theories of the IMF.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0105517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0105517</id><created>2001-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farnell</keyname><forenames>D. J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Phase Transitions in Spin Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 12 Postscipt figures; Accepted for publication in World
  Scientific</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Quantum Many-Body Theory, Vol. 5, edited by Raymond F.
  Bishop, Klaus A. Gernoth, and Niels R. Walet, (World Scientific 2001), p. 239</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812799760_0022</doi><abstract>  We discuss the influence of strong quantum fluctuations on zero-temperature
phase transitions in a two-dimensional spin-half Heisenberg system. Using a
high-order coupled cluster treatment, we study competition of magnetic bonds
with and without frustration. We find that the coupled cluster treatment is
able to describe the zero-temperature transitions in a qualitatively correct
way, even if frustration is present and other methods such as quantum Monte
Carlo fail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9410115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9410115</id><created>1994-10-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hale</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xian</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Systematic Inclusion of High-Order Multi-Spin Correlations for the
  Spin-$1\over2$ $XXZ$ Models</title><categories>cond-mat</categories><comments>(to appear in PRL). 4 pages, ReVTeX, two figures available upon
  request. UMIST Preprint MA-000-0001</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 73 (1994), 3157-3160</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.73.3157</doi><abstract>  We apply the microscopic coupled-cluster method (CCM) to the spin-$1\over2$
$XXZ$ models on both the one-dimensional chain and the two-dimensional square
lattice. Based on a systematic approximation scheme of the CCM developed by us
previously, we carry out high-order {\it ab initio} calculations using
computer-algebraic techniques. The ground-state properties of the models are
obtained with high accuracy as functions of the anisotropy parameter.
Furthermore, our CCM analysis enables us to study their quantum critical
behavior in a systematic and unbiased manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9411012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9411012</id><created>1994-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidson</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xian</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>A nonperturbative microscopic theory of Hamiltonian lattice gauge
  systems</title><categories>cond-mat</categories><comments>11 pages, LaTeX, two figures available upon request</comments><journal-ref>&quot;Recent Progress in Many-Body Theories,&quot; Vol. 4, (eds. E.
  Schachinger, H. Mitter and H. Sormann), Plenum, New York, 1995, 237-248</journal-ref><abstract>  A review is given of our recent application of a systematic microscopic
formulation of quantum many-body theory, namely the coupled-cluster method
(CCM), to Hamiltonian $U(1)$ lattice gauge models in the pure gauge sector. It
is emphasized that our CCM results represent a natural extension or resummation
of the results from the strong-coupling perturbation theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9611012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9611012</id><created>1996-11-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames><affiliation>Syracuse Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Farnell</keyname><forenames>D. J. J.</forenames><affiliation>UMIST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames><affiliation>UMIST</affiliation></author></authors><title>An efficient implementation of high-order coupled-cluster techniques
  applied to quantum magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>25 pages, including 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 90 (1998), 327-361</journal-ref><doi>10.1023/A:1023220222019</doi><abstract>  We illustrate how the systematic inclusion of multi-spin correlations of the
quantum spin-lattice systems can be efficiently implemented within the
framework of the coupled-cluster method by examining the ground-state
properties of both the square-lattice and the frustrated triangular-lattice
quantum antiferromagnets. Various physical quantities including the
ground-state energy, the anisotropy susceptibility, and the sublattice
magnetisation are calculated and compared with those obtained from such other
methods as series expansions and quantum Monte Carlo simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9804079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9804079</id><created>1998-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>Raymond F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farnell</keyname><forenames>Damian J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkinson</keyname><forenames>John B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transitions in the Spin-Half J_1--J_2 Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>28 pages, Latex, 2 postscript figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 58 (1998), 6394-6402</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.58.6394</doi><abstract>  The coupled cluster method (CCM) is a well-known method of quantum many-body
theory, and here we present an application of the CCM to the spin-half J_1--J_2
quantum spin model with nearest- and next-nearest-neighbour interactions on the
linear chain and the square lattice. We present new results for ground-state
expectation values of such quantities as the energy and the sublattice
magnetisation. The presence of critical points in the solution of the CCM
equations, which are associated with phase transitions in the real system, is
investigated. Completely distinct from the investigation of the critical
points, we also make a link between the expansion coefficients of the
ground-state wave function in terms of an Ising basis and the CCM ket-state
correlation coefficients. We are thus able to present evidence of the
breakdown, at a given value of J_2/J_1, of the Marshall-Peierls sign rule which
is known to be satisfied at the pure Heisenberg point (J_2 = 0) on any
bipartite lattice. For the square lattice, our best estimates of the points at
which the sign rule breaks down and at which the phase transition from the
antiferromagnetic phase to the frustrated phase occurs are, respectively, given
(to two decimal places) by J_2/J_1 = 0.26 and J_2/J_1 = 0.61.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9806324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9806324</id><created>1998-06-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farnell</keyname><forenames>D. J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab Initio Simulation of the Nodal Surfaces of Heisenberg
  Antiferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>24 pages, Latex, 3 postscript figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 59 (1999), 1000-1007</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.59.1000</doi><abstract>  The spin-half Heisenberg antiferromagnet (HAF) on the square and triangular
lattices is studied using the coupled cluster method (CCM) technique of quantum
many-body theory. The phase relations between different expansion coefficients
of the ground-state wave function in an Ising basis for the square lattice HAF
is exactly known via the Marshall-Peierls sign rule, although no equivalent
sign rule has yet been obtained for the triangular lattice HAF. Here the CCM is
used to give accurate estimates for the Ising-expansion coefficients for these
systems, and CCM results are noted to be fully consistent with the
Marshall-Peierls sign rule for the square lattice case. For the triangular
lattice HAF, a heuristic rule is presented which fits our CCM results for the
Ising-expansion coefficients of states which correspond to two-body excitations
with respect to the reference state. It is also seen that Ising-expansion
coefficients which describe localised, $m$-body excitations with respect to the
reference state are found to be highly converged, and from this result we infer
that the nodal surface of the triangular lattice HAF is being accurately
modeled. Using these results, we are able to make suggestions regarding
possible extensions of existing quantum Monte Carlo simulations for the
triangular lattice HAF.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/9902219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/9902219</id><created>1999-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farnell</keyname><forenames>D. J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkinson</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sign Rules for Anisotropic Quantum Spin Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 ps-figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 61 (2000), 6775-6779</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.61.6775</doi><abstract>  We present new and exact ``sign rules'' for various spin-s anisotropic
spin-lattice models. It is shown that, after a simple transformation which
utilizes these sign rules, the ground-state wave function of the transformed
Hamiltonian is positive-definite. Using these results exact statements for
various expectation values of off-diagonal operators are presented, and
transitions in the behavior of these expectation values are observed at
particular values of the anisotropy. Furthermore, the effects of sign rules in
variational calculations and quantum Monte Carlo calculations are considered.
They are illustrated by a simple variational treatment of a one-dimensional
anisotropic spin model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
