<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:38:22Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-08-11" from="2017-08-11" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0709.2414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0709.2414</id><created>2007-09-15</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Ying-Qiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Constraints on the Cosmological Parameters</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In cosmology, the cosmic curvature $K$ and the cosmological constant
$\Lambda$ are two important parameters, and the values have strong influence on
the behavior of the universe. In the context of normal cosmology, under the
ordinary assumptions of positive mass-energy and initial negative pressure, we
find the initial singularity of the universe is certainly absent and we have
$K=1$. This means total spatial structure of the universe should be a
3-dimensional sphere $S^3$. For the cyclic cosmological model, we have
$\Lambda\lesssim 10^{-24} {\rm ly}^{-2}$. Obviously, such constraints would be
helpful for the researches on the properties of dark matter and dark energy in
cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1102.2949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1102.2949</id><created>2011-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Decio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomova</keyname><forenames>Zora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winternitz</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Are there Contact Transformations for Discrete Equations?</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys A: Math.Theor., 44 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/44/26/265201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define infinitesimal contact transformations for ordinary difference
schemes as transformations that depend on $K+1$ lattice points $(K \geq 1)$ and
can be integrated to form a local or global Lie group. We then prove that such
contact transformations do not exist.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.4643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.4643</id><created>2011-08-23</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandori</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Periodic Higgs, Inflaton, Axion Potentials and the Sine-Gordon
  Universality Class</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Higgs, inflaton and axion physics are examples where scalar fields naturally
appear, in the two former cases, usually with a polynomial type
self-interaction. In this work possible applications of periodic scalar
potentials are discussed which belong to the sine-Gordon universality class.
For example, a periodic self-interaction is proposed here as a possible
extension, UV completion of the standard model Higgs potential. Using the usual
parametrisation of the field around the first minimum, one recovers the
Lagrangian of the Higgs sector but with a periodic interaction term for a
single-component real scalar field. Another possible application is
inflationary cosmology where the so called natural inflation i.e., the periodic
PNGB potential has already been used as a competing inflationary model.
Finally, one has to mention the periodic axion potential which was proposed to
retain the CP conserving nature of QCD where, in principle, gauge symmetry and
renormalizability allow the inclusion of CP violating terms but experimental
data do not favour such an extension. The purpose of this work is to map out
the exact phase structure of the sine-Gordon model by the functional
renormalization group (RG) method in arbitrary dimension and to study the
consequences of its renormalization on Higgs, inflaton and axion physics. It is
shown that the pure sine-Gordon model has a single (broken) phase for d&gt;2.
Results are used to study the phase structure of the equivalent neutral Coulomb
gas and to demonstrate that the isotropic XY spin model belongs to a different
universality class for d&gt;2. The findings (i) open a new platform to perform
stability studies for models with periodic type Higgs potential which can be
used as a possible UV completion, (ii) clarify the role of the RG running of
the frequency parameter in the PNGB inflationary model, (iii) confirm the
flattening of the axion potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.0448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.0448</id><created>2013-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Arbuzov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopylova</keyname><forenames>T. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Off-mass-shell muon anomalous magnetic moment</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Part. Nucl. Lett. 11, 339-341 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1547477114040086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interaction of charged leptons with photons is considered for the case when
one of the lepton legs is off the mass shell. The effect due to off-mass-shell
shift in the anomalous magnetic moment is computed within one-loop
approximation. Possible contributions of this effect in the muon $g-2$
measurements are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.2487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.2487</id><created>2014-08-11</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yi-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudakov</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strong</keyname><forenames>Courtenay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golden</keyname><forenames>Kenneth M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ising model for melt ponds on Arctic sea ice</title><categories>physics.ao-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures; comprehensively rewritten with simplified model</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Perhaps the most iconic feature of melting Arctic sea ice is the formation of
distinctive, complex ponds on its surface during late spring. The evolution of
melt ponds and their geometrical characteristics determines the albedo of sea
ice, a key parameter in climate modeling. However, a theoretical understanding
of this evolution, and predictions of geometrical features, have remained
elusive. To address this fundamental problem in polar climate science, here we
introduce a two dimensional random field Ising model for melt ponds. The ponds
are identified as metastable states of the system, where the binary spin
variable corresponds to the presence of melt water or ice on the sea ice
surface. With only a minimal set of physical parameters, the model predictions
agree very closely with observed power law scaling of the pond size
distribution and critical length scale where melt ponds undergo a transition in
fractal geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0999</id><created>2014-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Haq</keyname><forenames>Sami Ul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khalique</keyname><forenames>Aeysha</forenames></author></authors><title>Long Distance Cavity Entanglement by Entanglement Swapping Using Atomic
  Momenta</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Communications, 334 pp. 290-293 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.optcom.2014.08.053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple technique to generate entanglement between distant
cavities by using entanglement swapping involving atomic momenta. For the
proposed scheme, we have two identical atoms, both initially in their ground
state, each incident on far apart cavities with particular initial momenta. The
two cavities are prepared initially in superposition of zero and one photon
state. First, we interact each atom with a cavity in dispersive way. The
interaction results into atom-field entangled state. Then we perform EPR state
measurement on both atomic momenta state which is an analog of Bell
measurement. The EPR state measurement is designed by passing the atoms through
cavity beam splitters which transfers the atomic momentum state into
superposition state. Finally, these atoms are detected by the detector. After
the detection of the atoms, we can distinguish that cavities in one of the Bell
states. This process leads to two distant cavity fields entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.01481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.01481</id><created>2015-01-07</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gungor</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence and Symmetries for Linear Parabolic Equations and
  Applications Revisited</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>59 pages, more misprints corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A systematic and unified approach to transformations and symmetries of
general second order linear parabolic partial differential equations is
presented. Equivalence group is used to derive the Appell type transformations,
specifically Mehler's kernel in any dimension. The complete symmetry group
classification is re-performed. A new criterion which is necessary and
sufficient for reduction to the standard heat equation by point transformations
is established. A similar criterion is also valid for the equations to have a
four- or six-dimensional symmetry group (nontrivial symmetry groups). In this
situation, the basis elements are listed in terms of coefficients. A number of
illustrative examples are given. In particular, some applications from the
recent literature are re-examined in our new approach. Applications include a
comparative discussion of heat kernels based on group-invariant solutions and
the idea of connecting Lie symmetries and classical integral transforms
introduced by Craddock and his coworkers. Multidimensional parabolic PDEs of
heat and Schr\&quot;odinger type are also considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04006</id><created>2015-04-15</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Daekyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labun</keyname><forenames>Ou Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Equality of hemisphere soft functions for $e^+e^-$, DIS and $pp$
  collisions at $\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^2)$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, uses elsarticle.cls. v2: several clarifications
  and references added. v3: references added, minor edits, Fig. B.1 improved,
  version published in PLB. v4,v5: minor typos and constant terms in soft
  function in Appendix A corrected</comments><report-no>LA-UR-15-22720</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 748, 45-54 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple observation about soft amplitudes and soft functions
appearing in factorizable cross sections in $ee$, $ep$, and $pp$ collisions
that has not clearly been made in previous literature, namely, that the
hemisphere soft functions that appear in event shape distributions in
$e^+e^-\to$ dijets, deep inelastic scattering (DIS), and in Drell-Yan (DY)
processes are equal in perturbation theory up to $\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^2)$,
even though individual amplitudes may have opposite sign imaginary parts due to
changing complex pole prescriptions in eikonal propagators for incoming vs.
outgoing lines. We also explore potential generalizations of this observation
to soft functions for other observables or with more jets in the final state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06728</id><created>2015-04-25</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faure</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weich</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic spectral gap for open partially expanding maps</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP nlin.CD</categories><comments>51 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a $\mathbb{R}$-extension of one dimensional uniformly expanding
open dynamical systems and prove a new explicit estimate for the asymptotic
spectral gap. To get these results, we use a new application of a &quot;global
normal form&quot; for the dynamical system, a &quot;semiclassical expression beyond the
Ehrenfest time&quot; that expresses the transfer operator at large time as a sum
over rank one operators (each is associated to one orbit). In this paper we
establish the validity of the so-called &quot;diagonal approximation&quot; up to twice
the local Ehrenfest time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05606</id><created>2015-06-18</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Suri</keyname><forenames>Dhavala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Hall Effect measurement techniques</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Rudimentary review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin Hall Effect is relativistic quantum mechanical effect which enables
non-magnetic materials show magnetic phenomena without the application of a
magnetic field. With spin Hall Effect, one can realize spintronics devices
operating purely on electrical and optical means and eliminate the use of
ferromagnets which have associated fringe fields. In this review article, we
present the experimental developments and current understanding of the Spin
Hall Effect Phenomena. We discuss various experiments as well as device
structures which employ electrical, optical or both techniques to demonstrate
Spin Hall effect. Most of these devices structures are simple and easy to
fabricate in modern laboratories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00775</id><created>2015-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Oveshnikov</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulbachinskii</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aronzon</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozhansky</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avkeriev</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kugel</keyname><forenames>K. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tripathi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Hall effect in a 2D magnetic semiconductor hetereostructure:
  Evidence of Berry phase effects in the hopping-transport regime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, Revtex4</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 5, Article number: 17158 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep17158</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The temperature and magnetic field dependences of the anomalous Hall effect
(AHE) are studied in Mn delta-doped semiconductor heterostructures with a
two-dimensional hole gas in a quantum well interacting with the Mn layer. The
analysis of experimental data reveals four distinct temperature ranges
differing in the behavior of AHE. The Mn layer induces an inhomogeneity of the
hole gas leading to an interplay between the hopping and drift conductivities.
It is shown that at sufficiently low temperatures, hopping conductivity favors
the mechanisms of AHE related to the geometric (Berry-Pancharatnam) phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06497</id><created>2015-10-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Arbuzov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopylova</keyname><forenames>T. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On higher order radiative corrections to elastic electron-proton
  scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C75, no.12, 603 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3833-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  QED radiative corrections to elastic electron-proton scattering at low
energies are discussed. Corrections to the electron line and effects due to
vacuum polarization are computed. Higher order effects are estimated for the
conditions of the experiment on the electric and magnetic proton form factors
by A1 Collaboration. Calculations are performed within the next-to-leading
approximation. Inclusion of the higher order effects can affect the value of
the proton charge radius extracted from the experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03396</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-04-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arbuzov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherny</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirilo-Lombardo</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazmitdinov</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Nguyen Suan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pervushin</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakharov</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Von Neumann's Quantization of General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, updated version with extended discussion</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Atom. Nucl. 80, no.3, 491-504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S106377881702003X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Von Neumann's procedure is applied for quantization of General Relativity. We
quantize the initial data of dynamical variables at the Planck epoch, where the
Hubble parameter coincides with the Planck mass. These initial data are defined
via the Fock simplex in the tangent Minkowskian space-time and the Dirac
conformal interval. The Einstein cosmological principle is applied for the
average of the spatial metric determinant logarithm over the spatial volume of
the visible Universe. We derive the splitting of the general coordinate
transformations into the diffeomorphisms (as the object of the second N\&quot;other
theorem) and the initial data transformations (as objects of the first N\&quot;other
theorem). Following von Neumann, we suppose that the vacuum state is a quantum
ensemble. The vacuum state is degenerated with respect to quantum numbers of
non-vacuum states with the distribution function that yields the Casimir effect
in gravidynamics in analogy to the one in electrodynamics. The generation
functional of the perturbation theory in gravidynamics is given as a solution
of the quantum energy constraint. We discuss the region of applicability of
gravidynamics and its possible predictions for explanation of the modern
observational and experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02153</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ying-Hai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Jainendra K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Abelian Parton Fractional Quantum Hall Effect in Multilayer Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 17, 4643 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The current proposals for producing non-Abelian anyons and Majorana
particles, which are neither fermions nor bosons, are primarily based on the
realization of topological superconductivity in two dimensions. We show
theoretically that the unique Landau level structure of bilayer graphene
provides a new possible avenue for achieving such exotic particles.
Specifically, we demonstrate the feasibility of a &quot;parton&quot; fractional quantum
Hall (FQH) state, which supports non-Abelian particles without the usual
topological superconductivity. Furthermore, we advance this state as the
fundamental explanation of the puzzling $1/2$ FQH effect observed in bilayer
graphene [Kim {\em et al.}, Nano Lett. {\bf 15}, 7445 (2015)], and predict that
it will also occur in trilayer graphene. We indicate experimental signatures
that differentiate the parton state from other candidate non-Abelian FQH states
and predict that a transverse electric field can induce a topological quantum
phase transition between two distinct non-Abelian FQH states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00489</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Tirthankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Abhik</forenames></author></authors><title>Active hydrodynamics of synchronization and ordering in moving
  oscillators</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of emergent collective behaviors of moving physical agents
interacting with their neighborhood is a long-standing open issue in physical
and biological systems alike. This calls for studies on the control of
synchronization and the degree of order in a collection of diffusively moving
noisy oscillators. We address this by constructing a generic hydrodynamic
theory for active phase fluctuations in a collection of large number of nearly
phase-coherent moving oscillators in two dimensions. Our theory describes the
general situation where phase fluctuations and oscillator mobility mutually
affect each other. We show that the interplay between the active effects and
the mobility of the oscillators leads to a variety of phenomena, ranging from
synchronization with long range, nearly long range and quasi long range orders
to instabilities and desynchronization with short range order of the oscillator
phases. We highlight the complex dependences of synchronization on the active
effects. These should be testable in wide ranging systems, e.g., oscillating
chemical reactions in the presence of different reaction
inhibitors/facilitators, live oriented cytoskeletal extracts, or vertebrate
segmentation clocks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03656</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03656</id><created>2016-06-11</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jize</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of dual fermion superconductivity in hole-doped cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2017) 90: 154</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-80233-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the discovery of the cuprate high-temperature superconductivity in
1986, a universal phase diagram has been constructed experimentally and
numerous theoretical models have been proposed. However, there remains no
consensus on the underlying physics thus far. Here, we theoretically
investigate the phase diagram of hole-doped cuprates based on an
itinerant-localized dual fermion model, with the charge carriers doped on the
oxygen sites and localized holes on the copper $d_{x^{2}-y^{2}}$ orbitals. We
analytically demonstrate that the puzzling anomalous normal state or the
strange metal could simply stem from a free Fermi gas of carriers bathing in
copper antiferromagnetic spin fluctuations. The short-range high-energy spin
excitations also act as the `magnetic glue' of carrier Cooper pairs and induce
$d$-wave superconductivity from the underdoped to overdoped regime, distinctly
diffrent from the conventional low-frequency magnetic fluctuation mechanism. We
further sketch out the characteristic dome-shaped critical temperature $T_c$
versus doping level. The emergence of the pseudogap is ascribed to the
localization of partial carriers coupled to the local copper moments or a
crossover from the strange metal to a nodal Kondo-like insulator. Our work
provides a consistent theoretical framework to understand the typical phase
diagram of hole-doped cuprates and paves a distinct way to the studies of both
non-Fermi liquid and unconventional superconductivity in strongly correlated
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08013</id><created>2016-06-26</created><updated>2017-08-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author></authors><title>Model for Topological Phononics and Phonon Diode</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Phys. Rev. B (accepted)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 064106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum anomalous Hall effect, an exotic topological state first
theoretically predicted by Haldane and recently experimentally observed, has
attracted enormous interest for low-power-consumption electronics. In this
work, we derived a Schr{\&quot;o}dinger-like equation of phonons, where
topology-related quantities, time reversal symmetry and its breaking can be
naturally introduced similar as for electrons. Furthermore, we proposed a
phononic analog of the Haldane model, which gives the novel quantum (anomalous)
Hall-like phonon states characterized by one-way gapless edge modes immune to
scattering. The topologically nontrivial phonon states are useful not only for
conducting phonons without dissipation but also for designing highly efficient
phononic devices, like an ideal phonon diode, which could find important
applications in future phononics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00734</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00734</id><created>2016-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Bo-Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>Insights into Phase Transitions and Entanglement from Density Functional
  Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics, 18, 113035 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/11/113035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density functional theory has made great success in solid state physics,
quantum chemistry and in computational material sciences. In this work we show
that density functional theory could shed light on phase transitions and
entanglement at finite temperatures. Specifically, we show that the equilibrium
state of an interacting quantum many-body system which is in thermal
equilibrium with a heat bath at a fixed temperature is a universal functional
of the first derivatives of the free energy with respect to temperature and
other control parameters respectively. This insight from density functional
theory enables us to express the average value of any physical observable and
any entanglement measure as a universal functional of the first derivatives of
the free energy with respect to temperature and other control parameters. Since
phase transitions are marked by the nonanalytic behavior of free energy with
respect to control parameters, the physical quantities and entanglement
measures may present nonanalytic behavior at critical point inherited from
their dependence on the first derivative of free energy. We use an
experimentally realizable model to demonstrate the idea. These results give new
insights for phase transitions and provide new profound connections between
entanglement and phase transition in interacting quantum many-body physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01464</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abu-Ajamieh</keyname><forenames>Fayez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houtz</keyname><forenames>Rachel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of Bulk Scalar Singlets in the Randall Sundrum Model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Int.J.Mod.Phys. A32, no.18, 1750113 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17501135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Randall-Sundrum toy model with an added scalar singlet that
couples only to KK fermions in the bulk. Such a scalar would nontrivially
affect radion phenomenology. In addition, we examine the radion phenomenology
in light of the new scalar and show how this scalar could present another probe
to search for the radion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07169</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>A Topological Representation for Taking Cities as a Coherent Whole</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures, and 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A city is a whole, as are all cities in a country. Within a whole, individual
cities possess different degrees of wholeness, defined by Christopher Alexander
as a life-giving order or simply a living structure. To characterize the
wholeness and in particular to advocate for wholeness as an effective design
principle, this paper develops a geographic representation that views cities as
a whole. This geographic representation is topology-oriented, so fundamentally
differs from existing geometry-based geographic representations. With the
topological representation, all cities are abstracted as individual points and
put into different hierarchical levels, according to their sizes and based on
head/tail breaks - a classification scheme and visualization tool for data with
a heavy tailed distribution. These points of different hierarchical levels are
respectively used to create Thiessen polygons. Based on polygon-polygon
relationships, we set up a complex network. In this network, small polygons
point to adjacent large polygons at the same hierarchical level and contained
polygons point to containing polygons across two consecutive hierarchical
levels. We computed the degrees of wholeness for individual cities, and
subsequently found that the degrees of wholeness possess both properties of
differentiation and adaptation. To demonstrate, we developed four case studies
of all China and UK natural cities, as well as Beijing and London natural
cities, using massive amounts of street nodes and Tweet locations. The
topological representation and the kind of topological analysis in general can
be applied to any design or pattern, such as carpets, Baroque architecture and
artifacts, and fractals in order to assess their beauty, echoing the
introductory quote from Christopher Alexander.
  Keywords: Wholeness, natural cities, head/tail breaks, complex networks,
scaling hierarchy, urban design
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01090</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Genqian</forenames></author></authors><title>Uniqueness in inverse elastic scattering with one incident wave</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1606.06529</comments><msc-class>74J20, 74J25 (Primary), 75Q74, 35R30 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we give a positive answer to a longstanding open problem for
determining the shape of an obstacle from the knowledge of the far field
pattern for the scattering of time-harmonic elastic wave. We show that the
elastic far field pattern by an incoming plane wave with a fixed frequency, a
fixed incident direction and a fixed polarization determines the obstacle $D$
and the boundary condition on $\partial D$ uniquely. The boundary condition on
$\partial D$ is either the Dirichlet, or the Neumann, or the Robin one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02540</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jihn E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity wave and model-independent axion</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages of TeX file</comments><journal-ref>J. Korean Phys. Soc. 71, 127 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3938/jkps.71.127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this short comment, we notice that the model-independent axion
contribution to the graviton mass at just outside the Schwarzschild radius is
completely negligible in GW150914. The model-independent axion contribution to
the graviton mass at the order $10^{-22}\,$eV might be possible for merger of
black holes of mass of order $2\times 10^{14}\,$kg.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01397</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kay</keyname><forenames>Alastair</forenames></author></authors><title>Tailoring Spin Chain Dynamics for Fractional Revivals</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>v3: 11 pages, 8 figures. Accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Quantum 1, 24 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-08-10-24</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The production of quantum states required for use in quantum protocols &amp;
technologies is studied by developing the tools to re-engineer a perfect state
transfer spin chain so that a separable input excitation is output over
multiple sites. We concentrate in particular on cases where the excitation is
superposed over a small subset of the qubits on the spin chain, known as
fractional revivals, demonstrating that spin chains are capable of producing a
far greater range of fractional revivals than previously known, at high speed.
We also provide a numerical technique for generating chains that produce
arbitrary single-excitation states, such as the W state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02229</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yepez</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum lattice gas model of spin-2 Bose-Einstein condensates and
  closed-form analytical continuation of nonlinear interactions in spin-2
  superfluids</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Version of the quantum lattice gas algorithm with an added
  spin-singlet density interaction, a more complete description of the quantum
  algorithm, and with a title update</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Presented is an unitary operator splitting method for handling the
spin-density interaction in spinor Bose-Einstein condensates. The zero
temperature behavior of a spinor BEC is given by mean field theory, where the
Hamiltonian includes a nonlinear hyperfine spin interaction. This hyperfine
interaction has a diagonal probability-density term (leading to the usual
Gross-Pitaevskii type equation of motion) but also has a nondiagonal
spin-density term. Since the F=2 spinor BEC (spin-2 BEC) has a non-Abelian
superfluid phase (nonperturbative cyclic phase in the strong spin-density
coupling regime), an infinite-order expansion of the quantum evolution operator
is needed for quantum simulation applications. An infinite-order expansion,
obtained by analytical continuation and expressed in analytically closed form,
for the spin-2 BEC is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00099</id><created>2016-10-01</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parshall</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pintschovius</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellan</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;tt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reznik</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-momentum nematic fluctuations soften phonons in the
  superconducting state of Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Co$_x$)$_2$As$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nematic order is ubiquitous in liquid crystals and is characterized by a
rotational symmetry breaking in an otherwise uniform liquid. Recently a similar
phenomenon has been observed in some electronic phases of quantum materials
related to high temperature superconductivity, particularly in the Fe-based
superconductors. While several experiments have probed nematic fluctuations,
they have been primarily restricted to the uniform nematic susceptibility, i.e.
q = 0 fluctuations. Here, we investigate the behavior of finite-momentum
nematic fluctuations by measuring transverse acoustic phonon modes with
wavelengths of up to 25 unit cells in the prototypical Fe-based compound
Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Co$_x$)$_2$As$_2$. While the slope of the phonon dispersion gives
information about the uniform nematic susceptibility, deviations from this
linear behavior at finite but small wave-vectors are attributed to
finite-momentum nematic fluctuations. Surprisingly, these non-zero q
fluctuations lead to a softening of the phonon mode below the superconducting
transition temperature, in contrast to the behavior of the phonon velocity at q
= 0, which increases below $T_c$. Our work not only establishes a sound method
to probe long wavelength nematic fluctuations, but also sheds light on the
unique interplay between nematicity and superconductivity in Fe-based
compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02144</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Apertet</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouerdane</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Small-signal model for frequency analysis of thermoelectric systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Energy Conversion and Management vol. 149, 564 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.enconman.2017.07.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how small-signal analysis, a standard method in electrical
engineering, may be applied to thermoelectric device performance measurement by
extending a dc model to the dynamical regime. We thus provide a physical ground
to \textit{ad-hoc} models used to interpret impedance spectroscopy of
thermoelectric elements from an electrical circuit equivalent for
thermoelectric systems in the frequency domain. We particularly stress the
importance of the finite thermal impedance of the thermal contacts between the
thermoelectric system and the thermal reservoirs in the derivation of such
models. The expression for the characteristic angular frequency of the
thermoelectric system we obtain is a generalization of the expressions derived
in previous studies. In particular, it allows to envisage impedance
spectroscopy measurements beyond the restrictive case of adiabatic boundary
conditions often difficult to achieve experimentally, and hence \emph{in-situ}
characterization of thermoelectric generators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03062</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fahey</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheirandish</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandenbroucke</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Donglian</forenames></author></authors><title>A search for neutrinos from fast radio bursts with IceCube</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>v2: updated to match version published in ApJ (now with discussion of
  long term outlook and comparison to diffuse astrophysical neutrino flux)</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 845 (2017) 1, 14</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7e28</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a search for neutrinos in coincidence in time and direction with
four fast radio bursts (FRBs) detected by the Parkes and Green Bank radio
telescopes during the first year of operation of the complete IceCube Neutrino
Observatory (May 2011 through May 2012). The neutrino sample consists of
138,322 muon neutrino candidate events, which are dominated by atmospheric
neutrinos and muons but also contain an astrophysical neutrino component.
Considering only neutrinos detected on the same day as each FRB, zero IceCube
events were found to be compatible with the FRB directions within the estimated
99\% error radius of the neutrino directions. Based on the non-detection, we
present the first upper limits on the neutrino fluence from fast radio bursts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01239</id><created>2016-12-04</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ishioka</keyname><forenames>Kunie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rustagi</keyname><forenames>Avinash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beyer</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolz</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volz</keyname><forenames>Kerstin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoefer</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petek</keyname><forenames>Hrvoje</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanton</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-picosecond acoustic pulses at buried GaP/Si interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 111, 062105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4997913</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the optical generation and detection of ultrashort acoustic
pulses that propagate in three-dimensional semiconductor crystals.
Photoexcitaiton of lattice-matched GaP layers grown on Si(001) gives rise to a
sharp spike in transient reflectivity due to the acoustic pulse generated at
the GaP/Si interface and detected at the GaP surface and vice versa. The
extremely short width of the reflectivity spike, 0.5 ps, would translate to a
spatial extent of 3 nm or 10 atomic bilayers, which is comparable with the
width of the intermixing layer at the GaP/Si interface. The reflectivity
signals are also modified by quasi-periodic Brillouin oscillations of GaP and
Si arising from the acoustic pulses during the propagation in the crystals. The
present results demonstrate the potential application of the simple optical
pump-probe scheme in the nondestructive evaluation of the buried semiconductor
interface quality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02436</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rychkov</keyname><forenames>Slava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simmons-Duffin</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zan</keyname><forenames>Bernardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-gaussianity of the critical 3d Ising model</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures; v2: refs added; v3: refs updated, published
  version; v4: acknowledgement added</comments><report-no>CERN PH-TH/2016-249</report-no><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 2, 001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.2.1.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the 4pt function of the critical 3d Ising model, extracted from
recent conformal bootstrap results. We focus on the non-gaussianity Q - the
ratio of the 4pt function to its gaussian part given by three Wick
contractions. This ratio reveals significant non-gaussianity of the critical
fluctuations. The bootstrap results are consistent with a rigorous inequality
due to Lebowitz and Aizenman, which limits Q to lie between 1/3 and 1.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03149</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Sangwoo S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolech</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple phase separation in one-dimensional mixtures of mass- and
  population-imbalanced attractive Fermi gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023609 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023609</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the attractive Fermi mixture of a
${}^{6}\mathrm{Li}$-${}^{40}\mathrm{K}$ gas in one dimension using the
continuous matrix product states variational ansatz and obtain the $T=0$ phase
diagram. We predict an axial density profile that contains four distinct phases
trapped induced along one-dimensional (1D) tubes, which is more intricate than
those observed in 1D mass-balanced systems or in higher-dimensional gas clouds.
The parameter regimes explored are realistic in view of possible future
experiments. This an application of continuous matrix product states to a
nonintegrable fermionic system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07701</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carracedo</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mas</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musso</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serantes</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Adiabatic pumping solutions in global AdS</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>23+12 pages, 12 figures. Version published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1705 (2017) 141</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a family of very simple stationary solutions to gravity coupled
to a massless scalar field in global AdS. They involve a constantly rising
source for the scalar field at the boundary and thereby we name them pumping
solutions. We construct them numerically in $D=4$. They are regular and,
generically, have negative mass. We perform a study of linear and nonlinear
stability and find both stable and unstable branches. In the latter case,
solutions belonging to different sub-branches can either decay to black holes
or to limiting cycles. This observation motivates the search for non-stationary
exactly time-periodic solutions which we actually construct. We clarify the
role of pumping solutions in the context of quasistatic adiabatic quenches. In
$D=3$ the pumping solutions can be related to other previously known solutions,
like magnetic or translationally-breaking backgrounds. From this we derive an
analytic expression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04524</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-08-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Ke-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Jing-Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Xin-Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of charmed and bottom baryons with hyperfine interaction</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><report-no>1701.04524</report-no><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C Vol. 41, No. 9, 093103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/9/093103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Up to now, the excited charmed and bottom baryon states are still not well
studied both experimentally and theoretically. In the present paper, we predict
the mass of $\Omega_b^*$, the only $L = 0$ baryon state which has not been
observed, to be 6069.2 MeV. The spectra of charmed and bottom baryons with the
orbital angular momentum $L = 1$ are studied in two popular constituent quark
models, the Goldstone boson exchange (GBE) and the one gluon exchange (OGE)
hyperfine interaction models, respectively. Inserting the latest experimental
data from the &quot;Review of Particle Physics&quot;, we find that in the GBE model,
there exist some multiplets ($\Sigma_{c(b)}$, $\Xi'_{c(b)}$ and
$\Omega_{c(b)}$) which total spins of three quarks in their lowest energy
states are 3/2, but in the OGE model there is no such phenomenon. This is the
most important difference between the GBE and OGE models. These results can be
tested in the near future. We suggest more efforts to study the excited charmed
and bottom baryons both theoretically and experimentally, not only for the
abundance of baryon spectra, but also for determining which hyperfine
interaction model is realized in nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00012</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>ChunJun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhitnitsky</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion detection via Topological Casimir Effect</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Updated to published version</comments><report-no>CALT-TH 2017-007</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 015013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.015013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new table-top experimental configuration for the direct
detection of dark matter axions with mass in the $(10^{-6} \rm eV - 10^{-2} \rm
eV)$ range using non-perturbative effects in a system with non-trivial spatial
topology. Different from most experimental setups found in literature on direct
dark matter axion detection, which relies on $\dot{\theta}$ or
$\vec{\nabla}\theta$, we found that our system is in principle sensitive to a
static $\theta\geq 10^{-14}$ and can also be used to set limit on the
fundamental constant $\theta_{\rm QED}$ which becomes the fundamental
observable parameter of the Maxwell system if some conditions are met.
Connection with Witten effect when the induced electric charge $e'$ is
proportional to $\theta$ and the magnetic monopole becomes the dyon with
non-vanishing $e'=-e \frac{\theta}{2\pi}$ is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00893</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yong-Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zong</keyname><forenames>Hong-Shi</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric influences of a particle confined to a curved surface embedded
  in three-dimensional Euclidean space</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 022116 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.022116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the spirit of the thin-layer quantization approach, we give the formula of
the geometric influences of a particle confined to a curved surface embedded in
three-dimensional Euclidean space. The geometric contributions can result from
the reduced commutation relation between the acted function depending on normal
variable and the normal derivative. According to the formula, we obtain the
geometric potential, geometric momentum, geometric orbital angular momentum,
geometric linear Rashba and cubic Dresselhaus spin-orbit couplings. As an
example, a truncated cone surface is considered. We find that the geometric
orbital angular momentum can provide an azimuthal polarization for spin, and
the sign of the geometric Dresselhaus spin-orbit coupling can be flipped
through the inclination angle of generatrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01453</id><created>2017-02-05</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Taira</keyname><forenames>Kunihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunton</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>Scott T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowley</keyname><forenames>Clarence W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colonius</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKeon</keyname><forenames>Beverley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Oliver T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordeyev</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theofilis</keyname><forenames>Vassilios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ukeiley</keyname><forenames>Lawrence S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modal Analysis of Fluid Flows: An Overview</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>43 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simple aerodynamic configurations under even modest conditions can exhibit
complex flows with a wide range of temporal and spatial features. It has become
common practice in the analysis of these flows to look for and extract
physically important features, or modes, as a first step in the analysis. This
step typically starts with a modal decomposition of an experimental or
numerical dataset of the flow field, or of an operator relevant to the system.
We describe herein some of the dominant techniques for accomplishing these
modal decompositions and analyses that have seen a surge of activity in recent
decades. For a non-expert, keeping track of recent developments can be
daunting, and the intent of this document is to provide an introduction to
modal analysis that is accessible to the larger fluid dynamics community. In
particular, we present a brief overview of several of the well-established
techniques and clearly lay the framework of these methods using familiar linear
algebra. The modal analysis techniques covered in this paper include the proper
orthogonal decomposition (POD), balanced proper orthogonal decomposition
(Balanced POD), dynamic mode decomposition (DMD), Koopman analysis, global
linear stability analysis, and resolvent analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02546</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torii</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asaoka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Decaying Fermionic Dark Matter Search with CALET</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>For better comprehensibility of CALET sensitivity study an appendix
  is added in this version which contains the results of the numerical
  calculations (section 2 before) and comparison of parametrization and
  numerical calculation (section 5.3 before). Secondary gamma-ray flux from the
  interaction of DM decay products and ISRF are calculated and results are
  shown in figure 3 for 1 TeV DM</comments><journal-ref>JCAP08(2017)012</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/08/012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ISS-based CALET (CALorimetric Electron Telescope) detector can play an
important role in indirect search for Dark Matter (DM), measuring the
electron+positron flux in the TeV region for the first time directly. With its
fine energy resolution of approximately $2\%$ and good proton rejection ratio
($1:10^5$) it has the potential to search for fine structures in the Cosmic Ray
(CR) electron spectrum. In this context we discuss the ability of CALET to
discern between signals originating from astrophysical sources and DM decay or
annihilation. We fit a parametrization of the local interstellar electron and
positron spectra to current measurements, with either a pulsar or 3-body decay
of fermionic DM as the extra source causing the positron excess. The expected
CALET data for scenarios in which DM decay explains the excess are calculated
and analyzed. The signal from this particular 3-body DM decay which can explain
the recent measurements of from the AMS$-02$ experiment is shown to be
distinguishable from a single pulsar source causing the positron excess by 5
years of observation with CALET, based on the shape of the spectrum. We also
study the constraints from extra-galactic diffuse $\gamma$-ray data on this
DM-only explanation of the positron excess and show that especially for the
possibly remaining parameter space a clearly identifiable signature in the CR
electron spectrum exists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04361</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prem</keyname><forenames>Abhinav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moroz</keyname><forenames>Sergej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurarie</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radzihovsky</keyname><forenames>Leo</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiply quantized vortices in fermionic superfluids: angular momentum,
  unpaired fermions, and spectral asymmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages + 11 pages supplemental material. Close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 067003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.067003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the orbital angular momentum $L_z$ of an s-wave paired superfluid
in the presence of an axisymmetric multiply quantized vortex. For vortices with
winding number $|k| &gt; 1$, we find that in the weak-pairing BCS regime $L_z$ is
significantly reduced from its value $\hbar N k/2$ in the Bose-Einstein
condensation (BEC) regime, where $N$ is the total number of fermions. This
deviation results from the presence of unpaired fermions in the BCS ground
state, which arise as a consequence of spectral flow along the vortex sub-gap
states. We support our results analytically and numerically by solving the
Bogoliubov-de-Gennes equations within the weak-pairing BCS regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04914</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valchev</keyname><forenames>Galin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dantchev</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Sign change in the net force in sphere-plate and sphere-sphere systems
  immersed in nonpolar critical fluid due to the interplay between the critical
  Casimir and dispersion van der Waals forces</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures, some misprints are corrected. arXiv admin note:
  text overlap with arXiv:1506.03272</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study systems in which both long-ranged van der Waals and critical Casimir
interactions are present. We study the interplay between these forces, as well
as the {\it total} force (TF) between a spherical colloid particle and a thick
planar slab, and between two spherical colloid particles. We do that using
general scaling arguments and mean-field type calculations utilizing the
Derjaguin and the surface integration approaches. They both are based on data
of the forces between two parallel slabs separated at a distance $L$ from each
other, confining the fluctuating fluid medium characterized by its temperature
$T$ and chemical potential $\mu$. The surfaces of the colloid particles and the
slab are coated by thin layers exerting strong preference to the liquid phase
of the fluid, or one of the components of the mixture, modeled by strong
adsorbing local surface potentials, ensuring the so-called $(+,+)$ boundary
conditions. On the other hand, the core region of the slab and the particles,
influence the fluid by long-ranged competing dispersion potentials. We
demonstrate that for a suitable set of colloids-fluid, slab-fluid, and
fluid-fluid coupling parameters the competition between the effects due to the
coatings and the core regions of the objects involved result, when one changes
$T$, $\mu$ or $L$, in {\it sign change} of the Casimir force (CF) {\it and} the
TF acting between the colloid and the slab, as well as between the colloids.
This can be used for governing the behavior of objects, say colloidal
particles, at small distances, say in colloid suspensions for preventing
flocculation. It can also provide a strategy for solving problems with
handling, feeding, trapping and fixing of microparts in nanotechnology. Data
for specific substances in support of the experimental feasibility of the
theoretically predicted behavior of the CF and TF have been also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04041</id><created>2017-03-11</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reinosa</keyname><forenames>Urko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serreau</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tissier</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wschebor</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xe1;s</forenames></author></authors><title>How nonperturbative is the infrared regime of Landau gauge Yang-Mills
  correlators?</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat</categories><comments>20 pages, 13 figures, published version (PRD)</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.014005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Landau gauge correlators of Yang-Mills fields for infrared
Euclidean momenta in the context of a massive extension of the Faddeev-Popov
Lagrangian which, we argue, underlies a variety of continuum approaches.
Standard (perturbative) renormalization group techniques with a specific,
infrared-safe renormalization scheme produce so-called decoupling and scaling
solutions for the ghost and gluon propagators, which correspond to nontrivial
infrared fixed points. The decoupling fixed point is infrared stable and weakly
coupled, while the scaling fixed point is unstable and generically strongly
coupled except for low dimensions $d\to2$. Under the assumption that such a
scaling fixed point exists beyond one-loop order, we find that the
corresponding ghost and gluon scaling exponents are, respectively,
$2\alpha_F=2-d$ and $2\alpha_G=d$ at all orders of perturbation theory in the
present renormalization scheme. We discuss the relation between the ghost wave
function renormalization, the gluon screening mass, the scale of spectral
positivity violation, and the gluon mass parameter. We also show that this
scaling solution does not realize the standard Becchi-Rouet-Stora-Tyutin
symmetry of the Faddeev-Popov Lagrangian. Finally, we discuss our findings in
relation to the results of nonperturbative continuum methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05368</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kandel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarian</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pogosyan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of dust absorption on spectroscopic studies of turbulence</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS, minor changes to match the published version</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 470, 3103-3123 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1358</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of dust absorption on the recovery velocity and density
spectra as well as on the anisotropies of magnetohydrodynamic turbulence using
the Velocity Channel Analysis (VCA), Velocity Coordinate Spectrum (VCS) and
Velocity Centroids. The dust limits volume up to an optical depth of unity. We
show that in the case of the emissivity proportional to the density of
emitters, the effects of random density get suppressed for strong dust
absorption intensity variations arise from the velocity fluctuations only.
However, for the emissivity proportional to squared density, both density and
velocity fluctuations affect the observed intensities. We predict a new
asymptotic regime for the spectrum of fluctuations for large scales exceeding
the physical depths to unit optical depth. The spectrum gets shallower by unity
in this regime. In addition, the dust absorption removes the degeneracy
resulted in the universal $K^{-3}$ spectrum of intensity fluctuations of
self-absorbing medium reported by Lazarian \&amp; Pogosyan. We show that the
predicted result is consistent with the available HII region emission data. We
find that for sub-Alfv\'enic and trans-Alfv\'enic turbulence one can get the
information about both the magnetic field direction and the fundamental
Alfv\'en, fast and slow modes that constitute MHD turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05563</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anselmi</keyname><forenames>Damiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piva</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbative unitarity of Lee-Wick quantum field theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>30 pages, 15 figures; v2: more details and comments on generality of
  approach; v3: minor changes, PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 045009 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.045009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the perturbative unitarity of the Lee-Wick models, formulated as
nonanalytically Wick rotated Euclidean theories. The complex energy plane is
divided into disconnected regions and the values of a loop integral in the
various regions are related to one another by a nonanalytic procedure. We show
that the one-loop diagrams satisfy the expected, unitary cutting equations in
each region: only the physical degrees of freedom propagate through the cuts.
The goal can be achieved by working in suitable subsets of each region and
proving that the cutting equations can be analytically continued as a whole. We
make explicit calculations in the cases of the bubble and triangle diagrams and
address the generality of our approach. We also show that the same
higher-derivative models violate unitarity if they are formulated directly in
Minkowski spacetime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10178</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>El-Menoufi</keyname><forenames>Basem Kamal</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum gravity effects on the thermodynamic stability of 4D
  Schwarzschild black hole</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in JHEP; 20 pages, 4 figures, few minor
  typos corrected and references updated</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the Euclidean approach, we consider the effects of quantum gravity
and mass-less matter on the thermodynamic properties of Schwarzschild black
hole. The techniques of effective field theory are utilized to analytically
construct the partition function at the one-loop level. Using the non-local
heat kernel formalism, the partition function is expressed as a curvature
expansion. We extensively discuss the effect of the corrections on the
thermodynamic stability. The one-loop free energy shows, remarkably, that a
large number of gauge fields is able to render Schwarzschild black hole
thermodynamically stable. The black hole mass at which stability is achieved
scales as $\sqrt{N}$ in Planck units, where $N$ is the number of gauge fields,
and is independent of any UV completion of quantum gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02616</id><created>2017-04-09</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bighin</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemeshko</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Diagrammatic approach to orbital quantum impurities interacting with a
  many-particle environment</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 085410 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.085410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently it was shown that an impurity exchanging orbital angular momentum
with a surrounding bath can be described in terms of the angulon quasiparticle
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 095301 (2017)]. The angulon consists of a quantum rotor
dressed by a many-particle field of boson excitations, and can be formed out
of, for example, a molecule or a nonspherical atom in superfluid helium, or out
of an electron coupled to lattice phonons or a Bose condensate. Here we develop
an approach to the angulon based on the path-integral formalism, which sets the
ground for a systematic, perturbative treatment of the angulon problem. The
resulting perturbation series can be interpreted in terms of Feynman diagrams,
from which, in turn, one can derive a set of diagrammatic rules. These rules
extend the machinery of the graphical theory of angular momentum - well known
from theoretical atomic spectroscopy - to the case where an environment with an
infinite number of degrees of freedom is present. In particular, we show that
each diagram can be interpreted as a 'skeleton', which enforces angular
momentum conservation, dressed by an additional many-body contribution. This
connection between the angulon theory and the graphical theory of angular
momentum is particularly important as it allows to systematically and
substantially simplify the analytical representation of each diagram. In order
to exemplify the technique, we calculate the 1- and 2-loop contributions to the
angulon self-energy, the spectral function, and the quasiparticle weight. The
diagrammatic theory we develop paves the way to investigate next-to-leading
order quantities in a more compact way compared to the variational approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04294</id><created>2017-04-13</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Curran</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A possible connection between the spin temperature of damped Lyman-alpha
  absorption systems and star formation history</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx933</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comprehensive analysis of the spin temperature/covering factor
degeneracy, T/f, in damped Lyman-alpha absorption systems. By normalising the
upper limits and including these via a survival analysis, there is, as
previously claimed, an apparent increase in T/f with redshift at z &gt; 1.
However, when we account for the geometry effects of an expanding Universe,
neglected by the previous studies, this increase in T/f at z &gt; 1 is preceded by
a decrease at z &lt; 1. Using high resolution radio images of the background
continuum sources, we can transform the T/f degeneracy to T/d^2, where d is the
projected linear size of the absorber. Again, there is no overall increase with
redshift, although a dip at z ~ 2 persists. Furthermore, we find d^2/T to
follow a similar variation with redshift as the star formation rate. This
suggests that, although the total hydrogen column density shows little relation
to the SFR, the fraction of the cold neutral medium may. Therefore, further
efforts to link the neutral gas with the star formation history should also
consider the cool component of the gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06573</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-06-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiba</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>Shuichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Distribution of Primordial Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures, references added, version to appear in PTEP</comments><report-no>RUP-17-5</report-no><journal-ref>PTEP 2017 8, 083E01 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We estimate the spin distribution of primordial black holes based on the
recent study of the critical phenomena in the gravitational collapse of a
rotating radiation fluid. We find that primordial black holes are mostly slowly
rotating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06805</id><created>2017-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Allan</keyname><forenames>Milan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Mark H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostojic</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andringa</keyname><forenames>Arjo</forenames></author></authors><title>Creating better superconductors by periodic nanopatterning</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.2.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quest to create superconductors with higher transition temperatures is as
old as superconductivity itself. One strategy, popular after the realization
that (conventional) superconductivity is mediated by phonons, is to chemically
combine different elements within the crystalline unit cell to maximize the
electron-phonon coupling. This led to the discovery of NbTi and Nb3Sn, to name
just the most technologically relevant examples. Here, we propose a radically
different approach to transform a `pristine' material into a better (meta-)
superconductor by making use of modern fabrication techniques: designing and
engineering the electronic properties of thin films via periodic patterning on
the nanoscale. We present a model calculation to explore the key effects of
different supercells that could be fabricated using nanofabrication or
deliberate lattice mismatch, and demonstrate that specific pattern will enhance
the coupling and the transition temperature. We also discuss how numerical
methods could predict the correct design parameters to improve
superconductivity in materials including Al, NbTi, and MgB2
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08415</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Weixuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Liming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shengfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zexi</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDowell</keyname><forenames>David L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Youping</forenames></author></authors><title>Ballistic-diffusive Phonon Heat Transport across Grain Boundaries</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Acta Materialia 136, 355-365 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.06.054</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The propagation of a heat pulse in a single crystal and across grain
boundaries (GBs) is simulated using a concurrent atomistic-continuum method
furnished with a coherent phonon pulse model. With a heat pulse constructed
based on a Bose-Einstein distribution of phonons, this work has reproduced the
phenomenon of phonon focusing in single and polycrystalline materials.
Simulation results provide visual evidence that the propagation of a heat pulse
in crystalline solids with or without GBs is partially ballistic and partially
diffusive, i.e., there is a co-existence of ballistic and diffusive thermal
transport, with the long-wavelength phonons traveling ballistically while the
short-wavelength phonons scatter with each other and travel diffusively. To
gain a quantitative understanding of GB thermal resistance, the kinetic energy
transmitted across GBs is monitored on the fly and the time-dependent energy
transmission for each specimen is measured; the contributions of coherent and
incoherent phonon transport to the energy transmission are estimated.
Simulation results reveal that the presence of GBs modifies the nature of
thermal transport, with the coherent long-wavelength phonons dominating the
heat conduction in materials with GBs. In addition, it is found the phonon-GB
interaction can result in the reconstruction of the GBs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08648</id><created>2017-04-27</created><updated>2017-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Itoyama</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ward identities and combinatorics of rainbow tensor models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>48 pages</comments><report-no>FIAN/TD-07/17; IITP/TH-06/17; ITEP/TH-12/17; OCU-PHYS 464</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 2017 (2017) 1</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the notion of renormalization group (RG) completion of
non-Gaussian Lagrangians and its treatment within the framework of
Bogoliubov-Zimmermann theory in application to the matrix and tensor models.
With the example of the simplest non-trivial RGB tensor theory (Aristotelian
rainbow), we introduce a few methods, which allow one to connect calculations
in the tensor models to those in the matrix models. As a byproduct, we obtain
some new factorization formulas and sum rules for the Gaussian correlators in
the Hermitian and complex matrix theories, square and rectangular. These sum
rules describe correlators as solutions to finite linear systems, which are
much simpler than the bilinear Hirota equations and the infinite Virasoro
recursion. Search for such relations can be a way to solving the tensor models,
where an explicit integrability is still obscure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00976</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-06-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the complete perturbative solution of one-matrix models</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><report-no>FIAN/TD-08/17; IITP/TH-07/17; ITEP/TH-13/17</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 771 (2017) pp. 503-507</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.094</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We summarize the recent results about complete solvability of Hermitian and
rectangular complex matrix models. Partition functions have very simple
character expansions with coefficients made from dimensions of representation
of the linear group $GL(N)$, and arbitrary correlators in the Gaussian phase
are given by finite sums over Young diagrams of a given size, which involve
also the well known characters of symmetric group. The previously known
integrability and Virasoro constraints are simple corollaries, but no vice
versa: complete solvability is a peculiar property of the matrix model
(hypergeometric) $\tau$-functions, which is actually a combination of these two
complementary requirements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01357</id><created>2017-05-03</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Jiaxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rychkov</keyname><forenames>Slava</forenames></author></authors><title>Cut-touching linear functionals in the conformal bootstrap</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, v2: author order corrected, v3: full domain of
  4pt analyticity made more precise, v4: misprint corrected and acknowledgement
  added</comments><report-no>CERN PH-TH/2017-098</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)076</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The modern conformal bootstrap program often employs the method of linear
functionals to derive the numerical or analytical bounds on the CFT data. These
functionals must have a crucial &quot;swapping&quot; property, allowing to swap infinite
summation with the action of the functional in the conformal bootstrap sum
rule. Swapping is easy to justify for the popular functionals involving finite
sums of derivatives. However, it is far from obvious for &quot;cut-touching&quot;
functionals, involving integration over regions where conformal block
decomposition does not converge uniformly. Functionals of this type were
recently considered by Mazac in his work on analytic derivation of optimal
bootstrap bounds. We derive general swapping criteria for the cut-touching
functionals, and check in a few explicit examples that Mazac's functionals pass
our criteria.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02075</id><created>2017-05-04</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hen</keyname><forenames>Itay</forenames></author></authors><title>Solving Spin Glasses with Optimized Trees of Clustered Spins</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an algorithm for the optimization and thermal equilibration of
spin glasses - or more generally, cost functions of the Ising form
$H=\sum_{\langle i j\rangle} J_{ij} s_i s_j + \sum_i h_i s_i$, defined on
graphs with arbitrary connectivity. The algorithm consists of two repeated
steps: i) the optimized construction of a random tree of spin clusters on the
input problem graph, and ii) the thermal sampling of the generated tree. The
randomly generated trees are constructed so as to optimize a balance between
the size of the tree and the complexity required to draw Boltzmann samples from
it. We benchmark the algorithm on several classes of problems and demonstrate
its advantages over existing approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04259</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chua</keyname><forenames>Alvin J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gair</keyname><forenames>Jonathan R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Fast and the Fiducial: Augmented kludge waveforms for detecting
  extreme-mass-ratio inspirals</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 044005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.044005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extreme-mass-ratio inspirals (EMRIs) of stellar-mass compact objects into
massive black holes are an important class of source for the future space-based
gravitational-wave detector LISA. Detecting signals from EMRIs will require
waveform models that are both accurate and computationally efficient. In this
paper, we present the latest implementation of an augmented analytic kludge
(AAK) model, publicly available at github.com/alvincjk/EMRI_Kludge_Suite as
part of an EMRI waveform software suite. This version of the AAK model has
improved accuracy compared to its predecessors, with two-month waveform
overlaps against a more accurate fiducial model exceeding 0.97 for a generic
range of sources; it also generates waveforms 5-15 times faster than the
fiducial model. The AAK model is well suited for scoping out data analysis
issues in the upcoming round of mock LISA data challenges. A simple analytic
argument shows that it might even be viable for detecting EMRIs with LISA
through a semi-coherent template bank method, while the use of the original
analytic kludge in the same approach will result in around 90% fewer
detections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05296</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belozerov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katanin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anisimov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Momentum-dependent susceptibilities and magnetic exchange in bcc iron
  from supercell DMFT calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the momentum- and temperature dependences of the magnetic
susceptibilities and magnetic exchange interaction in paramagnetic bcc iron by
a combination of density functional theory and dynamical mean-field theory
(DFT+DMFT). By considering a general derivation of the orbital-resolved
effective model for spin degrees of freedom for Hund's metals, we relate
momentum-dependent susceptibilities in the paramagnetic phase to the magnetic
exchange. We then calculate non-uniform orbital-resolved susceptibilities at
high-symmetry wave vectors by constructing appropriate supercells in the DMFT
approach. Extracting the irreducible parts of susceptibilities with respect to
Hund's exchange interaction, we determine the corresponding orbital-resolved
exchange interactions, which are then interpolated to the whole Brillouin zone.
Using the spherical model we estimate the temperature dependence of the
resulting exchange between local moments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05351</id><created>2017-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Moritz</keyname><forenames>Clemens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tr&#xf6;ster</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dellago</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay of fast and slow dynamics in rare transition pathways: the
  disk-to-slab transition in the 2d Ising model</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 147, 152714 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4997479</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rare transitions between long-lived stable states are often analyzed in terms
of free energy landscapes computed as functions of a few collective variables.
Here, using transitions between geometric phases as example, we demonstrate
that the effective dynamics of a system along these variables are an essential
ingredient in the description of rare events and that the static perspective
provided by the free energy alone may be misleading. In particular, we
investigate the disk-to-slab transition in the two-dimensional Ising model
starting with a calculation of a two-dimensional free energy landscape and the
distribution of committor probabilities. While at first sight it appears that
the committor is incompatible with the free energy, they can be reconciled with
each other using a two-dimensional Smoluchowski equation that combines the free
energy landscape with state dependent diffusion coefficients. These results
illustrate that dynamical information is not only required to calculate rate
constants but that neglecting dynamics may also lead to an inaccurate
understanding of the mechanism of a given process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06399</id><created>2017-05-17</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Bo-Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Transverse charge densities of the deuteron in soft-wall AdS/QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 latex pages, 4 figures, final version for journal publication</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. A 968 (2017) 14-22</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2017.07.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the transverse charge densities of the deuteron in a soft-wall
AdS/QCD model by considering both the unpolarized and the transversely
polarized cases. The deuteron form factors are derived from the soft-wall
AdS/QCD model and it is shown that the calculated results agree with the
phenomenological parametrization and experimental data. The transverse charge
densities of the deuteron are also derived from the soft-wall AdS/QCD model,
and we notice slight deviations from those of the phenomenological
parametrization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06470</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-08-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piroli</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact dynamics following an interaction quench in a one-dimensional
  anyonic gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 7 figures; v2: minor revision and references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023611 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023611</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the nonequilibrium quench dynamics of a one-dimensional anyonic gas.
We focus on the integrable anyonic Lieb-Liniger model and consider the quench
from non-interacting to hard-core anyons. We study the dynamics of the local
properties of the system. By means of integrability-based methods we compute
analytically the one-body density matrix and the density-density correlation
function at all times after the quench and in particular at infinite time. Our
results show that the system evolves from an initial state where the local
momentum distribution function is non-symmetric to a steady state where it
becomes symmetric. Furthermore, while the initial momentum distribution
functions (and the equilibrium ones) explicitly depend on the anyonic
parameter, the final ones do not. This is reminiscent of the dynamical
fermionization observed in the context of free expansions after release from a
confining trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08456</id><created>2017-05-23</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rampf</keyname><forenames>Cornelius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frisch</keyname><forenames>Uriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Shell-crossing in quasi-one-dimensional flow</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages; received 2017 May 24, and accepted 2017 June 21 at MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 471, 671-679 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Blow-up of solutions for the cosmological fluid equations, often dubbed
shell-crossing or orbit crossing, denotes the breakdown of the single-stream
regime of the cold-dark-matter fluid. At this instant, the velocity becomes
multi-valued and the density singular. Shell-crossing is well understood in one
dimension (1D), but not in higher dimensions. This paper is about
quasi-one-dimensional (Q1D) flow that depends on all three coordinates but
differs only slightly from a strictly 1D flow, thereby allowing a perturbative
treatment of shell-crossing using the Euler--Poisson equations written in
Lagrangian coordinates. The signature of shell-crossing is then just the
vanishing of the Jacobian of the Lagrangian map, a regular perturbation
problem. In essence the problem of the first shell-crossing, which is highly
singular in Eulerian coordinates, has been desingularized by switching to
Lagrangian coordinates, and can then be handled by perturbation theory. Here,
all-order recursion relations are obtained for the time-Taylor coefficients of
the displacement field, and it is shown that the Taylor series has an infinite
radius of convergence. This allows the determination of the time and location
of the first shell-crossing, which is generically shown to be taking place
earlier than for the unperturbed 1D flow. The time variable used for these
statements is not the cosmic time $t$ but the linear growth time $\tau \sim
t^{2/3}$. For simplicity, calculations are restricted to an Einstein--de Sitter
universe in the Newtonian approximation, and tailored initial data are used.
However it is straightforward to relax these limitations, if needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10318</id><created>2017-05-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Woessner</keyname><forenames>Achim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parret</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydovskaya</keyname><forenames>Diana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Yuanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jhih-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundeberg</keyname><forenames>Mark B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanot</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillenbrand</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fogler</keyname><forenames>Michael M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hone</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koppens</keyname><forenames>Frank H. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical detection of hyperbolic phonon-polaritons in heterostructures
  of graphene and boron nitride</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>npj 2D Materials and Applications 1, 25 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41699-017-0031-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light properties in the mid-infrared can be controlled at a deep
subwavelength scale using hyperbolic phonons-polaritons (HPPs) of hexagonal
boron nitride (h-BN). While propagating as waveguided modes HPPs can
concentrate the electric field in a chosen nano-volume. Such a behavior is at
the heart of many applications including subdiffraction imaging and sensing.
Here, we employ HPPs in heterostructures of h-BN and graphene as new
nano-optoelectronic platform by uniting the benefits of efficient hot-carrier
photoconversion in graphene and the hyperbolic nature of h-BN. We demonstrate
electrical detection of HPPs by guiding them towards a graphene pn-junction. We
shine a laser beam onto a gap in metal gates underneath the heterostructure,
where the light is converted into HPPs. The HPPs then propagate as confined
rays heating up the graphene leading to a strong photocurrent. This concept is
exploited to boost the external responsivity of mid-infrared photodetectors,
overcoming the limitation of graphene pn-junction detectors due to their small
active area and weak absorption. Moreover this type of detector exhibits
tunable frequency selectivity due to the HPPs, which combined with its high
responsivity paves the way for efficient high-resolution mid-infrared imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06127</id><created>2017-06-19</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>P. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple Chirality in Nuclear Rotation: A Microscopic View</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 773 (2017) 1-5</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.08.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Covariant density functional theory and three-dimensional tilted axis
cranking are used to investigate multiple chirality in nuclear rotation for the
first time in a fully self-consistent and microscopic way. Two distinct sets of
chiral solutions with negative and positive parities, respectively, are found
in the nucleus 106Rh. The negative-parity solutions reproduce well the
corresponding experimental spectrum as well as the B(M1)/B(E2) ratios of the
transition strengths. This indicates that a predicted positive-parity chiral
band should also exist. Therefore, it provides a further strong hint that
multiple chirality is realized in nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07008</id><created>2017-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Khalack</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallant</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thibeault</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Project VeSElkA: Abundance analysis of chemical species in HD41076 and
  HD148330</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, 8 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><journal-ref>MNRAS, 471, 926 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1563</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new semi-automatic approach is employed to carry out the abundance analysis
of high-resolution spectra of HD41076 and HD148330 obtained recently with the
spectropolarimetre ESPaDOnS at the CFHT. This approach allows to prepare in a
semi-automatic mode the input data for the modified ZEEMAN2 code and to analyse
several hundreds of line profiles in sequence during a single run. It also
provides more information on abundance distribution for each chemical element
at the deeper atmospheric layers. Our analysis of the Balmer profiles observed
in the spectra of HD41076 and HD148330 has resulted in the estimates of their
effective temperature, gravity, metallicity and radial velocity. The respective
models of stellar atmosphere have been calculated with the code PHOENIX and
used to carry out abundance analysis employing the modified ZEEMAN2 code. The
analysis shows a deficit of the C, N, F, Mg, Ca, Ti, V, Cu, Y, Mo, Sm and Gd,
and overabundance of Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Sr, Zr, Ba, Ce, Nd and Dy in the
stellar atmosphere of HD41076. In the atmosphere of HD148330, the C, N and Mo
appear to be underabundant, while the Ne, Na, Al, Si, P, Ca, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe,
Co, Ni, Zn, Sr, Y, Zr, Ba, Ce, Pr, Nd, Sm, Eu, Gd and Dy are overabundant. We
also have found signatures of vertical abundance stratification of Fe, Ti, Cr
and Mn in HD41076, and of Fe, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Y, Zr, Ce, Nd, Sm and Gd in
HD148330.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07301</id><created>2017-06-21</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>SangChul</forenames></author></authors><title>Lagrangian and Hamiltonian formulations of the Palatini action</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>This paper is not understood as the author intended. I do not think
  it should be here anymore</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the Ashtekar-Barbero variables in Loop Quantum Gravity(LQG)
starting from the Palatini action. We find that we need either the torsion-free
condition or the compatibility condition for the Palatini action to describe
General Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08199</id><created>2017-06-25</created><updated>2017-07-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author></authors><title>A Proof of Vivo-Pato-Oshanin's Conjecture on the Fluctuation of von
  Neumann Entropy</title><categories>math-ph cs.IT math.IT math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Physical Review E</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E, 96, 022106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It was recently conjectured by Vivo, Pato, and Oshanin [Phys. Rev. E 93,
052106 (2016)] that for a quantum system of Hilbert dimension $mn$ in a pure
state, the variance of the von Neumann entropy of a subsystem of dimension
$m\leq n$ is given by \begin{equation*}
-\psi_{1}\left(mn+1\right)+\frac{m+n}{mn+1}\psi_{1}\left(n\right)-\frac{(m+1)(m+2n+1)}{4n^{2}(mn+1)},
\end{equation*} where $\psi_{1}(\cdot)$ is the trigamma function. We give a
proof of this formula.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08422</id><created>2017-06-26</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barter</keyname><forenames>Edmund</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Thilo</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial effects in meta-food-webs</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In ecology it is widely recognised that many landscapes comprise a network of
discrete patches of habitat. The species that inhabit the patches interact with
each other through a foodweb, the network of feeding interactions. The
meta-foodweb model proposed by Pillai et al. combines the feeding relationships
at each patch with the dispersal of species between patches, such that the
whole system is represented by a network of networks. Previous work on
meta-foodwebs has focussed on landscape networks that do not have an explicit
spatial embedding, but in real landscapes the patches are usually distributed
in space. Here we compare the dispersal of a meta-foodweb on \ER networks, that
do not have a spatial embedding, and random geometric networks, that do have a
spatial embedding. We found that local structure and large network distances in
spatially embedded networks, lead to meso-scale patterns of patch occupation by
both specialist and omnivorous species. In particular, we found that spatial
separations make the coexistence of competing species more likely. Our results
highlight the effects of spatial embeddings for meta-foodweb models, and the
need for new analytical approaches to them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09609</id><created>2017-06-29</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>YU</keyname><forenames>Mian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Hui-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Yi-Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Chun-Wang</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Determination of One- and Two-Neutron Separation Energies
  for Neutron-Rich Copper Isotopes</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C 41(9) 094001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/9/094001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method is proposed to determine the one-neutron $S_n$ or two-neutron
$S_{2n}$ separation energy of neutron-rich isotopes. Relationships between
$S_n$ ($S_{2n}$) and isotopic cross sections have been deduced from an
empirical formula, i.e., the cross section of an isotope exponentially depends
on the average binding energy per nucleon $B/A$. The proposed relationships
have been verified using the neutron-rich copper isotopes measured in the 64$A$
MeV $^{86}$Kr + $^{9}$Be reaction. $S_n$, $S_{2n}$, and $B/A$ for the very
neutron-rich $^{77, 78, 79}$Cu isotopes are determined from the proposed
correlations. It is also proposed that the correlations between $S_n$, $S_{2n}$
and isotopic cross sections can be used to find the location of neutron drip
line isotopes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01594</id><created>2017-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Erkaev</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odert</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lammer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kislyakova</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fossati</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezentsev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubyshkina</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaikhislamov</keyname><forenames>I. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khodachenko</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of stellar wind induced magnetic fields on planetary obstacles of
  non-magnetized hot Jupiters</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables, accepted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 470:4330-4336 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1471</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the interaction between the magnetized stellar wind plasma and
the partially ionized hydrodynamic hydrogen outflow from the escaping upper
atmosphere of non- or weakly magnetized hot Jupiters. We use the well-studied
hot Jupiter HD 209458b as an example for similar exoplanets, assuming a
negligible intrinsic magnetic moment. For this planet, the stellar wind plasma
interaction forms an obstacle in the planet's upper atmosphere, in which the
position of the magnetopause is determined by the condition of pressure balance
between the stellar wind and the expanded atmosphere, heated by the stellar
extreme ultraviolet (EUV) radiation. We show that the neutral atmospheric atoms
penetrate into the region dominated by the stellar wind, where they are ionized
by photo-ionization and charge exchange, and then mixed with the stellar wind
flow. Using a 3D magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) model, we show that an induced
magnetic field forms in front of the planetary obstacle, which appears to be
much stronger compared to those produced by the solar wind interaction with
Venus and Mars. Depending on the stellar wind parameters, because of the
induced magnetic field, the planetary obstacle can move up to ~0.5-1 planetary
radii closer to the planet. Finally, we discuss how estimations of the
intrinsic magnetic moment of hot Jupiters can be inferred by coupling
hydrodynamic upper planetary atmosphere and MHD stellar wind interaction models
together with UV observations. In particular, we find that HD 209458b should
likely have an intrinsic magnetic moment of 10-20% that of Jupiter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01625</id><created>2017-08-04</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Neukart</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Compostella</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidel</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Dollen</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarkoni</keyname><forenames>Sheir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parney</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames></author></authors><title>Traffic flow optimization using a quantum annealer</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum annealing algorithms belong to the class of meta-heuristic tools,
applicable for solving binary optimization problems. Hardware implementations
of quantum annealing, such as the quantum processing units (QPUs) produced by
D-Wave Systems, have been subject to multiple analyses in research, with the
aim of characterizing the technology's usefulness for optimization and sampling
tasks. In this paper, we present a real-world application that uses quantum
technologies. Specifically, we show how to map certain parts of the real-world
traffic flow optimization problem to be suitable for quantum annealing. We show
that time-critical optimization tasks, such as continuous redistribution of
position data for cars in dense road networks, are suitable candidates for
quantum applications. Due to the limited size and connectivity of
current-generation D-Wave QPUs, we use a hybrid quantum and classical approach
to solve the traffic flow problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02159</id><created>2017-08-07</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Horstmann</keyname><forenames>Gerrit Maik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weier</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling and stability of interfacial waves in liquid metal batteries</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the interfacial wave coupling dynamics in liquid metal
batteries and their effects to the battery's operation safety. Similar to
aluminum reduction cells, liquid metal batteries can be highly susceptible to
magnetohydrodynamical instabilities that excite undesired interfacial waves
capable to provoke short-circuits. However, in liquid metal batteries the wave
dynamics is far more complex since two metal-electrolyte interfaces are present
that may step into resonance. In the first part of this paper, we present a
Potential analysis of coupled gravity-capillary interfacial waves in a
three-layer battery model of cylindrical shape. Analytical expressions for the
amplitude ratio and the wave frequencies are derived and it is shown that the
wave coupling can be completely described by two independent dimensionless
parameters. We provide a decoupling criterion clarifying that wave coupling
will be present in most future liquid metal batteries. In the second part, the
theory is validated by comparing it with multiphase direct numerical
simulations. An accompanying parameter study is conducted to analyze the system
stability for differently strongly coupled interfaces. Three different coupling
regimes are identified involving characteristic coupling dynamics. For strongly
coupled interfaces we observe novel instabilities that may have beneficial
effects on the operational safety.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02467</id><created>2017-08-08</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jingjing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Danhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Shengyong</forenames></author></authors><title>Wireless Communication in Biosystems</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrical signals play the primary role in rapid communication among organs,
tissues and cells in biosystems. We have analyzed and discussed three phenomena
of electrical communication in biosystems, including direction-changing
movement of paramecia, prey behavior of flytraps, and simultaneous discharge of
electric ells. These discussions lead to a conclusion that in biosystems the
electrical signals are mainly soliton-like electromagnetic pulses, which are
generated by transient transmembrane ion currents through protein ion-channels.
These electromagnetic signals mainly propagate along the softmaterial waveguide
which is basically composed of dielectric membrane, sandwiched in two ionic
liquid layers at both sides. In myelinated axons, the dielectric layer is as
thick as several microns as it consists of tens of lipid bilayers. This
transmission model implies that a wireless communication mechanism has been
naturally developed in biosystem. This hypothesis may shed some light on the
working mechanism of ten billion neurons in a human brain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02842</id><created>2017-08-09</created><updated>2017-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vishkayi</keyname><forenames>Sahar Izadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagani</keyname><forenames>Meysam Bagheri</forenames></author></authors><title>Edge-dependent electronic and magnetic characteristics of freestanding
  \beta_12-Borophene Nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanoribbons produced from cutting {\beta}_12-Borophene sheet is investigated
by density functional theory. The electronic and magnetic properties of
Borophene nanoribbons are studied and found that all considered ribbons are
metal which is in good agreement with recent experimental results.
{\beta}_12-Borophene nanoribbons have a lot of diversity due to existence of 5
Boron atoms in a unit cell of the sheet. The magnetic properties of ribbons are
strongly dependent on the cutting direction and the edge profile. It is
interesting that a ribbon with a specific width can be a normal or
ferromagnetic metal with magnetization in just one edge or two edges. The spin
anisotropy is observed in some ribbons so that magnetic moment is not the same
in both edges in antiferromagnetic configuration. The effect comes from the
edge asymmetry of the ribbons and results in the breaking of spin degeneracy in
the bandstructure. Our findings show that {\beta}_12 nanoribbons are potential
candidates for next-generation spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02938</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Siddiqa</keyname><forenames>Amnah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niazi</keyname><forenames>Muaz A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Novel Formal Agent-based Simulation Modeling Framework of an AIDS
  Complex Adaptive System</title><categories>cs.MA nlin.PS q-bio.PE</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><acm-class>J.3; D.2.4; D.3.1; F.1.1; J.4; K.4.2</acm-class><journal-ref>International Journal of Agent Technologies and Systems (IJATS),
  5(3), 33-53 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.4018/ijats.2013070103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  HIV/AIDS spread depends upon complex patterns of interaction among various
sub-sets emerging at population level. This added complexity makes it difficult
to study and model AIDS and its dynamics. AIDS is therefore a natural candidate
to be modeled using agent-based modeling, a paradigm well-known for modeling
Complex Adaptive Systems (CAS). While agent-based models are also well-known to
effectively model CAS, often times models can tend to be ambiguous and the use
of purely text-based specifications (such as ODD) can make models difficult to
be replicated. Previous work has shown how formal specification may be used in
conjunction with agent-based modeling to develop models of various CAS.
However, to the best of our knowledge, no such model has been developed in
conjunction with AIDS. In this paper, we present a Formal Agent-Based
Simulation modeling framework (FABS-AIDS) for an AIDS-based CAS. FABS-AIDS
employs the use of a formal specification model in conjunction with an
agent-based model to reduce ambiguity as well as improve clarity in the model
definition. The proposed model demonstrates the effectiveness of using formal
specification in conjunction with agent-based simulation for developing models
of CAS in general and, social network-based agent-based models, in particular.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02964</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Ting-Ting</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-neutral charged two-dimension system and its quasihole structure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most of our current knowledge on condensed matters contains a default
assumption: the matters are neutral charged. On the other hand, the
two-dimension(2D) vortex-Coulomb gas charge analogy is a very successful
theoretical tool in explaining superfluid, type-II superconductor and
fractional quantum Hall effect(FQHE), because the interaction among vortices
show similarity with 2D Coulomb potential. Here, by breaking the 'neutral
charged' assumption, we suggest the positively charged 2D semiconductor system
can possess non-trivial particle-like charge centers(called 'quasihole'), which
is the charge version of 'vortex'. Using the hypernetted-chain (HNC)
approximation, the structure of quasihole is elucidated. Numerical calculations
show that the quasihole can be projected onto another 2D layer, producing an
electric field configuration characterized by 3/2 topological charge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02988</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Androulidakis</keyname><forenames>Charalampos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koukaras</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahova</keyname><forenames>Jaroslava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampathkumar</keyname><forenames>Krishna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parthenios</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papagelis</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>Otakar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galiotis</keyname><forenames>Costas</forenames></author></authors><title>Wrinkled few-layer graphene as highly efficient load bearer</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces, 9 (31), pp 26593-26601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsami.7b07547</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multilayered graphitic materials are not suitable as load-bearers due to
their inherent weak interlayer bonding (for example, graphite is a solid
lubricant in certain applications). This situation is largely improved when
two-dimensional (2-D) materials such as a monolayer (SLG) graphene are
employed. The downside in these cases is the presence of thermally or
mechanically induced wrinkles which are ubiquitous in 2-D materials. Here we
set out to examine the effect of extensive large wavelength/ amplitude
wrinkling on the stress transfer capabilities of exfoliated simply-supported
graphene flakes. Contrary to common belief we present clear evidence that this
type of &quot;corrugation&quot; enhances the load bearing capacity of few-layer graphene
as compared to 'flat' specimens. This effect is the result of the significant
increase of the graphene/polymer interfacial shear stress per increment of
applied strain due to wrinkling and paves the way for designing affordable
graphene composites with highly improved stress-transfer efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02994</id><created>2017-08-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Guosheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Deyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Shanshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>LuHua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Minghong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Haiping</forenames></author></authors><title>NaCl crystal from salt solution with far below saturated concentration
  under ambient condition</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under ambient conditions, we directly observed NaCl crystals experimentally
in the rGO membranes soaked in the salt solution with concentration below and
far below the saturated concentration. Moreover, in most probability, the NaCl
crystals show stoichiometries behavior. We attribute this unexpected
crystallization to the cation-{\pi} interactions between the ions and the
aromatic rings of the rGO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02996</id><created>2017-08-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yapa</keyname><forenames>N. U. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samarasekara</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Third order perturbed Heisenberg Hamiltonian of sc ferromagnetic films
  with fifty spin layers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic energy of simple cubic structured ferromagnetic films with 10 to 50
spin layers was determined using third order perturbed Heisenberg Hamiltonian.
By plotting 3-D plot of energy versus angle and stress induced anisotropy, the
values of stress induced anisotropy corresponding to energy minimums and
maximums were determined. By plotting the graphs of energy versus angle at
these different stress induced anisotropy values, the easy and hard directions
were determined. Magnetic easy and hard directions are related to energy
minimums and maximums of the curve. Similar graphs were plotted for spin
exchange interaction to determine the easy and hard directions. Graphs of
energy versus angle were plotted by keeping all the magnetic energy parameters
at constant values for each number of spin layers to determine the variation of
magnetic easy directions, hard direction and corresponding energies with the
number of spin layers. The magnetic easy axis gradually rotates from out of
plane to in plane direction as the number of spin layers is increased. In
addition, the magnetic anisotropy energy increases with the number of spin
layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03005</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>The HAWC Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>The IceCube Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Combined Analysis of Cosmic-Ray Anisotropy with IceCube and HAWC</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Presented at the 35th International Cosmic Ray Conference (ICRC2017),
  Bexco, Busan, Korea. See arXiv:1708.02572 for all HAWC contributions, (1)
  http://www.hawc-observatory.org/collaboration/icrc2017.php, (2)
  http://icecube.wisc.edu/collaboration/authors/icrc17_icecube</comments><report-no>HAWC-ICRC/2017/28</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the past two decades, experiments in both the northern and southern
hemispheres have observed a small but measurable energy-dependent sidereal
anisotropy in the arrival direction distribution of Galactic cosmic rays with
relative intensities at the level of one per mille. Individually, these
measurements are restricted by limited sky coverage, and so the power spectrum
of the anisotropy obtained from any one measurement displays a systematic
correlation between different multipole modes $C_\ell$. We present the results
of a joint analysis of the anisotropy on all angular scales using cosmic-ray
data collected during 336 days of operation of the High-Altitude Water
Cherenkov (HAWC) Observatory (located at 19$^\circ$ N) and 5 years of data
taking from the IceCube Neutrino Observatory (located at 90$^\circ$ S) The
results include a combined sky map and an all-sky power spectrum in the
overlapping energy range of the two experiments at around 10 TeV. We describe
the methods used to combine the IceCube and HAWC data, address the individual
detector systematics, and study the region of overlapping field of view between
the two observatories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03016</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Sluchinskaya</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebedev</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>An experimental and theoretical study of Ni impurity centers in
  Ba$_{0.8}$Sr$_{0.2}$TiO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Physics of the Solid State, v. 59, p. 1512 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S106378341708025X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The local environment and the charge state of a nickel impurity in cubic
Ba$_{0.8}$Sr$_{0.2}$TiO$_3$ are studied by XAFS spectroscopy. According to the
XANES data, the mean Ni charge state is $\sim$2.5+. An analysis of the EXAFS
spectra and their comparison with the results of first-principle calculations
of the defect geometry suggest that Ni$^{2+}$ ions are in a high-spin state at
the $B$ sites of the perovskite structure and the difference of the Ni$^{2+}$
and Ti$^{4+}$ charges is mainly compensated by distant oxygen vacancies. In
addition, a considerable amount of nickel in the sample is in a second phase
BaNiO$_{3-\delta}$. The measurements of the lattice parameter show a decrease
in the unit cell volume upon doping, which can indicate the existence of a
small amount of Ni$^{4+}$ ions at the $B$ sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03033</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Rettie</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for New High Mass Phenomena Decaying to Muon Pairs using
  Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}$ = 13 TeV with the ATLAS Detector at
  the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a search for new high mass phenomena using the latest data
collected by the ATLAS detector at the LHC, corresponding to 36.1 fb$^{-1}$ at
$\sqrt{s}$ = 13 TeV. The search is conducted for both resonant and non-resonant
new phenomena in dimuon final states. The dimuon invariant mass spectrum is the
discriminating variable used in the search. No significant deviations from the
Standard Model expectation are observed. Lower limits are set on the signal
parameters of interest at 95% credibility level, using a Bayesian
interpretation. In particular, a Sequential Standard Model Z' resonance is
excluded for masses below 4.0 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03040</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Susskind</keyname><forenames>Leonard</forenames></author></authors><title>Dear Qubitzers, GR=QM</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Letter to Colleagues</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  These are some thoughts contained in a letter to colleagues, about the close
relation between gravity and quantum mechanics, and also about the possibility
of seeing quantum gravity in a lab equipped with quantum computers. I expect
this will become feasible sometime in the next decade or two.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03050</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Jian</keyname><forenames>Chao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rasmussen</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Cenke</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent Symmetry and Tricritical Points near the deconfined Quantum
  Critical Point</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent proposal of the duality between the $N=2$ noncompact QED$_3$ and the
easy-plane noncompact CP$^1$ (NCCP$^1$) model suggests that the deconfined
quantum critical point (dQCP) between the easy-plane antiferromagnet and the
VBS order on the square lattice may have an emergent O(4) symmetry, due to the
self-duality of the $N=2$ noncompact QED$_3$. Recent numerical progresses
suggest that this easy-plane dQCP does exist and it has an emergent O(4)
symmetry. But for the O(4) symmetry to really emerge at the dQCP, certain O(4)
symmetry breaking perturbations need to be irrelevant at the putative O(4)
fixed point. It is more convenient to study these symmetry breaking
perturbations in the $N=2$ noncompact QED$_3$. We demonstrate that a natural
large-$N$ generalization and a controlled $1/N$ expansion supports the
stability of the O(4) fixed point against the symmetry breaking perturbations.
We also develop the theory for two tricritical points close to the easy-plane
dQCP. One tricritical point is between the dQCP and a {\it self-dual} $Z_2$
topological order; the other is the tricritical point that connects the
continuous dQCP and a first order N\'{e}el-VBS transition, motivated by recent
numerical results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03056</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>Daniel Juliano Pamplona</forenames></author></authors><title>Crossing-effect in non-isolated and non-symmetric systems of patches</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main result of this article is the determination of the minimal size for
the general case of problems with two identical patches. This solution is
presented in the explicit form, which allows to recuperate all the cases found
in the literature as particular cases, namely, one isolated fragment, one
single fragment communicating with its neighborhood, a system with two
identical fragments isolated from the matrix but mutually communicating and a
system of two identical fragments inserted in a homogeneous matrix. It is also
addressed the new problem of a single fragment communicating with the matrix,
with different life difficulty of each side. As application, it is found that
the internal condition $a_{0}$ can set which system is the worst to life. This
prediction confirms and extends the prediction already found in the literature
between isolated and non-isolated systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03082</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Durkin</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondragon-Shem</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Taylor L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Nadya</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of domain wall motion in a polycrystalline vortex lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements showing how disorder determines the dynamics of a
vortex lattice. Using superconductor-normal-superconductor (SNS) arrays placed
in finite magnetic fields, disorder is introduced by shifting the field away
from values where the vortex lattice is commensurate with the SNS array. By
applying a current to drive vortex motion, we observe a two-step transition at
incommensurate fields: first from pinned vortices to lattice defect motion, and
then from individual defect to bulk vortex lattice flow. This behavior is
consistent with a polycrystalline vortex structure where defects form on the
edges of crystalline domains. This demonstrates that a disordered, interacting
vortex system can favor interface physics rather than a quasiperiodic regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03085</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral transition line for the extended Harper's model in the positive
  Lyapunov exponent regime</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spectral transition line of the extended Harper's model in the
positive Lyapunov exponent regime. We show that both pure point spectrum and
purely singular continuous spectrum occur for dense subsets of frequencies on
the transition line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03089</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Shin</keyname><forenames>Yeong Jae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lingfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yoonkoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ho-Hyun Nahm Daesu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jeong Rae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Sang Mo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Jong-Gul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Jin-Seok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Miyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Seo Hyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noh</keyname><forenames>Tae Won</forenames></author></authors><title>Oxygen Partial Pressure during Pulsed Laser Deposition: Deterministic
  Role on Thermodynamic Stability of Atomic Termination Sequence at
  SrRuO3/BaTiO3 Interface</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 6 figures, Supporting Information</comments><doi>10.1021/acsami.7b07813</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With recent trends on miniaturizing oxide-based devices, the need for
atomic-scale control of surface/interface structures by pulsed laser deposition
(PLD) has increased. In particular, realizing uniform atomic termination at the
surface/interface is highly desirable. However, a lack of understanding on the
surface formation mechanism in PLD has limited a deliberate control of
surface/interface atomic stacking sequences. Here, taking the prototypical
SrRuO3/BaTiO3/SrRuO3 (SRO/BTO/SRO) heterostructure as a model system, we
investigated the formation of different interfacial termination sequences
(BaO-RuO2 or TiO2-SrO) with oxygen partial pressure (PO2) during PLD. We found
that a uniform SrO-TiO2 termination sequence at the SRO/BTO interface can be
achieved by lowering the PO2 to 5 mTorr, regardless of the total background gas
pressure (Ptotal), growth mode, or growth rate. Our results indicate that the
thermodynamic stability of the BTO surface at the low-energy kinetics stage of
PLD can play an important role in surface/interface termination formation. This
work paves the way for realizing termination engineering in functional oxide
heterostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03098</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Neelesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhir</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author></authors><title>Charmed Axial Vector and Pseudoscalar Mesons Emitting Decays of Bottom
  Meson in NRQM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two body nonleptonic weak decays of bottom mesons to a pseudoscalar meson and
an axial-vector meson involving charmed states are studied using the
non-relativistic quark model. We calculate the branching ratios of these decays
by employing the factorization hypothesis. Obtained results are in good
agreement with the existing experimental data. We also calculated the branching
ratios in the light of heavy quark symmetry constraints and compared with the
exiting theoretical analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03101</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>Chizu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moynier</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author></authors><title>Gallium isotopic evidence for extensive volatile loss from the Moon
  during its formation</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 tables, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Advances 3, (7) 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1700571</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The distribution and isotopic composition of volatile elements in planetary
materials holds a key to the characterization of the early solar system and the
Moon's formation. The Moon and Earth are chemically and isotopically very
similar. However, the Moon is highly depleted in volatile elements and the
origin of this depletion is still debated. We present gallium isotopic and
elemental measurements in a large set of lunar samples to constrain the origin
of this volatile depletion. We show that while Ga has a geochemical behavior
different from zinc, both elements show a systematic enrichment in the heavier
isotopes in lunar mare basalts and Mg-suite rocks compared to the silicate
Earth, pointing to a global-scale depletion event. On the other hand, the
ferroan anorthosites are isotopically heterogeneous, suggesting a secondary
distribution of Ga at the surface of the Moon by volatilization and
condensation. The isotopic difference of Ga between Earth and the Moon and the
isotopic heterogeneity of the crustal ferroan anorthosites suggest that the
volatile depletion occurred following the giant impact and during the lunar
magma ocean phase. These results point toward a Moon that has lost its volatile
elements during a whole-scale evaporation event and that is now relatively dry
compared to Earth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03107</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Takano</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Yoku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chahadih</keyname><forenames>Abdallah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghaddar</keyname><forenames>Abbas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Xiang-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaurette</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakata</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyamaru</keyname><forenames>Fumiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hangyo</keyname><forenames>Masanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akalin</keyname><forenames>Tahsin</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy loss of terahertz electromagnetic waves by nano-sized connections
  in near-self-complementary metallic checkerboard patterns</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics, 122, 063101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4997882</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The design of a self-complementary metallic checkerboard pattern achieves
broadband, dispersion-less, and maximized absorption, concentrating in the deep
subwavelength resistive connections between squares, without any theoretical
limitation on the energy absorbing area. Here, we experimentally and
numerically investigate the electromagnetic response in the limit of extremely
small connections. We show that finite conductivity and randomness in a
near-self-complementary checkerboard pattern plays a crucial role in producing
a frequency-independent energy loss in the terahertz frequency region. Here
metals behave like an almost perfect conductor. When the checkerboard pattern
approaches the perfect self-complementary pattern, the perfect conductor
approximation spontaneously breaks down, owing to the finite conductivity at
the nano- scale connection, leading to broadband absorption. It is also shown
that the random connections between metallic squares also lead to broadband and
maximized energy loss through scattering loss, similar to finite conductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03114</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Musacchio</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boffetta</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author></authors><title>Split energy cascade in turbulent thin fluid layers</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Fluids 29, 111106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4986001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the phenomenology of the split energy cascade in a
three-dimensional thin fluid layer by mean of high resolution numerical
simulations of the Navier-Stokes equations. We observe the presence of both an
inverse energy cascade at large scales, as predicted for two-dimensional turbu-
lence, and of a direct energy cascade at small scales, as in three-dimensional
turbulence. The inverse energy cascade is associated with a direct cascade of
enstrophy in the intermediate range of scales. Notably, we find that the
inverse cascade of energy in this system is not a pure 2D phenomenon, as the
coupling with the 3D velocity field is necessary to guarantee the constancy of
fluxes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03125</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Jalla</keyname><forenames>Deepak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolwankar</keyname><forenames>Kiran M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multifractal invariant measures in expanding piecewise linear coupled
  maps</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze invariant measures of two coupled piecewise linear and everywhere
expanding maps on the synchronization manifold. We observe that though the
individual maps have simple and smooth functions as their stationary densities,
they become multifractal as soon as two of them are coupled nonlinearly even
with a small coupling. For some maps, the multifractal spectrum seems to be
robust with the coupling or map parameters and for some other maps, there is a
substantial variation. The origin of the multifractal spectrum here is
intriguing as it does not seem to conform to the existing theory of
multifractal functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03135</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>MicroBooNE collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Acciarri</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthony</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asaadi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagby</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balasubramanian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baller</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barr</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bass</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bay</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blake</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolton</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camilleri</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caratelli</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carls</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>R. Castillo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavanna</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Church</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cianci</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collin</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Convery</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crespo-Anadon</keyname><forenames>J. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Tutto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devitt</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dytman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberly</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ereditato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>L. Escudero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esquivel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fadeeva</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleming</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foreman</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furmanski</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Gomez</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garvey</keyname><forenames>G. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genty</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goeldi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gollapinni</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graf</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramellini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenlee</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosso</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guenette</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hackenburg</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamilton</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hen</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hewes</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horton-Smith</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hourlier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>E. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Vries</keyname><forenames>J. Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jen</keyname><forenames>C. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jostlein</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaleko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karagiorgi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketchum</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirby</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirby</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobilarcik</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreslo</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laube</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lister</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Littlejohn</keyname><forenames>B. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lockwitz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorca</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louis</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luethi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundberg</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchionni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caicedo</keyname><forenames>D. A. Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meddage</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miceli</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mills</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mooney</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousseau</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murrells</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naples</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nienaber</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palamara</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papavassiliou</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pate</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlovic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piasetzky</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porzio</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pulliam</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raaf</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rafique</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rochester</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Rohr</keyname><forenames>C. Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitz</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schukraft</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seligman</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaevitz</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snider</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soderberg</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soldner-Rembold</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soleti</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spentzouris</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spitz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>John</keyname><forenames>J. St.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strauss</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szelc</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagg</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terao</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toups</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Y. -T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tufanli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van De Pontseele</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Water</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viren</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wickremasinghe</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolbers</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wongjirad</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodruff</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yates</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeller</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zennamo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Pandora multi-algorithm approach to automated pattern recognition of
  cosmic-ray muon and neutrino events in the MicroBooNE detector</title><categories>hep-ex physics.data-an</categories><comments>Preprint to be submitted to The European Physical Journal C</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development and operation of Liquid-Argon Time-Projection Chambers for
neutrino physics has created a need for new approaches to pattern recognition
in order to fully exploit the imaging capabilities offered by this technology.
Whereas the human brain can excel at identifying features in the recorded
events, it is a significant challenge to develop an automated, algorithmic
solution. The Pandora Software Development Kit provides functionality to aid
the design and implementation of pattern-recognition algorithms. It promotes
the use of a multi-algorithm approach to pattern recognition, in which
individual algorithms each address a specific task in a particular topology.
Many tens of algorithms then carefully build up a picture of the event and,
together, provide a robust automated pattern-recognition solution. This paper
describes details of the chain of over one hundred Pandora algorithms and tools
used to reconstruct cosmic-ray muon and neutrino events in the MicroBooNE
detector. Metrics that assess the current pattern-recognition performance are
presented for simulated MicroBooNE events, using a selection of final-state
event topologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03139</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Lopez-Coto</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hahn</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greus</keyname><forenames>F. Salesa</forenames></author><author><keyname>BenZvi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisa</keyname><forenames>M. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>EDGE: a code to calculate diffusion of cosmic-ray electrons and their
  gamma-ray emission</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Presented at the 35th International Cosmic Ray Conference (ICRC2017),
  Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The positron excess measured by PAMELA and AMS can only be explained if there
is one or several sources injecting them. Moreover, at the highest energies, it
requires the presence of nearby ($\sim$hundreds of parsecs) and middle age
(maximum of $\sim$hundreds of kyr) source. Pulsars, as factories of electrons
and positrons, are one of the proposed candidates to explain the origin of this
excess. To calculate the contribution of these sources to the electron and
positron flux at the Earth, we developed EDGE (Electron Diffusion and Gamma
rays to the Earth), a code to treat diffusion of electrons and compute their
diffusion from a central source with a flexible injection spectrum. We can
derive the source's gamma-ray spectrum, spatial extension, the all-electron
density in space and the electron and positron flux reaching the Earth. We
present in this contribution the fundamentals of the code and study how
different parameters affect the gamma-ray spectrum of a source and the electron
flux measured at the Earth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03150</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Dittmar</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>A Regional Oil Extraction and Consumption Model. Part II: Predicting the
  declines in regional oil consumption</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 9 figures and 7 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In part I of this analysis, the striking similarities of the declining oil
production in the North Sea, Indonesia and Mexico were used to model the future
maximum possible oil production per annum in all larger countries and regions
of the planet from 2015 to 2050.
  In part II, the oil export and oil consumption patterns, that were
established in recent decades, are combined with the consequences of the
forecast declines in regional oil production that were developed in part I of
this analysis. The results are quantitative predictions of the maximum possible
region-by-region oil consumption during the next 20 years.
  The predictions indicate that several of the larger oil consuming and
importing countries and regions will be confronted with the economic
consequences of the onset of the world's final oil supply crisis as early as
2020. In particular, during the next few years a reduction of the average per
capita oil consumption of about 5%/year is predicted for most OECD countries in
Western Europe, and slightly smaller reductions, about 2-3%/year, is predicted
for all other oil importing countries and regions. The consequences of the
predicted oil supply crisis are thoroughly at odds with business-as-usual,
never-ending-global-growth predictions of oil production and consumption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03153</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Shang-Hsuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Ming-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Sheng-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Wei-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Chih-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Yia-Chung</forenames></author></authors><title>A Design Based on Stair-case Band Alignment of Electron Transport Layer
  for Improving Performance and Stability in Planar Perovskite Solar Cells</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Among the n-type metal oxide materials used in the planar perovskite solar
cells, zinc oxide (ZnO) is a promising candidate to replace titanium dioxide
(TiO2) due to its relatively high electron mobility, high transparency, and
versatile nanostructures. Here, we present the application of low temperature
solution processed ZnO/Al-doped ZnO (AZO) bilayer thin film as electron
transport layers (ETLs) in the inverted perovskite solar cells, which provide a
stair-case band profile. Experimental results revealed that the power
conversion efficiency (PCE) of perovskite solar cells were significantly
increased from 12.25 to 16.07% by employing the AZO thin film as the buffer
layer. Meanwhile, the short-circuit current density (Jsc), open-circuit voltage
(Voc), and fill factor (FF) were improved to 20.58 mA/cm2, 1.09V, and 71.6%,
respectively. The enhancement in performance is attributed to the modified
interface in ETL with stair-case band alignment of ZnO/AZO/CH3NH3PbI3, which
allows more efficient extraction of photogenerated electrons in the CH3NH3PbI3
active layer. Thus, it is demonstrated that the ZnO/AZO bilayer ETLs would
benefit the electron extraction and contribute in enhancing the performance of
perovskite solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03168</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Wilkinson</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimbblet</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stott</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Evolutionary Sequence of Post-Starburst Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables, accepted in mnras</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are multiple ways in which to select post-starburst galaxies in the
literature. In this work, we present a study into how two well-used selection
techniques have consequences on observable post-starburst galaxy parameters,
such as colour, morphology and environment and how this affects interpretations
of their role in the galaxy duty cycle. We identify a master sample of
H$\delta$ strong (EW$_{H\delta}$ &gt; 3\AA) post-starburst galaxies from the
value-added catalogue in the 7th data release of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey
(SDSS DR7) over a redshift range 0.01 &lt; $z$ &lt; 0.1. From this sample we select
two E+A subsets, both having a very little [OII] emission (EW$_{[OII]}$ $&gt;
-2.5$\AA) but one having an additional cut on EW$_{H\alpha}$ ($&gt; -3$\AA). We
examine the differences in observables and AGN fractions to see what effect the
H$\alpha$ cut has on the properties of post-starburst galaxies and what these
differing samples can tell us about the duty cycle of post-starburst galaxies.
We find that H$\delta$ strong galaxies peak in the `blue cloud', E+As in the
`green valley' and pure E+As in the `red sequence'. We also find that pure E+As
have a more early-type morphology and a higher fraction in denser environments
compared with the H$\delta$ strong and E+A galaxies. These results suggest that
there is an evolutionary sequence in the post-starburst phase from blue disky
galaxies with residual star formation to passive red early-types.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03170</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Biernat</keyname><forenames>Elmar P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schweiger</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>$\rho$-Meson Form Factors in the Point Form</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, Presented at the 9th Excited QCD conference, 7-13
  May 2017, Sintra, Portugal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a calculation of the electromagnetic form factors of the $\rho^+$
meson. Our formalism is based on the point-form of relativistic quantum
mechanics. Electron-$\rho$-meson scattering is formulated as a coupled-channel
problem for a Bakamjian-Thomas mass operator, such that the dynamics of the
exchanged photon is taken explicitly into account. The $\rho$-meson current is
extracted from on-shell matrix elements of the optical potential of the
scattering process. As a consequence of the violation of cluster separability
in the Bakamjian-Thomas framework, our current includes additional, unphysical
contributions, which can be separated from the physical ones uniquely. Our
results for the form factors are in good agreement with other approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03171</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Komin</keyname><forenames>Nukri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haupt</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>H. E. S. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of VHE Gamma-Ray Emission from the Binary System LMC P3</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, proceedings of the 35th International Cosmic Ray
  Conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the $\gamma$-ray emission at MeV and GeV energies from the object
LMC P3 in the Large Magellanic Cloud has been discovered to be modulated with a
10.3-days period, making it the first extra-galactic $\gamma$-ray binary. This
work aims at the detection of TeV $\gamma$-ray and the search for modulation of
the signal with the orbital period of the binary system. The H.E.S.S. data set
has been folded with the known orbital period of the system in order to test
for variability of the emission. Energy spectra are obtained for the
orbit-averaged data set and for orbital phases in which the TeV flux is found
at its maximum. TeV $\gamma$-ray emission is detected with a statistical
significance of 6.4\,$\sigma$. The data clearly show variability which is
phase-locked to the orbital period of the system. Periodicity cannot be deduced
from the H.E.S.S. data set alone. The orbit-averaged luminosity in the 1-10 TeV
energy range is $(1.4 \pm 0.2) \times 10^{35}\,\mathrm{erg\,s}^{-1}$. A
luminosity of $(5 \pm 1) \times 10^{35}\,\mathrm{erg\,s}^{-1}$ is reached
during 20% of the orbit, when the MeV/GeV emission is at its minimum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03175</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Piotrowska</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacosa</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong decays of excited vector mesons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 tables. To appear in the proceedings of Excited QCD 2017,
  7-13 May 2017, Sintra, Portugal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study two nonets of excited vector mesons, predominantly corresponding to
radially excited vector mesons with quantum numbers $n\hspace{0.08cm}
^{2S+1}L_{J}$ $=2^3S_1$ and to orbitally excited vector mesons with quantum
numbers $n\hspace{0.08cm} ^{2S+1}L_{J}=1^3D_1$. We evaluate two types of decays
of these mesons: into two pseudoscalar mesons and into a pseudoscalar and a
ground-state vector meson. We compare the results with experimental data taken
from PDG. We also make predictions for the strange-antistrange state in the
$1^3D_1$ nonet denoted as $\phi(1930)$, which has not yet been discovered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03179</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Garifullin</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamilov</keyname><forenames>R. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the integrability of a lattice equation with two continuum limits</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><msc-class>37K10, 35G50, 39A10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a new example of lattice equation being one of the key equations of
a recent generalized symmetry classification of five-point
differential-difference equations. This equation has two different continuum
limits which are the well-known fifth order partial-differential equations,
namely, the Sawada-Kotera and Kaup-Kupershmidt equations. We justify its
integrability by constructing an $L-A$ pair and a hierarchy of conservation
laws.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03188</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Mortensen</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author></authors><title>Shenfun -- automating the spectral Galerkin method</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Presented at MekIT'17, the 9th National Conference on Computational
  Mechanics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the shenfun Python module (github.com/spectralDNS/shenfun) an effort is
made towards automating the implementation of the spectral Galerkin method for
simple tensor product domains, consisting of (currently) one non-periodic and
any number of periodic directions. The user interface to shenfun is
intentionally made very similar to FEniCS (fenicsproject.org). Partial
Differential Equations are represented through weak variational forms and
solved using efficient direct solvers where available. MPI decomposition is
achieved through the {mpi4py-fft} module (bitbucket.org/mpi4py/mpi4py-fft), and
all developed solver may, with no additional effort, be run on supercomputers
using thousands of processors. Complete solvers are shown for the linear
Poisson and biharmonic problems, as well as the nonlinear and time-dependent
Ginzburg-Landau equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03195</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubertrand</keyname><forenames>Remy</forenames></author></authors><title>WKB approach to evaluate series of Mathieu functions in scattering
  problems</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The scattering of a wave obeying Helmholtz equation by an elliptic obstacle
can be described exactly using series of Mathieu functions. This situation is
relevant in optics, quantum mechanics and fluid dynamics. We focus on the case
when the wavelength is comparable to the obstacle size, when the most standard
approximations fail. The approximations of the radial (or modified) Mathieu
functions using WKB method are shown to be especially efficient, in order to
precisely evaluate series of such functions. It is illustrated with the
numerical computation of the Green function when the wave is scattered by a
single slit or a strip (ribbon).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03207</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Bilski</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brahma</keyname><forenames>Suddhasattwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcian&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>Antonino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mielczarek</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author></authors><title>Klein-Gordon field from the XXZ Heisenberg model</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the recently introduced idea of Spin-Field Correspondence focusing
on the example of the spin system described by the XXZ Heisenberg model with
external magnetic field. The Hamiltonian of the resulting nonlinear scalar
field theory is derived for arbitrary value of the anisotropy parameter
$\Delta$. We show that the linear scalar field theory is reconstructed in the
large spin limit. For $\Delta=1$ a non-relativistic scalar field theory
satisfying the Born reciprocity principle is recovered. As expected, for the
vanishing anisotropy parameter $\Delta \rightarrow 0$ the standard relativistic
Klein-Gordon field is obtained. Various aspects of the obtained class of the
scalar fields are studied, including the fate of the relativistic symmetries
and the properties of the emerging interaction terms. We show that, in a
certain limit, the so-called polymer quantisation of the field variables is
recovered. This and other discussed properties suggest a possible relevance of
the considered framework in the context of quantum gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03213</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Tasson</keyname><forenames>Jay D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antimatter, Lorentz Symmetry, and Gravity</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the 12th International Conference on Low Energy
  Antiproton Physics, Kanazawa Japan, March 6-11, 2016, Accepted for
  publication in JPS Conference Proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A brief introduction to the Standard-Model Extension (SME) approach to
testing CPT and Lorentz symmetry is provided. Recent proposals for tests with
antimatter are summarized, including gravitational and spectroscopic tests.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03222</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>Chul Ki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konno</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segawa</keyname><forenames>Etsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Hyun Jae</forenames></author></authors><title>How does Grover walk recognize the shape of crystal lattice?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the support of the limit distribution of the Grover walk on
crystal lattices with the linear scaling. The orbit of the Grover walk is
denoted by the parametric plot of the pseudo-velocity of the Grover walk in the
wave space. The region of the orbit is the support of the limit distribution.
In this paper, we compute the regions of the orbits for the triangular,
hexagonal and kagome lattices. We show every outer frame of the support is
described by an ellipse. The shape of the ellipse depends only on the
realization of the fundamental lattice of the crystal lattice in
$\mathbb{R}^2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03226</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Pedro</keyname><forenames>Francisco G.</forenames></author></authors><title>UV physics and the speed of sound during inflation</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-17-065</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider inflation as an effective field theory and study the effects of
the addition to the Lagrangian of irrelevant operators with higher powers of
first derivatives on its dynamics and observables. We find that significant
deviations from the two-derivative dynamics are possible within the regime of
validity of the effective field theory. Focusing on monomial potentials we show
that the main effect of the terms under consideration is to reduce the speed of
sound thereby reducing the tensor fraction, while having little impact on the
scalar tilt. Crucially, these effects can arise even when the UV cut-off is
well above the inflationary Hubble parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03243</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Abidi</keyname><forenames>Abdessalem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tawbi</keyname><forenames>Samar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guyeux</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouall&#xe8;gue</keyname><forenames>Belgacem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machhout</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author></authors><title>Summary of Topological Study of Chaotic CBC Mode of Operation</title><categories>nlin.CD cs.CR</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1605.02950,
  arXiv:1608.05838, arXiv:1601.08139</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In cryptography, block ciphers are the most fundamental elements in many
symmetric-key encryption systems. The Cipher Block Chaining, denoted CBC,
presents one of the most famous mode of operation that uses a block cipher to
provide confidentiality or authenticity. In this research work, we intend to
summarize our results that have been detailed in our previous series of
articles. The goal of this series has been to obtain a complete topological
study of the CBC block cipher mode of operation after proving his chaotic
behavior according to the reputed definition of Devaney.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03261</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kochubei</keyname><forenames>Anatoly N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear and Nonlinear Heat Equations on a p-Adic Ball</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1611.08863</comments><msc-class>35S05 (Primary) 11S80, 35K55, 35R11 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Vladimirov fractional differentiation operator $D^\alpha_N$,
$\alpha &gt;0, N\in \mathbb Z$, on a $p$-adic ball $B_N=\{ x\in \mathbb Q_p:\
|x|_p\le p^N\}$. To its known interpretations via restriction from a similar
operator on $\mathbb Q_p$ and via a certain stochastic process on $B_N$, we add
an interpretation as a pseudo-differential operator in terms of the Pontryagin
duality on the additive group of $B_N$. We investigate the Green function of
$D^\alpha_N$ and a nonlinear equation on $B_N$, an analog the classical porous
medium equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03284</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Ramelli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Setzer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engelhard</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paglia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenflo</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;veler</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plewe</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atlas of the solar intensity spectrum and its center to limb variation</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Proceedings paper of the Solar Polarization
  Workshop 8, held in Florence (I), September, 12-16 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The solar limb darkening function is well known and is widely employed in
models of the solar atmosphere. However, there has been a lack of systematic
spectrally resolved measurements. Therefore we recently decided to start an
observing campaign with the Gregory Coud\'e Telescope at IRSOL in Locarno in
order to produce a spectral atlas obtained at 10 different heliocentric angles
$\theta$, chosen so that $\mu = \cos\theta$ covers the interval from 0.1 to 1.0
in step of 0.1. The measurements carried out till now include the spectral
range from 439 nm to 666 nm. The collected data provide information about the
anisotropy of the emergent radiation field on the solar surface, allowing a
better modeling of the Second Solar Spectrum. In addition the data give
observational constraints that should be taken into account when modeling the
solar atmosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03286</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Ball</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carstensen</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction of martensitic microstructures in adjacent grains</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure, submitted to ICOMAT 2017 Proceedings</comments><msc-class>74N10, 74N15, 49J45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is often observed that martensitic microstructures in adjacent polycrystal
grains are related. For example, micrographs of Arlt exhibit propagation of
layered structures across grain boundaries in the cubic-to-tetragonal phase
transformation in $\rm BaTiO_3$. Such observations are related to requirements
of compatibility of the deformation at the grain boundary. Using a
generalization of the Hadamard jump condition, this is explored in the
nonlinear elasticity model of martensitic transformations for the case of a
bicrystal with suitably oriented columnar geometry, in which the microstructure
in both grains is assumed to involve just two martensitic variants, with a
planar or non-planar interface between the grains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03290</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>Sabya Sachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masud</keyname><forenames>Mehedi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquini</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valle</keyname><forenames>J. W. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cornering the revamped BMV model with neutrino oscillation data</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>IFIC/17-XXX</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the latest global determination of neutrino oscillation parameters
from~\cite{deSalas:2017kay} we examine the status of the simplest revamped
version of the BMV (Babu-Ma-Valle) model, proposed in~\cite{Morisi:2013qna}.
The model predicts a striking correlation between the &quot;poorly determined&quot;
atmospheric angle $\theta_{23}$ and CP phase $\delta_{CP}$, leading to either
maximal CP violation or none, depending on the preferred $\theta_{23}$ octants.
We determine the allowed BMV parameter regions and compare with the general
three-neutrino oscillation scenario. We show that in the BMV model the higher
octant is possible only at $99\%$ C.L., a stronger rejection than found in the
general case. By performing quantitative simulations of forthcoming DUNE and
T2HK experiments, using only the four &quot;well-measured&quot; oscillation parameters
and the indication for normal mass ordering, we also map out the potential of
these experiments to corner the model. The resulting global sensitivities are
given in a robust form, that holds irrespective of the true values of the
oscillation parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03300</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for Close Stellar Encounters with the Solar System from Data on
  Nearby Dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Reports, Vol. 61, No 10, pp. 883-890 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S106377291710002X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Trigonometric parallaxes measured with ground-based telescopes of the RECONS
consortium as part of the CTIOPI program are used to search for stars that have
either had an encounter with the solar system in the past or will have such an
encounter in the future, at distances of less than a few parsecs. These are
mainly low-mass dwarfs and subdwarfs of types M, L, and T currently at
distances of less than 30 pc from the Sun. Six stars for which encounters with
the solar orbit at distances of less than 1 pc are possible have been
identified for the first time. For example, the minimum distance for the star
**SOZ 3A will 0.72+/- 0.11 pc at an epoch of 103+/-44 thousand years in the
future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03301</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Pedreros</keyname><forenames>G. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baquero</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity under pressure: application of the functional
  derivative</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><report-no>BAQ 02 2017 /DFM</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we calculate the superconducting critical temperature as a
function of pressure, Tc(P ), using a method based on the functional derivative
of the critical temperature with the Eliashberg function, dTc/dA2F. The coulomb
electron-electron repulsion parameter, mu*(p) at each pressure is obtained in a
consistent way by solving the linearized Migdal-Eliashberg equation. This
method requires as the starting input only the knowledge of Tc(P ) at the
starting pressure. It applies to superconductors for which the
Migdal-Eliashberg equations hold. We study Al, a typical BCS weak coupling
superconductor with a low Tc . Our results of Tc(P ) as a function of pressure
for Al show an excellent agreement with the calculations of Profeta et al.
(Phys. Rev. Lett.96, 047003 (2006)) which agree well with experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:math-ph/0405063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>math-ph/0405063</id><created>2004-05-26</created><updated>2005-03-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kalnins</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomova</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winternitz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Subgroup type coordinates and the separation of variables in
  Hamilton-Jacobi and Schr\H{o}dinger equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Nonlin. Math. Phys., 12, p. 178-208 (2005)</journal-ref><doi>10.2991/jnmp.2005.12.2.4</doi><abstract>  Separable coordinate systems are introduced in the complex and real
four-dimensional flat spaces. We use maximal Abelian subgroups to generate
coordinate systems with a maximal number of ignorable variables. The results
are presented (also graphically) in terms of subgroup chains. Finally, the
explicit solutions of the Schr\H{o}dinger equation in the separable coordinate
systems are computed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:math/9805024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>math/9805024</id><created>1998-05-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomova</keyname><forenames>Zora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winternitz</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal Abelian Subalgebras of e(p,q) algebras</title><categories>math.GR math-ph math.MP math.RA</categories><comments>29 pages, Latex</comments><report-no>CRM-2516</report-no><journal-ref>Lin. Algebra Appl., 291: 245-274 (1999)</journal-ref><abstract>  Maximal abelian subalgebras of one of the classical real inhomogeneous Lie
algebras are constructed, namely those of the pseudoeuclidean Lie algebra
e(p,q). Use is made of the semidirect sum structure of e(p,q) with the
translations T(p+q) as an abelian ideal. We first construct splitting MASAs
that are themselves direct sums of abelian subalgebras of o(p,q) and of
subalgebras of T(p+q). The splitting subalgebras are used to construct the
complementary nonsplitting ones. We present general decomposition theorems and
construct indecomposable MASAs for all algebras e(p,q), p \geq q \geq 0. The
case of q=0 and 1 were treated earlier in a physical context. The case q=2 is
analyzed here in detail as an illustration of the general results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/9707005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/9707005</id><created>1997-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomova</keyname><forenames>Zora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winternitz</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal Abelian Subgroups of the Isometry and Conformal Groups of
  Euclidean and Minkowski Spaces</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, Latex (+ latexsym)</comments><report-no>CRM-2473</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A 31: 1831-1858 (1998)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0305-4470/31/7/016</doi><abstract>  The maximal Abelian subalgebras of the Euclidean e(p,0) and pseudoeuclidean
e(p,1)Lie algebras are classified into conjugacy classes under the action of
the corresponding Lie groups E(p,0) and E(p,1), and also under the conformal
groups O(p+1,1) and O(p+1,2), respectively. The results are presented in terms
of decomposition theorems. For e(p,0) orthogonally indecomposable MASAs exist
only for p=1 and p=2. For e(p,1), on the other hand, orthogonally
indecomposable MASAs exist for all values of p. The results are used to
construct new coordinate systems in which wave equations and Hamilton-Jacobi
equations allow the separation of variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0201086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0201086</id><created>2002-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Khalique</keyname><forenames>Aeysha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saif</keyname><forenames>Farhan</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement between external degrees of freedom of atoms via Bragg
  deflection</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A. 37, 314 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0375-9601(03)00879-X</doi><abstract>  We suggest that atoms undergoing Bragg deflection from a cavity field
introduce entanglement between their external degrees of freedom. The atoms
interact with an electromagnetic cavity field which is far detuned from atomic
transition frequency and is in superposition state. We provide a set of
experimental parameters in order to perform the suggested experiment within the
frame work of the presently available technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0204047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0204047</id><created>2002-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Khalique</keyname><forenames>Aeysha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saif</keyname><forenames>Farhan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Nondemolition State Measurement via Atomic Scattering in Bragg
  Regime</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages text, 4 eps figures, to appear in letter section of journal
  of physical society of Japan</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 71, 2587 (2002)</journal-ref><doi>10.1143/JPSJ.71.2587</doi><abstract>  We suggest a quantum nondemolition scheme to measure a quantized cavity field
state using scattering of atoms in general Bragg regime. Our work extends the
QND measurement of a cavity field from Fock state, based on first order Bragg
deflection [9], to any quantum state based on Bragg deflection of arbitrary
order. In addition a set of experimental parameters is provided to perform the
experiment within the frame work of the presently available technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:solv-int/9612003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>solv-int/9612003</id><created>1996-12-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomova</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winternitz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakrzewski</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solutions of (2+1)-dimensional spin systems</title><categories>solv-int hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>TeX and phyzzx, 33 pages</comments><report-no>CRM-2373</report-no><journal-ref>J.Math.Phys. 39, 3927-3944 (1998)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.532476</doi><abstract>  We use the methods of group theory to reduce the equations of motion of two
spin systems in (2+1) dimensions to sets of coupled ordinary differential
equations. We present solutions of some classes of these sets and discuss their
physical significance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
