<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:40:23Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-08-18" from="2017-08-18" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0906.4745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0906.4745</id><created>2009-06-25</created><updated>2010-01-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bentrem</keyname><forenames>Frank W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Q-Ising model application for linear-time image segmentation</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.comp-ph physics.med-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures, revtex, uses subfigure.sty. Central European
  Journal of Physics, in press (2010)</comments><journal-ref>Open Physics, vol. 8, pp. 689-698 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.2478/s11534-009-0165-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A computational method is presented which efficiently segments digital
grayscale images by directly applying the Q-state Ising (or Potts) model. Since
the Potts model was first proposed in 1952, physicists have studied lattice
models to gain deep insights into magnetism and other disordered systems. For
some time, researchers have realized that digital images may be modeled in much
the same way as these physical systems (i.e., as a square lattice of numerical
values). A major drawback in using Potts model methods for image segmentation
is that, with conventional methods, it processes in exponential time. Advances
have been made via certain approximations to reduce the segmentation process to
power-law time. However, in many applications (such as for sonar imagery),
real-time processing requires much greater efficiency. This article contains a
description of an energy minimization technique that applies four Potts
(Q-Ising) models directly to the image and processes in linear time. The result
is analogous to partitioning the system into regions of four classes of
magnetism. This direct Potts segmentation technique is demonstrated on
photographic, medical, and acoustic images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.0394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.0394</id><created>2013-06-03</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sur</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhatia</keyname><forenames>Arshdeep Singh</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining Torsion in Maximally symmetric (sub)spaces</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages, No figures, 2 Tables</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 31 (2014) 025020</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/31/2/025020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We look into the general aspects of space-time symmetries in presence of
torsion, and how the latter is affected by such symmetries. Focusing in
particular to space-times which either exhibit maximal symmetry on their own,
or could be decomposed to maximally symmetric subspaces, we work out the
constraints on torsion in two different theoretical schemes. We show that at
least for a completely antisymmetric torsion tensor (for e.g. the one motivated
from string theory), an equivalence is set between these two schemes, as the
non-vanishing independent torsion tensor components turn out to be the same.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6608</id><created>2014-11-24</created><updated>2015-09-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Carl A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Yaoyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal security for randomness expansion from the spot-checking
  protocol</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>v3: The main result has been strengthened and the proofs rewritten.
  The paper now includes a self-contained proof of security under Renyi
  entropies (simplifying arXiv:1402.0489). 27 pages</comments><journal-ref>SIAM Journal on Computing 46, No. 4, pp. 1304-1335 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colbeck (Thesis, 2006) proposed using Bell inequality violations to generate
certified random numbers. While full quantum-security proofs have been given,
it remains a major open problem to identify the broadest class of Bell
inequalities and lowest performance requirements to achieve such security. In
this paper, working within the broad class of spot-checking protocols, we prove
exactly which Bell inequality violations can be used to achieve full security.
Our result greatly improves the known noise tolerance for secure randomness
expansion: for the commonly used CHSH game, full security was only known with a
noise tolerance of 1.5%, and we improve this to 10.3%. We also generalize our
results beyond Bell inequalities and give the first security proof for
randomness expansion based on Kochen-Specker inequalities. The central
technical contribution of the paper is a new uncertainty principle for the
Schatten norm, which is based on the uniform convexity inequality of Ball,
Carlen, and Lieb (Inventiones mathematicae, 115:463-482, 1994).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00012</id><created>2015-08-31</created><updated>2015-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buehler</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author></authors><title>Status of space-based gamma-ray astronomy</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>This article is the write-up of a rapporteur talk on &quot;Space based
  gamma-ray astronomy&quot; given at the 34th International Cosmic Ray Conference
  (19 pages, 10 figures). Accompanying articles summarize the status of related
  fields of cosmic-ray research discussed at this conference (references in the
  text)</comments><journal-ref>PoS(ICRC2015)017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gamma-ray observations give us a direct view into the most extreme
environments of the universe. They help us to study astronomical particle
accelerators as supernovae remnants, pulsars, active galaxies or gamma-ray
bursts and help us to understand the propagation of cosmic rays through our
Milky Way. This article summarizes the status of gamma-ray observations from
space; it is the write-up of a rapporteur talk given at the 34th ICRC in The
Hague, The Netherlands. The primary instrument used in the presented studies is
the Large Area Telescope on-board the Fermi Spacecraft, which images the whole
gamma-ray sky at photon energies between 20 MeV and 2 TeV. The Fermi mission is
currently in its 8th year of observations. This article will review many of the
exciting discoveries made in this time, focusing on the most recent ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01244</id><created>2016-01-06</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baldini</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiodo</keyname><forenames>Letizia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominguez</keyname><forenames>Adriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palummo</keyname><forenames>Maurizia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moser</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazdi</keyname><forenames>Meghdad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aub&#xf6;ck</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mallett</keyname><forenames>Benjamin P. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Helmuth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magrez</keyname><forenames>Arnaud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grioni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chergui</keyname><forenames>Majed</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly bound excitons in anatase TiO2 single crystals and
  nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 13 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-00016-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anatase TiO$_2$ is among the most studied materials for light-energy
conversion applications, but the nature of its fundamental charge excitations
is still unknown. Yet it is crucial to establish whether light absorption
creates uncorrelated electron-hole pairs or bound excitons and, in the latter
case, to determine their character. Here, by combining steady-state
angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy and spectroscopic ellipsometry with
state-of-the-art ab initio calculations, we demonstrate that the direct optical
gap of single crystals is dominated by a strongly bound exciton rising over the
continuum of indirect interband transitions. This exciton possesses an
intermediate character between the Wannier-Mott and Frenkel regimes and
displays a peculiar two-dimensional wavefunction in the three-dimensional
lattice. The nature of the higher-energy excitations is also identified. The
universal validity of our results is confirmed up to room temperature by
observing the same elementary excitations in defect-rich samples (doped single
crystals and nanoparticles) via ultrafast two-dimensional deep-ultraviolet
spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02508</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huaibao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagavi</keyname><forenames>Kaveh A.</forenames></author></authors><title>An introduction to the derivation of surface balance equations without
  the excruciating pain</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figures</comments><journal-ref>Martin, A., Zhang, H., and Tagavi, K. A., &quot;An introduction to a
  systematic derivation of surface balance equations without the excruciating
  pain,&quot; Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer, Vol. 115, Part A, Dec 2017, pp. 992-999</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2017.07.078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analyzing complex fluid flow problems that involve multiple coupled domains,
each with their respective set of governing equations, is not a trivial
undertaking. Even more complicated is the elaborate and tedious task of
specifying the interface and boundary conditions between various domains. This
paper provides an elegant, straightforward and universal method that considers
the nature of those shared boundaries and derives the appropriate conditions at
the interface, irrespective of the governing equations being solved. As a first
example, a well-known interface condition is derived using this method. For a
second example, the set of boundary condi- tions necessary to solve a baseline
aerothermodynamics coupled plain/porous flow problem is derived. Finally, the
method is applied to two more flow configurations, one consisting of an
impermeable adiabatic wall and the other an ablating surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03444</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Mi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Hoi-Yin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigol</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarola</keyname><forenames>Vito W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equilibration Dynamics of Strongly Interacting Bosons in 2D Lattices
  with Disorder</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 073002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.073002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent optical lattice experiments [J.-y. Choi et al., Science
352, 1547 (2016)], we study the dynamics of strongly interacting bosons in the
presence of disorder in two dimensions. We show that Gutzwiller mean-field
theory (GMFT) captures the main experimental observations, which are a result
of the competition between disorder and interactions. Our findings highlight
the difficulty in distinguishing glassy dynamics, which can be captured by
GMFT, and many-body localization, which cannot be captured by GMFT, and
indicate the need for further experimental studies of this system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06212</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carson</keyname><forenames>Zaq</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hampton</keyname><forenames>Shaun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathur</keyname><forenames>Samir D.</forenames></author></authors><title>One-Loop Transition Amplitudes in the D1D5 CFT</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>58 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the issue of thermalization in the D1D5 CFT. Thermalization is
expected to correspond to the formation of a black hole in the dual gravity
theory. We start from the orbifold point, where the theory is essentially free,
and does not thermalize. In earlier work it was noted that there was no clear
thermalization effect when the theory was deformed off the orbifold point to
first order in the relevant twist perturbation. In this paper we consider the
deformation to second order in the twist, where we do find effects that can
cause thermalization of an initial perturbation. We consider a 1-loop process
where two untwisted copies of the CFT are twisted to one copy and then again
untwisted to two copies. We start with a single oscillator excitation on the
initial CFT, and compute the effect of the two twists on this state. We find
simple approximate expressions for the Bogoliubov coefficients and the behavior
of the single oscillator excitation in the continuum limit, where the mode
numbers involved are taken to be much larger than unity. We also prove a number
of useful relationships valid for processes with an arbitrary number of twist
insertions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00430</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gazzola</keyname><forenames>Mattia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dudte</keyname><forenames>Levi H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCormick</keyname><forenames>Andrew G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahadevan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational mechanics of soft filaments</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Soft slender structures are ubiquitous in natural and artificial systems and
can be observed at scales that range from the nanometric to the kilometric,
from polymers to space tethers. We present a practical numerical approach to
simulate the dynamics of filaments that, at every cross-section, can undergo
all six possible modes of deformation, allowing the filament to bend, twist,
stretch and shear, while interacting with complex environments via muscular
activity, surface contact, friction and hydrodynamics. We examine the accuracy
of our method by means of several benchmark problems with known analytic
solutions. We then demonstrate the capabilities and robustness of our approach
to solve forward problems in physics and mechanics related to solenoid and
plectoneme formation in twisted, stretched filaments, and inverse problems
related to active biophysics of limbless locomotion on solid surfaces and in
bulk liquids. All together, our approach provides a robust computational
framework to characterize the mechanical response and design of soft active
slender structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01052</id><created>2016-08-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Dae-Yup</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-lying energy bands in a finite periodic multiple-well potential</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Eur. J. Phys. 38 (2017) 055401</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6404/aa7b68</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the low-lying states for a one-dimensional potential consisting of
$N$ identical wells, assuming that the wells are parabolic around the minima.
Matching the exact wave functions around the minima and the WKB wave functions
in the barriers, we find a quantization condition which is then solved to give
a formula for the energy eigenvalues explicitly written in terms of the
potential. In addition, constructing $N$ localized approximate eigenstates each
of which matches on to that of the harmonic oscillator in one of the parabolic
wells, and diagonalizing the Hamiltonian in the subspace spanned by the
localized states on the assumption that the localized states form an orthogonal
basis, we also find the same formula for the energy eigenvalues which the
method of matching the wave functions gives. In the large-$N$ limit, the
formula reproduces, at the leading order, the expression for the widths of the
narrow energy bands of the Mathieu equation present in the mathematical
literature. As there are differences between the $N$-well system in the
large-$N$ limit and the fully periodic system, we include a two-dimensional
model in which the quadratic minima are located on the vertices of a regular
$N$-sided polygon with rotational symmetry of order $N$. We argue that the
lowest band of the two-dimensional model closely resembles the tight-binding
energy bands of the fully periodic one-dimensional system in that most of the
eigenvalues are degenerate in the large-$N$ limit with the eigenfunctions
satisfying the Bloch condition under the discrete rotations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03145</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tlusty</keyname><forenames>Tsvi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libchaber</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckmann</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical model of the genotype-to-phenotype map of proteins</title><categories>physics.bio-ph nlin.AO q-bio.BM</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021037 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How DNA is mapped to functional proteins is a basic question of living
matter. We introduce and study a physical model of protein evolution which
suggests a mechanical basis for this map. Many proteins rely on large-scale
motion to function. We therefore treat protein as learning amorphous matter
that evolves towards such a mechanical function: Genes are binary sequences
that encode the connectivity of the amino acid network that makes a protein.
The gene is evolved until the network forms a shear band across the protein,
which allows for long-range, soft modes required for protein function. The
evolution reduces the high-dimensional sequence space to a low-dimensional
space of mechanical modes, in accord with the observed dimensional reduction
between genotype and phenotype of proteins. Spectral analysis of the space of
$10^6$ solutions shows a strong correspondence between localization around the
shear band of both mechanical modes and the sequence structure. Specifically,
our model shows how mutations of the gene and their correlations occur at amino
acids whose interactions determine the functional mode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08889</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferraro</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhorukov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction effects in a multi-channel Fabry-P\'erot interferometer in
  the Aharonov-Bohm regime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>20 pages (single column), 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.2.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a Fabry-P\'erot interferometer in the integer Hall regime in
which only one edge channel is transmitted and n channels are trapped into the
interferometer loop. Addressing recent experimental observations, we assume
that Coulomb blockade effects are completely suppressed due to screening, while
keeping track of a residual strong short range electron-electron interaction
between the co-propagating edge channels trapped into the interferometer loop.
This kind of interaction can be completely described in the framework of the
edge-magnetoplasmon scattering matrix theory allowing us to evaluate the
backscattering current and the associated differential conductance as a
function of the bias voltage. The remarkable features of these quantities are
discussed as a function of the number of trapped channels. The developed
formalism reveals very general and provides also a simple way to model the
experimentally relevant geometry in which some of the trapped channels are
absorbed into an Ohmic contact, leading to energy dissipation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04137</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Midya</keyname><forenames>Jiarul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Subir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size scaling study of dynamic critical phenomena in a
  vapor-liquid transition</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4974506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Via a combination of molecular dynamics (MD) simulations and finite-size
scaling (FSS) analysis, we study dynamic critical phenomena for the
vapor-liquid transition in a three dimensional Lennard-Jones system. The phase
behavior of the model, including the critical point, have been obtained via the
Monte Carlo simulations. The transport properties, viz., the bulk viscosity and
the thermal conductivity, are calculated via the Green-Kubo relations, by
taking inputs from the MD simulations in the microcanonical ensemble. The
critical singularities of these quantities are estimated via the FSS method.
The results thus obtained are in nice agreement with the predictions of the
dynamic renormalization group and mode-coupling theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06173</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bilmes</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanker</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heimes</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marthaler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;n</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ustinov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisenfeld</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic Decoherence of Two-Level Systems in a Josephson Junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 064504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensitivity of superconducting qubits allows for spectroscopy and
coherence measurements on individual two-level systems present in the
disordered tunnel barrier of an $\mathrm{Al/AlO_x/Al}$ Josephson junction. We
report experimental evidence for the decoherence of two-level systems by
Bogoliubov quasiparticles leaking into the insulating $\mathrm{AlO_x}$ barrier.
We control the density of quasiparticles in the junction electrodes either by
the sample temperature or by injecting them using an on-chip dc-SQUID driven to
its resistive state. The decoherence rates were measured by observing the
two-level system's quantum state evolving under application of resonant
microwave pulses and were found to increase linearly with quasiparticle
density, in agreement with theory. This interaction with electronic states
provides a noise and decoherence mechanism that is relevant for various
microfabricated devices such as qubits, single-electron transistors, and
field-effect transistors. The presented experiments also offer a possibility to
determine the location of the probed two-level systems across the tunnel
barrier, providing clues about the fabrication step in which they emerge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07496</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alhambra</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvaro M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Mischa P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical maps, quantum detailed balance and Petz recovery map</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>main text: 5 pages. Appendix: 11 pages. V3: The conjectures in V2
  have been proven. This is close to the journal published version, but with
  improved citations</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 022118 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.022118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Markovian master equations (formally known as quantum dynamical semigroups)
can be used to describe the evolution of a quantum state $\rho$ when in contact
with a memoryless thermal bath. This approach has had much success in
describing the dynamics of real-life open quantum systems in the lab. Such
dynamics increase the entropy of the state $\rho$ and the bath until both
systems reach thermal equilibrium, at which point entropy production stops. Our
main result is to show that the entropy production at time $t$ is bounded by
the relative entropy between the original state and the state at time $2t$. The
bound puts strong constraints on how quickly a state can thermalise, and we
prove that the factor of $2$ is tight. The proof makes use of a key physically
relevant property of these dynamical semigroups -- detailed balance, showing
that this property is intimately connected with the field of recovery maps from
quantum information theory. We envisage that the connections made here between
the two fields will have further applications. We also use this connection to
show that a similar relation can be derived when the fixed point is not
thermal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07584</id><created>2016-09-24</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paolucci</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timossi</keyname><forenames>Giuliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solinas</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giazotto</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent Manipulation of Thermal Transport by Tunable Electron-Photon
  and Electron-Phonon Interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 121, 244305 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4990286</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a system where coherent thermal transport between two reservoirs
in non-galvanic contact is modulated by independently tuning the
electron-photon and the electron-phonon coupling. The scheme is based on two
gate-controlled electrodes capacitively coupled through a dc-SQUID as
intermediate phase-tunable resonator. Thereby the electron-photon interaction
is modulated by controlling the flux threading the dc-SQUID and the impedance
of the two reservoirs, while the electron-phonon coupling is tuned by
controlling the charge carrier concentration in the electrodes. To
quantitatively evaluate the behavior of the system we propose to exploit
graphene reservoirs. In this case, the scheme can work at temperatures reaching
1 K, with unprecedented temperature modulations as large as 245 mK,
transmittance up to 99% and energy conversion efficiency up to 50%. Finally,
the accuracy of heat transport control allows to use this system as an
experimental tool to determine the electron-phonon coupling in two dimensional
electronic systems (2DES).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05364</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yanpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Wujun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumov</keyname><forenames>Pavel G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Nitesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sankar</keyname><forenames>Raman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnelle</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shekhar</keyname><forenames>Chandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Binghai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medvedev</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological quantum phase transition and superconductivity induced by
  pressure in the bismuth tellurohalide BiTeI</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Main text + Supplementary Information</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Mater. 2017, 29, 1605965</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adma.201605965</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A pressure-induced topological quantum phase transition has been
theoretically predicted for the semiconductor BiTeI with giant Rashba spin
splitting. In this work, the evolution of the electrical transport properties
in BiTeI and BiTeBr is investigated under high pressure. The pressure-dependent
resistivity in a wide temperature range passes through a minimum at around 3
GPa, indicating the predicted transition in BiTeI. Superconductivity is
observed in both BiTeI and BiTeBr while the resistivity at higher temperatures
still exhibits semiconducting behavior. Theoretical calculations suggest that
the superconductivity may develop from the multi-valley semiconductor phase.
The superconducting transition temperature Tc increases with applied pressure
and reaches a maximum value of 5.2 K at 23.5 GPa for BiTeI (4.8 K at 31.7 GPa
for BiTeBr), followed by a slow decrease. Our results demonstrate that BiTeX (X
= I, Br) compounds with non-trivial topology of electronic states display new
ground states upon compression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08232</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Puthumpally-Joseph</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viau-Trudel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen-Dang</keyname><forenames>T. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atabek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charron</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser-Induced Electron Diffraction: Inversion of Photoelectron Spectra
  for Molecular Orbital Imaging</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Molecular Physics 115, 1889 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00268976.2017.1290837</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we discuss the possibility of imaging molecular orbitals from
photoelectron spectra obtained via Laser Induced Electron Diffraction (LIED) in
linear molecules. This is an extension of our work published recently in
Physical Review A \textbf{94}, 023421 (2016) to the case of the HOMO-1 orbital
of the carbon dioxide molecule. We show that such an imaging technique has the
potential to image molecular orbitals at different internuclear distances in a
sub-femtosecond time scale and with a resolution of a fraction of an
Angstr\&quot;om.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08234</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen-Dang</keyname><forenames>T. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viau-Trudel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couture-Bienvenue</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puthumpally-Joseph</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charron</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atabek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser-Induced Electron Diffraction: Alignment Defects and Symmetry
  Breaking</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Molecular Physics 115, 1934 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00268976.2017.1317858</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fringe pattern that allows geometrical and orbital structure information
to be extracted from LIED spectra of symmetric molecules is shown to reflect a
symmetry conservation principle. We show that under a field polarization which
preserves certain symmetry elements of the molecule, the symmetry character of
the initial wave function is conserved during its time-evolution. We present a
symmetry analysis of a deviation from a perfect alignment by decomposing the
field into a major, symmetry-determining part, and a minor, symmetry breaking,
part. This decomposition leads to a corresponding factorization of the
time-evolution operator. The formalism is applied to the analysis of the
robustness of LIED readings and inversions with respect to deviations from a
perfect perpendicular and parallel alignment of a symmetric ABA triatomic
molecule. The results indicate a particularly strong stability of the type of
LIED spectra associated with the perpendicular alignment situation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00654</id><created>2016-11-02</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sur</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhatia</keyname><forenames>Arshdeep Singh</forenames></author></authors><title>Weakly dynamic dark energy via metric-scalar couplings with torsion</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>39 pages, 16 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1707 (2017) 039</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamical aspects of dark energy in the context of a
non-minimally coupled scalar field with curvature and torsion. Whereas the
scalar field acts as the source of the trace mode of torsion, a suitable
constraint on the torsion pseudo-trace provides a mass term for the scalar
field in the effective action. In the equivalent scalar-tensor framework, we
find explicit cosmological solutions representing dark energy in both Einstein
and Jordan frames. We demand the dynamical evolution of the dark energy to be
weak enough, so that the present-day values of the cosmological parameters
could be estimated keeping them within the confidence limits set for the
standard $\L$CDM model from recent observations. For such estimates, we examine
the variations of the effective matter density and the dark energy equation of
state parameters over different redshift ranges. In spite of being weakly
dynamic, the dark energy component differs significantly from the cosmological
constant, both in characteristics and features, for e.g. it interacts with the
cosmological (dust) fluid in the Einstein frame, and crosses the phantom
barrier in the Jordan frame. We also obtain the upper bounds on the torsion
mode parameters and the lower bound on the effective Brans-Dicke parameter. The
latter turns out to be fairly large, and in agreement with the local gravity
constraints, which therefore come in support of our analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04252</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Arijit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>Arun M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emerging trends in Topological Insulator and Topological Superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>This is the published version of the popular article written for
  &quot;Resonance&quot;. A very pedagogical discussion on the subject is presented</comments><journal-ref>Resonance, Vol. 22, No. 8, pp. 787-800, (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological insulators are new class of materials which are characterized by
a bulk band gap like ordinary band insulator but have protected conducting
states on their edge or surface. These states emerge out due to the combination
of spin-orbit coupling and time reversal symmetry. Also these states are
insensitive to scattering by non-magnetic impurities. A two-dimensional (2D)
topological insulator has one dimensional (1D) edge states in which the
spin-momentum locking of the electrons gives rise to quantum spin Hall effect.
A three-dimensional (3D) topological insulator supports novel spin-polarized 2D
Dirac fermions on its surface. These topological insulator materials have been
theoretically predicted and experimentally observed in a variety of 2D and 3D
systems, including $\rm HgTe$ quantum wells, $\rm BiSb$ alloys, and $\rm
Bi_{2}Te_{3}$, $\rm Bi_{2}Se_{3}$ crystals. Moreover, proximity induced
superconductivity in these systems can lead to a state that supports zero
energy Majorana fermion and the phase is known as topological superconductors.
In this article, the basic idea of topological insulators and topological
superconductors are presented along with their experimental development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05812</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-08-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pe&#xf1;afiel</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravera</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Infinite S-Expansion with Ideal Subtraction and Some Applications</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>43 pages, title and abstract modified to better represent the
  content, some sections clarified. Version accepted for publication in Journal
  of Mathematical Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 58, 081701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4991378</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to the literature, the S-expansion procedure involving a finite
semigroup is valid no matter what the structure of the original Lie
(super)algebra is; However, when something about the structure of the starting
(super)algebra is known and when certain particular conditions are met, the
S-expansion method (with its features of resonance and reduction) is able not
only to lead to several kinds of expanded (super)algebras, but also to
reproduce the effects of the standard as well as the generalized
In\&quot;on\&quot;u-Wigner contraction. In the present paper, we propose a new
prescription for S-expansion, involving an infinite abelian semigroup
$S^{(\infty)}$ and the subtraction of an infinite ideal subalgebra. We show
that the subtraction of the infinite ideal subalgebra corresponds to a
reduction. Our approach is a generalization of the finite S-expansion procedure
presented in the literature, and it offers an alternative view of the
generalized In\&quot;on\&quot;u-Wigner contraction. We then show how to write the
invariant tensors of the target (super)algebras in terms of those of the
starting ones in the infinite S-expansion context presented in this work. We
also give some interesting examples of application on algebras and
superalgebras.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02026</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02026</id><created>2016-12-06</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bashkirov</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronov</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On homotopy Lie bialgebroids</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, 1 figure; the new version is significantly revised</comments><report-no>IPMU16-0198</report-no><msc-class>53D17 (Primary), 16E45, 18G55, 58A50 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A well-known result of A. Vaintrob characterizes Lie algebroids and their
morphisms in terms of homological vector fields on supermanifolds. We give an
interpretation of Lie bialgebroids and their morphisms in terms of odd
symplectic dg-manifolds, building on the approach of D. Roytenberg. This
extends naturally to the homotopy Lie case and leads to the notion of
$L_\infty$-bialgebroids and $L_\infty$-morphisms between them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03437</id><created>2016-12-11</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abu-Shady</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effect of Strange Quark on the Chiral Symmetry Breaking in Magnetic
  Background in the framework of logarithmic quark-sigma model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1507.01372, arXiv:1612.02151</comments><journal-ref>Open Access Scifed Journal of Quantum Physics 1, 1-6 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The chiral symmetry breaking in the presence of an external magnetic field is
studied in the framework of logarithmic quark-sigma model with three flavors
(u,d,s). The effective logarithmic mesonic potential is extended to strange
quark and is numerically solved in the mean-field approximation. The present
results show that the chiral symmetry breaking is sensitive for the strange
quark flavour in the presence an external magnetic field. In addition, the
effect of the free parameters is studied. A comparison with original sigma
model is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00174</id><created>2016-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Sukharev</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charron</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular plasmonics: the role of ro-vibrational molecular states in
  exciton-plasmon materials under strong coupling conditions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.comp-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, submitted to PRB</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 95, 115406 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the model of exciton-plasmon materials to include a ro-vibrational
structure of molecules using wave-packet propagations on electronic potential
energy surfaces. The new model replaces conventional two-level emitters with
more complex molecules allowing to examine the influence of alignment and
vibrational dynamics on strong coupling with surface plasmon-polaritons. We
apply the model to a hybrid system comprising a thin layer of molecules placed
on top of a periodic array of slits. Rigorous simulations are performed for two
types of molecular systems described by vibrational bound-bound and
bound-continuum electronic transitions. Calculations reveal new features in
transmission, reflection and absorption spectra including the observation of
significantly higher values of the Rabi splitting and vibrational patterns
clearly seen in the corresponding spectra. We also examine the influence of
anisotropic initial conditions on optical properties of hybrid materials
demonstrating that the optical response of the system is significantly affected
by an initial pre-alignment of the molecules. Our work demonstrates that
pre-aligned molecules could serve as an efficient probe for the sub-diffraction
characterization of the near-field near metal interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01826</id><created>2017-01-07</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salewski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poltavtsev</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yugova</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karczewski</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiater</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wojtowicz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakovlev</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akimov</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>High resolution two-dimensional optical spectroscopy of electron spins</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev X 7, 031030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.031030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multidimensional coherent optical spectroscopy is one of the most powerful
tools for investigating complex quantum mechanical systems. While it was
conceived decades ago in magnetic resonance spectroscopy using micro- and
radio-waves, it has recently been extended into the visible and UV spectral
range. However, resolving MHz energy splittings with ultrashort laser pulses
has still remained a challenge. Here, we analyze two-dimensional Fourier
spectra for resonant optical excitation of resident electrons to localized
trions or donor-bound excitons in semiconductor nanostructures subject to a
transverse magnetic field. Particular attention is devoted to Raman coherence
spectra which allow one to accurately evaluate tiny splittings of the electron
ground state and to determine the relaxation times in the electron spin
ensemble. A stimulated step-like Raman process induced by a sequence of two
laser pulses creates a coherent superposition of the ground state doublet which
can be retrieved only optically due to selective excitation of the same
sub-ensemble with a third pulse. This provides the unique opportunity to
distinguish between different complexes that are closely spaced in energy in an
ensemble. The related experimental demonstration is based on photon echo
measurements in an n-type CdTe/(Cd,Mg)Te quantum well structure detected by a
heterodyne technique. The difference in the sub-$\mu$eV range between the
Zeeman splittings of donor-bound electrons and electrons localized at potential
fluctuations can be resolved even though the homogeneous linewidth of the
optical transitions is larger by two orders of magnitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01914</id><created>2017-01-07</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shiraishi</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tajima</keyname><forenames>Hiroyasu</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficiency versus Speed in Quantum Heat Engines: Rigorous Constraint
  from Lieb-Robinson Bound</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 022138 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.022138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A long standing open problem whether a heat engine with finite power achieves
the Carnot efficiency is investigated. We rigorously prove a general trade-off
inequality on thermodynamic efficiency and time interval of a cyclic process
with quantum heat engines. In a first step, employing the Lieb-Robinson bound
we establish an inequality on the change in a local observable caused by an
operation far from support of the local observable. This inequality provides a
rigorous characterization of the following intuitive picture that most of the
energy released from the engine to the cold bath remains near the engine when
the cyclic process is finished. Using the above description, we finally prove
an upper bound on efficiency with the aid of quantum information geometry. In
addition, since our inequality falls down into the conventional second law of
thermodynamics in Markovian limit, we adopt a completely different treatment
which is developed in the context of classical stochastic processes. Our result
generally excludes the possibility of a process with finite speed at the Carnot
efficiency in quantum heat engines. In particular, the obtained constraint
covers engines evolving with non-Markovian dynamics, which almost all previous
studies on this topics fail to address.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01267</id><created>2017-02-04</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhatia</keyname><forenames>Arshdeep Singh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sur</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical system analysis of dark energy models in scalar coupled
  metric-torsion theories</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>34 pages, 4 tables, 9 figures (26 plots in all)</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D 26 (2017) 1750149</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817501498</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the phase space dynamics of cosmological models in the theoretical
formulations of non-minimal metric-torsion couplings with a scalar field, and
investigate in particular the critical points which yield stable solutions
exhibiting cosmic acceleration driven by the {\em dark energy}. The latter is
defined in a way that it effectively has no direct interaction with the
cosmological fluid, although in an equivalent scalar-tensor cosmological setup
the scalar field interacts with the fluid (which we consider to be the
pressureless dust). Determining the conditions for the existence of the stable
critical points we check their physical viability, in both Einstein and Jordan
frames. We also verify that in either of these frames, the evolution of the
universe at the corresponding stable points matches with that given by the
respective exact solutions we have found in an earlier work (arXiv: 1611.00654
[gr-qc]). We not only examine the regions of physical relevance for the
trajectories in the phase space when the coupling parameter is varied, but also
demonstrate the evolution profiles of the cosmological parameters of interest
along fiducial trajectories in the effectively non-interacting scenarios, in
both Einstein and Jordan frames.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02058</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Lun-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chih-Chieh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fu-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Charge/spin density Wave in InAs/GaSb Quantum Wells under an
  In-plane Magnetic Field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 Pages, 3 figures. Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075130 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study interaction effect of quantum spin Hall state in InAs/GaSb quantum
wells under an in-plane magnetic field by using the self-consistent mean field
theory. We construct a phase diagram as a function of intra-layer and
inter-layer interactions, and identify two novel phases, a charge/spin density
wave phase and an exciton condensate phase. The charge/spin density wave phase
is topologically non-trivial with helical edge transport at the boundary, while
the exciton condensate phase is topologically trivial. The Zeeman effect is
strongly renormalized due to interaction in certain parameter regimes of the
system, leading to a much smaller g-factor, which may stabilize the helical
edge transport.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02245</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jae-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boeuf</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takagi</keyname><forenames>Shinichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takenaka</keyname><forenames>Mitsuru</forenames></author></authors><title>High-modulation-efficiency InGaAsP/Si hybrid MOS optical modulator with
  Mach-Zehnder interferometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures for the main manuscript. 22 pages, 16 figures for
  the supplementary</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 11, 486-490 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2017.122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A high-modulation-efficiency optical modulator integrated on silicon (Si) is
a key enabler for low-power and high-capacity optical interconnects. However,
Si-based optical modulators suffer from low phase modulation efficiency owing
to the weak plasma dispersion effect in Si. Therefore, it is essential to find
a novel modulation scheme that is compatible with a Si photonics platform.
Here, we demonstrate an InGaAsP/Si hybrid metal-oxide-semiconductor (MOS)
optical modulator with a Mach-Zehnder interferometer (MZI) formed by direct
wafer bonding with an Al2O3 bonding interface. Electron accumulation at the
InGaAsP MOS interface enables the extraction of the electron-induced refractive
index change in InGaAsP, which is significantly greater than that in Si. The
presented modulator exhibits a phase modulation efficiency of 0.047 Vcm, which
is approximately 5 times higher than that of Si MOS optical modulators. This
approach provides a new efficient scheme of phase modulation on a Si photonics
platform for low-power, high-speed, and high-density optical links.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02674</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Fangzhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louie</keyname><forenames>Steven G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Phases in Graphene Nanoribbons: Junction States, Spin
  Centers and Quantum Spin Chains</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 076401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.076401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Knowledge of the topology of the electronic ground state of materials has led
to deep insights to novel phenomena such as the integer quantum Hall effect and
fermion-number fractionalization, as well as other properties of matter.
Joining two insulators of different topological classes produces fascinating
boundary states in the band gap. Another exciting recent development is the
bottom-up synthesis (from molecular precursors) of graphene nanoribbons (GNRs)
with atomic precision control of their edge and width. Here we connect these
two fields, and show for the first time that semiconducting GNRs of different
width, edge, and end termination belong to different topological classes. The
topology of GNRs is protected by spatial symmetries and dictated by the
terminating unit cell. We have derived explicit formula for their topological
invariants, and show that localized junction states developed between two GNRs
of distinct topology may be tuned by lateral junction geometry. The topology of
a GNR can be further modified by dopants, such as a periodic array of boron
atoms. In a superlattice consisted of segments of doped and pristine GNRs, the
junction states are stable spin centers, forming a Heisenberg antiferromagnetic
spin 1/2 chain with tunable exchange interaction. The discoveries here are not
only of scientific interest for studies of quasi one-dimensional systems, but
also open a new path for design principles of future GNR-based devices through
their topological characters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07809</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheung</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>Ramona</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarized Heavy Quarkonium Production in the Color Evaporation Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 074021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.074021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore polarized heavy quarkonium production using the color evaporation
model at leading order. We present the polarized to total yield ratio as a
function of center of mass energy and rapidity in $p+p$ collisions. At energies
far above the $Q \overline Q$ production threshold, we find charmonium and
bottomonium production to be longitudinally polarized ($J_z=0$). The quarkonium
states are also longitudinally polarized at central rapidity, becoming
transversely polarized ($J_z=\pm1$) at the most forward rapidities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08365</id><created>2017-02-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Oliva-Leyva</keyname><forenames>Maurice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chumin</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-energy theory for strained graphene: an approach up to second-order
  in the strain tensor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>To appear in Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 165301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa62c9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An analytical study of low-energy electronic excited states in an uniformly
strained graphene is carried out up to second-order in the strain tensor. We
report an new effective Dirac Hamiltonian with an anisotropic Fermi velocity
tensor, which reveals the graphene trigonal symmetry being absent in low-energy
theories to first-order in the strain tensor. In particular, we demonstrate the
dependence of the Dirac-cone elliptical deformation on the stretching direction
respect to graphene lattice orientation. We further analytically calculate the
optical conductivity tensor of strained graphene and its transmittance for a
linearly polarized light with normal incidence. Finally, the obtained
analytical expression of the Dirac point shift allows a better determination
and understanding of pseudomagnetic fields induced by nonuniform strains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08710</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nirov</keyname><forenames>Khazret S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Razumov</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Highest $\ell$-Weight Representations and Functional Relations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 043, 31 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.043</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss highest $\ell$-weight representations of quantum loop algebras and
the corresponding functional relations between integrability objects. In
particular, we compare the prefundamental and $q$-oscillator representations of
the positive Borel subalgebras of the quantum group $\mathrm{U}_q(\mathcal
L(\mathfrak{sl}_{l+1}))$ for arbitrary values of $l$. Our article has partially
the nature of a short review, but it also contains new results. These are the
expressions for the $L$-operators, and the exact relationship between different
representations, as a byproduct resulting in certain conclusions about
functional relations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02828</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-08-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Masahiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Nobuto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Kunihiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Stronger selection can slow down evolution driven by recombination on a
  smooth fitness landscape</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>PLoS ONE 12(8): e0183120 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0183120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stronger selection implies faster evolution---that is, the greater the force,
the faster the change. This apparently self-evident proposition, however, is
derived under the assumption that genetic variation within a population is
primarily supplied by mutation (i.e.\ mutation-driven evolution). Here, we show
that this proposition does not actually hold for recombination-driven
evolution, i.e.\ evolution in which genetic variation is primarily created by
recombination rather than mutation. By numerically investigating population
genetics models of recombination, migration and selection, we demonstrate that
stronger selection can slow down evolution on a perfectly smooth fitness
landscape. Through simple analytical calculation, this apparently
counter-intuitive result is shown to stem from two opposing effects of natural
selection on the rate of evolution. On the one hand, natural selection tends to
increase the rate of evolution by increasing the fixation probability of fitter
genotypes. On the other hand, natural selection tends to decrease the rate of
evolution by decreasing the chance of recombination between immigrants and
resident individuals. As a consequence of these opposing effects, there is a
finite selection pressure maximizing the rate of evolution. Hence, stronger
selection can imply slower evolution if genetic variation is primarily supplied
by recombination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07530</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Isi</keyname><forenames>Maximiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitkin</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinstein</keyname><forenames>Alan J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Dynamical Gravity with the Polarization of Continuous
  Gravitational Waves</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>27 pages, 23 figures</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1600305</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 042001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.042001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The direct detection of gravitational waves provides the opportunity to
measure fundamental aspects of gravity which have never been directly probed
before, including the polarization of gravitational waves. In the context of
searches for continuous waves from known pulsars, we present novel methods to
detect signals of any polarization content, measure the modes present and place
upper-limits on the amplitude of non-tensorial components. This will allow us
to obtain new model-independent, dynamical constraints on deviations from
general relativity. We test this framework on multiple potential sources using
simulated data from three advanced-era detectors at design sensitivity. We find
that signals of any polarization will become detectable and distinguishable for
characteristic strains $h\gtrsim 3\times10^{-27} \sqrt{1~{\rm yr}/T}$, for an
observation time $T$. We also find that our ability to detect non-tensorial
components depends only on the power present in those modes, irrespective of
the strength of the tensorial strain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08272</id><created>2017-03-23</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>DeBrota</keyname><forenames>John B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negativity Bounds for Weyl-Heisenberg Quasiprobability Representations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages. v2: journal version, added references</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, 47 (8), 1009-1030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-017-0098-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The appearance of negative terms in quasiprobability representations of
quantum theory is known to be inevitable, and, due to its equivalence with the
onset of contextuality, of central interest in quantum computation and
information. Until recently, however, nothing has been known about how much
negativity is necessary in a quasiprobability representation. Zhu proved that
the upper and lower bounds with respect to one type of negativity measure are
saturated by quasiprobability representations which are in one-to-one
correspondence with the elusive symmetric informationally complete quantum
measurements (SICs). We define a family of negativity measures which includes
Zhu's as a special case and consider another member of the family which we call
&quot;sum negativity.&quot; We prove a sufficient condition for local maxima in sum
negativity and find exact global maxima in dimensions $3$ and $4$. Notably, we
find that Zhu's result on the SICs does not generally extend to sum negativity,
although the analogous result does hold in dimension $4$. Finally, the Hoggar
lines in dimension $8$ make an appearance in a conjecture on sum negativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10322</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chhiber</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subedi</keyname><forenames>Prachanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usmanov</keyname><forenames>Arcadi V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthaeus</keyname><forenames>William H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruffolo</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Melvyn L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parashar</keyname><forenames>Tulasi N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Ray Diffusion Coefficients Throughout The Inner Heliosphere From
  Global Solar Wind Simulation</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, Volume 230, Number 2
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa74d2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulation of the solar wind
to calculate cosmic ray diffusion coefficients throughout the inner heliosphere
($2~R_\odot - 3$ AU). The simulation resolves large-scale solar wind flow,
which is coupled to small-scale fluctuations through a turbulence model.
Simulation results specify background solar wind fields and turbulence
parameters, which are used to compute diffusion coefficients and study their
behavior in the inner heliosphere. The parallel mean free path is evaluated
using quasi-linear theory, while the perpendicular mean free path is determined
by non-linear guiding center theory with the random ballistic interpretation.
Several runs examine varying turbulent energy and different solar source dipole
tilts. We find that for most of the inner heliosphere, the radial mean free
path (mfp) is dominated by diffusion parallel to the mean magnetic field; the
parallel mfp remains at least an order of magnitude larger than the
perpendicular mfp, except in the heliospheric current sheet, where the
perpendicular mfp may be a few times larger than the parallel mfp; in the
ecliptic region, the perpendicular mfp may influence the radial mfp at
heliocentric distances larger than 1.5 AU; our estimations of the parallel mfp
in the ecliptic region at 1 AU agree well with the Palmer &quot;consensus&quot; range of
$0.08 - 0.3$ AU; solar activity increases perpendicular diffusion and reduces
parallel diffusion; the parallel mfp varies with rigidity $(P)$ as $P^{.33}$,
and the perpendicular mfp is weakly dependent on $P$; the mfps are weakly
influenced by the choice of long wavelength power spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00101</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baragiola</keyname><forenames>Ben Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum trajectories for propagating Fock states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 023819 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.023819</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive quantum trajectories (also known as stochastic master equations)
that describe an arbitrary quantum system probed by a propagating wave packet
of light prepared in a continuous-mode Fock state. We consider three detection
schemes of the output light: photon counting, homodyne detection, and
heterodyne detection. We generalize to input field states that are
superpositions and or mixtures of Fock states and illustrate the formalism with
several examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00422</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-05-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nazarenko</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blavatska</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymmetric Random Walk in a One-Dimensional Multi-Zone Environment</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ukr. J. Phys. 62(6), pp.508-517 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ujpe62.06.0508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a random walk model in a one-dimensional environment, formed by
several zones of finite width with the fixed transition probabilities. It is
also assumed that the transitions to the left and right neighboring points have
unequal probabilities. In continuous limit, we derive analytically the
probability distribution function, which is mainly determined by a walker
diffusion and drift and accounts perturbatively for interface effects between
zones. It is used for computing the probability to find a walker in a given
space-time point and the time dependence of the mean squared displacement of a
walker, which reveals the transient anomalous diffusion. To justify our
approach, the probability function is compared with the results of numerical
simulations for a three-zone environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01530</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the $k_\mathrm{t}$ splitting scales in $Z \to \ell\ell$
  events in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>42 pages in total, author list starting page 26, 8 figures, 1 table,
  published in JHEP, All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2015-14/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2017-033</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP08 (2017) 026</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2017)026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement of the splitting scales occuring in the $k_\mathrm{t}$
jet-clustering algorithm is presented for final states containing a $Z$ boson.
The measurement is done using 20.2 fb$^{-1}$ of proton-proton collision data
collected at a centre-of-mass energy of $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV by the ATLAS
experiment at the LHC in 2012. The measurement is based on charged-particle
track information, which is measured with excellent precision in the
$p_\mathrm{T}$ region relevant for the transition between the perturbative and
the non-perturbative regimes. The data distributions are corrected for detector
effects, and are found to deviate from state-of-the-art predictions in various
regions of the observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01743</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Micheletti</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orland</keyname><forenames>Henri</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient sampling of knotting-unknotting pathways for semiflexible
  Gaussian chains</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Polymers, vol. 9, p. 196 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/polym9060196</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a stochastic method to generate exactly the overdamped Langevin
dynamics of semi-flexible Gaussian chains, conditioned to evolve between given
initial and final conformations in a preassigned time. The initial and final
conformations have no restrictions, and hence can be in any knotted state. Our
method allows the generation of statistically independent paths in a
computationally efficient manner. We show that these conditioned paths can be
exactly generated by a set of local stochastic differential equations. The
method is used to analyze the transition routes between various knots in
crossable filamentous structures, thus mimicking topological reconnections
occurring in soft matter systems or those introduced in DNA by topoisomerase
enzymes. We find that the average number of crossings, writhe and unknotting
number are not necessarily monotonic in time and that more complex topologies
than the initial and final ones can be visited along the route.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02857</id><created>2017-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Grenz</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;hler</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiesendanger</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the Nanoskyrmion Lattice on Fe/Ir(111) with Magnetic Exchange
  Force Microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 047205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.047205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that the magnetic nanoskyrmion lattice on the Fe monolayer on
Ir(111) and the positions of the Fe atoms can be resolved simultaneously using
magnetic exchange force microscopy. Thus, the relation between magnetic and
atomic structure can be determined straightforwardly by evaluating the Fourier
transformation of the real space image data. We further show that the magnetic
contrast can be mapped on a Heisenberg-like magnetic interaction between tip
and sample spins. Since our imaging technique is based on measuring forces, our
observation paves the way to study skyrmions or other complex spin textures on
insulating sample systems with atomic resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02941</id><created>2017-04-10</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Biswaranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Munir</keyname><forenames>Shoaib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poulose</keyname><forenames>Poulose</forenames></author></authors><title>Two Higgs bosons near 125 GeV in the NMSSM: beyond the narrow width
  approximation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 9 figures. Typos corrected, some figures and text improved.
  Version published in EPJC</comments><report-no>KIAS-P17020</report-no><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.8, 544</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5096-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the next-to-minimal supersymmetric (NMS) Standard Model (SM), it is
possible for either one of the additional singlet-like scalar and pseudoscalar
Higgs bosons to be almost degenerate in mass with the ~125 GeV SM-like Higgs
state. In the real NMSSM (rNMSSM), when the mass difference between two scalar
states is comparable to their individual total decay widths, the quantum
mechanical interference, due to the relevant diagonal as well as off-diagonal
terms in the propagator matrix, between them can become sizable. This
possibility invalidates usage of the narrow width approximation (NWA) to
compute the cross section for the production of a di-photon pair with a given
invariant mass via resonant Higgs boson(s) in the gluon fusion process at the
Large Hadron Collider (LHC). When, motivated by the baryon asymmetry of the
universe, CP-violating (CPV) phases are explicitly invoked in the Higgs sector
of the NMSSM, all the interaction eigenstates mix to give five CP-indefinite
physical Higgs bosons. In this scenario, the interference effects due the
off-diagonal terms in the Higgs mass matrix that mix the pseudoscalar-like
state with the SM-like one can also become significant, when these two are
sufficiently mass-degenerate. We perform a detailed analysis, in both the real
and complex NMSSM, of these interference effects, when the full propagator
matrix is taken into account, in the production of a photon pair with an
invariant mass near 125 GeV through gluon fusion. We find that these effects
can account for up to ~40% of the total cross section for certain model
parameter configurations. We also investigate how such mutually interfering
states contributing to the ~125 GeV signal observed at the LHC can be
distinguished from a single resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.09009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.09009</id><created>2017-04-28</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandenburg</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathur</keyname><forenames>Savita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metcalfe</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of coexisting long and short period stellar activity cycles</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures, 4 tables, published in ApJ</comments><report-no>NORDITA 2017-041</report-no><journal-ref>Astrophys. J. 845, 79 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7cfa</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetic activity of the Sun becomes stronger and weaker over roughly an
11 year cycle, modulating the radiation and charged particle environment
experienced by the Earth as &quot;space weather&quot;. Decades of observations from the
Mount Wilson Observatory have revealed that other stars also show regular
activity cycles in their Ca II H+K line emission, and identified two different
relationships between the length of the cycle and the rotation rate of the
star. Recent observations at higher cadence have allowed the discovery of
shorter cycles with periods between 1-3 yr. Some of these shorter cycles
coexist with longer cycle periods, suggesting that two underlying dynamos can
operate simultaneously. We combine these new observations with previous data,
and we show that the longer and shorter cycle periods agree remarkably well
with those expected from an earlier analysis based on the mean activity level
and the rotation period. The relative turbulent length scales associated with
the two branches of cyclic behavior suggest that a near-surface dynamo may be
the dominant mechanism that drives cycles in more active stars, whereas a
dynamo operating in deeper layers may dominate in less active stars. However,
several examples of equally prominent long and short cycles have been found at
all levels of activity of stars younger than 2.3 Gyr. Deviations from the
expected cycle periods show no dependence on the depth of the convection zone
or on the metallicity. For some stars that exhibit longer cycles, we compute
the periods of shorter cycles that might be detected with future high-cadence
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00010</id><created>2017-04-28</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chamberland</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jochym-O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Tomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Error suppression via complementary gauge choices in Reed-Muller codes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages + 4 appendices, 6 figures. In v2, Fig.1 was added to conform
  to journal specifications</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, vol. 2, no. 3, p. 035008, (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa7c4a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Concatenation of two quantum error correcting codes with complementary sets
of transversal gates can provide a means towards universal fault-tolerant
computation. We first show that it is generally preferable to choose the inner
code with the higher pseudo-threshold in order to achieve lower logical failure
rates. We then explore the threshold properties of a wide range of
concatenation schemes. Notably, we demonstrate that the concatenation of
complementary sets of Reed-Muller codes can increase the code capacity
threshold under depolarizing noise when compared to extensions of previously
proposed concatenation models. We also analyze the properties of logical errors
under circuit level noise, showing that smaller codes perform better for all
sampled physical error rates. Our work provides new insights into the
performance of universal concatenated quantum codes for both code capacity and
circuit level noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00549</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00549</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Li-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Si-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Constructing new pseudoscalar meson nonets with the observed $X(2100)$,
  $X(2500)$, and $\eta(2225)$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 tables and 10 figures. More discussions added and typos
  corrected. Accepted by Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 034013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.034013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stimulated by the BESIII observation of $X(2100)$, $X(2500)$, and
$\eta(2225)$, we try to pin down new pseudoscalar meson nonets including these
states. The analysis of mass spectra and the study of strong decays indicate
that $X(2120)$ and $\eta(2225)$ associated with $\pi(2070)$ and the predicted
kaon $K(2150)$ may form a new pseudoscalar meson nonet. In addition, more
experimental data for $X(2100)$ are necessary to determine its structure of
nonets. Then, $X(2500)$, $X(2370)$, $\pi(2360)$, and the predicted kaon
$K(2414)$ can be grouped into another new nonet. These assignments to the
discussed pseudoscalar states can be further tested in experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01940</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tingting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Carbon nanotubes heavy metal detection with stripping voltammetry: A
  review paper</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1002/elan.201700276</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The challenge of heavy metal detection for environmental, industrial and
medical purposes has led to the development of many analytical techniques.
Stripping voltammetry is a very sensitive electrochemical method and has been
widely used for heavy metal detection. Carbon nanotubes, a well-studied carbon
material with physical and chemical properties suited for electrode material is
commonly employed for sensitive and selective metal detection in
electrochemistry. This article reviews the recent (2011-2016) applications of
carbon nanotubes as an electrode or electrode surface modifier for heavy metals
detection with stripping voltammetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03752</id><created>2017-04-28</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Novikov-Borodin</keyname><forenames>Andrey V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ontological Systems In Cognition</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>pages 1-16 in English and pages 16-31 in Russian</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are investigated the generalized methods of cognition of the Existing,
i.e. everything that is able to influence to the cognizer, and everything
differed from the Existing is postulated as indistinguishable from the
non-existing and incognizable. The traditional methods of cognition, based on
the identification of the objects of the surrounding world, take into account
not all influences, because are limited by the nature, understood as the
ontology of the subject of cognition. The ontology is determined on the level
of basic notions and definitions, so even if objects from the representation
systems different by ontology are identified, they look undetermined, uncertain
and paradoxical, exactly as, for example, the quantum mechanical objects or
cosmological dark matter and energy. The representation systems with different
ontology are incompatible with each other on the level of basic notions and
cannot be unified on frames of one consistent system or theory. The concept of
incompatible representations unifies on the level exceeded the ontological
frames the different by ontology representation systems and incompatible
approaches, such as relativistic and quantum ones. The concept gives a
possibility to eliminate the principal contradictions of the system approach in
scientific cognition, so solves the problem of understanding in science. The
generalized methods of cognition are by definition on the foundations of
different representation systems: scientific, philosophical, religious and
social ones, what gives a possibility of general analysis and revision of their
foundations. The interconnections of some physical theories, the philosophical,
religious and social systems are briefly analyzed from this point of view.
There are briefly considered the multi-polar picture of the world, which the
concept of incompatible representations leads to.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03841</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Awoga</keyname><forenames>Oladunjoye A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouhon</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Black-Schaffer</keyname><forenames>Annica M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Domain walls in a chiral d-wave superconductor on the honeycomb lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 014521 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.014521</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a fully self-consistent study of domain walls between different
chiral domains in chiral $d_{x^2-y^2} \pm id_{xy}-wave superconductors with an
underlying honeycomb lattice structure. We investigate domain walls along all
possible armchair and zigzag directions and with a finite global phase shift
across the domain wall, in addition to the change of chirality. For armchair
domain walls we find the lowest domain wall energy at zero global phase shift,
while the most favorable zigzag domain wall has a finite global phase shift
dependent on the doping level. Below the van Hove singularity the armchair
domain wall is most favorable, while at even higher doping the zigzag domain
wall has the lowest energy. The domain wall causes a local suppression of the
superconducting order parameter, with the superconducting recovery length
following a universal curve for all domain walls. Moreover, we always find four
subgap states crossing zero energy and well localized to the domain wall.
However, the details of their energy spectrum vary notably, especially with the
global phase shift across the domain wall.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04812</id><created>2017-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Slowman</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blythe</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Solution of Two Interacting Run-and-Tumble Random Walkers with
  Finite Tumble Duration</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.SI</categories><comments>27 pages, 4 figures, Mathematica notebook as supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>J Phys A: Math. Theor. 50 375601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa80af</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a model of interacting run-and-tumble random walkers operating under
mutual hardcore exclusion on a one-dimensional lattice with periodic boundary
conditions. We incorporate a finite, Poisson-distributed, tumble duration so
that a particle remains stationary whilst tumbling, thus generalising the
persistent random walker model. We present the exact solution for the
nonequilibrium stationary state of this system in the case of two random
walkers. We find this to be characterised by two lengthscales, one arising from
the jamming of approaching particles, and the other from one particle moving
when the other is tumbling. The first of these lengthscales vanishes in a
scaling limit where the continuous-space dynamics is recovered whilst the
second remains finite. Thus the nonequilibrium stationary state reveals a rich
structure of attractive, jammed and extended pieces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05136</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kniehl</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pikelner</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veretin</keyname><forenames>O. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-loop massive tadpoles and polylogarithms through weight six</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>26 pages, 4 ancillary files, v3: version published in JHEP: minor
  additions, file with results for massive three-loop form-factor integrals
  added</comments><report-no>DESY 17-070</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1708 (2017) 024</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2017)024</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate the three-loop massive vacuum bubble diagrams in terms of
polylogarithms up to weight six. We also construct the basis of irrational
constants being harmonic polylgarithms of arguments $e^{k i \pi/3}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05221</id><created>2017-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Yijin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chung-Lung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuwen</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiscale Simulation of Surface Nanostructure Effect on Bubble
  Nucleation</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1115/1.4036692</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effects of nanostructured defects of copper solid surface on the bubble
growth in liquid argon have been investigated through a hybrid
atomistic-continuum method. The same solid surfaces with five different
nanostructures, namely, wedge defect, deep rectangular defect (R-I), shallow
rectangular defect (R-II), small rectangular defect (R-III) and no defect, have
been modeled at molecular level. The liquid argon is placed on top of the hot
solid copper with superheat of 30 K after equilibration is achieved with CFD-MD
coupled simulation. Phase change of argon on five nanostructures has been
observed and analyzed accordingly. The results showed that the solid surface
with wedge defect tends to induce a nano-bubble relatively more easily than the
others, and the larger the size of the defect is the easier the bubble
generate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05419</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>I. Turk</forenames><affiliation>Giresun Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yilmaz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Giresun Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Denizli</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Abant Izzet Baysal Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Senol</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Abant Izzet Baysal Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Karadeniz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Giresun Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames><affiliation>Ankara Univ.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Probing the Anomalous FCNC tqgamma Couplings at Large Hadron electron
  Collider</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the anomalous flavour changing neutral current (FCNC)
interactions of top quark through the process $e^{-}p\to e^{-}W^{\pm}q+X$. We
calculate the signal and background cross sections in electron proton
collisions at Large Hadron electron Collider (LHeC) with a 7 TeV proton beam
from the LHC and a new 60 GeV electron beam from energy recovery linac (ERL).
We study the relevant background processes including one electron and three
jets in the final state. The distributions of the invariant mass of two jets
and an additional jet tagged as $b$-jet are used to account signal and
background events after the analysis cuts. We find upper bounds on anomalous
FCNC couplings $\lambda$ of the order of $10^{-2}$ at LHeC for a luminosity
projection of $100$ fb$^{-1}$ together with the fast simulation of detector
effects. As a matter of interest, we analyze the sensitivity to the couplings
$(\lambda_{u},\lambda_{c})$ and find an enhanced sensitivity to $\lambda_{c}$
at the LHeC when compared to the results from the HERA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06752</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Petropoulou</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coenders</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasilopoulos</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamble</keyname><forenames>Atish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sironi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Point-source and diffuse high-energy neutrino emission from Type IIn
  supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 2017, vol. 470, issue 2, pp. 1881-1893</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1251</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type IIn supernovae (SNe), a rare subclass of core collapse SNe, explode in
dense circumstellar media that have been modified by the SNe progenitors at
their last evolutionary stages. The interaction of the freely expanding SN
ejecta with the circumstellar medium gives rise to a shock wave propagating in
the dense SN environment, which may accelerate protons to multi-PeV energies.
Inelastic proton-proton collisions between the shock-accelerated protons and
those of the circumstellar medium lead to multi-messenger signatures. Here, we
evaluate the possible neutrino signal of type IIn SNe and compare with IceCube
observations. We employ a Monte Carlo method for the calculation of the diffuse
neutrino emission from the SN IIn class to account for the spread in their
properties. The cumulative neutrino emission is found to be ~ 10 per cent of
the observed IceCube neutrino flux above 60 TeV. Type IIn SNe would be the
dominant component of the diffuse astrophysical flux, only if 4 per cent of all
core collapse SNe were of this type and 20 to 30 per cent of the shock energy
was channeled to accelerated protons. Lower values of the acceleration
efficiency are accessible by the observation of a single type IIn SN as a
neutrino point source with IceCube using up-going muon neutrinos. Such an
identification is possible in the first year following the SN shock breakout
for sources within 20 Mpc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08892</id><created>2017-05-24</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Owerre</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Magnon Bands and Unconventional Thermal Hall Effect on the
  Frustrated Honeycomb and Bilayer Triangular Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures. Final version to be published in J. Phys.:
  Condens. Mat</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 385801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa7dd2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the conventional ferromagnetic systems, topological magnon bands and
thermal Hall effect are due to the Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction (DMI). In
principle, however, the DMI is either negligible or it is not allowed by
symmetry in some quantum magnets. Therefore, we expect that topological magnon
features will not be present in those systems. In addition, quantum magnets on
the triangular-lattice are not expected to possess topological features as the
DMI or spin-chirality cancels out due to equal and opposite contributions from
adjacent triangles. Here, however, we predict that the isomorphic frustrated
honeycomb-lattice and bilayer triangular-lattice antiferromagnetic system will
exhibit topological magnon bands and topological thermal Hall effect in the
absence of an intrinsic DMI. These unconventional topological magnon features
are present as a result of magnetic-field-induced non-coplanar spin
configurations with nonzero scalar spin chirality. The relevance of the results
to realistic bilayer triangular antiferromagnetic materials are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09685</id><created>2017-05-26</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vinson</keyname><forenames>Alec M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Brad M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Spin States of Habitable Zone Exoplanets Around M Dwarfs: The
  Effect of a Near-Resonant Companion</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 16 figures; Accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2100</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One longstanding problem for the potential habitability of planets within M
dwarf systems is their likelihood to be tidally locked in a synchronously
rotating spin state. This problem thus far has largely been addressed only by
considering two objects: the star and the planet itself. However, many systems
have been found to harbor multiple planets, with some in or very near to
mean-motion resonances. The presence of a planetary companion near a
mean-motion resonance can induce oscillatory variations in the mean-motion of
the planet, which we demonstrate can have significant effects on the spin-state
of an otherwise synchronously rotating planet. In particular, we find that a
planetary companion near a mean-motion resonance can excite the spin states of
planets in the habitable zone of small, cool stars, pushing otherwise
synchronously rotating planets into higher amplitude librations of the spin
state, or even complete circulation resulting in effective stellar days with
full surface coverage on the order of years or decades. This increase in
illuminated area can have potentially dramatic influences on climate, and thus
on habitability. We also find that the resultant spin state can be very
sensitive to initial conditions due to the chaotic nature of the spin state at
early times within certain regimes. We apply our model to two hypothetical
planetary systems inspired by the K00255 and TRAPPIST-1 systems, which both
have Earth-sized planets in mean-motion resonances orbiting cool stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01676</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Calzona</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambetta</keyname><forenames>Filippo Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavaliere</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrega</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sassetti</keyname><forenames>Maura</forenames></author></authors><title>Quench-induced entanglement and relaxation dynamics in Luttinger liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 085423 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.085423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the time evolution towards the asymptotic steady state of a
one dimensional interacting system after a quantum quench. We show that at
finite time the latter induces entanglement between right- and left- moving
density excitations, encoded in their cross-correlators, which vanishes in the
long-time limit. This behavior results in a universal time-decay in system
spectral properties $ \propto t^{-2} $, in addition to non-universal power-law
contributions typical of Luttinger liquids. Importantly, we argue that the
presence of quench-induced entanglement clearly emerges in transport
properties, such as charge and energy currents injected in the system from a
biased probe, and determines their long-time dynamics. In particular, energy
fractionalization phenomenon turns out to be a promising platform to observe
the universal power-law decay $ \propto t^{-2} $ induced by entanglement and
represents a novel way to study the corresponding relaxation mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01940</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jimbo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagoya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>CFT approach to the $q$-Painlev\'e VI equation</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Iorgov, Lisovyy, and Teschner established a connection between isomonodromic
deformation of linear differential equations and Liouville conformal field
theory at $c=1$. In this paper we present a $q$ analog of their construction.
We show that the general solution of the $q$-Painlev\'e VI equation is a ratio
of four tau functions, each of which is given by a combinatorial series arising
in the AGT correspondence. We also propose conjectural bilinear equations for
the tau functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04947</id><created>2017-06-15</created><updated>2017-07-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magee</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanna</keyname><forenames>Chad</forenames></author></authors><title>Disentangling the potential dark matter origin of LIGO's black holes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 845, Number 2 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa831c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of dark matter remains one of the biggest open questions in
physics. Intriguingly, it has been suggested that dark matter may be explained
by another recently observed phenomenon: the detection of gravitational waves
by LIGO. LIGO's detection of gravitational waves from merging stellar mass
black holes renewed attention toward the possibility that dark matter consists
solely of black holes created in the very early universe and that these
primordial black holes are what LIGO is presently observing. Subsequent work on
this topic has ruled out the possibility that dark matter could consist solely
of black holes similar to those that LIGO has detected with masses above 10
solar masses. However, LIGO's connection to dark matter remains an open
question and in this work we consider a distribution of primordial black holes
that accounts for all of the dark matter, is consistent with LIGO's
observations arising from primordial black hole binaries, and resolves tension
in previous surveys of microlensing events in the Milky Way halo. The
primordial black hole mass distribution that we consider offers an important
prediction--LIGO may detect black holes smaller than have ever been observed
with ~1% of the black holes it detects having a mass less than the mass of our
Sun. Approximately one year of operating advanced LIGO at design sensitivity
should be adequate to begin to see a hint of a primordial black hole mass
distribution. Detecting primordial black hole binaries below a solar mass will
be readily distinguishable from other known compact binary systems, thereby
providing an unambiguous observational window for advanced LIGO to pin down the
nature of dark matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09540</id><created>2017-06-28</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandenburg</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashurova</keyname><forenames>Mohira B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jabbari</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author></authors><title>Compensating Faraday depolarization by magnetic helicity in the solar
  corona</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, published in ApJL</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2017-064</report-no><journal-ref>Astrophys. J. Lett. 845, L15 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa844b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A turbulent dynamo in spherical geometry with an outer corona is simulated to
study the sign of magnetic helicity in the outer parts. In agreement with
earlier studies, the sign in the outer corona is found to be opposite to that
inside the dynamo. Line-of-sight observations of polarized emission are
synthesized to explore the feasibility of using the local reduction of Faraday
depolarization to infer the sign of helicity of magnetic fields in the solar
corona. This approach was previously identified as an observational diagnostic
in the context of galactic magnetic fields. Based on our simulations, we show
that this method can be successful in the solar context if sufficient
statistics is gathered by using averages over ring segments in the corona
separately for the regions north and south of the solar equator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03460</id><created>2017-07-11</created><updated>2017-08-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flint</keyname><forenames>Charles L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakrishnan</keyname><forenames>Purnima P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahalingam</keyname><forenames>Krishnamurthy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urwin</keyname><forenames>Brittany</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vailionis</keyname><forenames>Arturas</forenames></author><author><keyname>NDiaye</keyname><forenames>Alpha T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafer</keyname><forenames>Padraic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arenholz</keyname><forenames>Elke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Yongseong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>Kevin H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>JiunHaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howe</keyname><forenames>Brandon M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisher</keyname><forenames>Ian R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author></authors><title>Tuning Perpendicular Magnetic Anisotropy by Oxygen Octahedral Rotations
  in (La$_{1-x}$Sr$_{x}$MnO$_{3}$)/(SrIrO$_{3}$) Superlattices</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.077201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Perpendicular magnetic anisotropy (PMA) plays a critical role in the
development of spintronics, thereby demanding new strategies to control PMA.
Here we demonstrate a conceptually new type of interface induced PMA that is
controlled by oxygen octahedral rotation. In superlattices comprised of
La$_{1-x}$Sr$_{x}$MnO$_{3}$ and SrIrO$_{3}$, we find that all superlattices
(0$\leq$x$\leq$1) exhibit ferromagnetism despite the fact that
La$_{1-x}$Sr$_{x}$MnO$_{3}$ is antiferromagnetic for x$&gt;$0.5. PMA as high as
4$\times$10$^6$ erg/cm$^3$ is observed by increasing x and attributed to a
decrease of oxygen octahedral rotation at interfaces. We also demonstrate that
oxygen octahedral deformation cannot explain the trend in PMA. These results
reveal a new degree of freedom to control PMA, enabling discovery of emergent
magnetic textures and topological phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05633</id><created>2017-07-16</created><updated>2017-08-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piparo</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames><affiliation>Ministero dell'Istruzione dell'Universit&#xe0; e della Ricerca</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Algebra of the Pseudo-Observables I: Why Quantum Mechanics is the
  ultimate description of Reality</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>* Added an acknowledgments section * Several minor changes</comments><msc-class>81P10 (Primary), 81P16 (Secondary)</msc-class><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is the first of several parts introducing a new powerful algebra:
the algebra of the pseudo-observables. This is a C*-algebra whose set is formed
by formal expressions involving observables. The algebra is constructed by
applying the Occam's razor principle, in order to obtain the minimal
description of physical reality. Proceeding in such a manner, every aspect of
quantum mechanics acquires a clear physical interpretation or a logical
explanation, providing, for instance, in a natural way the reason for the
structure of complex algebra and the matrix structure of Werner Heisenberg's
formulation of quantum mechanics. Last but not least, the very general
hypotheses assumed, allow one to state that quantum mechanics is the unique
minimal description of physical reality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.00664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.00664</id><created>2017-08-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kole</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Produit</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tymieniecka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwolinska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernasconi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cadoux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>M. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauvin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hajdas</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcinkowski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orsi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybka</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabelski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>B. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Instrument Performance and Simulation Verification of the POLAR Detector</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Preprint Accepted for Publication in Nuclear Instruments and Methods
  in Physics Research A</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.07.070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  POLAR is a new satellite-born detector aiming to measure the polarization of
an unprecedented number of Gamma-Ray Bursts in the 50-500 keV energy range. The
instrument, launched on-board the Tiangong-2 Chinese Space lab on the 15th of
September 2016, is designed to measure the polarization of the hard X-ray flux
by measuring the distribution of the azimuthal scattering angles of the
incoming photons. A detailed understanding of the polarimeter and specifically
of the systematic effects induced by the instrument's non-uniformity are
required for this purpose. In order to study the instrument's response to
polarization, POLAR underwent a beam test at the European Synchrotron Radiation
Facility in France. In this paper both the beam test and the instrument
performance will be described. This is followed by an overview of the Monte
Carlo simulation tools developed for the instrument. Finally a comparison of
the measured and simulated instrument performance will be provided and the
instrument response to polarization will be presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02907</id><created>2017-08-09</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kastner</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kauffman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Are Dark Energy and Dark Matter Different Aspects of the Same Physical
  Process?</title><categories>gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>Some typos corrected. Comments welcome, pro or con</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is suggested that the apparently disparate cosmological phenomena
attributed to so-called 'dark matter' and 'dark energy' arise from the same
fundamental physical process: the emergence, from the quantum level, of
spacetime itself. This creation of spacetime results in metric expansion around
mass points in addition to the usual curvature due to stress-energy sources of
the gravitational field. A recent modification of Einstein's theory of general
relativity by Chadwick, Hodgkinson, and McDonald incorporating spacetime
expansion around mass points, which accounts well for the observed galactic
rotation curves, is adduced in support of the proposal. Recent observational
evidence corroborates a prediction of the model that the apparent amount of
'dark matter' increases with the age of the universe. In addition, the proposal
leads to the same result for the small but nonvanishing cosmological constant,
related to 'dark energy, as that of the causet model of Sorkin et al.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02935</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Mian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Baizhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Qingyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author></authors><title>Preparation of CH3NH3PbI3 thin films with tens of micrometer scale at
  high temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><comments>10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 8458 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-09109-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fabrication of high-quality organic-inorganic hybrid halide perovskite
layers is the key prerequisite for the realization of high efficient photon
energy harvest and electric energy conversion in their related solar cells. In
this article, we report a novel fabrication technique of CH3NH3PbI3 layer based
on high temperature chemical vapor reaction. CH3NH3PbI3 layers have been
prepared by the reaction of PbI2 films which were deposited by pulsed laser
deposition, with CH3NH3I vapor at various temperatures from 160 oC to 210 oC.
X-ray diffraction patterns confirm the formation of pure phase, and
photoluminescence spectra show the strong peak at around 760 nm. Scanning
electron microscopy images confirm the significantly increased average grain
size from nearly 1 {\mu}m at low reaction temperature of 160 oC to more than 10
{\mu}m at high reaction temperature of 200 oC. The solar cells were fabricated,
and short-circuit current density of 15.75 mA/cm2, open-circuit voltage of 0.49
V and fill factor of 71.66% have been obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03166</id><created>2017-08-10</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onuki</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author></authors><title>Acoustic resonance in periodically sheared glass</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using molecular dynamics simulation, we study acoustic resonance in
low-temperature glass by applying a small periodic shear at a boundary wall.
Shear wave resonance occurs as the frequency $\omega$ approaches $\omega_\ell=
\pi c_\perp\ell/L$ ($\ell=1, 2, 3,...)$. Here, $c_\perp$ is the transverse
sound speed and $L$ is the cell length. At resonance, large-amplitude sound
waves appear after many cycles even for very small applied strains. They then
induce plastic events, which are heterogeneous in space and intermittent on
time scales longer than the oscillation period $2\pi/\omega$. From these
irreversible particle motions, there arises strong dissipation suppressing the
growth of sounds. After many resonant cycles, we observe a phenomenon of forced
aging, where the shear modulus (measured after switching off the oscillation)
is increased significantly.Sometimes, exceptionally large plastic events and
system-size sliding motions induce a transition from resonant to off-resonant
states. At resonance, translational diffusion becomes appreciable as well as
aging due to enhanced configurational changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03916</id><created>2017-08-13</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Villa-Cort&#xe9;s</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baquero</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse Isotope Effect in PdH(D)</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 pages. No figures</comments><report-no>RBP 03 2017 ISOT EFF</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we take a new approach to the explanation of the inverse
isotope effect in PdH(D). Our approach introduces two new aspects. First, we
took into account the experimental evidence that at temperatures below 50 K,
the crystal structure of PdH and of PdD is zincblende. Second, we studied the
contribution of both, the electron-phonon and the electron-electron
interactions. We used the Migdal-Eliashberg theory to perform our ab initio
calculations. We found that the electron-electron contribution is the most
important one to explain the inverse isotope effect. We reproduced the
experimentally found values for the critical temperature and the isotope
coefficient. Our analysis represents a direct and simple explanation for the
inverse isotope effect in PdH(D).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03929</id><created>2017-08-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Dabrowski</keyname><forenames>Mariusz P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Singularities and Cyclic Universes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Phys. Pol. (Proc. Suppl.) B10, 415 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolBSupp.10.415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The models of cyclic universes and cyclic multiverses based on the
alternative gravity theories of varying constants are considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04184</id><created>2017-08-14</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tchapda</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenmoe</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kammogne</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fai</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau-Zener transitions in a qubit periodically driven in both
  longitudinal and transverse directions</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate the dynamics of a spin-qubit periodically driven
in both longitudinal and transverse directions by two classical fields
respectively a radio-frequency (RF) and a microwave (MW) field operating at
phase difference $\phi$. The qubit is simultaneously locally subject to a
linearly polarized magnetic field which changes its sign at a degeneracy point
in the longitudinal direction and remains constant in the transverse direction.
We superimpose the RF and MW signals respectively to the longitudinal and
transverse components of the magnetic field. The proposed model may be used to
optimize the control of a qubit in quantum devices. The various fields applied
are relevant to {\it nearly-decouple} the spin-qubit from its environment,
minimize decoherence effects and improve on the coherence time. The study is
carried out in the Schr\&quot;odinger and Bloch pictures. We consider the limits of
weak and strong longitudinal drives set up by comparing the characteristic time
of non-adiabatic transitions with the coherence time of the longitudinal drive.
Expressions for populations are compared with numerics and remarkable
agreements are observed as both solutions are barely discernible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04904</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04904</id><created>2017-08-16</created><updated>2017-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lockwood</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owens</keyname><forenames>Mathew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnard</keyname><forenames>Luke A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Chris J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watt</keyname><forenames>Clare E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Space Climate and Space Weather over the past 400 years: 1. The Power
  input to the Magnetosphere</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>In press, accepted for publication by J. Space Weather Space Clim.
  Ms# swsc170035 (accepted version, 28 pages, 2 Tables, 12 Figures)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using information on geomagnetic activity, sunspot numbers and cosmogenic
isotopes, supported by historic eclipse images and in conjunction with models,
it has been possible to reconstruct annual means of solar wind speed and number
density and heliospheric magnetic field (HMF) intensity since 1611, when
telescopic observations of sunspots began. These models are developed and tuned
using data recorded by near-Earth interplanetary spacecraft and by solar
magnetograms over the past 53 years. In this paper, we use these
reconstructions to quantify power input into the magnetosphere over the past
400 years. For each year, both the annual mean power input is computed and its
distribution in daily means. This is possible because the distribution of daily
values divided by the annual mean is shown to maintain the same lognormal form
with a constant variance. This study is another important step towards the
development of a physics-based, long-term climatology of space weather
conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04958</id><created>2017-08-16</created><updated>2017-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Biplab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Alka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Bhavesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>Kunjal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jejurikar</keyname><forenames>Suhas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senguttuvan</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husale</keyname><forenames>Sudhir</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of robust 2D transport and Efros-Shklovskii variable range
  hopping in disordered topological insulator (Bi2Se3) nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci Rep., 7 (1):7825 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-08018-6.</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the experimental observation of variable range hopping conduction
in focused-ion-beam (FIB) fabricated ultra-narrow nanowires of topological
insulator (Bi2Se3). The value of the exponent in the hopping equation was
extracted as ~ 1/2 for different widths of nanowires, which is the proof of the
presence of Efros-Shklovskii hopping transport mechanism in a strongly
disordered system. High localization lengths (0.5nm, 20nm) were calculated for
the devices. A careful analysis of the temperature dependent fluctuations
present in the magnetoresistance curves, using the standard Universal
Conductance Fluctuation theory, indicates the presence of 2D topological
surface states. Also, the surface state contribution to the conductance was
found very close to one conductance quantum. We believe that our experimental
findings shed light on the understanding of quantum transport in disordered
topological insulator based nanostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05035</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cha</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Topologically ordered states in infinite quantum spin systems</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>104 pages, Ph.D. dissertation, University of California, Davis.
  Chapter 4 is an extended version of arXiv:1608.04449</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This dissertation discusses some properties of topologically ordered states
as they appear in the setting of infinite quantum spin systems. We begin by
studying the set of infinite volume ground states for Kitaev's abelian quantum
double models. We show that states describing a single excitation in the bulk
are infinite volume ground states, that is, local perturbations cannot remove
the charge. The single excitations states, which are inequivalent for distinct
charges, give a complete characterization of the sector theory for the set of
ground states. Furthermore, any pure ground state is equivalent to some single
excitation ground state. We proceed to study the stability of charges that are
classified by certain representations of the algebra of observables. We
introduce a new superselection criterion selecting almost localized and
transportable $*$-endomorphisms with respect to a vacuum state. Equivalence
classes of representations satisfying the superselection criterion form
different charged superselection sectors of the system. We show that if the
vacuum state satisfies certain locality conditions then the superselection
structure will be a braided tensor $C^*$-category.
  Further, this superselection structure is stable up to deformations by a
quasi-local dynamics.
  This result is then applied to show that the anyon structure of the abelian
quantum double models is stable under local perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05036</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author></authors><title>Astronomical Observability of the Cassini Entry into Saturn</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Cassini spacecraft will enter Saturn's atmosphere on 15th September 2017.
This event may be visible from Earth as a 'meteor' flash, and entry dynamics
simulations and results from observation of spacecraft entries at Earth are
summarized to develop expectations for astronomical observability
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05051</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Kunlun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair-Kanneganti</keyname><forenames>Aparna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casara</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahl</keyname><forenames>Aubrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carle</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective magnetic susceptibility of suspensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize how suspensions of magnetic particles in a liquid respond to
a magnetic field in terms of the effective magnetic susceptibility $\chi_{eff}$
using inductance measurements. We test a model that predicts how $\chi_{eff}$
varies due to demagnetization, as a function of sample aspect ratio, particle
packing fraction, and particle aspect ratio. For spherical particles or
cylindrical particles aligned with external magnetic field, the model can be
fitted to the measured data with agreement within 17\%. However, we find that
the random alignment of particles relative to the magnetic field plays a role,
reducing $\chi_{eff}$ by a factor of 3 in some cases, which is not accounted
for in models yet. While suspensions are predicted to have $\chi_{eff}$ that
approach the particle material susceptibility in the limit of large particle
aspect ratio, instead we find a much smaller particle aspect ratio where
$\chi_{eff}$ is maximized. A prediction that $\chi_{eff}$ approaches the bulk
material susceptibility in the limit of the packing fraction of the
liquid-solid transition also fails. We find $\chi_{eff}$ no larger than about 4
for suspensions of iron particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05055</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Belokurov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shavgulidze</keyname><forenames>Evgeniy T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the Universe caused by the averaged potential of the
  quantum scalar field</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum theory of the singular scalar field $\varphi $ minimally
coupled to gravity. In our approach, the scalar field is treated as a true
quantum variable, while the scale factor $a(t)$ is supposed to be classical. We
evaluate the quantum average of the self-interaction potential $V(\varphi)$ and
use it in the modified differential equation for the Hubble parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05056</id><created>2017-06-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Tixier</keyname><forenames>Mireille</forenames><affiliation>UVSQ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pouget</keyname><forenames>Jo&#xeb;l</forenames><affiliation>DALEMBERT</affiliation></author></authors><title>Conservation laws and constitutive equations for an electro-active
  polymer</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ionic electro-active polymer (Nafion for example) can be used as sensor or
actuator. To this end, a thin film of the water-saturated material is
sandwiched between two electrodes. Water saturation causes a quasi-complete
dissociation of the polymer and the release of small cations. The application
of an electric field across the thickness results in the bending of the strip.
Conversely, a voltage can be detected between the two electrodes when the strip
is bent. This phenomenon involves multiphysics couplings of
electro-mechanical-chemical type. The system is modeled by a deformable porous
medium in which flows an ionic solution and we use a continuous medium
approach. Maxwell's equations and conservation laws of mass, linear momentum
and energy are first written at the microscopic scale for each phase and
interfaces, then for the complete material using an average technique.
Thermodynamics of linear irreversible processes provides the constitutive
equations : a Kelvin-Voigt stress-strain relation,generalized Fourier's and
Darcy's laws and a Nernst-Planck equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05058</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Borges</keyname><forenames>Paulo de F</forenames></author></authors><title>Introducing advanced concepts for young students</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The compound Atwood's machine (Atm) problem is revisited in order to
introduce young students on advanced concepts in Physics. Atm is an
old-fashioned device. However, it allows us to speak about relativity of
motion, principle of equivalence, inertial and non-inertial frames of
reference, general covariance and invariance under coordinate transformations.
Besides, it also provides experimental support for our theoretical models. We
have started with coordinate transformations and inertial and non inertial
reference frames followed by the principle of equivalence. The composed Atm was
worked out in the following. We calculate the acceleration in the machine
applying Newton's Laws to describe its dynamics in an inertial frame on the
fixed pulley center and in a non-inertial one on the moving pulley center.
Coordinate transformations mapping inertial frame solutions in non-inertial
ones and vice-versa allow students catch on relativity concepts and the role
played by general covariance. A comparison between these solutions showed the
importance of the principle of equivalence in the evaluation of the intensity
of gravity locally. In addition, according to this coordinate transformation
the non-inertial reference frame equations of motion are equivalent to one
single Atm plus one falling mass. Our results have also shown, in agreement
with experimental outcomes, that after movement starts single Atm becomes
lighter than $m_{3}$ mass, consequently $m_{3}$ mass is falling. It is a
non-intuitive experimental result first observed for the 1854 Poggendorff's
fall machine. A measure of single Atm's mass reduction was reported in 2016's
last issue of Physics Education.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05064</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halder</keyname><forenames>Subrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>James C. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rugged HBT Class-C Power Amplifiers with Base-Emitter Clamping</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1109/MWSYM.2011.5972559</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ruggedness of HBT Class-C power amplifiers was improved by adding an
anti-parallel diode to the amplifier input to limit the negative swing of the
base-emitter voltage. The improved amplifier could withstand 3:1 instead of 2:1
mismatch in CW operation, and 2.5:1 instead of 1.5:1 mismatch in pulse
operation. In contrast to other approaches with emitter ballast, active
feedback, or electrostatic discharge protection circuits, the present approach
is simple to implement and has negligible impact on overall amplifier output
power, gain or efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05065</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Sigismondi</keyname><forenames>Costantino</forenames></author></authors><title>Umbra in partial lunar eclipses at moonrise</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>2 pages, 2 figures in color. Text in English with Italian Abstract.
  Submitted to Gerbertus</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The darkness of the umbra of the lunar eclipse of August 7 2017 corresponded
to the predictions of A. Danjon for the Sun at its minimum. It appeared partial
at moonrise in Rome similarly to the one of April 3, 33 AD in Jerusalem,
supposed following the Crucifixion of Christ. The hypothesis of Sun at maximum
activity for that historical eclipse is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05107</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kar</keyname><forenames>Payel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>The VERITAS</forenames></author></authors><title>Decadal VERITAS Observation of LS I +61$^{\circ}$303 : Detection of TeV
  emission around the entire orbit</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, ICRC 2017 (Bexco, Busan, S. Korea)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The TeV binary system \lsi has a compact object in an eccentric orbit around
a Be star about 2 kpc from Earth. \lsi exhibits modulated gamma-ray emission
around its 26.5 days orbit, mostly detectable at TeV energies around its
apastron passage, with maximum flux during the $\phi = 0.55-0.65$ phase range.
Multiple flaring episodes with nightly flux variability at TeV energies have
been observed since its detection in 2006. At one time significant TeV emission
was also detected in late 2010 from the source close to its periastron passage
at superior conjunction. The TeV spectrum is well fitted by a power law with
small variations of spectral index of $\sim2.6$ over the years. GeV, X-ray, and
radio emission have been detected along the entire orbit, enabling detailed
study of the modulation pattern and its super-orbital period, such
comprehensive study of the \lsi orbit in the TeV regime has not been presented
before. VERITAS has observed \lsi for over a decade now, accruing 200+ hours of
data during different parts of its orbit. In this work, we have analyzed all
available data for \lsi since September 2007 in individual phase bins of width
$\Delta \phi = 0.1$ and performed a spectral analysis for two different parts
of the orbit. TeV emission is now detected in 9 out of 10 phase bins, around
the entire orbit for the first time in VERITAS data. Hint of spectral variation
might also be present between different parts of the orbit. The implication of
these results is discussed in the context of determining the nature of the
unknown compact object (neutron star or microquasar) and a discussion of the
absorption mechanisms in the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05110</id><created>2017-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Guevara</keyname><forenames>Adolfo</forenames></author></authors><title>Backgrounds in the search for Second Class Currents in $\tau$ decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>XXXI Annual Meeting of the Division of Particles and Fields
  conference proceedings, to be published in IOP Conf. Ser., 10 pages, 9
  figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As constructed, the Standard Model does not include genuine Second Class
Currents, however these can be induced through the breaking of isospin or
charge conjugation. The experimental limits from B-Factories are getting closer
to the predictions made for induced Second Class Currents through isospin
breaking in the processes $\tau\to\pi\eta^{(\prime)}\nu_\tau$, therefore a more
careful analysis of the background in these decays becomes necessary. In this
work we analyze the $\tau\to\pi\eta^{(\prime)}\gamma\nu_\tau$ decays as
background of the non-radiative process. We find that the radiative processes
are very important background for the non-radiative ones whenever the photon
escapes detection. Photons cannot be completely excluded since they need to be
kept for the identification of the eta and eta' in the final state. However, we
find that making appropriate cuts in the energy of the photon, this process can
be disregarded as an important background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05128</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc1;lvarez-Mu&#xf1;iz</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batista</keyname><forenames>Rafael Alves</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustamante</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Washington</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charrier</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cognard</keyname><forenames>Isma&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Jong</keyname><forenames>Sijbrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Vries</keyname><forenames>Krijn D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finley</keyname><forenames>Chad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gou</keyname><forenames>Quanbu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Junhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;pin</keyname><forenames>Claire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>Jordan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Hongbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotera</keyname><forenames>Kumiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coz</keyname><forenames>Sandra Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martineau-Huynh</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>Clementina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostafa</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mottez</keyname><forenames>Fabrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niess</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oikonomou</keyname><forenames>Foteini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasse</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timmermans</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renault-Tinacci</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tueros</keyname><forenames>Mat&#xed;as</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiang-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zarka</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zech</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zilles</keyname><forenames>Anne</forenames></author></authors><title>The Giant Radio Array for Neutrino Detection (GRAND): Present and
  Perspectives</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Proceedings of the 35th International Cosmic Ray Conference
  (ICRC2017), Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><journal-ref>PoS(ICRC2017)996</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Giant Radio Array for Neutrino Detection (GRAND) aims at detecting
ultra-high energy extraterrestrial neutrinos via the extensive air showers
induced by the decay of tau leptons created in the interaction of neutrinos
under the Earth's surface. Consisting of an array of $\sim10^5$ radio antennas
deployed over $\sim 2\times10^5\,\rm {km}^2$, GRAND plans to reach, for the
first time, an all-flavor sensitivity of $\sim1.5\times10^{-10} \,\rm GeV\,
cm^{-2} \,s^{-1}\, sr^{-1}$ above $5\times10^{17}$ eV and a sub-degree angular
resolution, beyond the reach of other planned detectors. We describe here
preliminary designs and simulation results, plans for the ongoing, staged
approach to the construction of GRAND, and the rich research program made
possible by GRAND's design sensitivity and angular resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05143</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmad</keyname><forenames>Naveel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Ranjeev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iqbal</keyname><forenames>Naseer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maqbool</keyname><forenames>Bari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamid</keyname><forenames>Mubashir</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the response of a standard accretion disc to stochastic viscous
  fluctuations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Astronomy, 58 (2018) 84-89</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.newast.2017.07.011</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The observed variability of X-ray binaries over a wide range of time-scales
can be understood in the framework of a stochastic propagation model, where
viscous fluctuations at different radii induce accretion rate variability that
propagate inwards to the X-ray producing region. The scenario successfully
explains the power spectra, the linear rms-flux relation as well as the
time-lag between different energy photons. The predictions of this model have
been obtained using approximate analytical solutions or empirically motivated
models which take into account the effect of these propagating variability on
the radiative process of complex accretion flows. Here, we study the variation
of the accretion rate due to such viscous fluctuations using a hydro-dynamical
code for the standard geometrically thin, gas pressure dominated $\alpha$-disc
with a zero torque boundary condition. Our results confirm earlier findings
that the time-lag between a perturbation and the resultant inner accretion rate
variation depends on the frequency (or time-period) of the perturbation. Here
we have quantified that the time-lag $t_{lag} \propto f^{-0.54}$, for
time-periods less than the viscous time-scale of the perturbation radius and is
nearly constant otherwise. This, coupled with radiative process would produce
the observed frequency dependent time-lag between different energy bands. We
also confirm that if there are random Gaussian fluctuations of the
$\alpha$-parameter at different radii, the resultant inner accretion rate has a
power spectrum which is a power-law.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05145</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>Swati</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Ashok Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Goodness of Isospin in Neutron Rich Systems from the Fission Fragment
  Distribution</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, published in Focus Issue on Nuclear Shapes and
  Symmetries:From Experiment to Theory in Physica Scripta</comments><journal-ref>Physica Scripta 92,094001(2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1402-4896/aa7f02</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of our calculations for the relative yields of
neutron-rich fission fragments emitted in $^{208}$Pb ($^{18}$O, fission)
reaction by using the concept of the conservation of isospin and compare with
the experimental data. We take into account a range of isospin values allowed
by the isospin algebra and assume that the fission fragments are formed in
Isobaric Analog States. We also take into account the neutron multiplicity data
for various neutron-emission channels in each partition, and use them to obtain
the weight factors in calculating the yields. We then calculate the relative
yields of the fission fragments. Our calculated results are able to reproduce
the experimental trends reasonably well. This is the first direct evidence of
the isospin conservation in neutron-rich systems and may prove a very useful
tool in their studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05151</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Henrichs</keyname><forenames>Leonard F.</forenames></author></authors><title>New materials for thin-film phase-plates</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Master Thesis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous Zernike phase-plates, for transmission-electron-microscopy (TEM)
have always been made out of carbon. A critical constraint on those
phase-plates is their fast degradation during use. Here, a Zernike phase-plate
consisting out of metal is produced and tested for the first time. For the new
aluminium phase-plate, no charging like for the carbon phase-plate is observed.
Under conditions of use, the stability of the aluminium phase-plate, is
excellent. For both materials, a distortion in the image's
Fourier-transformation is observed, when inserting the thin-film into the beam
at the back-focal-plane. This distortion is a negative, spatial-frequency
dependent phase-shift, that is not equal to a focus-change. A phase-shift and
an increase of contrast, is observed for the tested phase-plates. Different
types of self-sustaining metal-films are produced with a technique, invented by
Janbroers et al. All metal-films, produced at room-temperature, exhibit a
polycrystalline structure, while carbon-films are amorphous. However, a high
crystallinity is unfavored, causing distortions in the image and an increase of
electron-scattering in the phase-plate, due to diffraction. Using
cryo-deposition, metal-films are obtained that combine an amorphous structure
with beneficial properties of metals such as lower charging and prolonged
durability. Investigations with TEM, show a great potential of those cryo-films
as material for Zernike phase-plates. Thickness-measurements are successfully
carried out with atomic-force-mycroscopy at step-edges between the thin-film
and its substrate. For this, a technique for the preparation of very narrow
step-edges is developed here.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05158</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>T. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimomura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higemoto</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuzaki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kageyama</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excited configurations of hydrogen in the BaTiO$_{3-x}$H$_x$ perovskite
  lattice associated with hydrogen exchange and transport</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 020301(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.020301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Excited configurations of hydrogen in the oxyhydride BaTiO$_{3-x}$H$_x$
($x=0.1-0.5$), which are considered to be involved in its hydrogen transport
and exchange processes, were investigated by positive muon spin relaxation
($\mu^+$SR) spectroscopy using muonium (Mu) as a pseudoisotope of hydrogen.
Muons implanted into the BaTiO$_{3-x}$H$_x$ perovskite lattice were mainly
found in two qualitatively different metastable states. One was assigned to a
highly mobile interstitial protonic state, which is commonly observed in
perovskite oxides. The other was found to form an entangled two
spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ system with the nuclear spin of an H$^-$ ion at the anion
site. The structure of the (H,Mu) complex agrees well with that of a
neutralized center containing two H$^-$ ions at a doubly charged oxygen
vacancy, which was predicted to form in the SrTiO$_{3-\delta}$ perovskite
lattice by a computational study [Y. Iwazaki $et$ $al$., APL Materials 2,
012103 (2014)]. Above 100 K, interstitial Mu$^+$ diffusion and retrapping to a
deep defect were observed, which could be a rate-limiting step of macroscopic
Mu/H transport in the BaTiO$_{3-x}$H$_x$ lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05162</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Avsar</keyname><forenames>Ahmet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Jun Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xin</keyname><forenames>Luo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoo</keyname><forenames>Khoong Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeo</keyname><forenames>Yuting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quek</keyname><forenames>Su Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozyilmaz</keyname><forenames>Barbaros</forenames></author></authors><title>van der Waals Bonded Co/h-BN Contacts to Ultrathin Black Phosphorus
  Devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Letters, August 9, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01817</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to the chemical inertness of 2D hexagonal-Boron Nitride (h-BN), few
atomic-layer h-BN is often used to encapsulate air-sensitive 2D crystals such
as Black Phosphorus (BP). However, the effects of h-BN on Schottky barrier
height, doping and contact resistance are not well known. Here, we investigate
these effects by fabricating h-BN encapsulated BP transistors with cobalt (Co)
contacts. In sharp contrast to directly Co contacted p-type BP devices, we
observe strong n-type conduction upon insertion of the h-BN at the Co/BP
interface. First principles calculations show that this difference arises from
the much larger interface dipole at the Co/h-BN interface compared to the Co/BP
interface, which reduces the work function of the Co/h-BN contact. The Co/h-BN
contacts exhibit low contact resistances (~ 4.5 k-ohm), and are Schottky
barrier free. This allows us to probe high electron mobilities (4,200 cm2/Vs)
and observe insulator-metal transitions even under two-terminal measurement
geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05166</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yanpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Hechang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Jiangang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Wujun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Binghai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosono</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in alkaline earth metal-filled skutterudites BaxIr4X12
  (X = As, P)</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 pages,4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2017, 139 (24), pp 8106-8109</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/jacs.7b04274</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report superconductive iridium pnictides BaxIr4X12 (X = As and P) with a
filled skutterudite structure, demonstrating that Ba filling dramatically
alters their electronic properties and induces a nonmetal-to-metal transition
with increasing the Ba content x. The highest superconducting transition
temperatures are 4.8 and 5.6 K observed for BaxIr4As12 and BaxIr4P12,
respectively. The superconductivity in BaxIr4X12 can classified into the
Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer type with intermediate coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05176</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Aiba</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demir</keyname><forenames>Firuz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishino</keyname><forenames>Tomoaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsukagoshi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saffarzadeh</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirczenow</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiguchi</keyname><forenames>Manabu</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling the thermoelectric effect by mechanical manipulation of the
  electron's quantum phase in atomic junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>25 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>A.Aiba, F.Demir, S.Kaneko, S.Fujii, T.Nishino, K.Tsukagoshi,
  A.Saffarzadeh, G.Kirczenow, M.Kiguchi, Scientific Reports 7, 7949 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-08553-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermoelectric voltage developed across an atomic metal junction (i.e., a
nanostructure in which one or a few atoms connect two metal electrodes) in
response to a temperature difference between the electrodes, results from the
quantum interference of electrons that pass through the junction multiple times
after being scattered by the surrounding defects. Here we report successfully
tuning this quantum interference and thus controlling the magnitude and sign of
the thermoelectric voltage by applying a mechanical force that deforms the
junction. The observed switching of the thermoelectric voltage is reversible
and can be cycled many times. Our ab initio and semi-empirical calculations
elucidate the detailed mechanism by which the quantum interference is tuned. We
show that the applied strain alters the quantum phases of electrons passing
through the narrowest part of the junction and hence modifies the electronic
quantum interference in the device. Tuning the quantum interference causes the
energies of electronic transport resonances to shift, which affects the
thermoelectric voltage. These experimental and theoretical studies reveal that
Au atomic junctions can be made to exhibit both positive and negative
thermoelectric voltages on demand, and demonstrate the importance and
tunability of the quantum interference effect in the atomic-scale metal
nanostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05177</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Refregier</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gamper</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Amara</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Heisenberg</keyname><forenames>Lavinia</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author></authors><title>PyCosmo: An Integrated Cosmological Boltzmann Solver</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. Submitted to Astronomy and Computing.
  See http://www.cosmology.ethz.ch/research/software-lab.html</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As wide-field surveys yield ever more precise measurements, cosmology has
entered a phase of high precision requiring highly accurate and fast
theoretical predictions. At the heart of most cosmological model predictions is
a numerical solution of the Einstein-Boltzmann equations governing the
evolution of linear perturbations in the Universe. We present PyCosmo, a new
Python-based framework to solve this set of equations using a special pur- pose
solver based on symbolic manipulations, automatic generation of C++ code and
sparsity optimisation. The code uses a consistency relation of the field
equations to adapt the time step and does not rely on physical approximations
for speed-up. After reviewing the system of first-order linear homogeneous
differential equations to be solved, we describe the numerical scheme
implemented in PyCosmo. We then compare the predictions and performance of the
code for the computation of the transfer functions of cosmological
perturbations and compare it to existing cosmological Boltzmann codes. We find
that we achieve comparable execution times for comparable accuracies. While
PyCosmo does not yet have all the features of other codes, our approach is
complementary to existing cosmological Boltzmann solvers and can be used as an
independent test of their numerical solutions. The symbolic representation of
the Einstein-Boltzmann equation system in PyCosmo provides a convenient
interface for implementing extended cosmological models. We also discuss how
the PyCosmo framework can also be used as a general framework to compute
cosmological quantities as well as observables for both interactive and
high-performance batch jobs applications. Information about the PyCosmo package
and future code releases are available at
http://www.cosmology.ethz.ch/research/software-lab.html.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05179</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Fletcher</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orton</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donnelly</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melin</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greathouse</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasaba</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiyoshi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>P. G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giles</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedovato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Jupiter's North Equatorial Belt expansion and thermal wave activity
  ahead of Juno's arrival</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>28 pages, 15 figures, published in Geophysical Research Letters</comments><journal-ref>Geophys. Res. Lett., 44, 7140-7148 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2017GL073383</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dark colors of Jupiter's North Equatorial Belt (NEB, $7-17^\circ$N)
appeared to expand northward into the neighboring zone in 2015, consistent with
a 3-5 year cycle of activity in the NEB. Inversions of thermal-IR imaging from
the Very Large Telescope revealed a moderate warming and reduction of aerosol
opacity at the cloud tops at $17-20^\circ$N, suggesting subsidence and drying
in the expanded sector. Two new thermal waves were identified during this
period: (i) an upper tropospheric thermal wave (wavenumber 16-17, amplitude 2.5
K at 170 mbar) in the mid-NEB that was anti-correlated with haze reflectivity;
and (ii) a stratospheric wave (wavenumber 13-14, amplitude 7.3 K at 5 mbar) at
$20-30^\circ$N. Both were quasi-stationary, confined to regions of eastward
zonal flow, and are morphologically similar to waves observed during previous
expansion events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05180</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Fletcher</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cycles of Activity in the Jovian Atmosphere</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figures, Commentary published in Geophysical Research
  Letters</comments><journal-ref>Geophys. Res. Lett., (2017) 44, 4725-4729</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2017GL073806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Jupiter's banded appearance may appear unchanging to the casual observer, but
closer inspection reveals a dynamic, ever-changing system of belts and zones
with distinct cycles of activity. Identification of these long-term cycles
requires access to datasets spanning multiple jovian years, but explaining them
requires multi-spectral characterization of the thermal, chemical, and aerosol
changes associated with visible color variations. The Earth-based support
campaign for Juno's exploration of Jupiter has already characterized two
upheaval events in the equatorial and temperate belts that are part of
long-term jovian cycles, whose underlying sources could be revealed by Juno's
exploration of Jupiter's deep atmosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05184</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Maurice</keyname><forenames>Emilie</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the LHCb Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Fixed-target physics at LHCb</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>LHCP 2017 proceeding</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LHCb experiment has the unique possibility, among the LHC experiments, to
be operated in fixed target mode, using its internal gas target SMOG. The
energy scale achievable at the LHC and the excellent detector capabilities for
vertexing, tracking and particle identification allow a wealth of measurements
of great interest for cosmic ray and heavy ions physics. We report the first
measurements made in this configuration: the measurement of antiproton
production in proton-helium collisions and the measurements of open and hidden
charm production in proton-argon collisions at $\sqrt{s_\textrm{NN}} =$ 110
GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05196</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Scalia</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leone</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giarrusso</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stift</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The multi-line slope method for the measure of the effective magnetic
  field of the cool stars: an application to the solar like cycle of {\epsilon}
  Eri</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, 6 tables</comments><report-no>MN-17-1641-MJ.R2</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method for the determination of integrated longitudinal stellar fields from
low-resolution spectra is the so-called slope method, which is based on the
regression of the Stokes V signal against the first derivative of Stokes I.
Here we investigate the possibility to extend this technique to measure the
magnetic fields of cool stars from high resolution spectra. For this purpose we
developed a multi-line modification to the slope method, called multi-line
slope method. We tested this technique by analysing synthetic spectra computed
with the COSSAM code and real observations obtained with the high resolution
spectropolarimeters Narval, HARPSpol and Catania Astrophysical Observatory
Spectropolarimeter (CAOS). We show that the multi-line slope method is a fast
alternative to the Least Squares Deconvolution (LSD) technique for the
measurement of the effective magnetic fields of cool stars. Using a Fourier
transform on the effective magnetic field variations of the star $\epsilon$
Eri, we find that the long term periodicity of the field corresponds to the
2.95 yr period of the stellar dynamo, revealed by the variation of the activity
index.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05220</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sancho</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>The exponential laws for emission and decaying of entangled atoms</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>EPJP (2017) 132:332</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first photon emission and the disentanglement of a pair of identical
bosonic atoms in excited entangled states follow an exponential law. We extend
the theory to distinguishable and identical fermionic two-atom systems. As a
byproduct of the analysis we determine the symmetries of the fermionic wave
function. We also derive the emission distributions of excited atoms in product
states, which must take into account the presence of simultaneous detections.
Comparing both distributions reveals a direct manifestation of the
modifications induced by entanglement on the atomic emission properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05230</id><created>2017-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Escartin</keyname><forenames>Juan Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chamorro-Posada</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden probe attacks on ultralong fiber laser key distribution systems</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures. Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In ultralong fiber laser key distribution, two sides use standard optical
equipment to create kilometer long fiber lasers in a communication link to
establish a secret key. Its security rests on the assumption that any attacker
would need much more sophisticated equipment and techniques than those of the
legitimate user in order to discover the generated key. We present a challenge
to that assumption with a hidden probe attack in which the eavesdropper hides a
weak signal in the unavoidable noise floor that appears in the laser during
amplification and probes with it the configuration of one or both communication
parties. We comment how this attack can compromise different proposals for
ultralong laser key distribution and propose possible countermeasures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05242</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Paschos</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Open Issues in Neutrino Reactions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerous investigations discuss neutrino properties from low to ultra high
energies. This review discusses several topics that are investigated in present
day experiments. The first section covers the detection of $\tau$-neutrinos of
cosmic origin and describes the significance of the results. The second topic
points out that the reported reduction of the antineutrino flux in reactor
experiments may be created by short wavelength oscillations where the detector
averages over several wavelengths and observes only an average reduction of the
antineutrino flux. In many theories the propagating particles are Majoranas and
have an anapole moment; they scatter on atomic electrons with a distinct
signature in $\bar\nu_e+e^-\rightarrow\bar\nu_e+e^-$ scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05247</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Mestiri</keyname><forenames>Tarek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darghouth</keyname><forenames>Ala Aldin M. H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casida</keyname><forenames>Mark E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alimi</keyname><forenames>Kamel</forenames></author></authors><title>Density-Functional Theory Study of the Optoelectronic Properties of
  {\pi}-Conjugated Copolymers for Organic Light-Emitting Diodes</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novel low-band-gap copolymer oligomers are proposed on the basis of density
functional theory (DFT) quantum chemical calculations of photophysical
properties. These molecules have an electron donor-accepter (D-A) architecture
involving poly(3-hexylthiophene-2,5-diyl) (P3HT) as D units and furan, aniline,
or hydroquinone as A units. Structural parameters, electronic properties,
highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO)-lowest unoccupied molecular orbital
(LUMO) gaps and molecular orbital densities are predicted. The charge transfer
process between the D unit and the A unit one is supported by analyzing the
optical absorption spectra of the compounds and the localization of the HOMO
and LUMO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05265</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Keathley</keyname><forenames>Phillip D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putnam</keyname><forenames>William P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurent</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vel&#xe1;squez-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Luis F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;rtner</keyname><forenames>Franz X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Examining the Transition from Multiphoton to Optical-Field Photoemission
  From Silicon Nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a detailed experimental and theoretical study of the transition
from multiphoton to optical-field photoemission from n-doped, single-crystal
silicon nanotips. Around this transition, we measure an enhanced emission rate
as well as intensity-dependent structure in the photoelectron yield from the
illuminated nanostructures. Numerically solving the time-dependent
Schr\&quot;odinger equation (TDSE), we demonstrate that the excess emission derives
from the build-up of standing electronic wavepackets near the surface of the
silicon, and the intensity dependent structure in this transition results from
the increased ponderomotive potential and channel closing effects. By way of
time-dependent perturbation theory (TDPT), we then show that the visibility of
intensity dependent structure, the transition rate from multiphoton to
optical-field emission, and scaling rate at high intensities are all consistent
with a narrow band of ground-state energies near the conduction band dominating
the emission process in silicon. These results highlight the importance of
considering both coherent electron wavepacket dynamics at the emitter surface
as well as the ground-state energy distribution when interpreting strong-field
photoemission from solids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05270</id><created>2017-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Nasser</keyname><forenames>Hanan</forenames><affiliation>IFSTTAR/MAST/LAMES</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chabot</keyname><forenames>Armelle</forenames><affiliation>IFSTTAR/MAST/LAMES</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Half-analytical Elastic Solution for 2D Analysis of Cracked Pavements</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1016/j.advengsoft.2017.06.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a half-analytical elastic solution convenient for
parametric studies of 2D cracked pavements. The pavement structure is reduced
to three elastic and homogeneous equivalent layers resting on a soil. In a
similar way than the Pasternak's modelling for concrete pavements, the soil is
modelled by one layer, named shear layer, connected to Winkler's springs in
order to ensure the transfer of shear stresses between the pavement structure
and the springs. The whole four-layer system is modelled using a specific model
developed for the analysis of delamination in composite materials. It reduces
the problem by one dimension and gives access to regular interface stresses
between layers at the edge of vertical cracks allowing the initial debonding
analysis. In 2D plane strain conditions, a system of twelve-second order
differential equations is written analytically. This system is solved
numerically by the finite difference method (Newmark) computed in the free
Scilab software. The calculus tool allows analysis of the impact of material
characteristics changing, loads and locations of cracks in pavements on the
distribution of mechanical fields. The approach with fracture mechanic concepts
is well suited for practical use and for some subsequent numerical developments
in 3D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05276</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Snigdha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranga</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rawat</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhibar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>G. Anil</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic Resolution of Compton Electrons in CeBr3 Scintillator using
  Compact CCT</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CeBr3 is emerging as one of the best scintillators having properties almost
similar to Cerium doped lanthanum halide scintillators. We have measured, for
the first time, the intrinsic energy resolution of Compton electrons in a
cylindrical 1&quot;x1&quot; CeBr3 detector using the sources, namely, 137Cs, 22Na and
60Co employing Compton Coincidence Technique (CCT). We have used PIXIE-4 data
acquisition system which makes the measurement setup quite compact. The results
have shown that non-proportionality is the major factor in limiting the overall
energy resolution of CeBr3 and the intrinsic resolution in CeBr3 arises due to
processes other than the scattering of electrons inside the scintillator. We
have also studied the dependence of intrinsic energy resolution on the
coincidence window and optimized its value for a given source
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05277</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Herega</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical aspects of self-organization processes in composites. 1.
  Simulation of percolation clusters of phases and of inner boundaries</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A range of percolation models of cluster systems of composites is discussed.
In the models the parameters of the clusters of a substance and inner
boundaries were obtained by the Monte Carlo method, and the possibility of
affecting the properties of composite materials at the early stages of
structure formation was studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05280</id><created>2017-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Arpan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarov</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rule</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>A two dimensional model of curvilinear blood vessels with layered
  elastic walls</title><categories>q-bio.TO cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a two dimensional model describing the elastic behaviour of the
wall of a curved blood vessel. The wall has a laminate structure consisting of
several anisotropic layers of varying thickness and is assumed to be much
smaller in thickness than the radius of the vessel which itself is allowed to
vary. Our two-dimensional model takes the interaction of the wall with the
surrounding tissue and the blood flow into account and is obtained via a
dimension reduction procedure. The curvature and twist of the vessel axis as
well as the anisotropy of the laminate wall present the main challenges in
applying the dimension reduction procedure so plenty of examples of canonical
shapes of vessels and their walls are supplied with explicit systems of
differential equations at the end.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05284</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhen</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imtiaz</keyname><forenames>Haroon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hongwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Assessing existent possibility of 2D materials through a simple
  mechanical model</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical and chemical properties of 2D material are highly sensitive to its
structures whose regularity are seldom investigated, here we proposed a simple
mechanical model whose covalent bonds are connected by angle springs, with
which we gave insight into stability, bending stiffness and some other
properties of 2D structures. It is found that Flat, Chair and Washboard possess
larger existent possibilities, which are consistent with existing 2D materials'
structures. This model is a tool to evaluate existent possibilities of periodic
2D structures from mechanical viewpoint.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05293</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mousavi</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matzkin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong and weak single particle nonlocality induced by time-dependent
  boundary conditions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1706.08617</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the issue of single particle nonlocality in a quantum system
subjected to time-dependent boundary conditions. We first prove that contrary
to earlier claims, there is no strong nonlocality: a quantum state localized at
the center of a well with infinitely high moving walls is not modified by the
wall's motion. We then show the existence of a weak form of nonlocality: when a
quantum state is extended over the well, the wall's motion induces a current
density all over the box instantaneously. We indicate how this current density
can in principle be measured by performing weak measurements of the particle's
momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05294</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zahedinejad</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaribafiyan</keyname><forenames>Arman</forenames></author></authors><title>Combinatorial Optimization on Gate Model Quantum Computers: A Survey</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The advent of quantum computing processors with possibility to scale beyond
experimental capacities magnifies the importance of studying their
applications. Combinatorial optimization problems can be one of the promising
applications of these new devices. These problems are recurrent in industrial
applications and they are in general difficult for classical computing
hardware. In this work, we provide a survey of the approaches to solving
different types of combinatorial optimization problems, in particular quadratic
unconstrained binary optimization (QUBO) problems on a gate model quantum
computer. We focus mainly on four different approaches including digitizing the
adiabatic quantum computing, global quantum optimization algorithms, the
quantum algorithms that approximate the ground state of a general QUBO problem,
and quantum sampling. We also discuss the quantum algorithms that are custom
designed to solve certain types of QUBO problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05297</id><created>2017-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Villaeys</keyname><forenames>Albert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zouari</keyname><forenames>Mabrouk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Kuo Kan</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization effects on intermolecular vibrational energy transfer
  analyzed by 2DIR spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>30 pages, 9 figures. To be submitted to Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, we analyze the influence of the polarization effects
taking place during the course of a 2DIR spectroscopy experiment performed on a
molecular system undergoing an intermolecular vibrational energy transfer
process. When both donor and acceptor molecules participating in the
vibrational energy transfer are embedded in a host solvent, they face
rotational diffusion that strongly distorts the resulting 2DIR spectra. It
could be expected that the difference between rotational diffusion constants
will be of particular interest. For this purpose, the polarization effects are
discussed according to the different orderings of the laser-molecule
interactions. Next, we study the distortions of the spectra as a function of
the rotational diffusion constants of the individual molecules. The knowledge
of these polarization effects are relevant to the interpretation of the
spectra. Finally, the conclusions reached in this work for a vibrational energy
transfer are valid for any other type of third-order optical process performed
on the same molecular system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05314</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yumo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frechette</keyname><forenames>Joelle</forenames></author></authors><title>Elastic Deformation of Soft Coatings Due to Lubrication Forces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Elastic deformation of rigid materials with soft coatings (stratified
materials) due to lubrication forces can also alter the interpretation of
dynamic surface forces measurements and prevent contact formation between
approaching surfaces. Understanding the role of elastic deformation on the
process of fluid drainage is necessary, and the case where one (or both) of the
interacting materials consists of a rigid substrate with a soft coating is
still limited. We combine lubrication theory and solid linear elasticity to
describe the dynamic of fluid drainage past a compliant stratified boundary.
The analysis presented covers the full range of coating thicknesses, from an
elastic foundation to a half-space for an incomressible coating. We decouple
the individual contributions of the coating thickness and material properties
on the elastic deformation, hydrodynamic forces, and fluid film thickness. We
obtain a simple expression for the shift in contact position during force
measurements that is valid for many experimental conditions. We compare
directly the effect of stratification on the out-of-contact deformation to the
well-known effect of stratification on indentation. We show that corrections
developed for stratification in contact mechanics are not applicable to
elastohydrodynamic deformation. Finally, we provide generalized contour maps
that can be employed directly to estimate the elastic deformation present in
most dynamic surface force measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05315</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Fa-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Dong-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chang-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>The visualization of the space probability distribution for a moving
  particle I: in a single ring-shaped Coulomb potential</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 6 tables, 1 figures</comments><msc-class>83C15</msc-class><acm-class>A.m</acm-class><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We first present the exact solutions of the single ring-shaped Coulomb
potential and then realize the visualizations of the space probability
distribution for a moving particle within the framework of this potential. We
illustrate the two-(contour) and three-dimensional (isosurface) visualizations
for those specifically given quantum numbers (n, l, m) essentially related to
those so-called quasi quantum numbers (n',l',m') through changing the single
ring-shaped Coulomb potential parameter b. We find that the space probability
distributions (isosurface) of a moving particle for the special case and the
usual case are spherical and circular ring-shaped, respectively by considering
all variables in spherical coordinates. We also study the features of the
relative probability values P of the space probability distributions. As an
illustration, by studying the special case of the quantum numbers (n, l, m)=(6,
5, 1) we notice that the space probability distribution for a moving particle
will move towards two poles of axis z as the relative probability value P
increases. Moreover, we discuss the series expansion of the deformed spherical
harmonics through the orthogonal and complete spherical harmonics and find that
the principal component decreases gradually and other components will increase
as the potential parameter b increases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05320</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Piparo</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author></authors><title>The Algebra of the Pseudo-Observables III: Transformations and Time
  Evolution</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><msc-class>81P05, 81S05, 81R05, 81P15</msc-class><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is the third part concluding the introduction of the powerful
algebra of the pseudo-observables. In this article will be dealt how to treat
the time evolution, and, more in general, the transformations, in the framework
of the new theory. It will be shown that this requires only minor changes with
respect to the Dirac-Jordan transformation theory that can be found in almost
any textbook, with some more care about the treatment of the continuous limit.
A remarkable difference is also in the introduction of the time reversal, which
gives the opportunity to a deeper insight about the Hermitian transposition. In
the conclusions, we will examine better the relationship between time evolution
and measurement, a very problematic aspect in the framework of the Copenhagen
interpretation (and in many others ones). Finally we will present a list of
compelling reasons for which the physics community would seriously have to
evaluate a switching to the new formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05326</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Makaremi</keyname><forenames>Meysam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mortazavi</keyname><forenames>Bohayra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Chandra Veer</forenames></author></authors><title>Adsorption of Metallic, Metalloidic, and Nonmetallic Adatoms on
  Two-Dimensional C3N</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional polyaniline with a C3N stoichiometry, is a newly fabricated
material that has expected to possess fascinating electronic, thermal,
mechanical and chemical properties . The possibility of further tuning the C3N
properties upon the adsorption of foreign adatoms is thus among the most
attractive researches. We carried out extensive ab-initio density functional
theory (DFT) simulations to investigate the adsorption of various elements
including nonmetallic, metalloidic and metallic elements on the C3N monolayer.
While pristine C3N acts as a semiconductor with an indirect electronic band
gap; the functionalization with nonmetallic and semimetallic elements leads to
a p-type doping and induces metallic behavior to the monolayer. On the other
hand, metallic adsorption depending on the adatom size and the number of
valence electrons may result in semiconducting, half-metallic or metallic
properties. Whenever metallic foreign atoms conduct metallic characteristics,
they mostly lead to the n-type doping by electron donation to the surface.
Moreover, adsorption of transition metals could enhance the magnetic behavior
of the monolayer due to the contribution of d electronic states. These results
suggest that C3N illustrates viable electronic-magnetic properties which could
be promising for semiconducting, nanosensores and catalytic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05350</id><created>2017-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Huan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Haobin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Bingjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of Hilbert-Huang decomposition to reduce noise and
  characterize for NMR FID signal of proton precession magnetometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det cs.CE</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The parameters in a nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) free induction decay
(FID) signal contain information that is useful in magnetic field measurement,
magnetic resonance sounding (MRS) and other related applications. A real time
sampled FID signal is well modeled as a finite mixture of exponential sequences
plus noise. We propose to use the Hilbert-Huang Transform (HHT) for noise
reduction and characterization, where the generalized Hilbert-Huang represents
a way to decompose a signal into so-called intrinsic mode function (IMF) along
with a trend, and obtain instantaneous frequency data. Moreover, the HHT for an
FID signal's feature analysis is applied for the first time. First, acquiring
the actual untuned FID signal by a developed prototype of proton magnetometer,
and then the empirical mode decomposition (EMD) is performed to decompose the
noise and original FID. Finally, the HHT is applied to the obtained IMFs to
extract the Hilbert energy spectrum, to indicate the energy distribution of the
signal on the frequency axis. By theory analysis and the testing of an actual
FID signal, the results show that, compared with general noise reduction
methods such as auto correlation and singular value decomposition (SVD),
combined with the proposed method can further suppress the interfered signals
effectively, and can obtain different components of FID signal, which can use
to identify the magnetic anomaly, the existence of groundwater etc. This is a
very important property since it can be exploited to separate the FID signal
from noise and to estimate exponential sequence parameters of FID signal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05358</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Minamitsuji</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author></authors><title>Proca stars with nonminimal coupling to the Einstein tensor</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 044017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.044017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate Proca star (PS) solutions, namely boson star (BS) type
solutions for a complex vector field with mass and nonminimal coupling to the
Einstein tensor. Irrespective of the existence of nonminimal coupling, PS
solutions are mini-BS type, but the inclusion of it changes properties. For
positive nonminimal coupling parameters, PS solutions do not exist for central
amplitudes above some certain value due to the singular behavior of the
evolution equations. For negative nonminimal coupling parameters, there is no
such singular behavior but sufficiently enhanced numerical resolutions are
requested for larger amplitudes. Irrespective of the sign of the nonzero
nonminimal coupling parameter, PSs with the maximal Arnowitt-Deser-Misner mass
and Noether charge are gravitationally bound. Properties of PSs are very
similar to those of BSs in scalar-tensor theories including healthy
higher-derivative terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05365</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Beamin</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minniti</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pullen</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>V. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bendek</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gromadzki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurtev</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>P. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butler</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for Faint Comoving Companions to the $\alpha$ Centauri system
  in the VVV Survey Infrared Images</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The VVV survey has observed the southern disk of the Milky Way in the near
infrared, covering 240 deg$^{2}$ in the $ZYJHK_S$ filters. We search the VVV
Survey images in a $\sim$19 deg$^{2}$ field around $\alpha$ Centauri, the
nearest stellar system to the Sun, to look for possible overlooked companions
that the baseline in time of VVV would be able to uncover. The photometric
depth of our search reaches $Y\sim$19.3 mag, $J\sim$19 mag, and $K_S\sim$17
mag. This search has yielded no new companions in $\alpha$ Centauri system,
setting an upper mass limit for any unseen companion well into the brown
dwarf/planetary mass regime. The apparent magnitude limits were turned into
effective temperature limits, and the presence of companion objects with
effective temperatures warmer than 325K can be ruled out using different
state-of-the-art atmospheric models.
  These limits were transformed into mass limits using evolutionary models,
companions with masses above 11 M$_{Jup}$ were discarded, extending the
constraints recently provided in the literature up to projected distances of
d&lt;7 000 AU from $\alpha$ Cen AB and $\sim$1200 AU from Proxima. In the next few
years, the VVV extended survey (VVVX) will allow to extend the search and place
similar limits on brown dwarfs/planetary companions to $\alpha$ Cen AB for
separations up to 20 000AU.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05371</id><created>2017-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Otiniano</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarado</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved calibration process for the WCDs of the LAGO project using
  semi-analytic model</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>in Spanish</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct measurements of VEM using scintillating plastic plates in water
Cherenkov prototype detectors and a muon flux model were previously used to
reproduce the charge histogram of a detector. In these measurements the VEM has
a significantly lower value than would be obtained by locating the charge
histogram maximum.
  In this technical note we will use the inverse process, being known the
charge histogram we will use a simple model to estimate the load distribution
of the VEM. We will then use this VEM distribution and a one-hour secondary
cosmic ray flux simulation to estimate the total muon component of the
histogram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
