<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:03:23Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-02-17" from="2017-02-17" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0812.1984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0812.1984</id><created>2008-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>Earl</forenames></author></authors><title>Potential-density pairs for a family of finite disks</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>13 pages 2 figures Accepted by ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 693, Issue 2, pp. 1310-1315
  (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/693/2/1310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exact analytical solutions are given for the three finite disks with surface
density $\Sigma_n=\sigma_0 (1-R^2/\alpha^2)^{n-1/2} \textrm{with} n=0, 1, 2$.
Closed-form solutions in cylindrical co-ordinates are given using only
elementary functions for the potential and for the gravitational field of each
of the disks.
  The n=0 disk is the flattened homeoid for which $\Sigma_{hom} =
\sigma_0/\sqrt{1-R^2/\alpha^2}$. Improved results are presented for this disk.
The n=1 disk is the Maclaurin disk for which $\Sigma_{Mac} = \sigma_0
\sqrt{1-R^2/\alpha^2}$. The Maclaurin disk is a limiting case of the Maclaurin
spheroid. The potential of the Maclaurin disk is found here by integrating the
potential of the n=0 disk over $\alpha$, exploiting the linearity of Poisson's
equation. The n=2 disk has the surface density $\Sigma_{D2}=\sigma_0
(1-R^2/\alpha^2)^{3/2}$. The potential is found by integrating the potential of
the n=1 disk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.2433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.2433</id><created>2011-08-11</created><updated>2011-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherically symmetric inhomogeneous model with Chaplygin gas</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><report-no>JCAP 1110 (2011) 002</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 2011</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2011/10/002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the late time acceleration with a Chaplygin type of gas in
spherically symmetric inhomogeneous model. At the early phase we get
Einstien-deSitter type of solution generalised to inhomogeneous spacetime. But
at late stage of the evolution our solutions admit the accelerating nature of
the universe. For a large scale factor our model behaves like a ?CDM model. We
calculate the deceleration parameter for this anisotropic model, which, unlike
its homogeneous counterpart, shows that the flip is not syn- chronous occurring
early at the outer shells. This is in line with other physical processes in any
inhomogeneous models. Depending upon initial conditions our solution also gives
bouncing universe. In the absence of inhomogeneity our solution reduces to
wellknown solutions in homogeneous case. We have also calculated the effective
deceleration parameter in terms of Hubble parameter. The whole situation is
later discussed with the help of wellknown Raychaudhury equation and the
results are compared with the previous case. This work is an extension of our
recent communication where an attempt was made to see if the presence of extra
dimensions and/or inhomogeneity can trigger an inflation in a matter dominated
Lemaitre Tolman Bondi model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.0361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.0361</id><created>2013-01-02</created><updated>2013-02-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bambi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the space-time geometry around black hole candidates with the
  available radio and X-ray data</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Invited review paper; 37 pages, 10 figures. v2: added a few
  references</comments><journal-ref>Astron.Rev.8:4-39,2013</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/21672857.2013.11519712</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Astrophysical black hole candidates are thought to be the Kerr black holes
predicted by General Relativity, but the actual nature of these objects has
still to be proven. The Kerr black hole hypothesis can be tested by observing
strong gravity features and check if they are in agreement with the predictions
of General Relativity. In particular, the study of the properties of the
electromagnetic radiation emitted by the gas of the accretion disk can provide
information on the geometry of the space-time around these objects and
constrain possible deviations from the Kerr background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.1875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.1875</id><created>2013-11-07</created><updated>2014-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ono</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nambu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katayama</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirata</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Negative Quantum Renormalization of Excitation Energies in the
  Spin-1/2 Kagome Lattice Antiferromagnet Cs$_2$Cu$_3$SnF$_{12}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, including Supplemental Materials</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 83, 043701 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.83.043701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic excitations in the spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ distorted kagome lattice
antiferromagnet Cs$_2$Cu$_3$SnF$_{12}$, which has an ordered ground state owing
to the strong Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction, were studied using inelastic
neutron scattering. Although the spin-wave dispersion can be qualitatively
understood in terms of linear spin-wave theory (LSWT), the excitation energies
are renormalized by a factor of approximately 0.6 from those calculated by
LSWT, almost irrespective of the momentum transfer. This inadequacy of LSWT,
which is attributed to quantum fluctuations, provides evidence of negative
quantum renormalization in the spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ kagome lattice
antiferromagnet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.6704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.6704</id><created>2013-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Lianyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Shijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Pengfei</forenames></author></authors><title>BCS-BEC crossover in relativistic Fermi systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con nucl-th</categories><comments>44 Pages, 20 figures, accepted by International Journal of Modern
  Physics A. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1007.1920,
  arXiv:1202.3490, arXiv:hep-ph/0703042</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A, 28, 1330054(2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X13300548</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  We review the BCS-BEC crossover in relativistic Fermi systems, including the
QCD matter at finite density. In the first part we study the BCS-BEC crossover
in a relativistic four-fermion interaction model and show how the relativistic
effect affects the BCS-BEC crossover. In the second part, we investigate both
two-color QCD at finite baryon density and pion superfluid at finite isospin
density, by using an effective Nambu--Jona-Lasinio model. We will show how the
model describes the weakly interacting diquark and pion condensates at low
density and the BEC-BCS crossover at high density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.8127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.8127</id><created>2014-01-31</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ara&#xfa;jo</keyname><forenames>Mateus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brukner</keyname><forenames>&#x10c;aslav</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational advantage from quantum-controlled ordering of gates</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4+5 pages, 2 figures. Fixed typos in Appendix E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 250402 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.250402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is usually assumed that a quantum computation is performed by applying
gates in a specific order. One can relax this assumption by allowing a control
quantum system to switch the order in which the gates are applied. This
provides a more general kind of quantum computing, that allows transformations
on blackbox quantum gates that are impossible in a circuit with fixed order.
Here we show that this model of quantum computing is physically realizable, by
proposing an interferometric setup that can implement such a quantum control of
the order between the gates. We show that this new resource provides a
reduction in computational complexity: we propose a problem that can be solved
using $O(n)$ blackbox queries, whereas the best known quantum algorithm with
fixed order between the gates requires $O(n^2)$ queries. Furthermore, we
conjecture that solving this problem in a classical computer takes exponential
time, which may be of independent interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3138</id><created>2014-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>Earl J</forenames></author></authors><title>Dwarf Galaxies in the Halo of NGC 891</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures. Submitted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 790, Issue 1, article id. 76, 13
  pp. (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/790/1/76</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results of a survey of the region within 40 arcmin of NGC 891,
a nearby nearly perfectly edge-on spiral galaxy. Candidate &quot;non-stars&quot; with
diameters greater than 15 arcsec were selected from the GSC 2.3.2 catalog and
cross-comparison of observations in several bands using archived \galex, DSS2,
WISE, and 2MASS images identified contaminating stars, artifacts and background
galaxies, all of which were excluded. The resulting 71 galaxies, many of which
were previously uncataloged, comprise a size limited survey of the region. A
majority of the galaxies are in the background of NGC 891 and are for the most
part members of the Abell 347 cluster at a distance of about 75 \Mpc. The new
finds approximately double the known membership of Abell 347, previously
thought to be relatively sparse. We identify a total of 7 dwarf galaxies, most
of which are new discoveries. The newly discovered dwarf galaxies are dim and
gas-poor and may be associated with the previously observed arcs of RGB halo
stars in the halo and the prominent HI filament and the lopsided features in
the disk of NGC 891. Several of the dwarfs show signs of disruption, consistent
with being remnants of an ancient collision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.8224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.8224</id><created>2014-07-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Saraiva</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baena</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calder&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koiller</keyname><forenames>Belita</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of one and two donors in Silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 27, 154208 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/27/15/154208</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide here a roadmap for modeling silicon nano-devices with one or two
group V donors (D). We discuss systems containing one or two electrons, that
is, D^0, D^-, D_2^+ and D_2^0 centers. The impact of different levels of
approximation is discussed. The most accurate instances -- for which we provide
quantitative results -- are within multivalley effective mass including the
central cell correction and a configuration interaction account of the
electron-electron correlations. We also derive insightful, yet less accurate,
analytical approximations and discuss their validity and limitations -- in
particular, for a donor pair, we discuss the single orbital LCAO method, the
Huckel approximation and the Hubbard model. Finally we discuss the connection
between these results and recent experiments on few dopant devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.2952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.2952</id><created>2014-08-13</created><updated>2014-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>David-Leon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hemperek</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;gging</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wermes</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>A method for precise charge reconstruction with pixel detectors using
  binary hit information</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2015.03.067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method is presented to precisely reconstruct charge spectra with pixel
detectors using binary hit information of individual pixels. The method is
independent of the charge information provided by the readout circuitry and has
a resolution mainly limited by the electronic noise. It relies on the ability
to change the detection threshold in small steps while counting hits from a
particle source. The errors are addressed and the performance of the method is
shown based on measurements with the ATLAS pixel chip FE-I4 bump bonded to a
230 {\mu}m 3D-silicon sensor. Charge spectra from radioactive sources and from
electron beams are presented serving as examples. It is demonstrated that a
charge resolution ({\sigma}&lt;200 e) close to the electronic noise of the ATLAS
FE-I4 pixel chip can be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.3699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.3699</id><created>2014-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Jauregui</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey L.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the lower semicontinuity of the ADM mass</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>53C20 (Primary), 83C99, 58Z05 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Comm. Anal. Geom., Vol. 26, No. 1, 2018</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ADM mass, viewed as a functional on the space of asymptotically flat
Riemannian metrics of nonnegative scalar curvature, fails to be continuous for
many natural topologies. In this paper we prove that lower semicontinuity holds
in natural settings: first, for pointed Cheeger--Gromov convergence (without
any symmetry assumptions) for $n=3$, and second, assuming rotational symmetry,
for weak convergence of the associated canonical embeddings into Euclidean
space, for $n \geq 3$. We also apply recent results of LeFloch and Sormani to
deal with the rotationally symmetric case, with respect to a pointed type of
intrinsic flat convergence. We provide several examples, one of which
demonstrates that the positive mass theorem is implied by a statement of the
lower semicontinuity of the ADM mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.00508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.00508</id><created>2015-06-01</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kivel&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>Mikko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>Mason A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Isomorphisms in Multilayer Networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DM cs.SI math.CO</categories><comments>Working paper; 18 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>05C82, 68R10, 91D30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the concept of graph isomorphisms to multilayer networks with any
number of &quot;aspects&quot; (i.e., types of layering). In developing this
generalization, we identify multiple types of isomorphisms. For example, in
multilayer networks with a single aspect, permuting vertex labels, layer
labels, and both vertex labels and layer labels each yield different
isomorphism relations between multilayer networks. Multilayer network
isomorphisms lead naturally to defining isomorphisms in any of the numerous
types of networks that can be represented as a multilayer network, and we
thereby obtain isomorphisms for multiplex networks, temporal networks, networks
with both of these features, and more. We reduce each of the multilayer network
isomorphism problems to a graph isomorphism problem, where the size of the
graph isomorphism problem grows linearly with the size of the multilayer
network isomorphism problem. One can thus use software that has been developed
to solve graph isomorphism problems as a practical means for solving multilayer
network isomorphism problems. Our theory lays a foundation for extending many
network analysis methods --- including motifs, graphlets, structural roles, and
network alignment --- to any multilayer network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04573</id><created>2015-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Naumov</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shkirmanov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse-square law violation and reactor antineutrino anomaly</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex physics.data-an</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, Talk at the International Workshop on Prospects
  of Particle Physics: &quot;Neutrino Physics and Astrophysics&quot;, Valday, Russia,
  February 1-8, 2015</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Part.Nucl.48 (2017) no.1,12-20; Fiz.Elem.Chast.Atom.Yadra 47
  (2016) no.6, 1884-1897</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063779616060174</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a possibility that the so-called reactor antineutrino anomaly can
be, at least in part, explained by applying a quantum field-theoretical
approach to neutrino oscillations, which in particular predicts a small
deviation from the classical inverse-square law at short but macroscopic
distances between the neutrino source and detector. An extensive statistical
analysis of the reactor data is performed to examine this speculation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05151</id><created>2015-09-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Shijun</forenames></author></authors><title>Deconfinement Phase Transition with External Magnetic Field in
  Friedberg-Lee Model</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages,4 figures,2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. Lett. 33, 112501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0256-307X/33/11/112501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deconfinement phase transition with external magnetic field is
investigated in the Friedberg-Lee model. In the frame of functional
renormalization group, we extend the often used potential expansion method for
continuous phase transitions to the first-order phase transition in the model.
By solving the flow equations we find that, the magnetic field displays a
catalysis effect and it becomes more difficult to break through the confinement
in hot and dense medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02198</id><created>2015-10-08</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Neil J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Algebraic and Logical Methods in Quantum Computation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Ph.D. thesis, Dalhousie University, August 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis contains contributions to the theory of quantum computation.
  We first define a new method to efficiently approximate special unitary
operators. Specifically, given a special unitary U and a precision {\epsilon} &gt;
0, we show how to efficiently find a sequence of Clifford+V or Clifford+T
operators whose product approximates U up to {\epsilon} in the operator norm.
In the general case, the length of the approximating sequence is asymptotically
optimal. If the unitary to approximate is diagonal then our method is optimal:
it yields the shortest sequence approximating U up to {\epsilon}.
  Next, we introduce a mathematical formalization of a fragment of the Quipper
quantum programming language. We define a typed lambda calculus called
Proto-Quipper which formalizes a restricted but expressive fragment of Quipper.
The type system of Proto-Quipper is based on intuitionistic linear logic and
prohibits the duplication of quantum data, in accordance with the no-cloning
property of quantum computation. We prove that Proto-Quipper is type-safe in
the sense that it enjoys the subject reduction and progress properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00895</id><created>2015-11-03</created><updated>2016-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Masoero</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raimondo</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valeri</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Bethe Ansatz and the Spectral Theory of affine Lie algebra--valued
  connections II. The non simply--laced case</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>37 pages, 1 figure. Continuation of arXiv:1501.07421. Minor change in
  the title. New subsection 5.1 on the action of the Weyl group on the Bethe
  Ansatz solutions</comments><msc-class>82B23, 17B67, 34M40, 37K30</msc-class><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. (2017) 349: 1063</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2744-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assess the ODE/IM correspondence for the quantum $\mathfrak{g}$-KdV model,
for a non-simply laced Lie algebra $\mathfrak{g}$. This is done by studying a
meromorphic connection with values in the Langlands dual algebra of the affine
Lie algebra ${\mathfrak{g}}^{(1)}$, and constructing the relevant $\Psi$-system
among subdominant solutions. We then use the $\Psi$-system to prove that the
generalized spectral determinants satisfy the Bethe Ansatz equations of the
quantum $\mathfrak{g}$-KdV model. We also consider generalized Airy functions
for twisted Kac--Moody algebras and we construct new explicit solutions to the
Bethe Ansatz equations. The paper is a continuation of our previous work on the
ODE/IM correspondence for simply-laced Lie algebras.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06158</id><created>2015-11-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Isacker</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape coexistence in the microscopically guided interacting boson model</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures; To appear in focus issue of Journal of Physics G
  &quot;Shape coexistence in nuclei&quot;</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43 (2016) 024008</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/2/024008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Shape coexistence has been a subject of great interest in nuclear physics for
many decades. In the context of the nuclear shell model, intruder excitations
may give rise to remarkably low-lying excited $0^+$ states associated with
different intrinsic shapes. In heavy open-shell nuclei, the dimension of the
shell-model configuration space that includes such intruder excitations becomes
exceedingly large, thus requiring a drastic truncation scheme. Such a framework
has been provided by the interacting boson model (IBM). In this article we
address the phenomenon of shape coexistence and its relevant spectroscopy from
the point of view of the IBM. A special focus is placed on the method developed
recently which makes use of the link between the IBM and the self-consistent
mean-field approach based on the nuclear energy density functional. The method
is extended to deal with various intruder configurations associated with
different equilibrium shapes. We assess the predictive power of the method and
suggest possible improvements and extensions, by considering illustrative
examples in the neutron-deficient Pb region, where shape coexistence has been
experimentally studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05892</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rutkevich</keyname><forenames>Sergei B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The three-dimensional $O(n)$ $\phi^4$ model on a strip with free
  boundary conditions: exact results for a nontrivial dimensional crossover in
  the limit $n\to\infty$</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Invited talk at MQFT2015, pdf-Latex, 26 pages</comments><journal-ref>TMF 190, 325-343 (2017); Engl. trans.: Theor. Math. Phys. 190,
  279-294 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.4213/tmf9120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent exact $n\to\infty$ results for critical Casimir forces of the $O(n)$
$\phi^4$ model on a three-dimensional strip bounded by two planar free surfaces
at a distance $L$ are surveyed. This model has long-range order below the bulk
critical temperature $T_c$ if $L=\infty$, but remains disordered for all $T&gt;0$
when $L&lt;\infty$. A proper analysis of its scaling behavior near $T_c$ is quite
challenging: Besides with bulk, boundary, and finite-size critical behaviors,
one must deal with a nontrivial dimensional crossover. The model can be solved
exactly in the limit $n\to\infty$ in terms of the eigenvalues and eigenenergies
of a selfconsistent Schr\&quot;odinger equation involving a potential $v(z)$ with
the near-boundary singular behavior $v(z\to 0+)\approx
-1/(4z^2)+4m/(\pi^{2}z)$, where $m=1/\xi_+(|t|)$ is the inverse bulk
correlation length and $t\sim (T-T_c)/T_c$, and a corresponding singularity at
the second boundary plane. The potential $v(z)$, the excess free energy, and
the Casimir force have been determined numerically with high precision. Exact
analytical results for a variety of properties such as series expansion
coefficients of $v(z)$, the scattering data of $v(z)$ in the semi-infinite case
$L=\infty$ for all $m\gtreqless 0$, and the low-temperature asymptotic behavior
of the residual free energy and the Casimir force can be obtained by a
combination of boundary-operator and short-distance expansions, proper
extensions of inverse scattering theory, new trace formulae, and semiclassical
expansions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06543</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06543</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Endo</keyname><forenames>Shimpei</forenames><affiliation>LKB</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Castin</keyname><forenames>Yvan</forenames><affiliation>LKB</affiliation></author></authors><title>The interaction-sensitive states of a trapped two-component ideal Fermi
  gas and application to the virial expansion of the unitary Fermi gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>32 pages, augmented version: with respect to published version,
  paragraph added at the end of section 5.3 and figure 3 added (comparison of
  our conjecture for the fourth cluster coefficient of the unitary Fermi gas to
  the Monte Carlo diagrammatic results of K. van Houcke et al, Nature Physics
  8, 366 (2012))</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, IOP
  Publishing, 2016, 49, pp.265301</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/26/265301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a two-component ideal Fermi gas in an isotropic harmonic
potential. Some eigenstates have a wavefunction that vanishes when two
distinguishable fermions are at the same location, and would be unaffected by
s-wave contact interactions between the two components. We determine the other,
interaction-sensitive eigenstates, using a Faddeev ansatz. This problem is
nontrivial, due to degeneracies and to the existence of unphysical Faddeev
solutions. As an application we present a new conjecture for the fourth-order
cluster or virial coefficient of the unitary Fermi gas, in good agreement with
the numerical results of Blume and coworkers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07123</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Weizhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Xinran</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental gaps of the Gross-Pitaevskii equation with repulsive
  interaction</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, 16 figures</comments><msc-class>35B40, 35P30, 35Q55, 65N25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study asymptotically and numerically the fundamental gaps (i.e. the
difference between the first excited state and the ground state) in energy and
chemical potential of the Gross-Pitaevskii equation (GPE) -- nonlinear
Schrodinger equation with cubic nonlinearity -- with repulsive interaction
under different trapping potentials including box potential and harmonic
potential. Based on our asymptotic and numerical results, we formulate a gap
conjecture on the fundamental gaps in energy and chemical potential of the GPE
on bounded domains with the homogeneous Dirichlet boundary condition, and in
the whole space with a convex trapping potential growing at least quadratically
in the far field. We then extend these results to the GPE on bounded domains
with either the homogeneous Neumann boundary condition or periodic boundary
condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04013</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Cortes</keyname><forenames>Cristian L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>Zubin</forenames></author></authors><title>Super-Coulombic atom-atom interactions in hyperbolic media</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>Note that this theory and subsequent experimental work was first
  presented in the following conferences: Metamaterials Oxford 2015, META New
  York 2015, SPIE San Diego 2015, DAMOP 2015, CLEO 2015, FIO 2013</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 14144 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms14144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dipole-dipole interactions which govern phenomena like cooperative Lamb
shifts, superradiant decay rates, Van der Waals forces, as well as resonance
energy transfer rates are conventionally limited to the Coulombic near-field.
Here, we reveal a class of real-photon and virtual-photon long-range quantum
electrodynamic (QED) interactions that have a singularity in media with
hyperbolic dispersion. The singularity in the dipole-dipole coupling, referred
to as a Super-Coulombic interaction, is a result of an effective interaction
distance that goes to zero in the ideal limit irrespective of the physical
distance. We investigate the entire landscape of atom-atom interactions in
hyperbolic media and propose practical implementations with phonon-polaritonic
hexagonal boron nitride in the infrared spectral range and plasmonic
super-lattice structures in the visible range. Our work paves the way for the
control of cold atoms in hyperbolic media and the study of many-body atomic
states where optical phonons mediate quantum interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00816</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bayindir</keyname><forenames>Cihan</forenames></author></authors><title>Early Detection of Rogue Waves Using Compressive Sensing</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD physics.ao-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1512.02583</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the possible usage of the compressive sampling for the early
detection of rogue waves. One of the promising techniques for the early
detection of the oceanic rogue waves is to measure the triangular Fourier
spectra which begin to appear at the early stages of their development. For the
early detection of the rogue waves it is possible to treat such a spectrum as a
sparse signal since we would mainly be interested in the high amplitude
triangular region located at the central wavenumber. Therefore compressive
sampling can be a very efficient tool for the rogue wave early warning systems.
Compressed measurements can be acquired by remote sensing techniques such as
coherent SAR which measure the ocean surface envelope or by insitu techniques
such as spectra measuring tools mounted on a ship hull or bottom mounted
pressure gauges. By employing a numerical approach we show that triangular
Fourier spectra can be sensed by compressive measurements at the early stages
of the development of rogue waves such as those in the form of Peregrine and
Akhmediev-Peregrine solitons. Our results may lead to development of the early
warning hardware systems which use the compressive sampling thus the memory
requirements for those systems can be greatly reduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02103</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sola</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Valent</keyname><forenames>Adria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Javier de Cruz</forenames></author></authors><title>First evidence of running cosmic vacuum: challenging the concordance
  model</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Published in: Astrophys.J. 836 (2017) no.1, 43</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/836/1/43</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the fact that a rigid $\Lambda$-term is a fundamental building block
of the concordance $\Lambda$CDM model, we show that a large class of
cosmological scenarios with dynamical vacuum energy density $\rho_{\Lambda}$
and/or gravitational coupling $G$, together with a possible non-conservation of
matter, are capable of seriously challenging the traditional phenomenological
success of the $\Lambda$CDM. In this paper, we discuss these &quot;running vacuum
models&quot; (RVM's), in which $\rho_{\Lambda}=\rho_{\Lambda}(H)$ consists of a
nonvanishing constant term and a series of powers of the Hubble rate. Such
generic structure is potentially linked to the quantum field theoretical
description of the expanding Universe. By performing an overall fit to the
cosmological observables $SNIa+BAO+H(z)+LSS+BBN+CMB$ (in which the WMAP9,
Planck 2013 and Planck 2015 data are taken into account), we find that the
class of RVM's appears significantly more favored than the $\Lambda$CDM, namely
at an unprecedented level of $\gtrsim4.2\sigma$. Furthermore, the Akaike and
Bayesian information criteria confirm that the dynamical RVM's are strongly
preferred as compared to the conventional rigid $\Lambda$-picture of the cosmic
evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06201</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chico</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hellsvik</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delin</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergman</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergqvist</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>A systematic study of magnetodynamic properties at finite temperatures
  in doped permalloy from first principles calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><report-no>PRB 94, 214410 (2016)</report-no><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of first principles calculations, we have systematically
investigated how the magnetodynamic properties Gilbert damping, magnetization
and exchange stiffness are affected when permalloy (Py)
(Fe$_{0.19}$Ni$_{0.81}$) is doped with 4d or 5d transition metal impurities. We
find that the trends in the Gilbert damping can be understood from relatively
few basic parameters such as the density of states at the Fermi level, the
spin-orbit coupling and the impurity concentration. % The temperature
dependence of the Gilbert damping is found to be very weak which we relate to
the lack of intraband transitions in alloys. % Doping with $4d$ elements has no
major impact on the studied Gilbert damping, apart from diluting the host.
However, the $5d$ elements have a profound effect on the damping and allows it
to be tuned over a large interval while maintaining the magnetization and
exchange stiffness. % As regards spin stiffness, doping with early transition
metals results in considerable softening, whereas late transition metals have a
minor impact. % Our result agree well with earlier calculations where
available. In comparison to experiments, the computed Gilbert damping appears
slightly underestimated while the spin stiffness show good general agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07990</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freund</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Sungkyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jesche</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kimchi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manni</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bombardi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manuel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gegenwart</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coldea</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Incommensurate Counterrotating Magnetic Order Stabilized by Kitaev
  Interactions in the Layered Honeycomb ${\alpha}$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 195158 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.195158</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The layered honeycomb magnet $\alpha$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$ has been theoretically
proposed as a candidate to display novel magnetic behaviour associated with
Kitaev interactions between spin-orbit entangled $j_{\rm eff}=1/2$ magnetic
moments on a honeycomb lattice. Here we report single crystal magnetic resonant
x-ray diffraction combined with powder magnetic neutron diffraction to reveal
an incommensurate magnetic order in the honeycomb layers with Ir magnetic
moments counter-rotating on nearest-neighbour sites. This type of magnetic
structure has not been reported experimentally before in honeycomb magnets and
cannot be explained by a spin Hamiltonian with dominant isotropic (Heisenberg)
couplings. The magnetic structure shares many key features with the magnetic
order in the structural polytypes $\beta$ and $\gamma$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$,
understood theoretically to be stabilized by dominant Kitaev interactions
between Ir moments located on the vertices of three-dimensional hyperhoneycomb
and stripyhoneycomb lattices, respectively. Based on this analogy and a
theoretical soft-spin analysis of magnetic ground states for candidate spin
Hamiltonians, we propose that Kitaev interactions also dominate in
$\alpha$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$, indicative of universal Kitaev physics across all three
members of the harmonic honeycomb family of Li$_2$IrO$_3$ polytypes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04310</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2016-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>Om</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Anil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamizhavel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramakrishnan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental evidence for bulk superconductivity in pure Bismuth single
  crystal at ambient pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>O. Prakash et al., Science 10.1126/science.aaf8227 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aaf8227</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bulk rhombohedral Bismuth (Bi) at ambient pressure is a semimetal and it
remains in the normal state down to 10~mK. The superconductivity (SC) in bulk
Bi is thought to be very unlikely due to extremely low carrier density. The
question of SC in Bi has remained unsolved both theoretically and
experimentally. Here, we report first ever observation of bulk SC in highly
pure Bi single crystals (99.9999\%) below 0.53~mK under ambient pressure with
an estimated critical magnetic field of 5.2~$\mu$T at 0~K. The conventional
Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) theory cannot explain the observed SC in Bi,
since the adiabatic approximation of the BCS theory, $\omega_D/E_F&lt;&lt; 1$, does
not hold true for Bi. Bi has a multi-valley type electronic band structure and
SC in Bi could be brought about by the inter-valley electron-phonon coupling.
Such a scenario calls for new theoretical ideas to understand SC in such low
carrier systems with unusual band structure in the non-adiabatic limit,
$\omega_D/E_F \gtrsim 1$. The observation of SC in Bi makes it the lowest
carrier density superconductor surpassing the record held by doped SrTiO$_3$
for nearly 50 years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04487</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salmilehto</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deppe</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Ventra</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Memristors with Superconducting Circuits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 42044 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep42044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Memristors are resistive elements retaining information of their past
dynamics. They have garnered substantial interest due to their potential for
representing a paradigm change in electronics, information processing and
unconventional computing. Given the advent of quantum technologies, a design
for a quantum memristor with superconducting circuits may be envisaged. Along
these lines, we introduce such a quantum device whose memristive behavior
arises from quasiparticle-induced tunneling when supercurrents are cancelled.
For realistic parameters, we find that the relevant hysteretic behavior may be
observed using current state-of-the-art measurements of the phase-driven
tunneling current. Finally, we develop suitable methods to quantify memory
retention in the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01548</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Peng-Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Guo-Zhu</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in two-dimensional disordered Dirac semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures, final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 054507 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.054507</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In two-dimensional Dirac semimetals, Cooper pairing instability occurs only
when the attractive interaction strength $|u|$ is larger than some critical
value $|u_{c}|$ because the density of states vanishes at Dirac points.
Disorders enhance the low-energy density of states but meanwhile shorten the
lifetime of fermions, which tend to promote and suppress superconductivity,
respectively. To determine which of the two competing effects wins, we study
the interplay of Cooper pairing interaction and disorder scattering by means of
renormalization group method. We consider three types of disorders, including
random mass, random gauge potential, and random chemical potential, and show
that the first two suppress superconductivity. In particular, the critical BCS
coupling $|u_{c}|$ is increased to certain larger value if the system contains
only random mass or random gauge potential, which makes the onset of
superconductivity more difficult. In the case of random chemical potential, the
effective disorder parameter flows to the strong coupling regime, where the
perturbation expansion breaks down and cannot provide a clear answer concerning
the fate of superconductivity. When different types of disorder coexist in one
system, their strength parameters all flow to strong couplings. In the strong
coupling regime, the perturbative renormalization group method becomes invalid,
and one needs to employ other methods to treat the disorder effects. We perform
a simple gap equation analysis of the impact of random chemical potential on
superconductivity by using the Abrikosov-Gorkov diagrammatic approach, and also
briefly discuss the possible generalization of this approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01837</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xd6;vg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation and Acceleration of the Universe by Nonlinear Magnetic
  Monopole Fields</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>two column, 6 pages, 2 figures, final published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 105</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4673-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite impressive phenomenological successes, cosmological models are
incomplete without an understanding of what happened at the big bang
singularity. Maxwell electrodynamics, considered as a source of the classical
Einstein field equations, leads to the singular isotropic Friedmann solutions.
In the context of Friedmann-Robertson-Walker (FRW) spacetime, we show that
singular behavior does not occur for a class of nonlinear generalizations of
the electromagnetic theory for strong fields. A new mathematical model is
proposed for which the analytical nonsingular extension of FRW solutions is
obtained by using the nonlinear magnetic monopole fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04233</id><created>2016-04-14</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mallick</keyname><forenames>Arindam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Sanjoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandrashekar</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino oscillations in discrete-time quantum walk framework</title><categories>quant-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>11 pages (2 columns), 5 figures; Published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) no. 2, 85</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4636-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we present neutrino oscillation in the frame-work of quantum walks.
Starting from a one spatial dimensional discrete-time quantum walk we present a
scheme of evolutions that will simulate neutrino oscillation. The set of
quantum walk parameters which is required to reproduce the oscillation
probability profile obtained in both, long range and short range neutrino
experiment is explicitly presented. Our scheme to simulate three-generation
neutrino oscillation from quantum walk evolution operators can be physically
realized in any low energy experimental set-up with access to control a single
six-level system, a multiparticle three-qubit or a qubit-qutrit system. We also
present the entanglement between spins and position space, during neutrino
propagation that will quantify the wave function delocalization around
instantaneous average position of the neutrino. This work will contribute
towards understanding neutrino oscillation in the framework of the quantum
information perspective.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07347</id><created>2016-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasca</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudnicki</keyname><forenames>Lukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walborn</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting entanglement of continuous variables with three mutually
  unbiased bases</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An uncertainty relation is introduced for a symmetric arrangement of three
mutually unbiased bases in continuous variable phase space, and then used to
derive a bipartite entanglement criterion based on the variance of global
operators composed of these three phase space variables. We test this criterion
using spatial variables of photon pairs, and show that the entangled photons
are correlated in three pairs of bases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04356</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2017-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Sixiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Lanjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Miao</forenames></author></authors><title>A closer look at the cosmological implications of the $\Lambda$HDE model</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 467 (1): 961-970</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx146</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous paper, we proposed a heterotic dark energy model, called
$\Lambda$HDE, in which dark energy is composed of two components: cosmological
constant (CC) and holographic dark energy (HDE). The aim of this work is to
give a more comprehensive and systematic investigation on the cosmological
implications of the $\Lambda$HDE model. Firstly, we make use of the current
observations to constrain the $\Lambda$HDE model, and compare its cosmology-fit
results with the results of the $\Lambda$CDM and the HDE model. Then, by
combining a qualitative theoretical analysis with a quantitative numerical
study, we discuss the impact of considering curvature on the cosmic evolutions
of fractional HDE density $\Omega_{hde}$ and fractional CC density
$\Omega_{\Lambda}$, as well as on the ultimate cosmic fate. Finally, we explore
the effects of adopting different types of observational data. We find that:
(1) the current observational data cannot distinguish the $\Lambda$HDE model
from the $\Lambda$CDM and the HDE model; this indicates that DE may contain
multiple components. (2) the asymptotic solution of $\Omega_{hde}$ and the
corresponding cosmic fate in a flat universe can be extended to the case of a
non-flat universe; moreover, compared with the case of a flat universe,
considering curvature will make HDE closer to a phantom dark energy. (3)
compared with JLA dataset, SNLS3 data more favor a phantom type HDE; in
contrast, using other types of observational data have no significant impact on
the cosmic evolutions of the $\Lambda$HDE model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05261</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hacker</keyname><forenames>Bastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Welte</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rempe</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>A photon-photon quantum gate based on a single atom in an optical
  resonator</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature 536, 193-196 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature18592</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two photons in free space pass each other undisturbed. This is ideal for the
faithful transmission of information, but prohibits an interaction between the
photons as required for a plethora of applications in optical quantum
information processing. The long-standing challenge here is to realise a
deterministic photon-photon gate. This requires an interaction so strong that
the two photons can shift each others phase by pi. For polarisation qubits,
this amounts to the conditional flipping of one photon's polarisation to an
orthogonal state. So far, only probabilistic gates based on linear optics and
photon detectors could be realised, as &quot;no known or foreseen material has an
optical nonlinearity strong enough to implement this conditional phase
shift...&quot; [Science 318, 1567]. Meanwhile, tremendous progress in the
development of quantum-nonlinear systems has opened up new possibilities for
single-photon experiments. Platforms range from Rydberg blockade in atomic
ensembles to single-atom cavity quantum electrodynamics. Applications like
single-photon switches and transistors, two-photon gateways, nondestructive
photon detectors, photon routers and nonlinear phase shifters have been
demonstrated, but none of them with the ultimate information carriers, optical
qubits. Here we employ the strong light-matter coupling provided by a single
atom in a high-finesse optical resonator to realise the Duan-Kimble protocol of
a universal controlled phase flip (CPF, pi phase shift) photon-photon quantum
gate. We achieve an average gate fidelity of F=(76.2+/-3.6)% and specifically
demonstrate the capability of conditional polarisation flipping as well as
entanglement generation between independent input photons. Our gate could
readily perform most of the hitherto existing two-photon operations. It also
discloses avenues towards new quantum information processing applications where
photons are essential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05603</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spitoni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vincenzo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matteucci</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>New analytical solutions for chemical evolution models: characterizing
  the population of star-forming and passive galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, A&amp;A in press</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629745</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analytical models of chemical evolution, including inflow and outflow of gas,
are important tools to study how the metal content in galaxies evolves as a
function of time. In this work, we present new analytical solutions for the
evolution of the gas mass, total mass and metallicity of a galactic system,
when a decaying exponential infall rate of gas and galactic winds are assumed.
We apply our model to characterize a sample of local star-forming and passive
galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey data, with the aim of reproducing
their observed mass-metallicity relation; in this way, we can derive how the
two populations of star-forming and passive galaxies differ in their particular
distribution of ages, formation time scales, infall masses and mass loading
factors. We find that the local passive galaxies are on average older and
assembled on shorter typical time-scales than the local star-forming ones; on
the other hand, the larger mass star-forming galaxies show generally older ages
and longer typical formation time-scales compared with the smaller mass
star-forming galaxies. Finally, we conclude that the local star-forming
galaxies experience stronger galactic winds than the passive galaxy population.
We explore the effect of assuming different initial mass functions in our
model, showing that to reproduce the observed mass-metallicity relation
stronger winds are requested if the initial mass function is top-heavy.
Finally, our analytical models predict the assumed sample of local galaxies to
lie on a tight surface in the 3D space defined by stellar metallicity, star
formation rate and stellar mass, thus mimicking the well-known &quot;fundamental
relation&quot;.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06829</id><created>2016-05-15</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ballesteros</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;ngel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Sagredo</keyname><forenames>Iv&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naranjo</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>On Hamiltonians with position-dependent mass from Kaluza-Klein
  compactifications</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures. New figures. Updated to match the published
  version in Physics Letters A</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 381 (2017) 701-706</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.12.040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper (J.R. Morris, Quant. Stud. Math. Found. 2 (2015) 359), an
inhomogeneous compactification of the extra dimension of a five-dimensional
Kaluza-Klein metric has been shown to generate a position-dependent mass (PDM)
in the corresponding four-dimensional system. As an application of this
dimensional reduction mechanism, a specific static dilatonic scalar field has
been connected with a PDM Lagrangian describing a well-known nonlinear PDM
oscillator. Here we present more instances of this construction that lead to
PDM systems with radial symmetry, and the properties of their corresponding
inhomogeneous extra dimensions are compared with the ones in the nonlinear
oscillator model. Moreover, it is also shown how the compactification
introduced in this type of models can alternatively be interpreted as a novel
mechanism for the dynamical generation of curvature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05571</id><created>2016-06-17</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Misiorny</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Carola</forenames></author></authors><title>Gate-voltage response of a one-dimensional ballistic spin valve without
  spin-orbit interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages with 10 figures, version as accepted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 7, 024011 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.7.024011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that engineering of tunnel barriers forming at the interfaces of a
one-dimensional spin valve provides a viable path to a strong gate-voltage
tunability of the magnetoresistance effect. In particular, we investigate
theoretically a carbon nanotube (CNT) spin valve in terms of the influence of
the CNT-contact interface on the performance of the device. The focus is on the
strength and the spin selectivity of the tunnel barriers that are modelled as
Dirac-delta potentials. The scattering matrix approach is used to derive the
transmission coefficient that yields the tunneling magnetoresistance (TMR). We
find a strong non-trivial gate-voltage response of the TMR in the absence of
spin-orbit coupling when the energy of the incident electrons matches the
potential energy of the barrier. Analytic expressions for the TMR in various
limiting cases are derived. These are used to explain previous experimental
results, but also to predict parameters for device optimization with respect to
size and tunability of the TMR effect in the ballistic transport regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07978</id><created>2016-06-25</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Avelino</keyname><forenames>P. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazeia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Losano</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>B. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>String networks with junctions in competition models</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>v2, 10 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A 381 (2017) 1014</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.01.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we give specific examples of competition models, with six and
eight species, whose three-dimensional dynamics naturally leads to the
formation of string networks with junctions, associated with regions that have
a high concentration of enemy species. We study the two- and three-dimensional
evolution of such networks, both using stochastic network and mean field theory
simulations. If the predation, reproduction and mobility probabilities do not
vary in space and time, we find that the networks attain scaling regimes with a
characteristic length roughly proportional to $t^{1/2}$, where $t$ is the
physical time, thus showing that the presence of junctions, on its own, does
not have a significant impact on their scaling properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08768</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alm</keyname><forenames>Jeremy F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mack</keyname><forenames>Keenan M. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Degree-correlation, robustness, and vulnerability in finite scale-free
  networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI math.CO q-bio.PE</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><msc-class>92D30, 05C80, 05C85</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many naturally occurring networks have a power-law degree distribution as
well as a non-zero degree correlation. Despite this, most studies analyzing the
robustness to random node-deletion and vulnerability to targeted node-deletion
have concentrated only on power-law degree distribution and ignored degree
correlation. This study looks specifically at the effect degree-correlation has
on robustness and vulnerability in scale-free networks. Our results confirm
Newman's finding that positive degree-correlation increases robustness and
decreases vulnerability. However, we found that networks with positive
degree-correlation are more vulnerable to random node-deletion than to targeted
deletion methods that utilize knowledge of initial node-degree only. Targeted
deletion sufficiently alters the topology of the network to render this method
less effective than uniform random methods unless changes in topology are
accounted for. This result indicates the importance of degree correlation in
certain network applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09048</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Martino</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masoero</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic analysis of noisy fitness maximization, applied to metabolism
  and growth</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>JSTAT (2016), n 12</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa4e8f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a population dynamics model coupling cell growth to a diffusion
in the space of metabolic phenotypes as it can be obtained from realistic
constraints-based modelling. In the asymptotic regime of slow diffusion, that
coincides with the relevant experimental range, the resulting non-linear
Fokker-Planck equation is solved for the steady state in the WKB approximation
that maps it into the ground state of a quantum particle in an Airy potential
plus a centrifugal term. We retrieve scaling laws for growth rate fluctuations
and time response with respect to the distance from the maximum growth rate
suggesting that suboptimal populations can have a faster response to
perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09482</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Biffin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xfc;egg</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Embs</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guidi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loidl</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsurkan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coldea</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field dependence of excitations near spin-orbital quantum
  criticality</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures. Revised version now matches published manuscript</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 067205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.067205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spinel FeSc$_2$S$_4$ has been proposed to realize a near-critical
spin-orbital singlet (SOS) state, where entangled spin and orbital moments
fluctuate in a global singlet state on the verge of spin and orbital order.
Here we report powder inelastic neutron scattering measurements that observe
the full bandwidth of magnetic excitations and we find that spin-orbital
triplon excitations of an SOS state can capture well key aspects of the
spectrum in both zero and applied magnetic fields up to 8.5 T. The observed
shift of low-energy spectral weight to higher energies upon increasing applied
field is naturally explained by the entangled spin-orbital character of the
magnetic states, a behavior that is in strong contrast to spin-only singlet
ground state systems, where the spin gap decreases upon increasing applied
field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09528</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bellotti</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dehkharghani</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinner</keyname><forenames>N. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing numerical and analytical approaches to strongly interacting
  two-component mixtures in one dimensional traps</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. D (2017) 71:37</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2017-70650-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate one-dimensional harmonically trapped two-component systems for
repulsive interaction strengths ranging from the non-interacting to the
strongly interacting regime for Fermi-Fermi mixtures. A new and powerful
mapping between the interaction strength parameters from a continuous
Hamiltonian and a discrete lattice Hamiltonian is derived. As an example, we
show that this mapping does not depend neither on the state of the system nor
on the number of particles. Energies, density profiles and correlation
functions are obtained both numerically (DMRG and Exact diagonalization) and
analytically. Since DMRG results do not converge as the interaction strength is
increased, analytical solutions are used as a benchmark to identify the point
where these calculations become unstable. We use the proposed mapping to set a
quantitative limit on the interaction parameter of a discrete lattice
Hamiltonian above which DMRG gives unrealistic results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06328</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06328</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>Renato M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirsch</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Lepton number violation in 331 models</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Matches the version published in Physical Review D</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-34</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 115003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.115003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Different models based on the extended $SU(3)_{C}\times SU(3)_{L}\times
U(1)_{X}$ (331) gauge group have been proposed over the past four decades. Yet,
despite being an active research topic, the status of lepton number in 331
models has not been fully addressed in the literature, and furthermore many of
the original proposals can not explain the observed neutrino masses. In this
paper we review the basic features of various 331 models, focusing on potential
sources of lepton number violation. We then describe different modifications
which can be made to the original models in order to accommodate neutrino (and
charged lepton) masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08182</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Brask</keyname><forenames>Jonatan Bohr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaves</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author></authors><title>Bell scenarios with communication</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures. Includes a more detailed explanation of results
  appearing in the appendix of arXiv:1411.4648 [quant-ph]</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 094001, 2017 [special issue: emerging
  talents]</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa5840</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical and quantum physics provide fundamentally different predictions
about experiments with separate observers that do not communicate, a phenomenon
known as quantum nonlocality. This insight is a key element of our present
understanding of quantum physics, and also enables a number of information
processing protocols with security beyond what is classically attainable.
Relaxing the pivotal assumption of no communication leads to new insights into
the nature quantum correlations, and may enable new applications where security
can be established under less strict assumptions. Here, we study such
relaxations where different forms of communication are allowed. We consider
communication of inputs, outputs, and of a message between the parties. Using
several measures, we study how much communication is required for classical
models to reproduce quantum or general no-signalling correlations, as well as
how quantum models can be augmented with classical communication to reproduce
no-signalling correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08594</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kadar</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author></authors><title>Inversion symmetry breaking and criticality in free fermionic lattices</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Acknowledgement added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the connection between inversion symmetry breaking and
criticality in free fermionic lattice models. It is shown that for
translation-invariant spinless fermions, the breaking of this symmetry in the
ground state implies criticality, i.e., the existence of long-range
correlations and the vanishing of the spectral gap; while for models with spin,
only the asymmetry of the spin-averaged covariance matrix implies a similar
conclusion. Our results are proved by introducing invariants under global
translation-invariant free fermion quenches. Using this result, we identify a
set of models where the generalized Hartree-Fock approximation must break down.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00244</id><created>2016-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Viability of Variable Generalised Chaplygin gas - a thermodynamical
  approach</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 Pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:0902.1532 by other authors</comments><report-no>Gen.Rel.Grav. 49 (2017) no.3, 35</report-no><journal-ref>Gen.Rel.Grav 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2199-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The viability of the variable generalised Chaplygin gas (VGCG) model is
analysed from the standpoint of its thermodynamical stability criteria with the
help of an equation of state, $P = - \frac{B}{\rho^{\alpha}}$, where $B =
B_{0}V^{-\frac{n}{3}}$. Here $B_{0}$ is assumed to be a positive universal
constant, $n$ is a constant parameter and $V$ is the volume of the cosmic
fluid. We get the interesting result that if the well-known stability
conditions of a fluid is adhered to, the values of $n$ are constrained to be
negative definite to make $ \left(\frac{\partial P}{\partial V}\right)_{S} &lt;0$
\&amp; $ \left(\frac{\partial P}{\partial V}\right)_{T} &lt;0$ throughout the
evolution. Moreover the positivity of thermal capacity at constant volume
$c_{V}$ as also the validity of the third law of thermodynamics are ensured in
this case. For the particular case $n = 0$ the effective equation of state
reduces to $\Lambda$CDM model in the late stage of the universe while for $n
&lt;0$ it mimics a phantom-like cosmology which is in broad agreement with the
present SNe Ia constraints like VGCG model. The thermal equation of state is
discussed and the EoS parameter is found to be an explicit function of
temperature only. Further for large volume the thermal equation of state
parameter is identical with the caloric equation of state parameter when $ T
\rightarrow 0$. It may also be mentioned that like Santos et al our model does
not admit of any critical points. We also observe that although the earlier
model of Lu explains many of the current observational findings of different
probes it fails to explain the crucial tests of thermodynamical stability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06022</id><created>2016-08-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Giacalone</keyname><forenames>Giuliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noronha-Hostler</keyname><forenames>Jacquelyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ollitrault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>The fluctuations of quadrangular flow</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 pages. 2 figures</comments><report-no>Saclay t16/086</report-no><journal-ref>J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 779 (2017) 012064</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/779/1/012064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ATLAS Collaboration has measured for the first time the fourth cumulant
of quadrangular flow, $v_4\{4\}^4$. Unlike the fourth cumulants of elliptic and
triangular flows, it presents a change of sign above 30\% centrality. We show
that this change of sign is predicted by event-by-event hydrodynamics. We argue
that it results from the combined effects of a nonlinear hydrodynamic response,
which couples quadrangular flow to elliptic flow, and elliptic flow
fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07797</id><created>2016-08-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Markovich</keyname><forenames>Tomer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andelman</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podgornik</keyname><forenames>Rudi</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Tension of Acid Solutions: Fluctuations beyond the Non-linear
  Poisson-Boltzmann Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Langmuir 33, 34-44 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b03186</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend our previous study of surface tension of ionic solutions and apply
it to the case of acids (and salts) with strong ion-surface interactions. These
ion-surface interactions yield a non-linear boundary condition with an
effective surface charge due to adsorption of ions from the bulk onto the
interface. The calculation is done using the loop-expansion technique, where
the zero-loop (mean field) corresponds of the non-linear Poisson-Boltzmann
equation. The surface tension is obtained analytically to one-loop order, where
the mean-field contribution is a modification of the Poisson-Boltzmann surface
tension, and the one-loop contribution gives a generalization of the
Onsager-Samaras result. Our theory fits well a wide range of different acids
and salts, and is in accord with the reverse Hofmeister series for acids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08006</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eleuch</keyname><forenames>Hichem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>Ingrid</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonances in open quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Title of the paper is changed. The Introduction is broaden. The
  difference of the non-Hermitian formalism for the description of open quantum
  systems in our paper to the description of PT-symmetric systems is
  underlined. Paper published: Phys.Rev.A 95, 022117 (2017)</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.022117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Hamilton operator of an open quantum system is non-Hermitian. Its
eigenvalues are, generally, complex and provide not only the energies but also
the lifetimes of the states of the system. The states may couple via the common
environment of scattering wavefunctions into which the system is embedded. This
causes an {\it external mixing} (EM) of the states. Mathematically, EM is
related to the existence of singular (the so-called exceptional) points (EPs).
The eigenfunctions of a non-Hermitian operator are biorthogonal, in contrast to
the orthogonal eigenfunctions of a Hermitian operator. A quantitative measure
for the ratio between biorthogonality and orthogonality is the phase rigidity
of the wavefunctions. At and near an EP, the phase rigidity takes its minimum
value. The lifetimes of two nearby eigenstates of a quantum system bifurcate
under the influence of an EP. At the parameter value of maximum width
bifurcation, the phase rigidity approaches the value one, meaning that the two
eigenfunctions become orthogonal. However, the eigenfunctions are externally
mixed at this parameter value. The S-matrix and therewith the cross section do
contain, in the one-channel case, almost no information on the EM of the
states. The situation is completely different in the case with two (or more)
channels where the resonance structure is strongly influenced by the EM of the
states and interesting features of non-Hermitian quantum physics are revealed.
We provide numerical results for two and three nearby eigenstates of a
non-Hermitian Hamilton operator which are embedded in one common continuum and
influenced by two adjoining EPs. The results are discussed. They are of
interest for an experimental test of the non-Hermitian quantum physics as well
as for applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08018</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2017-01-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamase</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bejas</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge-Density-Excitation Spectrum in the t-t'-J-V Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn 86, 034706 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.034706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the density-density correlation function in a large-N scheme of the
t-t'-J-V model. When the nearest-neighbor Coulomb interaction V is zero, our
model exhibits phase separation in a wide doping region and we obtain large
spectral weight near momentum q=(0,0) at low energy, which originates from the
proximity to phase separation. These features are much stronger for electron
doping than for hole doping. However, once phase separation is suppressed by
including a finite V, the low-energy spectral weight around q=(0,0) is
substantially suppressed. Instead a sharp zero-sound mode is stabilized above
the particle-hole continuum. We discuss that the presence of a moderate value
of V, which is frequently neglected in the t-J model, is important to
understand low-energy charge excitations especially close to q=(0,0) for
electron doping. This insight should be taken into account in a future study of
x-ray scattering measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01895</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Constable</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballou</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decorse</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brubach</keyname><forenames>J. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lhotel</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del-Rey</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonet</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petit</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>deBrion</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double Vibronic process in the quantum spin ice candidate
  Tb$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ revealed by terahertz spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 020415 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.020415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of quantum fluctuations responsible for the spin liquid state in
Tb$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ has remained a long standing problem. By synchrotron-based
terahertz measurements, we show evidence of strong coupling between the
magnetic and lattice degrees of freedom that provides a path to the quantum
melting process. As revealed by hybrid crystal electric field-phonon
excitations that appear at 0.67 THz below 200 K, and around 0.42 THz below 50
K, the double vibronic process is unique for Tb$^{3+}$ in the titanate family
due to adequate energy matching and strong quadrupolar moments. The results
suggest that lattice motion can indeed be the driving force behind spin flips
within the hybridized ground and first excited states, promoting quantum terms
in the effective Hamiltonian that describes Tb$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01964</id><created>2016-09-03</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malekjani</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basilakos</keyname><forenames>Spyros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heidari</keyname><forenames>Neda</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical collapse model and cluster number counts in power law $f(T)$
  gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, accepted in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 466(3), 3488 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3367</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spherical collapse model (SCM) in the framework of spatially
flat power law $f(T) \propto (-T)^{b}$ gravity model. We find that the linear
and non-linear growth of spherical overdensities of this particular $f(T)$
model are affected by the power-law parameter $b$. Finally, we compute the
predicted number counts of virialized haloes in order to distinguish the
current $f(T)$ model from the expectations of the concordance $\Lambda$
cosmology. Specifically, the present analysis suggests that the $f(T)$ gravity
model with positive (negative) $b$ predicts more (less) virialized objects with
respect to those of $\Lambda$CDM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02056</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-01-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Tunneling of Spin-1 Particles from a 5D
  Einstein-Yang-Mills-Gauss-Bonnet Black Hole Beyond Semiclassical
  Approximation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, accepted by EPL (Europhysics Letters)</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 116 (2016) 60013</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/60013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper we study the Hawking radiation as a quantum tunneling
effect of spin-$1$ particles from a five-dimensional, spherically symmetric,
Einstein-Yang-Mills-Gauss-Bonnet (5D EYMGB) black hole. We solve the Proca
equation (PE) by applying the WKB approximation and separation of variables via
Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) equation which results in a set of five differential
equations, and reproduces in this way, the Hawking temperature. In the second
part of this paper, we extend our results beyond the semiclassical
approximation. In particular, we derive the logarithmic correction to the
entropy of the 5D EYMGB black hole and show that the quantum corrected specific
heat indicates the possible existence of a remnant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03354</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>The XENON Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Aprile</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aalbers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agostini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alfonsi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaro</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthony</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arneodo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrow</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baudis</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauermeister</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benabderrahmane</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breur</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruenner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budnik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;tikofer</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calv&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>J. M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervantes</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cichon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coderre</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colijn</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cussonneau</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decowski</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Perio</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Gangi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Giovanni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diglio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchovni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferella</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fieguth</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulgione</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosso</keyname><forenames>A. Gallo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galloway</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garbini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goetzke</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grignon</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasterok</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogenbirk</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itay</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaminsky</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kessler</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kish</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landsman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lellouch</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levinson</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calloch</keyname><forenames>M. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levy</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindemann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>J. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfredini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Undagoitia</keyname><forenames>T. Marrod&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masbou</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massoli</keyname><forenames>F. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masson</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayani</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messina</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micheneau</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miguez</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molinario</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murra</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naganoma</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberlack</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orrigo</keyname><forenames>S. E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakarha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelssers</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persiani</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piastra</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pienaar</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piro</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plante</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Priel</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosendahl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupp</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>J. M. F. dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sartorelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheibelhut</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavina</keyname><forenames>L. Scotto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selvi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shagin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simgen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sivers</keyname><forenames>M. v.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thers</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiseni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trinchero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tunnell</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wall</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinheimer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wulf</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for Two-Neutrino Double Electron Capture of $^{124}$Xe with
  XENON100</title><categories>nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 024605, Published 13 February 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.024605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-neutrino double electron capture is a rare nuclear decay where two
electrons are simultaneously captured from the atomic shell. For $^{124}$Xe
this process has not yet been observed and its detection would provide a new
reference for nuclear matrix element calculations. We have conducted a search
for two-neutrino double electron capture from the K-shell of $^{124}$Xe using
7636 kg$\cdot$d of data from the XENON100 dark matter detector. Using a
Bayesian analysis we observed no significant excess above background, leading
to a lower 90 % credibility limit on the half-life $T_{1/2}&gt;6.5\times10^{20}$
yr. We also evaluated the sensitivity of the XENON1T experiment, which is
currently being commissioned, and find a sensitivity of
$T_{1/2}&gt;6.1\times10^{22}$ yr after an exposure of 2 t$\cdot$yr.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03573</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buck</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dowker</keyname><forenames>Fay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jubb</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorkin</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author></authors><title>The Sorkin-Johnston State in a Patch of the Trousers Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav. 34 (2017) 5, 055002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa589c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum scalar field in a patch of a fixed, topology-changing, $1+1$
dimensional &quot;trousers&quot; spacetime is studied using the Sorkin-Johnston
formalism. The isometry group of the patch is the dihedral group, the symmetry
group of the square. The theory is shown to be pathological in a way that can
be interpreted as the topology change giving rise to a divergent energy, in
agreement with previous results. In contrast to previous results, it is shown
that the infinite energy is localised not only on the future light cone of the
topology changing singularity, but also on the past cone, due to the time
reversal symmetry of the Sorkin-Johnston state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05978</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blazek</keyname><forenames>Jonathan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEwen</keyname><forenames>Joseph E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirata</keyname><forenames>Christopher M.</forenames></author></authors><title>FAST-PT II: an algorithm to calculate convolution integrals of general
  tensor quantities in cosmological perturbation theory</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>32 pages, 5 figures, 4 tables. Minor changes. Published in JCAP. Code
  available at https://github.com/JoeMcEwen/FAST-PT</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 02(2017)030</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/02/030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmological perturbation theory is a powerful tool to predict the statistics
of large-scale structure in the weakly non-linear regime, but even at 1-loop
order it results in computationally expensive mode-coupling integrals. Here we
present a fast algorithm for computing 1-loop power spectra of quantities that
depend on the observer's orientation, thereby generalizing the FAST-PT
framework (McEwen et al., 2016) that was originally developed for scalars such
as the matter density. This algorithm works for an arbitrary input power
spectrum and substantially reduces the time required for numerical evaluation.
We apply the algorithm to four examples: intrinsic alignments of galaxies in
the tidal torque model; the Ostriker-Vishniac effect; the secondary CMB
polarization due to baryon flows; and the 1-loop matter power spectrum in
redshift space. Code implementing this algorithm and these applications is
publicly available at https://github.com/JoeMcEwen/FAST-PT .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07390</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kowalski</keyname><forenames>Adam F.</forenames><affiliation>University of Maryland College Park/NASA-GSFC, and University of Colorado Boulder/National Solar Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Allred</keyname><forenames>Joel C.</forenames><affiliation>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Daw</keyname><forenames>Adrian N.</forenames><affiliation>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cauzzi</keyname><forenames>Gianna</forenames><affiliation>INAF-Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Carlsson</keyname><forenames>Mats</forenames><affiliation>University of Oslo</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Atmospheric Response to High Nonthermal Electron Beam Fluxes in
  Solar Flares I: Modeling the Brightest NUV Footpoints in the X1 Solar Flare
  of 2014 March 29</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>42 pages, 14 figures, 5 tables, accepted for publication in the
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/836/1/12</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The 2014 March 29 X1 solar flare (SOL20140329T17:48) produced bright
continuum emission in the far- and near-ultraviolet (NUV) and highly asymmetric
chromospheric emission lines, providing long-sought constraints on the heating
mechanisms of the lower atmosphere in solar flares. We analyze the continuum
and emission line data from the Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph (IRIS) of
the brightest flaring magnetic footpoints in this flare. We compare the NUV
spectra of the brightest pixels to new radiative-hydrodynamic predictions
calculated with the RADYN code using constraints on a nonthermal electron beam
inferred from the collisional thick-target modeling of hard X-ray data from
RHESSI. We show that the atmospheric response to a high beam flux density
satisfactorily achieves the observed continuum brightness in the NUV. The NUV
continuum emission in this flare is consistent with hydrogen (Balmer)
recombination radiation that originates from low optical depth in a dense
chromospheric condensation and from the stationary beam-heated layers just
below the condensation. A model producing two flaring regions (a condensation
and stationary layers) in the lower atmosphere is also consistent with the
asymmetric Fe II chromospheric emission line profiles observed in the impulsive
phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08741</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magana-Loaiza</keyname><forenames>Omar S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirhosseini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yiyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Boshen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rafsanjani</keyname><forenames>Seyed Mohammad Hashemi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Guilu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Digital spiral object identification using random light</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Light: Science &amp; Applications (2017) 6, e17013</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/lsa.2017.13.</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photons that are entangled or correlated in orbital angular momentum have
been extensively used for remote sensing, object identification and imaging. It
has recently been demonstrated that intensity fluctuations give rise to the
formation of correlations in the orbital angular momentum components and
angular positions of random light. Here, we demonstrate that the spatial
signatures and phase information of an object, with rotational symmetries, can
be identified using classical orbital angular momentum correlations in random
light. The Fourier components imprinted in the digital spiral spectrum of the
object, measured through intensity correlations, unveil its spatial and phase
information. Sharing similarities with conventional compressive sensing
protocols that exploit sparsity to reduce the number of measurements required
to reconstruct a signal, our technique allows sensing of an object with fewer
measurements than other schemes that use pixel-by-pixel imaging. One remarkable
advantage of our technique is the fact that it does not require the preparation
of fragile quantum states of light and works at both low- and high-light
levels. In addition, our technique is robust against environmental noise, a
fundamental feature of any realistic scheme for remote sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00469</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2016-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nik&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vretenar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures of shape phase transitions in odd-mass nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures; Accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 064310 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.064310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum phase transitions between competing ground-state shapes of atomic
nuclei with an odd number of protons or neutrons are investigated in a
microscopic framework based on nuclear energy density functional theory and the
particle-plus-boson-core coupling scheme. The boson-core Hamiltonian, as well
as the single-particle energies and occupation probabilities of the unpaired
nucleon, are completely determined by constrained self-consistent mean-field
calculations for a specific choice of the energy density functional and paring
interaction, and only the strength parameters of the particle-core coupling are
adjusted to reproduce selected spectroscopic properties of the odd-mass system.
We apply this method to odd-A Eu and Sm isotopes with neutron number $N \approx
90$, and explore the influence of the single unpaired fermion on the occurrence
of a shape phase transition. Collective wave functions of low-energy states are
used to compute quantities that can be related to quantum order parameters:
deformations, excitation energies, E2 transition rates and separation energies,
and their evolution with the control parameter (neutron number) is analysed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03652</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>C. Vacacela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisarra</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gravina</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riccardi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sindona</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmon properties and hybridization effects in Silicene</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 085419 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.085419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The plasmonic character of monolayer silicene is investigated by
time-dependent density functional theory in the random phase approximation. The
energy-loss function of the system is analyzed, with particular reference to
its induced charge-density fluctuations, i.e., plasmon resonances and
corresponding dispersions, occurring in the investigated energy-momentum
region. At energies larger than 1.5eV, two intrinsic interband modes are
detected and characterized. The first one is a hybridized pi-like plasmon,
which is assisted by competing one-electron processes involving sp2 and sp3
states. The second one is a more conventional pi-sigma plasmon, which is more
intense than the pi-like plasmon and more affected by one-electron processes
involving the sigma bands, with respect to the analogous collective oscillation
in monolayer graphene. At energies below 1eV, two extrinsic intraband modes are
predicted to occur, which are generated by distinct types of Dirac electrons
(associated with different Fermi velocities at the so-called Dirac points). The
most intense of them is a two-dimensional plasmon, having an energy-momentum
dispersion that resembles that of a two-dimensional electron gas. The other is
an acoustic plasmon that occurs for specific momentum directions and competes
with the two-dimensional plasmon at mid infrared energies. The strong
anisotropic character of this mode cannot be explained in terms of the widely
used Dirac-cone approximation. As in mono-, bi-, and few-layer graphene, the
extrinsic oscillations of silicene are highly sensitive to the concentration of
injected or ejected charge carriers. More importantly, the two-dimensional and
acoustic plasmons appear to be a signature of the honeycomb lattice,
independently of the chemistry of the group-IV elements and the details of the
unit-cell geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03686</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Karpiuk</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brewczyk</keyname><forenames>Miros&#x142;aw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rz&#x105;&#x17c;ewski</keyname><forenames>Kazimierz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaj</keyname><forenames>Anita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krupp</keyname><forenames>Alexander T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;w</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofferberth</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfau</keyname><forenames>Tilman</forenames></author></authors><title>Condensate losses and oscillations induced by Rydberg atoms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 50 (2017) 055003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa5245</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically analyze the impact of a single Rydberg electron onto a
Bose-Einstein condensate. Both $S-$ and $D-$ Rydberg states are studied. The
radial size of $S-$ and $D-$states are comparable, hence the only difference is
due to the angular dependence of the wavefunctions. We find the atom losses in
the condensate after the excitation of a sequence of Rydberg atoms.
Additionally, we investigate the mechanical effect in which the Rydberg atoms
force the condensate to oscillate. Our numerical analysis is based on the
classical fields approximation. Finally, we compare numerical results to
experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05136</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dupont</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capponi</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laflorencie</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Disorder-induced Revival of the Bose-Einstein Condensation in
  Ni(Cl$_{1-x}$Br$_x$)$_2$-4SC(NH$_2$)$_2$ at High Magnetic Fields</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 067204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.067204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Building on recent NMR experiments [Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 067203], we
theoretically investigate the high magnetic field regime of the disordered
quasi-one-dimensional $S=1$ antiferromagnetic material
Ni(Cl$_{1-x}$Br$_x$)$_2$-4SC(NH$_2$)$_2$. The interplay between disorder,
chemically controlled by Br-doping, interactions, and the external magnetic
field, leads to a very rich phase diagram. Beyond the well-known
antiferromagnetically ordered regime, analog of a Bose condensate of magnons,
which disappears when $H\ge 12.3$ T, we unveil a resurgence of phase coherence
at higher field $H\sim 13.6$ T, induced by the doping. Interchain couplings
stabilize finite temperature long-range order whose extension in the field -
temperature space is governed by the concentration of impurities $x$. Such a
&quot;mini-condensation&quot; contrasts with previously reported Bose-glass physics in
the same regime, and should be accessible to experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05385</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kane</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillman</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denman</keyname><forenames>Craig A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hart</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>R. Phillip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purucker</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potashnik</keyname><forenames>Stephen J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser remote magnetometry using mesospheric sodium</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP physics.atom-ph physics.ins-det physics.space-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 15 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have demonstrated a remote magnetometer based on sodium atoms in the
Earth's mesosphere, at a 106-kilometer distance from our instrument. A
1.33-watt laser illuminated the atoms, and the magnetic field was inferred from
back-scattered light collected by a telescope with a 1.55-meter-diameter
aperture. The measurement sensitivity was 162 nT/$\sqrt{Hz}$. The value of
magnetic field inferred from our measurement is consistent with an estimate
based on the Earth's known field shape to within a fraction of a percent.
Projected improvements in optics could lead to sensitivity of 20
nT/$\sqrt{Hz}$, and the use of advanced lasers or a large telescope could
approach 1-nT/$\sqrt{Hz}$ sensitivity. All experimental and theoretical
sensitivity values are based on a 60$^\circ$ angle between the laser beam axis
and the magnetic field vector; at the optimal 90$^\circ$ angle sensitivity
would be improved by about a factor of two.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06101</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-02-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miskovic</keyname><forenames>Olivera</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olea</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Debraj</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum energy in asymptotically flat 2+1 gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures; introduction extended, references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B767 (2017) 258-263</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.02.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the vacuum energy of three-dimensional asymptotically flat space
based on a Chern-Simons formulation for the Poincare group. The equivalent
action is nothing but the Einstein-Hilbert term in the bulk plus half of the
Gibbons-Hawking term at the boundary. The derivation is based on the evaluation
of the Noether charges in the vacuum. We obtain that the vacuum energy of this
space has the same value as the one of the asymptotically flat limit of
three-dimensional anti-de Sitter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07102</id><created>2016-10-22</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scheel</keyname><forenames>Arnd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tikhomirov</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>Depinning asymptotics in ergodic media</title><categories>nlin.PS math.DS</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study speeds of fronts in bistable, spatially inhomogeneous media at
parameter regimes where speeds approach zero. We provide a set of conceptual
assumptions under which we can prove power-law asymptotics for the speed, with
exponent depending a local dimension of the ergodic measure near extremal
values. We also show that our conceptual assumptions are satisfied in a context
of weak inhomogeneity of the medium and almost balanced kinetics, and compare
asymptotics with numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01469</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2017-01-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scardigli</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambiase</keyname><forenames>Gaetano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vagenas</keyname><forenames>Elias</forenames></author></authors><title>GUP parameter from quantum corrections to the Newtonian potential</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>v1: 6 pages, no figures; v2: minor corrections, physics unchanged, to
  appear in Phys. Lett. B. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1407.0113</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 767 (2017) 242</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.054</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a technique to compute the deformation parameter of the
generalized uncertainty principle by using the leading quantum corrections to
the Newtonian potential. We just assume General Relativity as theory of
Gravitation, and the thermal nature of the GUP corrections to the Hawking
spectrum. With these minimal assumptions our calculation gives, to first order,
a specific numerical result. The physical meaning of this value is discussed,
and compared with the previously obtained bounds on the generalized uncertainty
principle deformation parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04554</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-01-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rotureau</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danielewicz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papenbrock</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical potential from first principles</title><categories>nucl-th physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures, a few points clarified, typos corrected,
  accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 024315 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.024315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a method to construct a microscopic optical potential from chiral
interactions for nucleon-nucleus scattering. The optical potential is
constructed by combining the Green's function approach with the coupled-cluster
method. To deal with the poles of the Green's function along the real energy
axis we employ a Berggren basis in the complex energy plane combined with the
Lanczos method. Using this approach, we perform a proof-of-principle
calculation of the optical potential for the elastic neutron scattering on
$^{16}{\rm O}$. For the computation of the ground-state of $^{16}{\rm O}$, we
use the coupled-cluster method in the singles-and-doubles approximation, while
for the $A=\pm 1$ nuclei we use particle-attached/removed equation-of-motion
method truncated at two-particle-one-hole and one-particle-two-hole
excitations, respectively. We verify the convergence of the optical potential
and scattering phase shifts with respect to the model-space size and the number
of discretized complex continuum states. We also investigate the absorptive
component of the optical potential (which reflects the opening of inelastic
channels) by computing its imaginary volume integral and find an almost
negligible absorptive component at low-energies. To shed light on this result,
we computed excited states of $^{16}{\rm O}$ using equation-of-motion
coupled-cluster method with singles-and-doubles excitations and we found no
low-lying excited states below 10~MeV. Furthermore, most excited states have a
dominant two-particle-two-hole component, making higher-order particle-hole
excitations necessary to achieve a precise description of these core-excited
states. We conclude that the reduced absorption at low-energies can be
attributed to the lack of correlations coming from the low-order cluster
truncation in the employed coupled-cluster method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04719</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Da-jun</forenames></author></authors><title>On a Second Discretization of the ZS-AKNS Spectral Problem: Revisit</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><msc-class>35Q51, 37K60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we revisit a discrete spectral problem which was proposed by
Ragnisco and Tu in 1989, as a second discretization of the ZS-AKNS spectral
problem. We show that the spectral problem corresponds to a bidirectional
discretization of the derivative of two wave functions $\phi_{1,x}$ and
$\phi_{2,x}$. As a connection with higher dimensional systems, the spectral
problem and a related hierarchy can be derived from Lax triads of the
differential-difference KP hierarchy via a symmetry constraint. Isospectral and
nonisospectral flows derived from the spectral problem compose a Lie algebra.
By considering its infinite dimensional subalgebras and continuum limit of
recursion operator, three semi-discrete AKNS hierarchies are constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06124</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-02-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsushima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Cruzeiro do Sul U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>de Melo</keyname><forenames>J. P. B. C</forenames><affiliation>Cruzeiro do Sul U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>In-Medium Pion Valence Distribution Amplitude</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, one paragraph added, typos corrected, to be
  published in the proceedings of &quot;Light Cone 2016&quot;, September 5-8, 2016,
  Lisbon, Portugal</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst (2017) 58: 85</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-017-1249-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After a brief review of the quark-based model for nuclear matter, and some
pion properties in medium presented in our previous works, we report new
results for the pion valence wave function as well as the valence distribution
amplitude in medium, which are presented in our recent article. We find that
both the in-medium pion valence distribution and the in-medium pion valence
wave function, are substantially modified at normal nuclear matter density, due
to the reduction in the pion decay constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06126</id><created>2016-11-18</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piroli</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pozsgay</keyname><forenames>Bal&#xe1;zs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vernier</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>From the Quantum Transfer Matrix to the Quench Action: The Loschmidt
  echo in $XXZ$ Heisenberg spin chains</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>49 pages, 13 figures; v2: minor revision</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 023106</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa5d1e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the computation of the Loschmidt echo after quantum quenches in
the interacting $XXZ$ Heisenberg spin chain both for real and imaginary times.
We study two-site product initial states, focusing in particular on the N\'eel
and tilted N\'eel states. We apply the Quantum Transfer Matrix (QTM) approach
to derive generalized TBA equations, which follow from the fusion hierarchy of
the appropriate QTM's. Our formulas are valid for arbitrary imaginary time and
for real times at least up to a time $t_0$, after which the integral equations
have to be modified. In some regimes, $t_0$ is seen to be either very large or
infinite, allowing to explore in detail the post-quench dynamics of the system.
As an important part of our work, we show that for the N\'eel state our
imaginary time results can be recovered by means of the quench action approach,
unveiling a direct connection with the quantum transfer matrix formalism. In
particular, we show that in the zero-time limit, the study of our TBA equations
allows for a simple alternative derivation of the recently obtained Bethe
ansatz distribution functions for the N\'eel, tilted N\'eel and tilted
ferromagnet states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06373</id><created>2016-11-19</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Chika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>$\epsilon$-Expansion in Critical $\phi^3$-Theory on Real Projective
  Space from Conformal Field Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, v2: some references added</comments><report-no>RUP-16-30</report-no><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 7 (2017) 1750045</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317500456</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a compatibility between the conformal symmetry and the equations of
motion to solve the one-point function in the critical $\phi^3$-theory (a.k.a
the critical Lee-Yang model) on the $d = 6 - \epsilon$ dimensional real
projective space to the first non-trivial order in the $\epsilon$-expansion. It
reproduces the conventional perturbation theory and agrees with the numerical
conformal bootstrap result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07769</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schaub</keyname><forenames>Michael T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delvenne</keyname><forenames>Jean-Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosvall</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambiotte</keyname><forenames>Renaud</forenames></author></authors><title>The many facets of community detection in complex networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.data-an physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>8 Pages, 1 Figure</comments><journal-ref>Schaub, M.T., Delvenne, JC., Rosvall, M. et al. Appl Netw Sci
  (2017) 2: 4</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s41109-017-0023-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Community detection, the decomposition of a graph into essential building
blocks, has been a core research topic in network science over the past years.
Since a precise notion of what constitutes a community has remained evasive,
community detection algorithms have often been compared on benchmark graphs
with a particular form of assortative community structure and classified based
on the mathematical techniques they employ. However, this comparison can be
misleading because apparent similarities in their mathematical machinery can
disguise different goals and reasons for why we want to employ community
detection in the first place. Here we provide a focused review of these
different motivations that underpin community detection. This problem-driven
classification is useful in applied network science, where it is important to
select an appropriate algorithm for the given purpose. Moreover, highlighting
the different facets of community detection also delineates the many lines of
research and points out open directions and avenues for future research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08453</id><created>2016-11-25</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Turgeon</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vermette</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexandrowicz</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peperstraete</keyname><forenames>Yoann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Philippe</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fillion</keyname><forenames>Jean-Hugues</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michaut</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayotte</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>Confinement effects on the nuclear spin isomer conversion of H$_2$O</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jpca.7b00893</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mechanism for interconversion between the nuclear spin isomers (NSI) of
H$_2$O remains shrouded in uncertainties. The temperature dependence displayed
by NSI interconversion rates for H$_2$O isolated in an Argon matrix provides
evidence that confinement effects are responsible for the dramatic increase in
their kinetics with respect to the gas phase, providing new pathways for
o-H$_2$O $\leftrightarrow$ p-H$_2$O conversion in endohedral compounds. This
reveals intramolecular aspects of the interconversion mechanism which may
improve methodologies for the separation and storage of NSI en route to
applications in nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy and imaging. It may
also improve astronomers' ability to use their relative abundance in the
interstellar medium as proxies, thereby providing a valuable &quot;astronomical
clock&quot;.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08539</id><created>2016-11-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Zampetaki</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockhofe</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelcher</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pinned-to-sliding transition and structural crossovers for helically
  confined charges</title><categories>cond-mat.soft nlin.PS</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 022205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.022205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the non-equilibrium dissipative dynamics of a system of identical
charged particles trapped on a closed helix. The particles are subject to an
external force accelerating them along the underlying structure. The effective
interactions between the charges induce a coupling of the center-of-mass to the
relative motion which in turn gives rise to a pinned-to-sliding transition with
increasing magnitude of the external force. In the sliding regime we observe an
Ohmic behaviour signified by a constant mobility. Within the same regime a
structural transition of the helical particle chain takes place with increasing
the helix radius leading to a global change of the crystalline arrangement. The
resulting crystal is characterized by the existence of multiple defects whose
number increases with the helix radius.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09103</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Skripnikov</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maison</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosyagin</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the scalar-pseudoscalar interaction in the francium atom</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>added analysis of inner-core contribution to Rs parameter within the
  perturbation theory</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 022507 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.022507</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fr atom can be successively used to search for the atomic permanent electric
dipole moment (EDM) [Hyperfine Interactions 236, 53 (2015); Journal of Physics:
Conference Series 691, 012017 (2016)]. It can be induced by the permanent
electron EDM predicted by modern extensions of the standard model to be nonzero
at the level accessible by the new generation of EDM experiments. We consider
another mechanism of the atomic EDM generation in Fr. This is caused by the
scalar-pseudoscalar nucleus-electron neutral current interaction with the
dimensionless strength constant, $k_{T,P}$. Similar to the electron EDM this
interaction violates both spatial parity and time-reversal symmetries and can
also induce permanent atomic EDM. It was shown in [Phys. Rev. D 89, 056006
(2014)] that the scalar-pseudoscalar contribution to the atomic EDM can
dominate over the direct contribution from the electron EDM within the standard
model. We report high-accuracy combined all-electron and two-step relativistic
coupled cluster treatment of the effect from the scalar-pseudoscalar
interaction in the Fr atom. Up to the quadruple cluster amplitudes within the
CCSDT(Q) method were included in correlation treatment. This calculation is
required for the interpretation of the experimental data in terms of $k_{T,P}$.
The resulted EDM of the Fr atom expressed in terms of $k_{T,P}$ is $d_{\rm Fr}=
k_{T,P} \cdot 4.50\cdot10^{-18} e\cdot {\rm cm}$, where $e$ is the charge of
the electron. The value of the ionization potential of the $^2S_{1/2}$ ground
state of Fr calculated within the same methods is in a very good agreement with
the experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00978</id><created>2016-12-03</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Ryuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultralight scalars and resonances in black-hole physics</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 044016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.044016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultralight degrees of freedom coupled to matter lead to resonances, which can
be excited when the Compton wavelength of the field equals a dynamical scale in
the problem. For binaries composed of a star orbiting a supermassive black
hole, these resonances lead to a smoking-gun effect: a periastron distance
which {\it stalls}, even in the presence of gravitational-wave dissipation.
This effect, also called a {\it floating orbit}, occurs for generic equatorial
but eccentric orbits and we argue that finite-size effects are not enough to
suppress it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03749</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03749</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-02-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;vg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Canonical Acoustic Thin-Shell Wormholes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, Accepted for publication in Modern Physics
  Letters A</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 7 (2017) 1750047</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231750047X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we model a canonical acoustic thin shell wormhole (CATSW) in
the framework of analogue gravity systems. In this model we apply cut and paste
technique to join together two spherically symmetric, analogue canonical
acoustic solutions, and compute the analogue surface density/surface pressure
of the fluid using the Darmois- Israel formalism. We study the stability
analyses by using a linear barotropic fluid (LBF), chaplygin fluid (CF),
logarithmic fluid (LogF), polytropic fluid (PF), and finally Van der Waals
Quintessence (VDWQ). We show that a kind of analog acoustic fluid with negative
energy is required at the throat to keep the wormhole stable. It is argued
that, CATSW can be a stabile thin-shell wormhole if we choose a suitable
parameter values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08353</id><created>2016-12-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Biplab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Alka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awana</keyname><forenames>V P S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senguttuvan</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husale</keyname><forenames>Sudhir</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of quantum oscillations in FIB fabricated nanowires of
  topological insulator (Bi2Se3)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures, accepted in JPCM</comments><journal-ref>Biplab Bhattacharyya et al 2017 J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29
  115602</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa5536</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since last few years, research based on topological insulators (TI) is in
great interests due to intrinsic exotic fundamental properties and future
potential applications such as quantum computers or spintronics. The
fabrication of TI nanodevices and study on their transport properties mostly
focused on high quality crystalline nanowires or nanoribbons. Here we report
robust approach of Bi2Se3 nanowire formation from deposited flakes using ion
beam milling method. The fabricated Bi2Se3 nanowire devices have been employed
to investigate the robustness of topological surface state (TSS) to gallium ion
doping and any deformation in the material due to fabrication tools. We report
the quantum oscillations in magnetoresistance curves under the parallel
magnetic field. The resistance versus magnetic field curves have been studied
and compared with Aharonov-Bohm (AB) interference effects which further
demonstrate the transport through TSS. The fabrication route and observed
electronic transport properties indicate clear quantum oscillations and can be
exploited further in studying the exotic electronic properties associated with
TI based nanodevices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01508</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Messias V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; B. da</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Leite</keyname><forenames>Marcelo M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neumann boundary conditions with null external quasi-momenta in
  finite-systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 11 figures, improved version, corrected minor misprints,
  more references added; a misprint in the title fixed, keywords included</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The order parameter of a critical system defined in a layered parallel plate
geometry subject to Neumann boundary conditions at the limiting surfaces is
studied. We utilize a one-particle irreducible vertex parts framework in order
to study the critical behavior of such a system. The renormalized vertex parts
are defined at zero external quasi-momenta, which makes the analysis
particularly simple. The distance between the boundary plates $L$
characterizing the finite size system direction perpendicular to the
hyperplanes plays a similar role here in comparison with our recent unified
treatment for Neumann and Dirichlet boundary conditions. Critical exponents are
computed using diagrammatic expansion at least up to two-loop order and are
shown to be identical to those from the bulk theory (limit $L \rightarrow
\infty$).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02596</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yaron</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perley</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gal-Yam</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groh</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horesh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ofek</keyname><forenames>E. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sollerman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fransson</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabo</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapir</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taddia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cenko</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arcavi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howell</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasliwal</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vreeswijk</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khazov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fox</keyname><forenames>O. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnat</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelly</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nugent</keyname><forenames>P. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filippenko</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laher</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wozniak</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebbapragada</keyname><forenames>U. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maguire</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soumagnac</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Confined Dense Circumstellar Material Surrounding a Regular Type II
  Supernova: The Unique Flash-Spectroscopy Event of SN 2013fs</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in Nature Phys., including methods and SI</comments><doi>10.1038/nphys4025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the advent of new wide-field, high-cadence optical transient surveys,
our understanding of the diversity of core-collapse supernovae has grown
tremendously in the last decade. However, the pre-supernova evolution of
massive stars, that sets the physical backdrop to these violent events, is
theoretically not well understood and difficult to probe observationally. Here
we report the discovery of the supernova iPTF13dqy = SN 2013fs, a mere ~3 hr
after explosion. Our rapid follow-up observations, which include
multiwavelength photometry and extremely early (beginning at ~6 hr
post-explosion) spectra, map the distribution of material in the immediate
environment (&lt;~ 10^15 cm) of the exploding star and establish that it was
surrounded by circumstellar material (CSM) that was ejected during the final ~1
yr prior to explosion at a high rate, around 10^-3 solar masses per year. The
complete disappearance of flash-ionised emission lines within the first several
days requires that the dense CSM be confined to within &lt;~ 10^15 cm, consistent
with radio non-detections at 70--100 days. The observations indicate that
iPTF13dqy was a regular Type II SN; thus, the finding that the probable red
supergiant (RSG) progenitor of this common explosion ejected material at a
highly elevated rate just prior to its demise suggests that pre-supernova
instabilities may be common among exploding massive stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04530</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Cirera</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Corona</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrera</keyname><forenames>G. Teruel F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reyes</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Teruel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Incorporating the Environmental Dimension into Multidimensional Poverty
  Measurement: An Initial Proposition</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, feb2017 version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multidimensional poverty measurement has captured the attention of
policy-makers and researchers during recent years. Mexico is one of the most
advanced countries in the measurement of poverty beyond income indicators.
However, both in Mexico and other countries which have attempted at measuring
poverty from a multidimensional perspective, the environmental dimension, has
been well under-represented. Based on international evidence and, using the
welfare-rights based methodological framework used in Mexico to measure
multi-dimensional poverty officially, the paper proposes an indicator and six
sub-indicators for measuring the lack of a minimum welfare to fulfil the right
to a healthy environment through 6 sub-indicators measuring effective access,
quality and continuity with regards to water, energy, biodiversity, air,
spatial health, waste management and the vulnerability to poverty from climate
change impacts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06565</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pacucci</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natarajan</keyname><forenames>Priyamvada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Feedback Limits to Maximum Seed Masses of Black Holes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ Letters</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, 2017, Volume 835, Number 2</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/835/2/L36</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most massive black holes observed in the Universe weigh up to $\sim
10^{10} \, \mathrm{M_{\odot}}$, nearly independent of redshift. Reaching these
final masses likely required copious accretion and several major mergers.
Employing a dynamical approach, that rests on the role played by a new,
relevant physical scale - the transition radius - we provide a theoretical
calculation of the maximum mass achievable by a black hole seed that forms in
an isolated halo, one that scarcely merged. Incorporating effects at the
transition radius and their impact on the evolution of accretion in isolated
haloes we are able to obtain new limits for permitted growth. We find that
large black hole seeds ($M_{\bullet} \gtrsim 10^4 \, \mathrm{M_{\odot}}$)
hosted in small isolated halos ($M_h \lesssim 10^9 \, \mathrm{M_{\odot}}$)
accreting with relatively small radiative efficiencies ($\epsilon \lesssim
0.1$) grow optimally in these circumstances. Moreover, we show that the
standard $M_{\bullet}-\sigma$ relation observed at $z \sim 0$ cannot be
established in isolated halos at high-$z$, but requires the occurrence of
mergers. Since the average limiting mass of black holes formed at $z \gtrsim
10$ is in the range $10^{4-6} \, \mathrm{M_{\odot}}$, we expect to observe them
in local galaxies as intermediate-mass black holes, when hosted in the rare
haloes that experienced only minor or no merging events. Such ancient black
holes, formed in isolation with subsequent scant growth, could survive, almost
unchanged, until present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01028</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pacif</keyname><forenames>S. K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakulov</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakulov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological parametrizations and their scalar field descendents</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 0 fig</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reconstruct the field potentials in case of (non)phantom fields for
different models resulting from parametrization of q(t), a(t) or H(t). In
addition we carry out similar procedure for tachyonic field. We also discuss
specific form of parametrization for reconstruction of scalar field potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01908</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Antoniadis</keyname><forenames>Ignatios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotsakis</keyname><forenames>Spiros</forenames></author></authors><title>The singularity problem in brane cosmology</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, to appear in the Special Issue &quot;100 Years of
  Chronogeometrodynamics: the Status of the Einstein's Theory of Gravitation in
  Its Centennial Year&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Universe 3 (2017) 11</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review results about the development and asymptotic nature of
singularities in `brane-bulk' systems. These arise for warped metrics obeying
the 5-dimensional Einstein equations with fluid-like sources, and including a
brane 4-metric that is either Minkowski or de Sitter or Anti-de Sitter. We
characterize all singular Minkowski brane solutions, and look for regular
solutions with nonzero curvature. We briefly comment on matching solutions,
energy conditions and finite Planck mass criteria for admissibility, and we
briefly discuss the connection of these results to ambient theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04502</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Heltai</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiendl</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeSimone</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reali</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>A natural framework for isogeometric fluid-structure interaction based
  on BEM-shell coupling</title><categories>math.NA cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>33 pages, 9 figures. To appear in &quot;Computer Methods in Applied
  Mechanics and Engineering&quot;</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cma.2016.08.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction between thin structures and incompressible Newtonian fluids
is ubiquitous both in nature and in industrial applications. In this paper we
present an isogeometric formulation of such problems which exploits a boundary
integral formulation of Stokes equations to model the surrounding flow, and a
non linear Kirchhoff-Love shell theory to model the elastic behaviour of the
structure. We propose three different coupling strategies: a monolithic, fully
implicit coupling, a staggered, elasticity driven coupling, and a novel
semi-implicit coupling, where the effect of the surrounding flow is
incorporated in the non-linear terms of the solid solver through its damping
characteristics. The novel semi-implicit approach is then used to demonstrate
the power and robustness of our method, which fits ideally in the isogeometric
paradigm, by exploiting only the boundary representation (B-Rep) of the thin
structure middle surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04724</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venumadhav</keyname><forenames>Tejaswi</forenames></author></authors><title>On the waveforms of gravitationally lensed gravitational waves</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong lensing by intervening galaxies can produce multiple images of
gravitational waves from sources at cosmological distances. These images
acquire additional phase-shifts as the over-focused wavefront passes through
itself along the line of sight. Time domain waveforms of Type-II images
(associated with saddle points of the time delay) exhibit a non-trivial
distortion from the unlensed waveforms. This phenomenon is in addition to the
usual frequency-independent magnification, and happens even in the geometric
limit where the wavelength is much shorter than the deflector's gravitational
length scale. Similarly, Type-III images preserve the original waveform's shape
but exhibit a sign flip. We show that for non-precessing binaries undergoing
circular inspiral and merger, these distortions are equivalent to rotating the
line of sight about the normal to the orbital plane by $45^\circ$ (Type II) and
$90^\circ$ (Type III). This effect will enable us to distinguish between the
different topological types among a set of multiple images, and give us
valuable insight into the lens model. Furthermore, we show that for eccentric
binaries, the waveform of a Type-II image is distorted in a manner that is
inequivalent to a change of the source's orbital parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04728</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanderlinde</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paradise</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klages</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masui</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bandura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyle</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobbs</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaspi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renard</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stairs</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyakov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>CHIME FRB: An application of FFT beamforming for a radio telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures, submitted to the XXXII International Union of
  Radio Science General Assembly &amp; Scientific Symposium (URSI GASS) 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed FFT beamforming techniques for the CHIME radio telescope,
to search for and localize the astrophysical signals from Fast Radio Bursts
(FRBs) over a large instantaneous field-of-view (FOV) while maintaining the
full angular resolution of CHIME. We implement a hybrid beamforming pipeline in
a GPU correlator, synthesizing 256 FFT-formed beams in the North-South
direction by four formed beams along East-West via exact phasing, tiling a sky
area of ~250 square degrees. A zero-padding approximation is employed to
improve chromatic beam alignment across the wide bandwidth of 400 to 800 MHz.
We up-channelize the data in order to achieve fine spectral resolution of
$\Delta\nu$=24 kHz and time cadence of 0.983 ms, desirable for detecting
transient and dispersed signals such as those from FRBs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04741</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Brazda</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Hoop</keyname><forenames>Maarten V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoermann</keyname><forenames>Guenther</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational formulation of the earth's elastic-gravitational
  deformations under low regularity conditions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>1 figure</comments><msc-class>86-02, 49S05,</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a construction of the action, in the framework of the calculus of
variations and Sobolev spaces, describing deformations and the oscillations of
a uniformly rotating, elastic and self-gravitating earth. We establish the
Fr\'{e}chet differentiability of the action under minimal regularity
assumptions, which constrain the possible composition of an earth model. Thus
we obtain well-defined Euler-Lagrange equations, weakly and strongly, that is,
the system of elastic-gravitational equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04754</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Margalli</keyname><forenames>Carlos A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergara</keyname><forenames>J. David</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge Freedom in complex holomorphic systems</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to introduce and analyze a new gauge symmetry that
appears in complex holomorphic systems. This symmetry allow us to project the
system, using different gauge conditions, to several real systems which are
connect by gauge transformations in the complex space. We prove that the space
of solutions of one system is related to the other by the gauge transformation.
The gauge transformations are in some cases canonical transformations. However,
in other cases are more general transformations that change the symplectic
structure, but there is still a map between the systems. In this way our
construction extend the group of canonical transformations in classical
mechanics. Also, we show how to extend the analysis to the quantum case using
path integrals by means of the Batalin-Fradkin-Vilkovisky theorem and within
the canonical formalism, where we show explicitly that solutions of the
Schr\&quot;odinger equation are gauge related.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04771</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Giuliani</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gattringer</keyname><forenames>Christof</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on the construction of worm algorithms for lattice field
  theories in worldline representation</title><categories>hep-lat cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a generalized worldline model where the partition function is a
sum over configurations of a conserved flux on a d-dimensional lattice. The
weights for the configurations of the corresponding worldlines have factors
living on the links of the lattice, as well as terms which live on the sites x
and depend on all fluxes attached to x. The model represents a general class of
worldline systems, among them the dual representation of the relativistic Bose
gas at finite density. We construct a suitable worm algorithm and show how to
correctly distribute the site weights in the various Metropolis probabilities
that determine the worm. We analyze the algorithm in detail and give a proof of
detailed balance. Our algorithm admits the introduction of an amplitude
parameter A that can be chosen freely. Using a numerical simulation of the
relativistic Bose gas we demonstrate that A allows one to influence the
starting and terminating probabilities and thus the average length and the
efficiency of the worm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04805</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sorensen</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron train backgrounds in liquid xenon dark matter search detectors
  are indeed due to thermalization and trapping</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron emission from liquid into gaseous xenon is a cornerstone of dark
matter search detectors such as ZEPLIN, XENON, LUX and LZ. The probability of
emission is a function of the applied electric field E, and electrons which
fail to pass from the liquid into the gas have been previously hypothesized to
become thermalized and trapped. This article shows, for the first time,
quantitative agreement between an electron emission model and existing data.
The model predicts that electrons in the liquid must surmount a typical
potential barrier phi_b=0.34+-0.01 eV in order to escape into the gas. This
value is a factor of about x2 smaller than has previously been calculated or
inferred. Knowledge of phi_b allows calculation of the lifetime of thermalized,
trapped electrons. The value is O(10) ms, which appears to be compatible with
XENON10 observations of electron train backgrounds. As these backgrounds limit
the sensitivity of dark sector dark matter searches, possible mitigations are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04819</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Battista</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troiani</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picano</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractal scaling of turbulent premixed flame fronts: application to LES</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>26 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow 51 (2015) 78-87</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijheatfluidflow.2014.08.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fractal scaling properties of turbulent premixed flame fronts have been
investigated and considered for modelling sub-grid scales in the
Large-Eddy-Simulation framework. Since the width of such thin reaction fronts
cannot be resolved into the coarse mesh of LES, the extent of wrinkled flame
surface contained in a volume is taken into account. The amount of unresolved
flame front is estimated via the &quot;wrinkling facto&quot; that depends on the
definition of a suitable fractal dimension and the scale at which the fractal
scaling is lost, the inner cut-off length {\epsilon}i. In this context, the
present study considers laboratory experiments and one-step reaction DNS of
turbulent premixed jet flames in different regimes of turbulent premixed
flames. Fractal dimension is found to be substantially constant and well below
that typical of passive scalar fronts. The inner cut-off length shows a clear
scaling with the dissipative scale of Kolmogorov for the regimes here
considered. These features have been exploited performing Large Eddy
Simulations. Good model performance has been found comparing the LES against a
corresponding DNS at moderate Reynolds number and experimental data at higher
Reynolds numbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04824</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bressan</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zipeng</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Controllability of Lagrangian Systems by Active Constraints</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP math.OC</categories><journal-ref>J. Differential Equations, 247 (2009), 543-563</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a mechanical system which is controlled by means of moving
constraints. Namely, we assume that some of the coordinates can be directly
assigned as functions of time by means of frictionless constraints. This leads
to a system of ODE's whose right hand side depends quadratically on the time
derivative of the control. In this paper we introduce a simplified dynamics,
described by a differential inclusion. We prove that every trajectory of the
differential inclusion can be uniformly approximated by a trajectory of the
original system, on a sufficiently large time interval, starting at rest. Under
a somewhat stronger assumption, we show this second trajectory reaches exactly
the same terminal point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04830</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Tieri</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Minghui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meiser</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holland</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of the crossover from lasing to steady state superradiance</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lasing and steady state superradiance are two phenomena that may appear at
first glance to be distinct. In a laser, phase information is maintained by a
macroscopic intracavity light field, and the robustness of this phase is what
leads to the coherence of the output light. In contrast, the coherence of
steady-state superradiant systems derives from the macroscopic collective
dipole of a many-atom ensemble. In this paper, we develop a quantum theory that
connects smoothly between these two extreme limits. We show that lasing and
steady-state superradiance should be thought of as the two extreme limits of a
continuous crossover. The properties of systems that lie in the superradiance,
lasing, and crossover parameter regions are compared. We find that for a given
output intensity a narrower linewidth can be obtained by operating closer to
the superradiance side of the crossover. We also find that the collective phase
is robust against cavity frequency fluctuations in the superradiant regime and
against atomic level fluctuations in the lasing regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04844</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Shibiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Guangyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malek</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Earl</keyname><forenames>Stuart K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Luping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kou</keyname><forenames>Shan Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Xiaocong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards broadband dynamic structuring of a complex plasmonic field</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to tailor a coherent surface plasmon polariton (SPP) field is an
important step towards a number of new opportunities for a broad range of
nanophotonic applications such as sensing [1,2], nano-circuitry [3,4], optical
data storage [5,6], super-resolution imaging [7,8], plasmonic tweezers [9,10]
and in-plane communications [11]. Scanning a converging SPP spot or designing
SPP profiles using an ensemble of spots have both been demonstrated previously
[12-14]. SPPs, however, are normally excited by intense, coherent light
sources-lasers. Hence, interference between adjacent spots is inevitable and
will affect the overall SPP field distributions. Here we report a
reconfigurable and wavelength-independent platform for generating a tailored 2D
SPP field distribution by considering the coherent field as a whole rather than
individual spots. The new perspective also enables us to reveal the inherent
constraints implied in a 2D coherent field distribution. Our generic design
methodology works not only for SPP waves but also for other two-dimensional
wave systems like surface acoustic waves [15].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04855</id><created>2017-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sengupta</keyname><forenames>Pratim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shanahan</keyname><forenames>Marie-Claire</forenames></author></authors><title>Open Science, Public Engagement and the University</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>This is a white paper commissioned by the NSF and NIH funded
  conference: http: //www.ncsa.illinois.edu/Conferences/ImagineU/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Contemporary debates on &quot;open science&quot; mostly focus on the pub- lic
accessibility of the products of scientific and academic work. In contrast,
this paper presents arguments for &quot;opening&quot; the ongoing work of science. That
is, this paper is an invitation to rethink the university with an eye toward
engaging the public in the dynamic, conceptual and representational work
involved in creating scientific knowledge. To this end, we posit that public
computing spaces, a genre of open- ended, public learning environment where
visitors interact with open source computing platforms to directly access,
modify and create complex and authentic scientific work, can serve as a
possible model of &quot;open science&quot; in the university.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04864</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Van Der Goetz</keyname><forenames>Brett</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neuscamman</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppressing ionic terms with number counting Jastrow factors in real
  space</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that 4-body real space Jastrow factors are, with the right
type of Jastrow basis function, capable of performing successful wave function
stenciling to remove unwanted ionic terms from an overabundant fermionic
reference without unduly modifying the remaining components. In addition to
greatly improving size consistency (restoring it exactly in the case of a
geminal power), real-space wave function stenciling is, unlike its Hilbert
space predecessors, immediately compatible with diffusion Monte Carlo, allowing
it to be used in the pursuit of compact, strongly correlated trial functions
with reliable nodal surfaces. We demonstrate the efficacy of this approach in
the context of a double bond dissociation by using it to extract a
qualitatively correct nodal surface despite being paired with a restricted
Slater determinant, that, due to ionic term errors, produces a ground state
with a qualitatively incorrect nodal surface when used in the absence of the
Jastrow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04876</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ovadyahu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonequilibrium transport and Electron-Glass effects in thin GexTe films</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 155151 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155151</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on results of nonequilibrium transport measurements made on thin
films of germanium-telluride (Ge_xTe) at cryogenic temperatures. Owing to a
rather large deviation from stoichiometry (app. 10% of Ge vacancies), these
films exhibit p-type conductivity with carrier-concentration N&gt;10^20cm^(-3) and
can be made either in the diffusive or strongly-localized regime by a judicious
choice of preparation and post-treatment conditions. In both regimes the system
shows persistent photoconductivity following excitation by a brief exposure to
infrared radiation. Persistent photoconductivity is also observed in GexTe
samples alloyed with Mn. However, in both Ge_xTe and GeMn_xTe_y the effect is
much weaker than that observable in GeSb_xTe_y alloys suggesting that antimony
plays an important role in the phenomenon. Structural studies of these films
reveal an unusual degree of texture that is rarely realized in
strongly-disordered systems with high carrier-concentrations.
Anderson-localized samples of Ge_xTe exhibit non-ergodic transport which are
characteristic of intrinsic electron-glasses, including a well developed
memory-dip and slow relaxation of the excess conductance created in the excited
state. These results support the conjecture that electron-glass effects with
inherently long relaxation times is a generic property of all
Anderson-localized systems with large carrier-concentration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04880</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Wondrak</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckert</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author></authors><title>Visualization of the global flow structure in a modified Rayleigh-Benard
  setup using contactless inductive flow tomography</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>31 pages, 20 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rayleigh-Benard convection is not only a classical problem in fluid dynamics
but plays also an important role in many metallurgical and crystal growth
applications. The measurement of the flow field and of the dynamics of the
emerging large-scale circulation in liquid metals is a challenging task due to
the opaqueness and the high temperature of the melts. Contactless inductive
flow tomography is a technique to visualize the mean three-dimensional flow
structure in liquid metals by measuring the flow induced magnetic field
perturbations under the influence of one or several applied magnetic fields. In
this paper, we present first measurements of the flow induced magnetic field in
a Rayleigh-Benard setup, which are also used to investigate the dynamics of the
large-scale circulation. Additionally, we investigate numerically the quality
of the reconstruction of the three-dimensional flow field for different sensor
configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04891</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Gongxun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jinda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Jianliao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuzhu</forenames></author></authors><title>Exponential decrease of Ramsey linewidth via coherent atomic phase
  tracking</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an effective method to decrease the Ramsey linewidth of microwave
atomic clock by tracking the coherent atomic phase through nondestructive
measurement. The free evolution time T between two Ramsey pulses is divided
into N subsections. In each subsection, the coherent phase of the atomic
ensemble is probed by an additional large-detuning laser. The probed phase in
the previous subsection is used to change the phase of the microwave pulse in
the following subsection. After tracking the coherent atomic phase for N-1
times, the final linewidth of Ramsey fringe decreases quickly as N/(2N-1). We
then demonstrate this proposal in a vapor cell atomic clock. The linewidth of
the Ramsey fringe is decreased down to 27 Hz after 5 successive
sub-interrogations, which is much narrower than the linewidth of 142 Hz
obtained by normal Ramsey spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04894</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Giorgilli</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Locatelli</keyname><forenames>Ugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sansottera</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Secular dynamics of a planar model of the Sun-Jupiter-Saturn-Uranus
  system; effective stability into the light of Kolmogorov and Nekhoroshev
  theories</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1010.2609</comments><journal-ref>Regular and Chaotic Dynamics, 22, 54--77 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S156035471701004X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the long-time stability of the Sun-Jupiter-Saturn-Uranus
system by considering a planar secular model, that can be regarded as a major
refinement of the approach first introduced by Lagrange. Indeed, concerning the
planetary orbital revolutions, we improve the classical circular approximation
by replacing it with a solution that is invariant up to order two in the
masses; therefore, we investigate the stability of the secular system for
rather small values of the eccentricities. First, we explicitly construct a
Kolmogorov normal form, so as to find an invariant KAM torus which approximates
very well the secular orbits. Finally, we adapt the approach that is at basis
of the analytic part of the Nekhoroshev's theorem, so as to show that there is
a neighborhood of that torus for which the estimated stability time is larger
than the lifetime of the Solar System. The size of such a neighborhood,
compared with the uncertainties of the astronomical observations, is about ten
times smaller.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04899</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zand</keyname><forenames>Jean in 't</forenames><affiliation>SRON</affiliation></author></authors><title>Understanding superbursts</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To be published in the proceedings of 'Seven years of MAXI:
  monitoring X-ray transients', a workshop held at RIKEN, Saitama, Japan, on
  5-7 December 2016. 7 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superbursts were discovered at the beginning of this millennium. Just like
type-I X-ray bursts, they are thought to be due to thermonuclear shell flashes
on neutron stars, only igniting much deeper. With respect to type-I bursts,
they last 10$^3$ times longer, are 10$^3$ as rare, ignite 10$^3$ times deeper
(in column depth) and are thought to be fueled by carbon instead of hydrogen
and helium. Observationally, they are sometimes hard to distinguish from
intermediate duration bursts which are due to pure helium flashes on cold
neutron stars. So far, 26 superbursts have been detected from 15 neutron stars
in low-mass X-ray binaries that also exhibit type-I bursts. They are very
difficult to catch and only 2 have been measured with highly sensitive
instrumentation. Superbursts are sensitive probes of the neutron star crust and
the accretion disk. The superburst phenomenon is not fully understood.
Questions remain about the nature of the fuel, the collection of that fuel and
the ignition conditions. The current state of affairs is reviewed and possible
resolutions that lay ahead in the future discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04902</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Avgitas</keyname><forenames>Theodore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourlis</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fanourakis</keyname><forenames>George K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gkialas</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leisos</keyname><forenames>Antonios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manthos</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsirigotis</keyname><forenames>Apostolos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzamarias</keyname><forenames>Spyros E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deployment and calibration procedures for accurate timing and
  directional reconstruction of EAS particle-fronts with HELYCON stations</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>34 pages, 26 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High energy cosmic rays, with energies thousands of times higher than those
encountered in particle accelerators, offer scientists the means of
investigating the elementary properties of matter. In order to detect high
energy cosmic rays, new detection hardware and experimental methods are being
developed. In this work, we describe the network of HELYCON (HEllenic LYceum
Cosmic Observatories Network) autonomous stations for the detection and
directional reconstruction of Extended Atmospheric Showers (EAS)
particle-fronts. HELYCON stations are hybrid stations consisting of three large
plastic scintillators plus a CODALEMA antenna for the RF detection of EAS
particle-fronts. We present the installation, operation and calibration of
three HELYCON stations and the electronic components for the remote control,
monitor and Data Acquisition. We report on the software package developed for
the detailed simulation of the detectors' response and for the stations'
operation. The simulation parameters have been fine tuned in order to
accurately describe each individual detector's characteristics and the
operation of each HELYCON station. Finally, the evaluation of the stations'
performance in reconstructing the direction of the EAS particle-front is being
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04905</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bakhti</keyname><forenames>Benaoumeur</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting fluids in an arbitrary external field</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new method for studying the equilibrium properties of interacting
fluids in an arbitrary external filed. The method is valid in any dimension and
it yields an exact results in one dimension. Using this approach, we derive a
recurrence relation for the pair distribution function of a three dimensional
in-homogeneous fluids, constitute of spherical molecules with arbitrary nearest
neighbour interaction that extends to two molecules diameter. By integrating
this recurrence relation, we get an explicit expressions for the entropy and
free energy functionals as a functionals of the density and the pair
distribution function. We show that for one dimensional systems, our results
coincide exactly with previously derived one using a completely different
approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04909</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaminchev</keyname><forenames>Kostadin G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal and structural properties of iron at high pressure by molecular
  dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures, 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the basic thermal, mechanical and structural properties of
body centred cubic iron ($\alpha$-Fe) at several temperatures and positive
loading by means of Molecular Dynamics simulations in conjunction with the
embedded-atom method potential and its modified counterpart one. Computations
of its thermal properties like average energy and density of atoms, transport
sound velocities at finite temperatures and pressures are detailed studied as
well. Moreover, there are suggestions to obtain hexagonal close- packed
structure ($\varepsilon$-phase) of this metal under positive loading. To
demonstrate that, one can increase sufficiently the pressure of simulated
system at several temperature's ranges; these structural changes depend only on
potential type used. The ensuring structures are studied via the pair radial
distribution functions (PRDF) and precise common- neighbour analysis method
(CNA) as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04911</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Landsgesell</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smiatek</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holm</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of weak polyelectrolytes: A comparison between the constant
  pH and the reaction ensemble method</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>3 figures</comments><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60324-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reaction ensemble and the constant pH method are well-known chemical
equilibrium approaches to simulate protonation and deprotonation reactions in
classical molecular dynamics and Monte Carlo simulations. In this article, we
show similarity between both methods {under certain conditions}. We perform
molecular dynamics simulations of a weak polyelectrolyte in order to compare
the titration curves obtained by both approaches. Our findings reveal a good
agreement between the methods when the reaction ensemble is used to sweep the
reaction constant. Pronounced differences between the reaction ensemble and the
constant pH method can be observed for stronger acids and bases in terms of
adaptive pH values. These deviations are due to the presence of explicit
protons in the reaction ensemble method which induce a screening of
electrostatic interactions between the charged titrable groups of the
polyelectrolyte. The outcomes of our simulation hint to a better applicability
of the reaction ensemble method for systems in confined geometries and titrable
groups in polyelectrolytes with different pK$_\text{a}$ values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04918</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04918</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kurebayashi</keyname><forenames>Daichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic theory of electrically induced spin torques in magnetic Weyl
  semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study electrical responses of magnetization in Weyl
semimetals. The Weyl semimetal is a new class of topological semimetals,
possessing hedgehog type spin textures in momentum space. Because of this
peculiar spin texture, an interplay of electron transport and spin dynamics
might provide new method to electrical control of magnetization. In this paper,
we consider the magnetically doped Weyl semimetals, and systematically study
current- and charge-induced spin torque exerted on the local magnetization in
three-dimensional Dirac-Weyl metals. We determine all current-induced spin
torques including spin-orbit torque, spin-transfer torque, and the so-called
$\beta$-term, up to first order with respect to spatial and temporal derivation
and electrical currents. We find that spin-transfer torque and $\beta$-term are
absent while spin-orbit torque is proportional to the axial current density. We
also calculate the charge-induced spin torque microscopically. We find the
charge-induced spin torque originates from the chiral anomaly due to the
correspondence between spin operators and axial current operators in our model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04926</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Sibandze</keyname><forenames>Dan B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Rituparno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maharaj</keyname><forenames>Sunil D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunsby</keyname><forenames>Peter K. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Echoes from the black holes: Evidence of higher order corrections to
  General Relativity in strong gravity regime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, Revtex 4</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the higher order curvature corrections to general relativity in
the strong gravity regime of near horizon scales produce a rapidly oscillating
and infalling Ricci scalar fireball just outside the horizon. This can generate
the ringdown modes of gravitational waves having the same natural frequency as
those which are generated by the black hole mergers. Our analysis provides a
viable explanation to the echoes in the ringdown modes recently detected from
the LIGO data, without invoking the existence of any exotic structures at the
horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04928</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhanabaev</keyname><forenames>Zeinulla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dikhanbayev</keyname><forenames>Kadyrzhan</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective parameters of porous layer in silicon cells</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>in Russian</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretically and experimentally we have proved the existence of optimal
thickness of the porous layer used as an anti-reflection coating in solar
cells. We have taken into account the joint mechanisms of generation and
recombination of electrons and holes stimulated by photons. The porous silicon
surface has been obtained by electrochemical etching. Results of scanning
electron microscopy, measuring short-circuit current, open circuit voltage, and
etching time have shown that in case thickness of the porous layer is
approximately 2/3 of electron diffusion length the solar cell efficiency
increases by 30% in comparison with the corresponding value in the absence of
texturing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04944</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dierick</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouche</keyname><forenames>A. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scohier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guille</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buisseret</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unstable Footwear as a Speed-Dependent Noise-Based Training Gear to
  Exercise Inverted Pendulum Motion During Walking</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 tables, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous research on unstable footwear has suggested that it may induce
plantar mechanical noise during walking. The purpose of this study was to
explore whether unstable footwear could be considered as a noise-based training
gear to exercise body center of mass (CoM) motion during walking or not. Ground
reaction forces were collected among 24 healthy young women walking at speeds
between 3 and 6 km h-1 with control running shoes and unstable rocker-bottom
shoes. The external mechanical work, the recovery of mechanical energy of the
CoM during and within the step cycles, and the phase shift between potential
and kinetic energy curves of the CoM were computed. Our findings support the
idea that unstable rocker-bottom footwear could serve as a speed-dependent
noise- based training gear to exercise CoM motion during walking. At slow
speed, it acts as a stochastic resonance or facilitator, whereas at brisk speed
it acts as a constraint.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04945</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsushita</keyname><forenames>E. T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Passos</keyname><forenames>E. J. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixture of two ultra cold bosonic atoms confined in a ring: stability
  and persistent currents</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we investigate the stability of quantized yrast (QY) states
in a mixture of two distinguishable equal mass bosonic atoms, $A$ and $B$,
confined in a ring. We focus our investigation in the study of the energetic
stability since the Bloch analysis and the Bogoliubov theory establish that
only energetically stable QY states are capable of sustain a persistent
current. Based on physical considerations the stability is studied in two
different two-dimensional planes. One is when we are studying the stability of
a single QY state which is realized in the $U_{AB}\times U$ plane spanned by
the inter and intraspecies interaction strengths with fixed values of angular
momentum per particle $l$ and population imbalance $f$ equal to the labels of
the QY state. We found that the energetic phase boundary is the positive branch
of a hyperbola and the energetically stable domain the internal region of this
positive branch. The other is when we are studying the stability at a fixed
dynamics which is realized in the $l\times f$ plane spanned by $l$ and $f$ with
fixed values of the interaction strengths. The QY states are introduced when we
postulate a correspondence between points in sector of the $l\times f$ plane of
physical significance (SPS), defined by $-\infty&lt; l&lt;\infty$ and $-1\leq f\leq
1$, and QY states. The stability diagram in the SPS is determined by the
overlap of the stability diagram in all $l\times f$ plane and the SPS. We found
that there are critical values of $f$ and $l$. $f_\mathrm{crit}(l)$ gives the
size of the window of energetic stability in the sense that for a given $l$
only QY states with $0\leq f&lt;f_\mathrm{crit}(l)$ are energetically stable. On
the other hand, $l_\mathrm{crit}$ states that there is none energetically
stable QY state with $l&gt;l_\mathrm{crit}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04968</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>Sananda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narasimhan</keyname><forenames>Shobhana</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple descriptor and predictor for the stable structures of
  two-dimensional surface alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Predicting the ground state of alloy systems is challenging due to the large
number of possible configurations. We identify an easily computed descriptor
for the stability of binary surface alloys, the effective coordination number
$\mathscr{E}$. We show that $\mathscr{E}(M)$ correlates well with the enthalpy
of mixing, from density functional theory (DFT) calculations on
$M_x$Au$_{1-x}$/Ru [$M$ = Mn or Fe]. At each $x$, the most favored structure
has the highest [lowest] value of $\mathscr{E}(M)$ if the system is
non-magnetic [ferromagnetic]. Importantly, little accuracy is lost upon
replacing $\mathscr{E}(M)$ by $\mathscr{E}^*(M)$, which can be quickly computed
without performing a DFT calculation, possibly offering a simple alternative to
the frequently used cluster expansion method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04972</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Jernajczyk</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gosek</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latka</keyname><forenames>Miroslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlowska</keyname><forenames>Klaudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swiecicki</keyname><forenames>Lukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Bruce J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Alpha Wavelet Power as a Biomarker of Antidepressant Treatment Response
  in Bipolar Depression</title><categories>q-bio.NC physics.med-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is mounting evidence of a link between the properties of
electroencephalograms (EEGs) of depressive patients and the outcome of
pharmacotherapy. The goal of this study was to develop an EEG biomarker of
antidepressant treatment response which would require only a single EEG
measurement. We recorded resting, 21-channel EEG in 17 inpatients suffering
from bipolar depression in eyes closed and eyes open conditions. The EEG
measurement was performed at the end of the short washout period which followed
previously unsuccessful pharmacotherapy. We calculated the normalized wavelet
power of alpha rhythm using two referential montages and an average reference
montage. In particular, in the occipital (O1, O2, Oz) channels the wavelet
power of responders was up to 84% higher than that of nonresponders. Using a
novel classification algorithm we were able to correctly predict the outcome of
treatment with 90% sensitivity and 100% specificity. The proposed biomarker
requires only a single EEG measurement and consequently is intrinsically
different from biomarkers which exploit the changes in prefrontal EEG induced
by pharmacotherapy over a given time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04975</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Priyotosh</forenames></author></authors><title>Charged Higgs bosons in the extended supersymmetric scenario at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, contribution to LHCP 2016 conference proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate an extension of the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model
(MSSM) containing a $SU(2)$ Higgs triplet of zero hypercharge and a gauge
singlet. We focus on a scenario of this model which allows a light pseudoscalar
and/or a scalar below $100$ GeV in the spectrum, consistent with the most
recent data from the LHC and the earlier data from the LEP experiments. The
triplet extension gives rise to two additional charged Higgs bosons which do
not couple to fermions but can decay into $Z W^\pm$. The presence of a very
light pseudoscalar opens $a_1 W^\pm$ decay mode for the light charged Higgs
boson just like $Z_3$ symmetric singlet-extension (NMSSM). A triplet type
charged Higgs can be produced via vector boson fusion at the tree-level which
is absent in 2HDM and MSSM and NMSSM. If such charged Higgs boson is pair
produced both $Z W^\pm$ and $a_1 W^\pm$ decay modes can be probed which can
prove the existence of triplet and singlet both.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04983</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kitadono</keyname><forenames>Yoshio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengming</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous dimension of the gauge invariant canonical decomposition for
  proton momentum with the background field method</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The anomalous dimension for the gauge-invariant-canonical decomposition of
the energy-momentum tensor for quarks and gluons is studied by the background
field method. In particular, the consistency between the background field
method and the renormalization in the gluonic sectors is investigated. The
analysis shows that the naive gauge-invariant-decomposition has an
inconsistency between its definition and the renormalization in the background
field method. Although we try to consider a trick to overcome this
inconsistency in computing the anomalous dimension, the gauge-parameter
dependence remains in the final result. This result should be extended to the
problems on the gauge-invariant-canonical-spin decomposition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04986</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lindell</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sihvola</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic Wave Reflection from Surface with General Boundary
  Conditions</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most general linear and local set of boundary conditions, involving
relations between the normal components of the D and B vectors and tangential
components of the E and H vectors at each point of the boundary, are considered
in this paper. Reflection of a plane wave from a boundary defined by general
conditions in an isotropic half space is analyzed and an analytic expression
for the reflection dyadic is derived. It is shown that any plane wave can be
decomposed in two components which do not interact in reflection. Properties of
plane waves matched to the general boundary are given. Certain special cases of
boundary conditions, arising naturally from the general theory and labeled as
E-boundary, H-boundary and EH-boundary conditions, are introduced as
interesting novelties and some of their properties are studied. Previously
known special cases are considered in verifying the theory. A possible
realization of the general boundary in terms of an interface of a general
bi-anisotropic medium is discussed in an Appendix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04987</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yong-Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological dark matter from the theory of composite electroweak
  symmetry breaking</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Comments are Welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The lightest electroweak baryon as a topological object is investigated by
using a general effective Lagrangian of composite electroweak symmetry breaking
and the spin-independent electroweak baryon-nucleon scattering cross section is
calculated. We explicitly show the masses of the electroweak baryons and the
cross section as functions of the Peskin-Takeuchi $S$ parameter and the ratio
of the masses of axial-vector and vector composite bosons. We find that it is
acceptable to regard the electroweak baryon as a dark matter candidate and the
even number of technicolor is favored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04988</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Netta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranner</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>A new computational method for a model of C. elegans biomechanics:
  Insights into elasticity and locomotion performance</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An organism's ability to move freely is a fundamental behaviour in the animal
kingdom. To understand animal locomotion requires a characterisation of the
material properties, as well as the biomechanics and physiology. We present a
biomechanical model of C. elegans locomotion together with a novel finite
element method. We formulate our model as a nonlinear initial-boundary value
problem which allows the study of the dynamics of arbitrary body shapes,
undulation gaits and the link between the animal's material properties and its
performance across a range of environments. Our model replicates behaviours
across a wide range of environments. It makes strong predictions on the viable
range of the worm's Young's modulus and suggests that animals can control speed
via the known mechanism of gait modulation that is observed across different
media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04993</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Invertibility of spectral x-ray photon counting data with pileup</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM physics.med-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1702.01006</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  -In the Alvarez-Macovski method [R.E. Alvarez and A. Macovski, Phys. Med.
Biol., 1976, 733-744], the attenuation coefficient is approximated as a linear
combination of functions of energy multiplied by coefficients that depend on
the material composition at points within the object. The method then computes
the line integrals of the basis set coefficient from measurements with
different x-ray spectra. This paper shows that the transformation from photon
counting detector data with pileup to the line integrals can become
ill-conditioned under some circumstances leading to highly increased noise.
Methods: An idealized model that includes pileup and quantum noise is used. The
noise variance of the line integral estimates is computed using the
Cram{\`e}r-Rao lower bound (CRLB). The CRLB is computed as a function of object
thickness for photon counting detector data with three and four bin pulse
height analysis (PHA) and low and high pileup. Results: With four bin PHA data
the transformation is well conditioned with either high or low pileup. With
three bin PHA and high pileup, the transformation becomes ill-conditioned for
specific values of object attenuation. At these values the CRLB variance
increases by approximately 10 5 compared with the four bin PHA or low pileup
results. The condition number of the forward transformation matrix also shows a
spike at those attenuation values. Conclusion: Designers of systems using
counting detectors should study the stability of the line integral estimator
output with their data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04996</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Hieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garimella</keyname><forenames>Kiran</forenames></author></authors><title>Understanding International Migration using Tensor Factorization</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Accepted as poster at WWW 2017, Perth</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding human migration is of great interest to demographers and social
scientists. User generated digital data has made it easier to study such
patterns at a global scale. Geo coded Twitter data, in particular, has been
shown to be a promising source to analyse large scale human migration. But
given the scale of these datasets, a lot of manual effort has to be put into
processing and getting actionable insights from this data.
  In this paper, we explore feasibility of using a new tool, tensor
decomposition, to understand trends in global human migration. We model human
migration as a three mode tensor, consisting of (origin country, destination
country, time of migration) and apply CP decomposition to get meaningful low
dimensional factors. Our experiments on a large Twitter dataset spanning 5
years and over 100M tweets show that we can extract meaningful migration
patterns.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04999</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Agaba</keyname><forenames>G. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyrychko</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blyuss</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathematical model for the impact of awareness on the dynamics of
  infectious diseases</title><categories>q-bio.PE nlin.CD q-bio.QM</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Math. Biosci. 286, 22-30 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mbs.2017.01.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper analyses an SIRS-type model for infectious diseases with account
for behavioural changes associated with the simultaneous spread of awareness in
the population. Two types of awareness are included into the model: private
awareness associated with direct contacts between unaware and aware
populations, and public information campaign. Stability analysis of different
steady states in the model provides information about potential spread of
disease in a population, and well as about how the disease dynamics is affected
by the two types of awareness. Numerical simulations are performed to
illustrate the behaviour of the system in different dynamical regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05001</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Tahir-Kheli</keyname><forenames>Jamil</forenames></author></authors><title>Latent Room-Temperature T$_c$ in Cuprate Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>100 pages, 61 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ancient phrase, &quot;All roads lead to Rome&quot; applies to Chemistry and
Physics. Both are highly evolved sciences, with their own history, traditions,
language, and approaches to problems. Despite all these differences, these two
roads generally lead to the same place. For high temperature cuprate
superconductors however, the Chemistry and Physics roads do not meet or even
come close to each other. In this paper, we analyze the physics and chemistry
approaches to the doped electronic structure of cuprates and find the chemistry
doped hole (out-of-the-CuO$\mathrm{_2}$-planes) leads to explanations of a vast
array of normal state cuprate phenomenology using simple counting arguments.
The chemistry picture suggests that phonons are responsible for
superconductivity in cuprates. We identify the important phonon modes, and show
that the observed T$\mathrm{_c} \sim 100$ K, the T$\mathrm{_c}$-dome as a
function of hole doping, the change in T$\mathrm{_c}$ as a function of the
number of CuO$\mathrm{_2}$ layers per unit cell, the lack of an isotope effect
at optimal T$\mathrm{_c}$ doping, and the D-wave symmetry of the
superconducting Cooper pair wavefunction are all explained by the chemistry
picture. Finally, we show that &quot;crowding&quot; the dopants in cuprates leads to a
pair wavefunction with S-wave symmetry and T$\mathrm{_c}\approx280-390$ K.
Hence, we believe there is enormous &quot;latent&quot; T$\mathrm{_c}$ remaining in the
cuprate class of superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05022</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Seidl</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Marino</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerolin</keyname><forenames>Augusto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nenna</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giesbertz</keyname><forenames>Klaas J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gori-Giorgi</keyname><forenames>Paola</forenames></author></authors><title>The strictly-correlated electron functional for spherically symmetric
  systems revisited</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>23 pages; 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strong-interaction limit of the Hohenberg-Kohn functional defines a
multimarginal optimal transport problem with Coulomb cost. From physical
arguments, the solution of this limit is expected to yield strictly-correlated
particle positions, related to each other by co-motion functions (or optimal
maps), but the existence of such a deterministic solution in the general
three-dimensional case is still an open question. A conjecture for the
co-motion functions for radially symmetric densities was presented in
Phys.~Rev.~A {\bf 75}, 042511 (2007), and later used to build approximate
exchange-correlation functionals for electrons confined in low-density quantum
dots. Colombo and Stra [Math.~Models Methods Appl.~Sci., {\bf 26} 1025 (2016)]
have recently shown that these conjectured maps are not always optimal. Here we
revisit the whole issue both from the formal and numerical point of view,
finding that even if the conjectured maps are not always optimal, they still
yield an interaction energy (cost) that is numerically very close to the true
minimum. We also prove that the functional built from the conjectured maps has
the expected functional derivative also when they are not optimal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05077</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Nocera</keyname><forenames>Emanuele R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Recent RHIC Data on Helicity-Dependent Parton Distribution
  Functions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables, contribution to the proceedings of the
  22nd International Spin Symposium (SPIN2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I study the impact of recent measurements performed at the Relativistic Heavy
Ion Collider on the determination of helicity-dependent parton distribution
functions of the proton. Specifically, I consider: preliminary data on
longitudinally single-spin asymmetries for $W$-boson production recorded by the
STAR experiment during the 2013 run at a center-of-mass energy $\sqrt{s}=510$
GeV; data on longitudinally double-spin asymmetries for di-jet production
recorded by the STAR experiment during the 2009 run at $\sqrt{s}=200$ GeV; and
data on longitudinally double-spin asymmetries for neutral pion production
recorded by the PHENIX experiment during a series of runs between 2006 and 2013
at $\sqrt{s}=200$ GeV and $\sqrt{s}=510$ GeV. The impact of the new data is
studied by applying Bayesian reweighting to NNPDFpol1.1, the most recent global
analysis of helicity-dependent parton distribution functions based on the NNDPF
methodology. In comparsion to NNDPFpol1.1, a slightly more positive polarized
gluon PDF, extended to somewhat smaller values of momentum fractions with
narrower uncertainties, as well as a slightly more marked and more precise
asymmetry between polarized up and down sea quarks are found in this study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05081</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Karpishkov</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saleev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shipilova</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy quark production at the LHC in the Parton Reggeization Approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, Talk at the Helmholtz - DIAS International
  Summer School, Quantum Field Theory at the Limits: from Strong Fields to
  Heavy Quarks, JINR, Dubna, 18-30 July, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the general introduction to the Parton Reggeization Approach and
discuss some new results on large-p_T production for heavy quarks at the LHC.
We concentrate here on study of different correlation spectra for b\barb-jet
pairs, D\barD-meson pairs and DD-meson pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
