<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:02:25Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-02-12" from="2017-02-12" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03802</id><created>2017-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sakari</keyname><forenames>Charli</forenames></author><author><keyname>McWilliam</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallerstein</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical Abundances of Two Stars in the Large Magellanic Cloud Globular
  Cluster NGC~1718</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Detailed chemical abundances of two stars in the intermediate-age Large
Magellanic Cloud (LMC) globular cluster NGC~1718 are presented, based on high
resolution spectroscopic observations with the MIKE spectrograph. The detailed
abundances confirm NGC~1718 to be a fairly metal-rich cluster, with an average
[Fe/H] ~ -0.55+/-0.01. The two red giants appear to have primordial O, Na, Mg,
and Al abundances, with no convincing signs of a composition difference between
the two stars---hence, based on these two stars, NGC~1718 shows no evidence for
hosting multiple populations. The Mg abundance is lower than Milky Way field
stars, but is similar to LMC field stars at the same metallicity. The previous
claims of very low [Mg/Fe] in NGC~1718 are therefore not supported in this
study. Other abundances (Si, Ca, Ti, V, Mn, Ni, Cu, Rb, Y, Zr, La, and Eu) all
follow the LMC field star trend, demonstrating yet again that (for most
elements) globular clusters trace the abundances of their host galaxy's field
stars. Similar to the field stars, NGC~1718 is found to be mildly deficient in
explosive $\alpha$-elements, but moderately to strongly deficient in O, Na, Mg,
Al, and Cu, elements which form during hydrostatic burning in massive stars.
NGC~1718 is also enhanced in La, suggesting that it was enriched in ejecta from
metal-poor AGB stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03935</id><created>2017-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Plevka</keyname><forenames>V&#xe1;clav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segaert</keyname><forenames>Pieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamp&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Chris M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>Mia</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of travel activity determinants using robust statistics</title><categories>stat.AP physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Transportation (2016) 43:979</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11116-016-9718-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This study investigates travel behavior determinants based on a multiday
travel survey conducted in the region of Ghent, Belgium. Due to the limited
data reliability of the data sample and the influence of outliers exerted on
classical principal component analysis, robust principal component analysis
(ROBPCA) is employed in order to reveal the explanatory variables responsible
for most of the variability. Interpretation of the results is eased by
utilizing ROSPCA. The application of ROSPCA reveals six distinct principal
components where each is determined by a few variables. Among others, our
results suggest a key role of variable categories such as journey
purpose-related impedance and journey inherent constraints. Surprisingly, the
variables associated with journey timing turn out to be less important.
Finally, our findings reveal the critical role of outliers in travel behavior
analysis. This suggests that a systematic understanding of how outliers
contribute to observed mobility behavior patterns, as derived from travel
surveys, is needed. In this regard, the proposed methods serve for processing
raw data typically used in activity-based modelling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03972</id><created>2017-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Baym</keyname><forenames>Gordon</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrarelativistic heavy ion collisions: the first billion seconds</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>Opening talk at QM2015, Kobe, 10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. A 956, 1-10 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.03.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I first review the early history of the ultrarelativistic heavy ion program,
starting with the 1974 Bear Mountain Workshop, and the 1983 Aurora meeting of
the U.S. Nuclear Science Committee, just one billion seconds ago, which laid
out the initial science goals of an ultrarelativistic collider. The primary
goal, to discover the properties of nuclear matter at the highest energy
densities, included finding new states of matter -- the quark-gluon plasma
primarily -- and to use collisions to open a new window on related problems of
matter in cosmology, neutron stars, supernovae, and elsewhere. To bring out how
the study of heavy ions and hot, dense matter in QCD has been fulfilling these
goals. I concentrate on a few topics, the phase diagram of matter in QCD, and
connections of heavy ion physics to cold atoms, cosmology, and neutron stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04019</id><created>2017-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Vural</keyname><forenames>Mert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pena-Francesch</keyname><forenames>Abdon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Huihun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terrones</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demirel</keyname><forenames>Melik C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Programmable Molecular Composites of Tandem Proteins with Graphene-Oxide
  for Efficient Bimoprh Actuators</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rapid expansion in the spectrum of two-dimensional (2D) materials has
driven the efforts of research on the fabrication of 2D composites and
heterostructures. Highly ordered structure of 2D materials provides an
excellent platform for controlling the ultimate structure and properties of the
composite material with precision. However, limited control over the structure
of the adherent material and its interactions with highly ordered 2D materials
results in defective composites with inferior performance. Here, we demonstrate
the successful synthesis, integration, and characterization of hybrid 2D
material systems consisting of tandem repeat (TR) proteins inspired by squid
ring teeth and graphene oxide (GO). The TR protein layer acts as a unique
programmable molecular spacer between GO layers. As an application, we further
demonstrate thermal actuation using bimorph molecular composite films. Bimorph
actuators made of molecular composite films (GO/TR) can lead to energy
efficiencies 18 times higher than regular bimorph actuators consisting of a GO
layer and a TR protein layer (i.e., conventional bulk composite of GO and TR).
Additionally, molecular composite bimorph actuators can reach curvature values
as high as 1.2 cm-1 by using TR proteins with higher molecular weight, which is
3 times higher than conventional GO and TR composites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04178</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Xu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao-Jun</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cun-Bo</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Tmurbagan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiu-Lin</keyname><forenames>Huang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng-Zhi</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author></authors><title>Singlet S-wave superfluidity of proton in neutron star matter</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The possible $^{1}S_{0}$ protonic superfluidity is investigated in neutron
star matter, and the corresponding energy gap as a function of baryonic density
is calculated on the basis of BCS gap equation. We have discussed particularly
the influence of hyperon degrees of freedom on $^{1}S_{0}$ protonic
superfluidity. It is found that the appearance of hyperons leads to a slight
decrease of $^{1}S_{0}$ protonic pairing energy gap in most density range of
existing $^{1}S_{0}$ protonic superfluidity. However, when the baryonic density
$\rho_{B}&gt;$0.377 (or 0.409) fm${^{-3}}$ for TM1 (or TMA) parameter set,
$^{1}S_{0}$ protonic pairing energy gap is significantly larger than the
corresponding values without hyperons. And the baryonic density range of
existing $^{1}S_{0}$ protonic superfluidity is widen due to the appearance of
hyperons. In our results, the hyperons not only change the EOS and bulk
properties but also change the size and baryon density range of $^{1}S_{0}$
protonic superfluidity in neutron star matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04204</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Galli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorburger</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pommerol</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jost</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poch</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brouet</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tulej</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface charging of thick porous water ice layers relevant for ion
  sputtering experiments</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1509.04008</comments><journal-ref>Planetary and Space Science 126 (2016), 63-71</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2016.03.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a laboratory facility to study the sputtering properties of
centimeter-thick porous water ice subjected to the bombardment of ions and
electrons to better understand the formation of exospheres of the icy moons of
Jupiter. Our ice samples are as similar as possible to the expected moon
surfaces but surface charging of the samples during ion irradiation may distort
the experimental results. We therefore monitor the time scales for charging and
dis- charging of the samples when subjected to a beam of ions. These
experiments allow us to derive an electric conductivity of deep porous ice
layers. The results imply that electron irradiation and sputtering play a
non-negligible role for certain plasma conditions at the icy moons of Jupiter.
The observed ion sputtering yields from our ice samples are similar to previous
experiments where compact ice films were sputtered off a micro-balance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04215</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zharaspayev</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aleksandrin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galper</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koldashov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-energy electron bursts in the inner Earth magnetosphere caused by
  precipitation from radiation belt</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.space-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Orbital experiment ARINA on the board of Russian satellite Resurs-DK1
launched in 2006 developed to study charged particle flux (electrons E ~ 3 -
30MeV , protons E ~ 30 - 100MeV ) in near-Earth space, especially high-energy
electron precipitation from the inner radiation belt caused by various
geophysical and solar-magnetospheric phenomena. Precipitated electrons under
certain conditions (energy, LB-coordinate) drifts around the Earth and can be
detected as fast increase in count rate of satellite spectrometer (so called
bursts). High-energy electron bursts can be caused by local geophysical
phenomena (like earthquakes or thunderstorms). Such bursts have distinct
features in their measured energy-time distribution. These features contains
information about initial location of electron precipitation. Several methods
(linear, robust regression) were used previously to find longitudinal distance
between region of precipitation and burst registration location on the board of
satellite. In this report, the new ensemble method was developed, it uses the
combining results from several methods in dependence of burst registration
conditions. Numerical simulation of local particles precipitations based on
well-known equations of relativistic particle movement in Earth magnetosphere.
In experimental data analysis, the results from ARINA experiment for 10 years
was used. Several results based on burst experimental data are shown. Ensemble
method shows better results than any single method alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04221</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Conti</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lain</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazzeretti</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lovisotto</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quattrociocchi</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>It's Always April Fools' Day! On the Difficulty of Social Network
  Misinformation Classification via Propagation Features</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given the huge impact that Online Social Networks (OSN) had in the way people
get informed and form their opinion, they became an attractive playground for
malicious entities that want to spread misinformation, and leverage their
effect. In fact, misinformation easily spreads on OSN and is a huge threat for
modern society, possibly influencing also the outcome of elections, or even
putting people's life at risk (e.g., spreading &quot;anti-vaccines&quot; misinformation).
Therefore, it is of paramount importance for our society to have some sort of
&quot;validation&quot; on information spreading through OSN. The need for a wide-scale
validation would greatly benefit from automatic tools.
  In this paper, we show that it is difficult to carry out an automatic
classification of misinformation considering only structural properties of
content propagation cascades. We focus on structural properties, because they
would be inherently difficult to be manipulated, with the the aim of
circumventing classification systems. To support our claim, we carry out an
extensive evaluation on Facebook posts belonging to conspiracy theories (as
representative of misinformation), and scientific news (representative of
fact-checked content). Our findings show that conspiracy content actually
reverberates in a way which is hard to distinguish from the one scientific
content does: for the classification mechanisms we investigated, classification
F1-score never exceeds 0.65 during content propagation stages, and is still
less than 0.7 even after propagation is complete.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04241</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Jia-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bing-Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Modularity-like objective function in annotated networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We ascertain the modularity-like objective function whose optimization is
equivalent to the maximum likelihood in annotated networks. We demonstrate that
the modularity-like objective function is a linear combination of modularity
and conditional entropy. In contrast with statistical inference methods, in our
method, the influence of the metadata is adjustable; when its influence is
strong enough, the metadata can be recovered. Conversely, when it is weak, the
detection may correspond to another partition. Between the two, there is a
transition. This paper provides a concept for expanding the scope of modularity
methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04593</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yueling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qingxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jinshu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ ${\to}$ $B_{c}P$ decays with perturbative QCD
  approach</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1610.06986</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 751, 171-176 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.10.018</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  With the potential prospects of the ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ at high-luminosity
dedicated heavy-flavor factories, the color-favored ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ ${\to}$
$B_{c}{\pi}$, $B_{c}K$ weak decays are studied with the pQCD approach. It is
found that branching ratios for the ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ ${\to}$ $B_{c}{\pi}$ decay
are as large as the order of ${\cal O}(10^{-11})$, which might be measured
promisingly by the future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04597</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yueling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qingxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Haiyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jinshu</forenames></author></authors><title>The ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ ${\to}$ $B_{c}D_{s}$, $B_{c}D_{d}$ decays with
  perturbative QCD approach</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1604.07040</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 752, 322-328 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.11.053</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The ${\Upsilon}(nS)$ ${\to}$ $B_{c}D_{s}$, $B_{c}D_{d}$ weak decays are
studied with the pQCD approach firstly. It is found that branching ratios
${\cal B}r({\Upsilon}(nS){\to}B_{c}D_{s})$ ${\sim}$ ${\cal O}(10^{-10})$ and
${\cal B}r({\Upsilon}(nS){\to}B_{c}D_{d})$ ${\sim}$ ${\cal O}(10^{-11})$, which
might be measurable in the future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04727</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kazarina</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezyazeekov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budnev</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gress</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haungs</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiller</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huege</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleifges</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korosteleva</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostunin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kromer</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kungel</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmichev</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubsandorzhiev</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshalkina</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirgazov</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monkhoev</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osipova</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakhorukov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pankov</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prosin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zagorodnikov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Tunka Radio Extension, an antenna array for high-energy cosmic-ray
  detection</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article presents the first results of the combined measurements of
Tunka-Rex and Tunka-Grande as well as studies of the antenna alignment effect
and an overview of the recent Tunka-Rex results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-02-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04760</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>H. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gab&#xe1;nyi</keyname><forenames>K. &#xc9;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paragi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cseh</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>X. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>VLBI observations of four radio quasars at $z&gt;4$: blazars or not?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Blazars are active galactic nuclei (AGN) whose relativistic jets point nearly
to the line of sight. Their compact radio structure can be imaged with very
long baseline interferometry (VLBI) on parsec scales. Blazars at extremely high
redshifts provide a unique insight into the AGN phenomena in the early
Universe. We observed four radio sources at redshift $z&gt;4$ with the European
VLBI Network (EVN) at 1.7 and 5 GHz. These objects were previously classified
as blazar candidates based on X-ray observations. One of them, J2134$-$0419 is
firmly confirmed as a blazar with our VLBI observations, due to its
relativistically beamed radio emission. Its radio jet extended to $\sim$10
milli-arcsec scale makes this source a promising target for follow-up VLBI
observations to reveal any apparent proper motion. Another target, J0839+5112
shows a compact radio structure typical of quasars. There is evidence for flux
density variability and its radio &quot;core&quot; has a flat spectrum. However, the EVN
data suggest that its emission is not Doppler-boosted. The remaining two blazar
candidates (J1420+1205 and J2220+0025) show radio properties totally unexpected
from radio AGN with small-inclination jet. Their emission extends to arcsec
scales and the Doppler factors of the central components are well below 1.
Their structures resemble that of double-lobed radio AGN with large inclination
to the line of sight. This is in contrast with the blazar-type modeling of
their multi-band spectral energy distributions. Our work underlines the
importance of high-resolution VLBI imaging in confirming the blazar nature of
high-redshift radio sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
