<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:45:43Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-01" from="2016-08-01" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.4716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.4716</id><created>2011-12-20</created><updated>2011-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budiardja</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billings</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hix</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messer</keyname><forenames>O. E. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roche</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMahon</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit Integration of Extremely-Stiff Reaction Networks: Asymptotic
  Methods</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Updated references</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Sci. Disc. 6, 015001 (2013)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that, even for extremely stiff systems, explicit integration may
compete in both accuracy and speed with implicit methods if algebraic methods
are used to stabilize the numerical integration. The required stabilizing
algebra depends on whether the system is well-removed from equilibrium or near
equilibrium. This paper introduces a quantitative distinction between these two
regimes and addresses the former case in depth, presenting explicit asymptotic
methods appropriate when the system is extremely stiff but only weakly
equilibrated. A second paper examines quasi-steady-state methods as an
alternative to asymptotic methods in systems well away from equilibrium and a
third paper extends these methods to equilibrium conditions in extremely stiff
systems using partial equilibrium methods. All three papers present systematic
evidence for timesteps competitive with implicit methods. Because an explicit
method can execute a timestep faster than an implicit method,
algebraically-stabilized explicit algorithms might permit integration of larger
networks than have been feasible before in various disciplines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.4738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.4738</id><created>2011-12-20</created><updated>2011-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billings</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hix</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit Integration of Extremely-Stiff Reaction Networks: Partial
  Equilibrium Methods</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Updated references</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Sci. Disc. 6, 015003 (2013)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In two preceding papers we have shown that, when reaction networks are
well-removed from equilibrium, explicit asymptotic and quasi-steady-state
approximations can give algebraically-stabilized integration schemes that rival
standard implicit methods in accuracy and speed for extremely stiff systems.
However, we also showed that these explicit methods remain accurate but are no
longer competitive in speed as the network approaches equilibrium. In this
paper we analyze this failure and show that it is associated with the presence
of fast equilibration timescales that neither asymptotic nor quasi-steady-state
approximations are able to remove efficiently from the numerical integration.
Based on this understanding, we develop a partial equilibrium method to deal
effectively with the approach to equilibrium and show that explicit asymptotic
methods, combined with the new partial equilibrium methods, give an integration
scheme that plausibly can deal with the stiffest networks, even in the approach
to equilibrium, with accuracy and speed competitive with that of implicit
methods. Thus we demonstrate that such explicit methods may offer alternatives
to implicit integration of even extremely stiff systems, and that these methods
may permit integration of much larger networks than have been possible before
in a number of fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.4750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.4750</id><created>2011-12-20</created><updated>2011-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit Integration of Extremely-Stiff Reaction Networks:
  Quasi-Steady-State Methods</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Updated references</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Sci. Disc. 6, 015002 (2013)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A preceding paper demonstrated that explicit asymptotic methods generally
work much better for extremely stiff reaction networks than has previously been
shown in the literature. There we showed that for systems well removed from
equilibrium explicit asymptotic methods can rival standard implicit codes in
speed and accuracy for solving extremely stiff differential equations. In this
paper we continue the investigation of systems well removed from equilibrium by
examining quasi-steady-state (QSS) methods as an alternative to asymptotic
methods. We show that for systems well removed from equilibrium, QSS methods
also can compete with, or even exceed, standard implicit methods in speed, even
for extremely stiff networks, and in many cases give somewhat better
integration speed than for asymptotic methods. As for asymptotic methods, we
will find that QSS methods give correct results, but with non-competitive
integration speed as equilibrium is approached. Thus, we shall find that both
asymptotic and QSS methods must be supplemented with partial equilibrium
methods as equilibrium is approached to remain competitive with implicit
methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.4778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.4778</id><created>2011-12-20</created><updated>2011-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author></authors><title>Algebraic Stabilization of Explicit Numerical Integration for Extremely
  Stiff Reaction Networks</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Updated references</comments><journal-ref>J. Comp. Phys. 231, 5266 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2012.04.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In contrast to the prevailing view in the literature, it is shown that even
extremely stiff sets of ordinary differential equations may be solved
efficiently by explicit methods if limiting algebraic solutions are used to
stabilize the numerical integration. The stabilizing algebra differs
essentially for systems well-removed from equilibrium and those near
equilibrium. Explicit asymptotic and quasi-steady-state methods that are
appropriate when the system is only weakly equilibrated are examined first.
These methods are then extended to the case of close approach to equilibrium
through a new implementation of partial equilibrium approximations. Using
stringent tests with astrophysical thermonuclear networks, evidence is provided
that these methods can deal with the stiffest networks, even in the approach to
equilibrium, with accuracy and integration timestepping comparable to that of
implicit methods. Because explicit methods can execute a timestep faster and
scale more favorably with network size than implicit algorithms, our results
suggest that algebraically-stabilized explicit methods might enable integration
of larger reaction networks coupled to fluid dynamics than has been feasible
previously for a variety of disciplines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.1869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.1869</id><created>2013-04-06</created><updated>2014-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cap</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gover</keyname><forenames>A. Rod</forenames></author></authors><title>Projective Compactifications and Einstein metrics</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>30 Pages. v2: Added a necessary technical assumption in Theorem 2.6.
  Adapted numbering to version to be published in J. reine angew. math.
  (Crelle's J.)</comments><msc-class>54D35, 53A20, 53B21, 53B10, 53C29, 35N10</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Reine Angew. Math. 717 (2016) 47-75</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/crelle-2014-0036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For complete affine manifolds we introduce a definition of compactification
based on the projective differential geometry (i.e.\ geodesic path data) of the
given connection. The definition of projective compactness involves a real
parameter $\alpha$ called the order of projective compactness. For volume
preserving connections, this order is captured by a notion of volume
asymptotics that we define. These ideas apply to complete pseudo-Riemannian
spaces, via the Levi-Civita connection, and thus provide a notion of
compactification alternative to conformal compactification. For each order
$\alpha$, we provide an asymptotic form of a metric which is sufficient for
projective compactness of the given order, thus also providing many local
examples.
  Distinguished classes of projectively compactified geometries of orders one
and two are associated with Ricci-flat connections and non--Ricci--flat
Einstein metrics, respectively. Conversely, these geometric conditions are
shown to force the indicated order of projective compactness. These special
compactifications are shown to correspond to normal solutions of classes of
natural linear PDE (so-called first BGG equations), or equivalently holonomy
reductions of projective Cartan/tractor connections. This enables the
application of tools already available to reveal considerable information about
the geometry of the boundary at infinity. Finally, we show that metrics
admitting such special compactifications always have an asymptotic form as
mentioned above.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.1382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.1382</id><created>2013-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author></authors><title>Newtonian Dynamics from the principle of Maximum Caliber</title><categories>physics.data-an cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics 44, 923-931 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-014-9819-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The foundations of Statistical Mechanics can be recovered almost in their
entirety from the Principle of Maximum Entropy. In this work we show that its
non-equilibrium generalization, the Principle of Maximum Caliber (Jaynes,
1980), when applied to the unknown trajectory followed by a particle, leads to
Newton's second law under two quite intuitive assumptions (the expected square
displacement in one step and the spatial probability distribution of the
particle are known at all times). Our derivation explicitly highlights the role
of mass as an emergent measure of the fluctuations in velocity (inertia) and
the origin of potential energy as a manifestation of spatial correlations.
According to our findings, the application of Newton's equations is not limited
to mechanical systems, and therefore could be used in modelling ecological,
financial and biological systems, among others.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7688</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7688</id><created>2014-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Fitting of interatomic potentials without forces: a parallel particle
  swarm optimization algorithm</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Comp. Phys. Comm. 185, 3090-3093 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2014.07.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a methodology for fitting interatomic potentials to ab initio
data, using the particle swarm optimization (PSO) algorithm, needing only a set
of positions and energies as input. The prediction error of energies associated
with the fitted parameters can be close to 1 meV/atom or lower, for reference
energies having a standard deviation of about 0.5 eV/atom. We tested our method
by fitting a Sutton-Chen potential for copper from \emph{ab initio} data, which
is able to recover structural and dynamical properties, and obtain a better
agreement of the predicted melting point versus the experimental value, as
compared to the prediction of the standard Sutton-Chen parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.3249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.3249</id><created>2014-04-11</created><updated>2015-09-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Hamiltonian formalism and path entropy maximization</title><categories>physics.data-an cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48, 425003 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/42/425003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Maximization of the path information entropy is a clear prescription for
constructing models in non-equilibrium statistical mechanics. Here it is shown
that, following this prescription under the assumption of arbitrary
instantaneous constraints on position and velocity, a Lagrangian emerges which
determines the most probable trajectory. Deviations from the probability
maximum can be consistently described as slices in time by a Hamiltonian,
according to a nonlinear Langevin equation and its associated Fokker-Planck
equation. The connections unveiled between the maximization of path entropy and
the Langevin/Fokker-Planck equations imply that missing information about the
phase space coordinate never decreases in time, a purely
information-theoretical version of the Second Law of Thermodynamics. All of
these results are independent of any physical assumptions, and thus valid for
any generalized coordinate as a function of time, or any other parameter. This
reinforces the view that the Second Law is a fundamental property of plausible
inference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3214</id><created>2014-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peralta</keyname><forenames>Joaqu&#xed;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navarrete</keyname><forenames>Yasm&#xed;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author></authors><title>A Bayesian interpretation of abrupt phase transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, Vol. 46, 3, pp 350-359 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-015-9967-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formalism used in describing the thermodynamics of abrupt (or
first-order) phase transitions is reviewed as an application of maximum entropy
inference. In this treatment, we show that the concepts of transition
temperature, latent heat and entropy difference between phases will inevitably
have an equivalent in any problem of inferring the result of a yes/no question,
given information in the form of expectation values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.4129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.4129</id><created>2014-06-16</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gnedin</keyname><forenames>Nickolay Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draine</keyname><forenames>Bruce T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Line Overlap and Self-Shielding of Molecular Hydrogen in Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Final version with a corrected large-scale fit</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/795/1/37</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of line overlap in the Lyman and Werner bands, often ignored in
galactic studies of the atomic-to-molecular transition, greatly enhances
molecular hydrogen self-shielding in low metallicity environments, and
dominates over dust shielding for metallicities below about 10% solar. We
implement that effect in cosmological hydrodynamics simulations with an
empirical model, calibrated against the observational data, and provide fitting
formulae for the molecular hydrogen fraction as a function of gas density on
various spatial scales and in environments with varied dust abundance and
interstellar radiation field. We find that line overlap, while important for
detailed radiative transfer in the Lyman and Werner bands, has only a minor
effect on star formation on galactic scales, which, to a much larger degree, is
regulated by stellar feedback.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.6702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.6702</id><created>2014-08-28</created><updated>2016-07-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pinto</keyname><forenames>Rafael S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saa</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchrony-optimized networks of Kuramoto oscillators with inertia</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures. Final version to appear in Physica A. Title and
  several parts of the text have changed, results and conclusions are
  unaltered. Some online material is available at
  http://vigo.ime.unicamp.br/PowerGrids/</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 463 (2016) 77-87</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.07.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate synchronization in networks of Kuramoto oscillators with
inertia. More specifically, we introduce a rewiring algorithm consisting
basically in a {\em hill climb} scheme in which the edges of the network are
swapped in order to enhance its synchronization capacity. We show that the the
synchrony-optimized networks generated by our algorithm have some interesting
topological and dynamical properties. In particular, they typically exhibit an
anticipation of the synchronization onset and are more robust against certain
types of perturbations. We consider synthetic random networks and also a
network with a topology based in an approximated model of the (high voltage)
power grid of Spain, since networks of Kuramoto oscillators with inertia have
been used recently as simplified models for power grids, for which
synchronization is obviously a crucial issue. Despite the extreme
simplifications adopted in these models, our results, among others recently
obtained in the literature, may provide interesting principles to guide the
future growth and development of real-world grids, specially in the case of a
change of the current paradigm of centralized towards distributed generation
power grids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.5826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.5826</id><created>2014-09-19</created><updated>2015-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brock</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belt</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billings</keyname><forenames>Jay Jay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit Integration with GPU Acceleration for Large Kinetic Networks</title><categories>physics.comp-ph astro-ph.SR cs.OH</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures, submitted to Journal of Computational Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Comp. Phys. 302, 591 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the first implementation of recently-developed fast explicit
kinetic integration algorithms on modern graphics processing unit (GPU)
accelerators. Taking as a generic test case a Type Ia supernova explosion with
an extremely stiff thermonuclear network having 150 isotopic species and 1604
reactions coupled to hydrodynamics using operator splitting, we demonstrate the
capability to solve of order 100 realistic kinetic networks in parallel in the
same time that standard implicit methods can solve a single such network on a
CPU. This orders-of-magnitude decrease in compute time for solving systems of
realistic kinetic networks implies that important coupled, multiphysics
problems in various scientific and technical fields that were intractible, or
could be simulated only with highly schematic kinetic networks, are now
computationally feasible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.1631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.1631</id><created>2014-12-04</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Rituparno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhuyan</keyname><forenames>Pranab Jyoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Madan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Chandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Active fluidization in dense glassy systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2016, 12, 6268 - 6276</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5SM02950C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dense soft glasses show strong collective caging behavior at sufficiently low
temperatures. Using molecular dynamics simulations of a model glass former, we
show that the incorporation of activity or self-propulsion, f0, can induce cage
breaking and fluidization, resulting in a disappearance of the glassy phase
beyond a critical f0 . The diffusion coefficient crosses over from being
strongly to weakly temperature dependent as f0 is increased. In addition, we
demonstrate that activity induces a crossover from a fragile to a strong glass
and a tendency for clustering of active particles. Our results are of direct
relevance to the collective dynamics of dense active colloidal glasses and to
recent experiments on tagged particle diffusion in living cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4969</id><created>2014-12-16</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mei&#xdf;ner</keyname><forenames>Ulf-G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xed;os</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusetsky</keyname><forenames>Akaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectrum of three-body bound states in a finite volume</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>An error in the calculation of the overlap integral in Eq. (11) is
  corrected. Our main result given in Eq. (26) remains the same, except the
  numerical value of the constant c, which changes approximately by 10%</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 114, 091602 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.114.091602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spectrum of a bound state of three identical particles with a mass $m$ in
a finite cubic box is studied. It is shown that in the unitary limit, the
energy shift of a shallow bound state is given by $\Delta E=c
(\kappa^2/m)\,(\kappa L)^{-3/2}|A|^2\exp(-2\kappa L/\sqrt{3})$, where $\kappa$
is the bound-state momentum, $L$ is the box size, $|A|^2$ denotes the
three-body analog of the asymptotic normalization coefficient of the bound
state wave function and $c$ is a numerical constant. The formula is valid for
$\kappa L\gg 1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00002</id><created>2014-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Chowdhury</keyname><forenames>Debanjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sachdev</keyname><forenames>Subir</forenames></author></authors><title>The enigma of the pseudogap phase of the cuprate superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>37 pages, 19 figures, 100+ references. Proceedings of the 50th
  Karpacz Winter School of Theoretical Physics, 2-9 March 2014, Karpacz, Poland</comments><doi>10.1142/9789814704090_0001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The last few years have seen significant experimental progress in
characterizing the copper-based hole-doped high temperature superconductors in
the regime of low hole density, p. Quantum oscillations, NMR, X-ray, and STM
experiments have shed much light on the nature of the ordering at low
temperatures. We review evidence that the order parameter in the
non-Lanthanum-based cuprates is a d-form factor density-wave. This novel order
acts as an unexpected window into the electronic structure of the pseudogap
phase at higher temperatures in zero field: we argue in favor of a
`fractionalized Fermi liquid' (FL*) with 4 pockets of spin S=1/2, charge +e
fermions enclosing an area specified by p.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.05943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.05943</id><created>2015-03-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ariwahjoedi</keyname><forenames>Seramika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosasih</keyname><forenames>Jusak Sali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovelli</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zen</keyname><forenames>Freddy P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Curvatures and discrete Gauss-Codazzi equation in (2+1)-dimensional loop
  quantum gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>IJGMMP 12: 1550112. (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887815501121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the Gauss-Codazzi equation in the holonomy and plane-angle
representations and we use the result to write a Gauss-Codazzi equation for a
discrete (2+1)-dimensional manifold, triangulated by isosceles tetrahedra. This
allows us to write operators acting on spin network states in (2+1)-dimensional
loop quantum gravity, representing the 3-dimensional intrinsic, 2-dimensional
intrinsic, and 2-dimensional extrinsic curvatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05417</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05417</id><created>2015-06-17</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duke</keyname><forenames>M. J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallin</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krauss</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mekarski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sibley</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A precise method to determine the activity of a weak neutron source
  using a germanium detector</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures, accepted manuscript</comments><journal-ref>Applied Radiation and Isotopes 116 (2016), pp. 51-56</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.apradiso.2016.06.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A standard high purity germanium (HPGe) detector was used to determine the
previously unknown neutron activity of a weak americium-beryllium (AmBe)
neutron source. Gamma rays were created through 27Al(n,n'), 27Al(n,gamma) and
1H(n,gamma) reactions induced by the neutrons on aluminum and acrylic disks,
respectively. These gamma rays were measured using the HPGe detector. Given the
unorthodox experimental arrangement, a Monte Carlo simulation was developed to
model the efficiency of the detector system to determine the neutron activity
from the measured gamma rays. The activity of our neutron source was determined
to be 307.4 +/- 5.0 n/s and is consistent for the different neutron-induced
gamma rays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07706</id><created>2015-06-25</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>John H.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Formulation of the Type IIB Superstring Action in $AdS_5 \times S^5$</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>40 pages; v3: extensive revision</comments><report-no>CALT-TH-2015-030</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous studies of the type IIB superstring in an ${AdS_5 \times S^5}$
background are based on a description of the superspace geometry as the
quotient space $PSU(2,2|4)/SO(4,1) \times SO(5)$. This paper develops an
alternative approach in which the Grassmann coordinates provide a nonlinear
realization of $PSU(2,2|4)$ based on the quotient space $PSU(2,2|4)/SU(2,2)
\times SU(4)$, and the bosonic coordinates are described as a submanifold of
$SU(2,2) \times SU(4)$. This formulation keeps all bosonic symmetries manifest,
and it provides the complete dependence on the Grassmann coordinates in terms
of simple analytic expressions. It is used to construct the superstring
world-sheet action in a form in which the $PSU(2,2|4)$ symmetry is manifest and
kappa symmetry can be established. This formulation might have some advantages
compared to previous ones, but this remains to be demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08778</id><created>2015-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Acharyya</keyname><forenames>Muktish</forenames></author></authors><title>Exit probability and first passage time of a lazy Pearson walker:
  Scaling behaviour</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 Pages Latex with 4 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1506.00096</comments><report-no>Phys-PU-7-15</report-no><journal-ref>Applied Mathematics 7 (2016) 1353</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/am.2016.712119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The motion of a lazy Pearson walker is studied with different probability
($p$) of jump in two and three dimensions. The probability of exit ($P_e$) from
a zone of radius $r_e$, is studied as a function of $r_e$ with different values
of jump probability $p$. The exit probability $P_e$ is found to scale as
${P_e}p^{\alpha}=F({r_e}p^{\beta})$, which is obtained by method of data
collapse. The first passage time ($t_1$) i.e., the time required for first exit
from a zone is studied. The probability distribution ($P(t_1)$) of first
passage time was studied for different values of jump probability ($p$). The
probability distribution of first passage time was found to scale as
${P(t_1)}p^{\gamma} = G({t_1}p^{\delta})$. Where, $F$ and $G$ are two scaling
functions and $\alpha$, $\beta$, $\gamma$ and $\delta$ are some exponents. In
both the dimensions, it is found that, $\alpha = 0$, $\beta=-1/2$, $\gamma=-1$
and $\delta=1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01819</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tessore</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metcalf</keyname><forenames>R. Benton</forenames></author></authors><title>The elliptical power law profile lens</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, accepted by A&amp;A; v2 corrects a typo in Eq. (17)
  and Fig. (2); sample code at https://github.com/ntessore/elliptical-power-law</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 580, A79 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526773</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deflection, potential, shear and magnification of a gravitational lens
following an elliptical power law mass model are investigated. This mass model
is derived from the circular power law profile through a rescaling of the axes,
similar to the case of a singular isothermal ellipsoid. The resulting
deflection can be calculated explicitly and given in terms of the Gaussian
hypergeometric function. Analytic expressions for the remaining lensing
properties are found as well. Because the power law profile lens contains a
number of well-known lens models as special cases, the equivalence of the new
expressions with known results is checked. Finally, it is shown how these
results naturally lead to a fast and accurate numerical scheme for computing
the deflection and other lens quantities, making this method a useful tool for
realistically modelling observed lenses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07745</id><created>2015-07-28</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oreshkov</keyname><forenames>Ognyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerf</keyname><forenames>Nicolas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Operational formulation of time reversal in quantum theory</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Phys. 11, 853-858 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The symmetry of quantum theory under time reversal has long been a subject of
controversy because the transition probabilities given by Born's rule do not
apply backward in time. Here, we resolve this problem within a rigorous
operational probabilistic framework. We argue that reconciling time reversal
with the probabilistic rules of the theory requires a notion of operation that
permits realizations via both pre- and post-selection. We develop the
generalized formulation of quantum theory that stems from this approach and
give a precise definition of time-reversal symmetry, emphasizing a previously
overlooked distinction between states and effects. We prove an analogue of
Wigner's theorem, which characterizes all allowed symmetry transformations in
this operationally time-symmetric quantum theory. Remarkably, we find larger
classes of symmetry transformations than those assumed before. This suggests a
possible direction for search of extensions of known physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03584</id><created>2015-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Lian-Ao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guidry</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author></authors><title>The Ground State of Monolayer Graphene in a Strong Magnetic Field</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 22423 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep22423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene SU(4) quantum Hall symmetry is extended to SO(8), permitting
analytical solutions for graphene in a magnetic field that break SU(4)
spontaneously. We recover standard graphene SU(4) physics as one limit, but
find new phases and new properties that may be relevant for understanding the
ground state. The graphene SO(8) symmetry is found to be isomorphic to one that
occurs extensively in nuclear structure physics, and very similar to one that
describes high-temperature superconductors, suggesting deep mathematical
connections among these physically-different fermionic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05339</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05339</id><created>2015-08-21</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magan</keyname><forenames>Javier M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Random free fermions: An analytical example of eigenstate thermalization</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 030401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.030401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Having analytical instances of the Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis (ETH)
is of obvious interest, both for fundamental and applied reasons. This is
generically a hard task, due to the belief that non-linear interactions are
basic ingredients of the thermalization mechanism. In this article we proof
that random gaussian free fermions satisfy ETH in the multiparticle sector, by
analytically computing the correlations and entanglement entropies of the
theory. With the explicit construction at hand, we finally comment on the
differences between fully random Hamiltonians and random Gaussian systems, and
on the connection between chaotic energy spectra and ETH.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02757</id><created>2015-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruiz-Perez</keyname><forenames>Lorena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messager</keyname><forenames>Lea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaitzsch</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joseph</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutto</keyname><forenames>Ludovico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gervasio</keyname><forenames>Francesco Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Polymersomes confined self-assembly: micellisation in 2D</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 Figures plus supporting information</comments><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1500948</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biological systems exploit self-assembly to create complex structures whose
arrangements are finely controlled from molecular to mesoscopic level. Herein
we report an example of using fully synthetic systems that mimic two levels of
self-assembly. We show the formation of vesicles using amphiphilic copolymers
whose chemical nature is chosen to control both membrane formation and
membrane-confined interactions. We report polymersomes with patterns that
emerge by engineering interfacial tension within the polymersome surface. This
allows the formation of domains whose topology is tailored by the chemical
synthesis paving the avenue to complex supramolecular designs functionally
similar to those found in viruses and trafficking vesicles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00548</id><created>2015-10-02</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spourdalakis</keyname><forenames>A. G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pappas</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalozoumis</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diakonos</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelcher</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-local Lagrangians: a variational approach to non-local conservation
  laws for wave mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>The paper has been withdrawn due to incomplete formalism. A new
  version can be found in arXiv:1607.06730</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a class of non-local Lagrangians which allow for the variational
derivation of non-local conser- vation laws in a self-consistent manner. The
formalism developed here generalizes previous approaches, used in the context
of $\mathcal{PT}$ symmetric quantum mechanics and optics in the paraxial
approximation in a twofold way: firstly it is valid for a larger set of linear
symmetry transforms and secondly it enables the derivation of additional
non-local conservation laws for general higher dimensional wave mechanical
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03072</id><created>2015-10-11</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of t t-bar production with additional jet activity,
  including b quark jets, in the dilepton channel using pp collisions at
  sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/TOP-12-041/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-TOP-12-041, CERN-PH-EP-2015-240</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 379</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4105-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Jet multiplicity distributions in top quark pair (t t-bar) events are
measured in pp collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV with the CMS
detector at the LHC using a data set corresponding to an integrated luminosity
of 19.7 inverse femtobarns. The measurement is performed in the dilepton decay
channels (e+ e-, mu+ mu-, and e+/- mu-/+). The absolute and normalized
differential cross sections for t t-bar production are measured as a function
of the jet multiplicity in the event for different jet transverse momentum
thresholds and the kinematic properties of the leading additional jets. The
differential t t-bar b and t t-bar b b-bar cross sections are presented for the
first time as a function of the kinematic properties of the leading additional
b jets. Furthermore, the fraction of events without additional jets above a
threshold is measured as a function of the transverse momenta of the leading
additional jets and the scalar sum of the transverse momenta of all additional
jets. The data are compared and found to be consistent with predictions from
several perturbative quantum chromodynamics event generators and a
next-to-leading order calculation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00042</id><created>2015-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Esmaielpour</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Whiteside</keyname><forenames>V. R.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vijeyaragunathan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mishima</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cairns</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>School of Chemical, Biological and Materials Engineering, Sarkey's Energy Center, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sellers</keyname><forenames>I. R.</forenames><affiliation>Homer L. Dodge, Department of Physics &amp; Astronomy, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Suppression of phonon-mediated hot carrier relaxation in type-II
  InAs/AlAs$_{x}$Sb$_{1-x}$ quantum wells: a practical route to hot carrier
  solar cells</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, submitted to &quot;Progress in Photovoltaics: Research
  and Applications&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications 24 (2016)
  591-599</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pip.2763</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  InAs/AlAs$_{x}$Sb$_{1-x}$ quantum wells are investigated for their potential
as hot carrier solar cells. Continuous wave power and temperature dependent
photoluminescence indicate a transition in the dominant hot carrier relaxation
process from conventional phonon-mediated carrier relaxation below 90 K to a
regime where inhibited radiative recombination dominates the hot carrier
relaxation at elevated temperatures. At temperatures below 90 K
photoluminescence measurements are consistent with type-I quantum wells that
exhibit hole localization associated with alloy/interface fluctuations. At
elevated temperatures hole delocalization reveals the true type-II band
alignment; where it is observed that inhibited radiative recombination due to
the spatial separation of the charge carriers dominates hot carrier relaxation.
This decoupling of phonon-mediated relaxation results in robust hot carriers at
higher temperatures even at lower excitation powers. These results indicate
type-II quantum wells offer potential as practical hot carrier systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00768</id><created>2015-12-02</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#x10c;ernot&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerer</keyname><forenames>Klemens</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement-Induced Long-Distance Entanglement of Superconducting Qubits
  using Optomechanical Transducers</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Updated figures, close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012340 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012340</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although superconducting systems provide a promising platform for quantum
computing, their networking poses a challenge as they cannot be interfaced to
light---the medium used to send quantum signals through channels at room
temperature. We show that mechanical oscillators can mediated such coupling and
light can be used to measure the joint state of two distant qubits. The
measurement provides information on the total spin of the two qubits such that
entangled qubit states can be postselected. Entanglement generation is possible
without ground-state cooling of the mechanical oscillators for systems with
optomechanical cooperativity moderately larger than unity; in addition, our
setup tolerates a substantial transmission loss. The approach is scalable to
generation of multipartite entanglement and represents a crucial step towards
quantum networks with superconducting circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01667</id><created>2015-12-05</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maurya</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T.</keyname><forenames>Smitha T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Farook</forenames></author></authors><title>A new exact solution for anisotropic compact stars of embedding class
  one</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures and 3 tables in European physical Journal A -
  2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have presented a new anisotropic solution of Einstein's field equations
for compact star models. The Einstein's field equations are solved by using the
class one condition \cite{1}. After that we constructed the physically valid
expression of anisotropy factor by the help of metric potentials and there
after we obtained the physical parameters like energy density, radial and
transverse pressure. These models parameters are well behaved inside the
compact star and satisfy all the required physical conditions. Also we observed
a very interesting result that all the physical parameters are depend on the
anisotropy factor. The present compact star models are quite compatible with
the observational astrophysical compact stellar objects like Her X-1, RXJ
1856-37, SAX J1808.4-3658(SS1), SAX J1808.4-3658(SS2)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01935</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Xiaobo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Hongbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Peixiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly-sensitive detection of the lattice distortion in single bent ZnO
  nanowires by second-harmonic generation microscopy</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.6b00286</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanogenerators based on ZnO nanowires (NWs) realize the energy conversion at
nanoscale, which are ascribed to the piezoelectric property caused by the
lattice distortion of the ZnO NWs. The lattice distortion can significantly
tune the electronic and optical properties, and requires a sensitive and
convenient measurement. However, high-resolution transmission electron
microscopy (HRTEM) technique provides a limited sensitivity of 0.01 nm on the
variation of the lattice spacing and requires vacuum conditions. Here we
demonstrate a highly-sensitive detection of the lattice distortion in single
bent ZnO NWs by second-harmonic generation (SHG) microscopy. As the curvature
of the single bent ZnO NW increases to 21 mm-1 (&lt;4% bending distortion), it
shows a significant decrease (~70%) in the SHG intensity ratio between
perpendicular and parallel excitation polarization with respect to c-axis of
ZnO NWs. Importantly, the extraordinary non-axisymmetrical SHG polarimetric
patterns are also observed, indicating the twisting distortion around c-axis of
ZnO NWs. Thus, SHG microscopy provides a sensitive all-optical and non-invasive
method for in situ detecting the lattice distortion under various
circumstances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04803</id><created>2015-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Paulisch</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kimble</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Tudela</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Quantum Computation in Waveguide QED using Decoherence Free
  Subspaces</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 043041</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/4/043041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction of quantum emitters with one-dimensional photon-like
reservoirs induces strong and long-range dissipative couplings that give rise
to the emergence of so-called Decoherence Free Subspaces (DFS) which are
decoupled from dissipation. When introducing weak perturbations on the
emitters, e.g., driving, the strong collective dissipation enforces an
effective coherent evolution within the DFS. In this work, we show explicitly
how by introducing single-site resolved drivings, we can use the effective
dynamics within the DFS to design a universal set of one and two-qubit gates
within the DFS of two-level atom-like systems. Using Liouvillian perturbation
theory we calculate the scaling with the relevant figures of merit of the
systems, such as the Purcell Factor and imperfect control of the drivings.
Finally, we compare our results with previous proposals using atomic $\Lambda$
systems in leaky cavities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04855</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chengcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nojiri</keyname><forenames>Mihoko M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Myeonghun</forenames></author></authors><title>Apparent unitarity violation in top quark's mass off-shell region from a
  new physics at high energy colliders</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Version accepted for publication in PLB</comments><report-no>CTPU-15-24, IPMU15-0209, KEK-TH-1882</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Perturbative unitarity conditions have been playing an important role by
estimating the energy scale of new physics, including the Higgs mass as one of
the most important examples. In this letter, we show that there is a
possibility to see the hint of a new physics (top quark partner) indirectly by
observing an &quot;apparent&quot; unitarity violation in $M_{bw}$ distribution well above
top quark mass in a process of a heavy resonance decaying into a pair of top
quarks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00963</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chevalier</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hines</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying System-Wide Early Warning Signs of Instability in Stochastic
  Power Systems</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Prior research has shown that spectral decomposition of the reduced power
flow Jacobian (RPFJ) can yield participation factors that describe the extent
to which particular buses contribute to particular spectral components of a
power system. Research has also shown that both variance and autocorrelation of
time series voltage data tend to increase as a power system with stochastically
fluctuating loads approaches certain critical transitions. This paper presents
evidence suggesting that a system's participation factors predict the relative
bus voltage variance values for all nodes in a system. As a result, these
participation factors can be used to filter, weight, and combine real time PMU
data from various locations dispersed throughout a power network in order to
develop coherent measures of global voltage stability. This paper first
describes the method of computing the participation factors. Next, two
potential uses of the participation factors are given: (1) predicting the
relative bus voltage variance magnitudes, and (2) locating generators at which
the autocorrelation of voltage measurements clearly indicate proximity to
critical transitions. The methods are tested using both analytical and
numerical results from a dynamic model of a 2383-bus test case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02910</id><created>2016-01-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todoroki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zha</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Muon Identification with Muon Telescope Detector at the STAR Experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.07.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Muon Telescope Detector (MTD) is a newly installed detector in the STAR
experiment. It provides an excellent opportunity to study heavy quarkonium
physics using the dimuon channel in heavy ion collisions. In this paper, we
report the muon identification performance for the MTD using proton-proton
collision at $\sqrt{s}$ = 500 GeV with various methods. The result using the
Likelihood Ratio method shows that the muon identification efficiency can reach
to $\sim$90% for muons with transverse momentum greater than 3 GeV/c and the
significance of J/$\psi$ signal is improved by $\sim$40% compared to using the
basic selection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03446</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Subias</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author></authors><title>B-splines as a Tool to Solve Constraints in Non-Hydrostatic Forecast
  Model</title><categories>physics.ao-ph math.NA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Finite elements has been proven to be an useful tool to discretize the
vertical coordinate in the hydrostatic forecast models allowing to define model
variables in full levels so that no staggering is needed. In the
non-hydrostatic case a constraint in the vertical operators appears (called C1)
that does not allow to reduce the set of semi-implicit linear equations to a
single equation in one variable as in the analytic case. Recently vertical
finite elements based in B-splines have been used with an iterative method to
relax the C1 constraint. In this paper we want to develop properly some
representations of vertical operators in terms of B-splines in order to keep
the C1-constraint. An invertibility relation between integral and derivative
operators between vertical velocity and vertical divergence is also presented.
The final scope of this paper is to provide a theoretical framework of
development of finite element vertical operators to be implemented in the
ALADIN-HIRLAM nwp system
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01917</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferguson</keyname><forenames>Kate R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beavan</keyname><forenames>Sarah E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longdell</keyname><forenames>Jevon J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sellars</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of light with multimode time-delayed entanglement using
  storage in a solid state spin-wave quantum memory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 020501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.020501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we demonstrate generating and storing entanglement in a solid state
spin-wave quantum memory with on-demand read out using the process of rephased
amplified spontaneous emission (RASE). Amplified spontaneous emission (ASE),
resulting from an inverted ensemble of Pr$^{3+}$ ions doped into a Y$_2$SiO$_5$
crystal, generates entanglement between collective states of the praseodymium
ensemble and the output light. The ensemble is then rephased using a four-level
photon echo technique. Entanglement between the ASE and its echo is confirmed
and the inseparability violation preserved when the RASE is stored as a
spin-wave for up to 5 $\mu$s. RASE is shown to be temporally multimode with
almost perfect distinguishability between two temporal modes demonstrated.
These results pave the way for the use of multimode solid state quantum
memories in scalable quantum networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02820</id><created>2016-02-08</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yonaga</keyname><forenames>Kouki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasebe</keyname><forenames>Kazuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>Naokazu</forenames></author></authors><title>Formulation of the Relativistic Quantum Hall Effect and &quot;Parity Anomaly&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>We have corrected the typographic errors in our article. There are
  three corrections: (1)2g -&gt; 2j in Fig.3 (2)2g -&gt; 2j in the caption of Fig.3
  (3)2g=12 -&gt; 2j = 64 in the caption of Fig.5</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235122 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a relativistic formulation of the quantum Hall effect on Haldane
sphere. An explicit form of the pseudopotential is derived for the relativistic
quantum Hall effect with/without mass term. We clarify particular features of
the relativistic quantum Hall states with the use of the exact diagonalization
study of the pseudopotential Hamiltonian. Physical effects of the mass term to
the relativistic quantum Hall states are investigated in detail. The mass term
acts as an interpolating parameter between the relativistic and
non-relativistic quantum Hall effects. It is pointed out that the mass term
unevenly affects the many-body physics of the positive and negative Landau
levels as a manifestation of the &quot;parity anomaly&quot;. In particular, we explicitly
demonstrate the instability of the Laughlin state of the positive first
relativistic Landau level with the reduction of the charge gap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03060</id><created>2016-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Liouville's Theorem from the Principle of Maximum Caliber in Phase Space</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1757, 020003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4959044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the cornerstones in non--equilibrium statistical mechanics (NESM) is
Liouville's theorem, a differential equation for the phase space probability
$\rho(q,p; t)$. This is usually derived considering the flow in or out of a
given surface for a physical system (composed of atoms), via more or less
heuristic arguments.
  In this work, we derive the Liouville equation as the partial differential
equation governing the dynamics of the time-dependent probability $\rho(q, p;
t)$ of finding a &quot;particle&quot; with Lagrangian $L(q, \dot{q}; t)$ in a specific
point $(q, p)$ in phase space at time $t$, with $p=\partial L/\partial
\dot{q}$. This derivation depends only on considerations of inference over a
space of continuous paths. Because of its generality, our result is valid not
only for &quot;physical&quot; systems but for any model depending on constrained
information about position and velocity, such as time series.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06248</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arrazola</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedernales</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamata</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Digital-Analog Quantum Simulation of Spin Models in Trapped Ions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 30534 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30534</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to simulate spin models in trapped ions using a
digital-analog approach, consisting in a suitable gate decomposition in terms
of analog blocks and digital steps. In this way, we show that the quantum
dynamics of an enhanced variety of spin models could be implemented with
substantially less number of gates than a fully digital approach. Typically,
analog blocks are built of multipartite dynamics providing the complexity of
the simulated model, while the digital steps are local operations bringing
versatility to it. Finally, we describe a possible experimental implementation
in trapped-ion technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08690</id><created>2016-02-28</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Divari</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergados</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino oscillations in the presence of super-light sterile neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 12 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1308.2823, arXiv:1403.2559 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>Int. Journal of Modern Physics A, Vol.31, 1650123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501232</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the effect of conversion of super-light sterile
neutrino (SLSN) to electron neutrino in matter like that of the Earth. In the
Sun the resonance conversion between SLSN and electron neutrino via the neutral
current is suppressed due to the smallness of neutron number. On the other
hand, neutron number density can play an important role in the Earth, making
the scenario of SLSN quite interesting. The effect of CP-violating phases on
active-SLSN oscillations is also discussed. Reactor neutrino experiments with
medium or short baseline may probe the scenario of SLSN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08762</id><created>2016-02-28</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for heavy resonances decaying to two Higgs bosons in final states
  containing four b quarks</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/EXO-12-053/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-EXO-12-053, CERN-EP-2016-041</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 371</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4206-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is presented for narrow heavy resonances X decaying into pairs of
Higgs bosons (H) in proton-proton collisions collected by the CMS experiment at
the LHC at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV. The data correspond to an integrated luminosity of
19.7 inverse femtobarns. The search considers HH resonances with masses between
1 and 3 TeV, having final states of two b quark pairs. Each Higgs boson is
produced with large momentum, and the hadronization products of the pair of b
quarks can usually be reconstructed as single large jets. The background from
multijet and t t-bar events is significantly reduced by applying requirements
related to the flavor of the jet, its mass, and its substructure. The signal
would be identified as a peak on top of the dijet invariant mass spectrum of
the remaining background events. No evidence is observed for such a signal.
Upper limits obtained at 95% confidence level for the product of the production
cross section and branching fraction sigma(gg to X) B(X to HH to b b-bar b
b-bar) range from 10 to 1.5 fb for the mass of X from 1.15 to 2.0 TeV,
significantly extending previous searches. For a warped extra dimension theory
with a mass scale Lambda[R] = 1 TeV, the data exclude radion scalar masses
between 1.15 and 1.55 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00509</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Havvaei</keyname><forenames>Elham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deo</keyname><forenames>Narsingh</forenames></author></authors><title>A Game-Theoretic Approach for Detection of Overlapping Communities in
  Dynamic Complex Networks</title><categories>cs.GT cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>The paper has been withdrawn from arxiv since it's under improvements</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex networks tend to display communities which are groups of nodes
cohesively connected among themselves in one group and sparsely connected to
the remainder of the network. Detecting such communities is an important
computational problem, since it provides an insight into the functionality of
networks. Further, investigating community structure in a dynamic network,
where the network is subject to change, is even more challenging. This paper
presents a game-theoretical technique for detecting community structures in
dynamic as well as static complex networks. In our method, each node takes the
role of a player that attempts to gain a higher payoff by joining one or more
communities or switching between them. The goal of the game is to reveal
community structure formed by these players by finding a Nash-equilibrium point
among them. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first game-theoretic
algorithm which is able to extract overlapping communities from either static
or dynamic networks. We present the experimental results illustrating the
effectiveness of the proposed method on both synthetic and real-world networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01021</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2016-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chaokai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yangwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ziqiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Langsheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Mingliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiong-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in topologically nontrivial material Au2Pb</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>npj Quantum Materials 1, Article number: 16005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/npjquantmats.2016.5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The search for nontrivial superconductivity in novel quantum materials is
currently a most attractive topic in condensed matter physics and material
science. The experimental studies have progressed quickly over the past couple
of years. In this article, we report systematic studies of superconductivity in
Au2Pb single crystals. The bulk superconductivity (onset transition
temperature, Tconset= 1.3 K) of Au2Pb is characterized by both transport and
diamagnetic measurements, where the upper critical field Hc2 shows unusual
quasi-linear temperature dependence. The superconducting gap is revealed by
point contact measurement with gold tip. However, when using tungsten (W) tip,
which is much harder, the superconducting gap probed is largely enhanced as
demonstrated by the increases of both Tconset and upper critical field (Hc2).
This can be interpreted as a result of increase in density of states under
external anisotropic stress imposed by the tip, as revealed by first-principles
calculations. Furthermore, novel phase winding of the pseudospin texture along
k-space loops around the Fermi energy is uncovered from the calculations,
indicating that the observed superconductivity in Au2Pb may have nontrivial
topology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01526</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bari&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Osor S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokalj</keyname><forenames>Jure</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balog</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prelov&#x161;ek</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical conductivity and its fluctuations along the crossover to
  many-body localization</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a numerical study of the many-body localization (MBL) phenomenon
in the high-temperature limit within an anisotropic Heisenberg model with
random local fields. Taking the dynamical spin conductivity $\sigma(\omega)$ as
the test quantity, we investigate the full frequency dependence of
sample-to-sample fluctuations and their scaling properties as a function of the
system size $L\leq 28$ and the frequency resolution. We identify differences
between the general interacting case $\Delta&gt;0$ and the anisotropy $\Delta=0$,
the latter corresponding to the standard Anderson localization. Except for the
extreme MBL case when the relative sample-to-sample fluctuations became large,
numerical results allow for the extraction of the low-$\omega$ dependence of
the conductivity. Results for the d.c. value $\sigma_0$ indicate a crossover
into the MBL regime, i.e. an exponential-like variation with the disorder
strength $W$. For the same regime, our numerical analysis indicates that the
low-frequency exponent $\alpha$ exhibits a small departure from $\alpha\sim 1$
only.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02683</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gingras</keyname><forenames>Michel J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin slush in an extended spin ice model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages + 7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12234 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12234</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new classical spin liquid on the pyrochlore lattice by
extending spin ice with further neighbour interactions. We find that this
disorder free spin model exhibits a form of dynamical heterogeneity with
extremely slow relaxation for some spins while others fluctuate quickly down to
zero temperature. We thus call this state &quot;spin slush&quot;, in analogy to the
heterogeneous mixture of solid and liquid water. This behaviour is driven by
the structure of the ground state manifold which extends the celebrated the
two-in/two-out ice states to include branching structures built from
three-in/one-out, three-out/one-in and all-in/all-out tetrahedra defects.
Distinctive liquid-like patterns in the spin correlations serve as a signature
of this intermediate range order. Possible applications to materials as well
the effects of quantum tunneling are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03010</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Badank&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hal&#xe1;sz</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vib&#xf3;k</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;.</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular vibrational trapping revisited: a case study with D2+</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>accepted in Scientific Report</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article presents a detailed study of the photodissociation probability
of D_{2}^{+} for a wide range of photon energy. One dimensional numerical
calculations have been performed to provide the best possible physical
quantities that characterize the vibrational trapping or bond hardening effect
during the photodissociation dynamics. These results undoubtedly show that the
nodes of the nuclear vibrational wave packets play a decisive role in the
vibrational trapping, in addition to the current understating of this
phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03680</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>En-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Chul-Sung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Heon-Young</forenames></author></authors><title>Classifying Gamma-Ray Bursts with Gaussian Mixture Model</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to a crucial error on
  the method of resampling analysis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) and Expectation Maximization Algorithm, we
perform an analysis of time duration ($T_{90}$) for \textit{CGRO}/BATSE,
\textit{Swift}/BAT and \textit{Fermi}/GBM Gamma-Ray Bursts. The $T_{90}$
distributions of 298 redshift-known \textit{Swift}/BAT GRBs have also been
studied in both observer and rest frames. Bayesian Information Criterion has
been used to compare between different GMM models. We find that two Gaussian
components are better to describe the \textit{CGRO}/BATSE and
\textit{Fermi}/GBM GRBs in the observer frame. Also, we caution that two groups
are expected for the \textit{Swift}/BAT bursts in the rest frame, which is
consistent with some previous results. However, \textit{Swift} GRBs in the
observer frame seem to show a trimodal distribution, of which the superficial
intermediate class may result from the selection effect of \textit{Swift}/BAT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09424</id><created>2016-03-30</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Concha</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durka</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inostroza</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merino</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>E. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pure Lovelock gravity and Chern-Simons theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages; V4: published version</comments><report-no>UAI-PHY-16/04</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 024055 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the possibility of finding Pure Lovelock gravity as a particular
limit of a Chern-Simons action for a specific expansion of the AdS algebra in
odd dimensions. We derive this relation at the level of the action in five and
seven dimensions. Additionally we provide the general result for higher
dimensions and discuss some issues arising from the obtained dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09452</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>Jose Amaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bueno</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furtado</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Dimensional Quantum ring in a Graphene Layer in the presence of a
  Aharonov-Bohm flux</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>21 pages, no figure, revised version, Annals of Physics (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 373, 273 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.07.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the relativistic quantum dynamics of a massless
fermion confined in a quantum ring. We use a model of confining potential and
introduce the interaction via Dirac oscillator coupling, which provides ring
confinement for massless Dirac fermions. We obtain the energy levels and
corresponding eigenfuctions for this model in graphene layer in the presence of
Aharonov-Bohm flux in the centre of the ring and the expression for persistent
current in this model. We also investigate the model for quantum ring in
graphene layer in the presence of disclination and magnetic flux. The energy
spectrum and wave function are obtained exactly for this case. We see that the
persistent current depends in parameters characterizing the topological defect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03353</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Islamov</keyname><forenames>Damir R.</forenames><affiliation>ISP SB RAS, NSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gritsenko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames><affiliation>ISP SB RAS, NSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Perevalov</keyname><forenames>Timofey V.</forenames><affiliation>ISP SB RAS, NSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Orlov</keyname><forenames>Oleg M.</forenames><affiliation>JSC MERI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Krasnikov</keyname><forenames>Gennady Ya.</forenames><affiliation>JSC MERI</affiliation></author></authors><title>The charge transport mechanism and electron trap nature in thermal oxide
  on silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109 (2016) 052901</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4960156</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The charge transport mechanism of electron via traps in amorphous SiO$_2$ has
been studied. Electron transport is limited by phonon-assisted tunneling
between traps. Thermal and optical trap energies $W_\mathrm{t}=1.6$ eV,
$W_\mathrm{opt}=3.2$ eV, respectively, were determined. Charge flowing leads to
oxygen vacancies generation, and the leakage current increases due to the
increase of charge trap density. Long-time annealing at high temperatures
decreased the leakage current to initial values due to oxygen vacancies
recombination with interstitial oxygen. It is found that the oxygen vacancies
act as electron traps in SiO$_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03822</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03822</id><created>2016-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Sunanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Li-Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Yawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berardan</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of ionized impurity scattering on the thermoelectric
  performances of rock salt AgPbmSnSe2+m</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, accepted in Advanced Functional Materials</comments><journal-ref>Advanced Functional Materials 26, 5149 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adfm.201600623</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the successful synthesis and on the properties of
polycrystalline AgPbmSnSe2+m (m = ++++, 100, 50, 25) samples with a rock salt
structure. Between 160 K and 400 K, the dominant scattering process of the
carriers in this system changes from acoustic phonon scattering in PbSe to
ionized impurity scattering in AgPbmSnSe2+m, which synergistically optimizes
electrical and thermal transport properties. Thanks to the faint amount of
AgSnSe2, the Seebeck coefficient is enhanced by boosting the scattering factor,
the electric conductivity is improved by the increase of the concentration of
holes coupled to a limited degradation of their mobility, and the total thermal
conductivity is reduced by suppressing bipolar thermal conductivity. Therefore,
ZT of AgPbmSnSe2+m (m = 50) reaches 1.3 at 889 K. The mechanism suggested in
this study opens new paths to improve the thermoelectric performances of other
families of materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05916</id><created>2016-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kojima</keyname><forenames>Shoya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasu</keyname><forenames>Joji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koga</keyname><forenames>Akihisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions in the Hubbard model for the bismuth nickelate</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study low temperature properties of the Hubbard model for the bismuth
nickelate, where degenerate orbitals in the nickel ions and a single orbital in
the bismuth ions are taken into account, combining dynamical mean-field theory
with the continuous-time quantum Monte Carlo method. We discuss the effect of
the attractive interactions to mimic the valence skipping phenomenon in the
bismuth ions. We demonstrate how the charge and magnetically ordered states are
stable against thermal fluctuations. It is furthermore clarified that the
ferromagnetically ordered and orbital ordered states are stabilized due to the
presence of the orbital degeneracy at low temperatures. The crossover between
metallic and insulating states is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07246</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cherroret</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delande</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Tiggelen</keyname><forenames>Bart A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Induced dipole-dipole interactions in light diffusion from point dipoles</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>revised version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a perturbative treatment of induced dipole-dipole interactions in
the diffusive transport of electromagnetic waves through disordered atomic
clouds. The approach is exact at order two in the atomic density and accounts
for the vector character of light. It is applied to the calculation of the
electromagnetic energy stored in the atomic cloud - which modifies the energy
transport velocity - and of the light scattering and transport mean free paths.
Results are compared to those obtained from a purely scalar model for light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07372</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tikhonov</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shovkun</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ercolani</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossella</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rocci</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roddaro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khrapai</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Local noise in a diffusive conductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>minor revision, accepted in Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 30621 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30621</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The control and measurement of local non-equilibrium configurations is of
utmost importance in applications on energy harvesting, thermoelectrics and
heat management in nano-electronics. This challenging task can be achieved with
the help of various local probes, prominent examples including superconducting
or quantum dot based tunnel junctions, classical and quantum resistors, and
Raman thermography. Beyond time-averaged properties, valuable information can
also be gained from spontaneous fluctuations of current (noise). From these
perspective, however, a fundamental constraint is set by current conservation,
which makes noise a characteristic of the whole conductor, rather than some
part of it. Here we demonstrate how to remove this obstacle and pick up a local
noise temperature of a current biased diffusive conductor with the help of a
miniature noise probe. This approach is virtually noninvasive and extends
primary local measurements towards strongly non-equilibrium regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07544</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghiglieri</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaczmarek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice constraints on the thermal photon rate</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages. v2: clarifications added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 016005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.016005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We estimate the photon production rate from an SU(3) plasma at temperatures
of about 1.1Tc and 1.3Tc. Lattice results for the vector current correlator at
spatial momenta k ~ (2-6)T are extrapolated to the continuum limit and analyzed
with the help of a polynomial interpolation for the corresponding spectral
function, which vanishes at zero frequency and matches to high-precision
perturbative results at large invariant masses. For small invariant masses the
interpolation is compared with the NLO weak-coupling result, hydrodynamics, and
a holographic model. At vanishing invariant mass we extract the photon rate
which for k \gsim 3T is found to be close to the NLO weak-coupling prediction.
For k \lsim 2T uncertainties remain large but the photon rate is likely to fall
below the NLO prediction, in accordance with the onset of a strongly
interacting behaviour characteristic of the hydrodynamic regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08205</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sparre</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springel</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author></authors><title>Zooming in on major mergers: dense, starbursting gas in cosmological
  simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1793</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the `Illustris zoom simulation project', which allows the study
of selected galaxies forming in the $\Lambda$CDM cosmology with a 40 times
better mass resolution than in the parent large-scale hydrodynamical Illustris
simulation. We here focus on the starburst properties of the gas in four
cosmological simulations of major mergers. The galaxies in our high-resolution
zoom runs exhibit a bursty mode of star formation with gas consumption
timescales 10 times shorter than for the normal star formation mode. The strong
bursts are only present in the simulations with the highest resolution, hinting
that a too low resolution is the reason why the original Illustris simulation
showed a dearth of starburst galaxies. Very pronounced bursts of star formation
occur in two out of four major mergers we study. The high star formation rates,
the short gas consumption timescales and the morphology of these systems
strongly resemble observed nuclear starbursts. This is the first time that a
sample of major mergers is studied through self-consistent cosmological
hydrodynamical simulations instead of using isolated galaxy models setup on a
collision course. We also study the orbits of the colliding galaxies and find
that the starbursting gas preferentially appears in head-on mergers with very
high collision velocities. Encounters with large impact parameters do typically
not lead to the formation of starbursting gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08238</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Repond</keyname><forenames>Jo&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>Combined Preheating on the lattice with applications to Higgs inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 30 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/07/043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use classical lattice simulations in 3+1 dimensions to study the interplay
between the resonant production of particles during preheating and the
subsequent decay of these into a set of secondary species. We choose to work in
a simplified version of Higgs inflation in which the Higgs field non-minimally
coupled to gravity plays the role of the inflaton. Our numerical results extend
the analytical estimates in the literature beyond the linear regime and shed
some light on the limitations of the analytical techniques. The inclusion of
fast and inefficient decays postpones the onset of parametric resonance by
depleting the particles produced at the bottom of the potential. In spite of
this delay, fermions are shown to play an important role on the destruction of
the inflaton field. The limitations of our approach and its applications to a
realistic Higgs inflation scenario are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08424</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Arata</forenames></author></authors><title>Berry phase in lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 052001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.052001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the lattice QCD calculation of the Berry phase which is defined by
the ground state of a single fermion. We perform the ground-state projection of
a single-fermion propagator, construct the Berry link variable on a
momentum-space lattice, and calculate the Berry phase. As the first
application, the first Chern number of the (2+1)-dimensional Wilson fermion is
calculated by the Monte Carlo simulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00683</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robin</keyname><forenames>Caroline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Litvinova</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear response theory for spin-isospin excitations in a relativistic
  quasiparticle-phonon coupling framework</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures. v3: convergence study added, other minor
  corrections and references added, version accepted for publication in The
  European Physical Journal A as part of the topical issue &quot;Finite range
  effective interactions and associated many-body methods - A tribute to Daniel
  Gogny&quot;. The final publication is available at Springer via
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epja/i2016-16205-0</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 205</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16205-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new theoretical approach to spin-isospin excitations in open-shell nuclei
is presented. The developed method is based on the relativistic meson-exchange
nuclear Lagrangian of Quantum Hadrodynamics and extends the response theory for
superfluid nuclear systems beyond relativistic quasiparticle random phase
approximation in the proton-neutron channel (pn-RQRPA). The coupling between
quasiparticle degrees of freedom and collective vibrations (phonons) introduces
a time-dependent effective interaction, in addition to the exchange of pion and
$\rho$-meson taken into account without retardation. The time-dependent
contributions are treated in the resonant time-blocking approximation, in
analogy to previously developed relativistic quasiparticle time blocking
approximation (RQTBA) in the neutral (non-isospin-flip) channel. The new method
is called proton-neutron RQTBA (pn-RQTBA) and applied to Gamow-Teller resonance
in a chain of neutron-rich Nickel isotopes $^{68-78}$Ni. A strong fragmentation
of the resonance along with quenching of the strength, as compared to pn-RQRPA,
is obtained. Based on the calculated strength distribution, beta-decay
half-lives of the considered isotopes are computed and compared to pn-RQRPA
half-lives and to experimental data. It is shown that a considerable
improvement of the half-life description is obtained in pn-RQTBA because of the
spreading effects, which bring the lifetimes to a very good quantitative
agreement with data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04256</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zechlin</keyname><forenames>Hannes-S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuoco</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donato</keyname><forenames>Fiorenza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fornengo</keyname><forenames>Nicolao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Regis</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Measurement of the Gamma-ray Source-count Distribution as a
  Function of Energy</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables; v2: minor changes, accepted for
  publication in ApJL</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 826, Number 2, L31
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/826/2/L31</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Statistical properties of photon count maps have recently been proven as a
new tool to study the composition of the gamma-ray sky with high precision. We
employ the 1-point probability distribution function of 6 years of Fermi-LAT
data to measure the source-count distribution dN/dS and the diffuse components
of the high-latitude gamma-ray sky as a function of energy. To that aim, we
analyze the gamma-ray emission in five adjacent energy bands between 1 GeV and
171 GeV. It is demonstrated that the source-count distribution as a function of
flux is compatible with a broken power law up to energies of ~50 GeV. The index
below the break is between 1.95 and 2.0. For higher energies, a simple
power-law fits the data, with an index of 2.2^{+0.7}_{-0.3} in the energy band
between 50 GeV and 171 GeV. Upper limits on further possible breaks as well as
the angular power of unresolved sources are derived. We find that point-source
populations probed by this method can explain 83^{+7}_{-13}% (81^{+52}_{-19}%)
of the extragalactic gamma-ray background between 1.04 GeV and 1.99 GeV (50 GeV
and 171 GeV). The method has excellent capabilities for constraining the
gamma-ray luminosity function and the spectra of unresolved blazars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05081</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>The MEG Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for the Lepton Flavour Violating Decay $\mu^{+} \to e^+ \gamma$
  with the Full Dataset of the MEG Experiment</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>30 pages, 31 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The final results of the search for the lepton flavour violating decay
$\mu^{+} \rightarrow {\rm e^{+}} \gamma$ based on the full dataset collected by
the MEG experiment at the Paul Scherrer Institut in the period 2009--2013 and
totalling $7.5\times 10^{14}$ stopped muons on target are presented. No
significant excess of events is observed in the dataset with respect to the
expected background and a new upper limit on the branching ratio of this decay
of $BR( \mu^{+} \rightarrow {\rm e^{+}} \gamma ) &lt; 4.2 \times 10^{-13}$ (90\%\
confidence level) is established, which represents the most stringent limit on
the existence of this decay to date.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00659</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paliathanasis</keyname><forenames>Andronikos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrow</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leach</keyname><forenames>P. G. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Solutions of $f(T)$ Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, accepted for publication by Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 023525 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.023525</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the cosmological scenario in $f\left( T\right) $ gravity, we find
analytical solutions for an isotropic and homogeneous universe containing a
dust fluid and radiation and for an empty anisotropic Bianchi I universe. The
method that we apply is that of movable singularities of differential
equations. For the isotropic universe, the solutions are expressed in terms of
a Laurent expansion, while for the anisotropic universe we find a family of
exact Kasner-like solutions in vacuum. Finally, we discuss when a nonlinear
$f\left( T\right) $-gravity theory provides solutions for the teleparallel
equivalence of general relativity and derive conditions for exact solutions of
general relativity to solve the field equations of an $f(T)$ theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01845</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sokolovski</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum measurements, stochastic networks, the uncertainty principle,
  and not so strange &quot;weak values&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The outcomes of a series of measurements, made on a quantum system, form a
sequence of random events which occur in a particular order. The system,
together with a meter or meters, can be seen as following the paths of a
stochastic network connecting all possible outcomes. The paths are shaped from
the virtual paths of the system, and the corresponding probabilities are
determined by the measuring devices employed. If the measurements are highly
accurate, the virtual paths become &quot;real&quot;, and the mean values of a quantity (a
functional) is directly related to the frequencies with which the paths are
travelled. If the measurements are highly inaccurate, the mean (weak) values
are expressed in terms of the relative probabilities amplitudes. For pre- and
post-selected systems they are bound to take arbitrary values, depending on the
chosen transition. This is a direct consequence of the uncertainty principle,
which forbids one to distinguish between interfering alternatives, while
leaving the interference between them intact.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02876</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Taketomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsumoto</keyname><forenames>Shingo</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Verification of a Spin-Interference Device Action</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the detection of spin interference signal in an Aharonov-Bohm type
interferometer with quantum dots on the conduction paths. We have found that
resonators like quantum dots can work as efficient spin rotators. The
interference signal appears only when spin-polarized electrons are injected
into the device. The interference pattern in the gate voltage-magnetic field
plane is checker board like, ensuring the modulation of spin wavefunction's
phase as well as the orbital phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03750</id><created>2016-06-12</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halir</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheben</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luque-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Jose Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarmiento-Merenguel</keyname><forenames>Jose Dar&#xed;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmid</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang&#xfc;emert-P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Dan-Xia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shurui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortega-Mo&#xf1;ux</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina-Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>&#xcd;&#xf1;igo</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra broadband waveveguide coupler using an anisotropic sub-wavelength
  metamaterial</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multimode interference couplers are a fundamental building block in many
integrated photonic systems, ranging from high-speed coherent receivers to
quantum splitters. However, their basic structure has remained fundamentally
unchanged for almost four decades, limiting their size and operation bandwidth.
Using sub-wavelength metamaterials, photonic devices with break-through size
and performance have been recently reported. Leveraging the inherent anisotropy
of these structures, here we derive a semi-analytic expression that enables the
design of compact and ultra broadband multimode interference couplers. We
experimentally demonstrate virtually perfect operation over a bandwidth in
excess of 300nm (500nm in simulation), for a device three times shorter than
its conventional counterpart, making this the most broadband multimode
interference coupler reported to date. These results will enable ultra
broadband integrated systems for applications in communications and sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07644</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Chao-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Chao</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation effect of gravitational wave on detector response</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><doi>10.1007/s11433-016-0268-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The response of a detector to gravitational wave is a function of frequency.
When the time a photon moving around in the Fabry-Perot cavities is the same
order of the period of a gravitational wave, the phase-difference due to the
gravitational wave should be an integral along the path. We present a formula
description for detector response to gravitational wave with varied
frequencies. The LIGO data for GW150914 and GW 151226 are reexamined in this
framework. For GW150924, the traveling time of a photon in the LIGO detector is
just a bit larger than a half period of the highest frequency of gravitational
wave and the similar result is obtained with LIGO and Virgo collaborations.
However, we are not always so luck. In the case of GW151226, the time of a
photon traveling in the detector is larger than the period of the highest
frequency of gravitational wave and the announced signal cannot match well the
template with the initial black hole masses 14.2M$_\odot$ and 7.5M$_\odot$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07713</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Riahi</keyname><forenames>Natascha</forenames></author></authors><title>Solving the time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation via Laplace transform</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 6 figures; abstract changed, introduction enlarged,
  references added, content added in section 4 and 5</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how the Laplace transform can be used to give a solution of the
time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation for an arbitrary initial wave packet if
the solution of the stationary equation is known. The solution is obtained
without summing up eigenstates nor do we need the path integral. We solve the
initial value problem for three characteristic piecewise constant potentials.
The results give an intuitive picture of the wave packet dynamics, reproducing
explicitly all possible reflection and transmission processes. We investigate
classical and quantum properties of the evolution and determine the reflection
and transmission probabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00794</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alekhin</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moch</keyname><forenames>Sven-Olaf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thier</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-top production in the s-channel and the top-quark mass</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, LaTeX (PoS style), 3 ps-figures. To appear in the
  proceedings of `DIS 2016', DESY, Hamburg (Germany), April 2016. v2: NNLL
  accuracy</comments><report-no>DESY 16-118</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a fixed-order expansion of resummed soft-gluon corrections to
determine an approximate NNLO formula for the partonic cross section of
single-top production in the $s$-channel. This formula is implemented in the
program Hathor for the numerical evaluation of hadronic cross sections. With
the resulting code, we perform a fit of the top-quark mass to Tevatron cross
section data. Results for $m_t$ are given in the pole-mass scheme and in the
$\overline{\mathrm{MS}}$ scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01650</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Ailong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Linyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hanming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zhizhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wenkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wanli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Guoen</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient Image Reconstruction and Practical Decomposition for
  Dual-energy Computed Tomography</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dual-energy computed tomography (DECT) has shown great potential and
promising applications in advanced imaging fields for its capabilities of
material decomposition. However, image reconstructions and decompositions under
sparse views dataset suffers severely from multi factors, such as
insufficiencies of data, appearances of noise, and inconsistencies of
observations. Under sparse views, conventional filtered back-projection type
reconstruction methods fails to provide CT images with satisfying quality.
Moreover, direct image decomposition is unstable and meet with noise boost even
with full views dataset. This paper proposes an iterative image reconstruction
algorithm and a practical image domain decomposition method for DECT. On one
hand, the reconstruction algorithm is formulated as an optimization problem,
which containing total variation regularization term and data fidelity term.
The alternating direction method is utilized to design the corresponding
algorithm which shows faster convergence speed compared with the existing ones.
On the other hand, the image domain decomposition applies the penalized least
square (PLS) estimation on decomposing the material mappings. The PLS includes
linear combination term and the regularization term which enforces the
smoothness on estimation images. The authors implement and evaluate the
proposed joint method on real DECT projections and compare the method with
typical and state-of-the-art reconstruction and decomposition methods. The
experiments on dataset of an anthropomorphic head phantom show that our methods
have advantages on noise suppression and edge reservation, without blurring the
fine structures in the sinus area in the phantom. Compared to the existing
approaches, our method achieves a superior performance on DECT imaging with
respect to reconstruction accuracy and decomposition quality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01866</id><created>2016-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Baek</keyname><forenames>Kyunghyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Son</keyname><forenames>Wonmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Unsharpness of generalized measurement and its effects in entropic
  uncertainty relations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 30228 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30228</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under the scenario of generalized measurements, it can be questioned how much
of quantum uncertainty can be attributed to measuring device, independent of
the uncertainty in the measured system. On the course to answer the question,
we suggest a new class of entropic uncertainty relation that differentiates
quantum uncertainty from device imperfection due to the unsharpness of
measurement. In order to quantify the unsharpness, we {suggest} and analyze the
quantity that characterizes the uncertainty in the measuring device, based on
Shannon entropy. Using the quantity, we obtain a new lower bound of entropic
uncertainty with unsharpness and it has been shown that the relation can also
be obtained under the scenario that sharp observables are affected by the white
noise and amplitude damping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04707</id><created>2016-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>C. V&#xe1;squez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>L. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lugones</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of strongly magnetized ultradense matter and their imprints
  on magnetar pulsations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>To be published in Physical Review C</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C94 (2016) 015807</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.015807</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of strong magnetic fields on the adiabatic radial
oscillations of hadronic stars. We describe magnetized hadronic matter within
the framework of the relativistic nonlinear Walecka model and integrate the
equations of relativistic radial oscillations to determine the fundamental
pulsation mode. We consider that the magnetic field increases, in a density
dependent way, from the surface, where it has a typical magnetar value of
$10^{15}$ G, to the interior of the star where it can be as large as $3 \times
10^{18}$ G. We show that magnetic fields of the order of $10^{18}$ G at the
stellar core produce a significant change in the frequency of neutron star
pulsations with respect to unmagnetized objects. If radial pulsations are
excited in magnetar flares, they can leave an imprint in the flare lightcurves
and open a new window for the study of highly magnetized ultradense matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06471</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mingo</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosen</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardcastle</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blain</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrera</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mateos</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pineau</keyname><forenames>F. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The MIXR sample: AGN activity versus star formation across the
  cross-correlation of WISE, 3XMM, and FIRST/NVSS</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>38 pages, 38 figures, 7 tables. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We cross-correlate the largest available Mid-Infrared (WISE), X-ray (3XMM)
and Radio (FIRST+NVSS) catalogues to define the MIXR sample of AGN and
star-forming galaxies. We pre-classify the sources based on their positions on
the WISE colour/colour plot, showing that the MIXR triple selection is
extremely effective to diagnose the star formation and AGN activity of
individual populations, even on a flux/magnitude basis, extending the
diagnostics to objects with luminosities and redshifts from SDSS DR12. We
recover the radio/mid-IR star formation correlation with great accuracy, and
use it to classify our sources, based on their activity, as radio-loud and
radio-quiet AGN, LERGs/LINERs, and non-AGN galaxies. These diagnostics can
prove extremely useful for large AGN and galaxy samples, and help develop ways
to efficiently triage sources when data from the next generation of instruments
becomes available. We study bias in detail, and show that while the widely-used
WISE colour selections for AGN are very successful at cleanly selecting samples
of luminous AGN, they miss or misclassify a substantial fraction of AGN at
lower luminosities and/or higher redshifts. MIXR also allows us to test the
relation between radiative and kinetic (jet) power in radio-loud AGN, for which
a tight correlation is expected due to a mutual dependence on accretion. Our
results highlight that long-term AGN variability, jet regulation, and other
factors affecting the $Q/L$$_{bol}$ relation, are introducing a vast amount of
scatter in this relation, with dramatic potential consequences on our current
understanding of AGN feedback and its effect on star formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08353</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Miceli</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquarello</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-compensation due to point defects in Mg-doped GaN</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 165207 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.165207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using hybrid density functional theory, we address point defects susceptible
to cause charge compensation upon Mg doping of GaN. We determine the free
energy of formation of the nitrogen vacancy and of several Mg-related defects.
The entropic contribution as a function of temperature is determined within the
quasiharmonic approximation. We find that the Mg interstitial shows a
noticeably lower free energy of formation than the Mg substitutional to Ga in
p-type conditions. Therefore, the Mg impurity is amphoteric behaving like an
acceptor when substitutional to Ga and like a double donor when accommodated in
an interstitial position. The hybrid-functional results are then linked to
experimental observations by solving the charge neutrality equations for
semiconductor dominated by impurities. We show that a thermodynamic equilibrium
model is unable to account for the experimental hole concentration as a
function of Mg doping density, due to nitrogen vacancies and Mg interstitials
acting as compensating donors. To explain the experimental result, which
includes a dropoff of the hole concentration at high Mg densities, we thus
resort to nonequilibrium models. We show that either nitrogen vacancies or Mg
interstitials could be at the origin of the self-compensation mechanism.
However, only the model based on interstitial Mg donors provides a natural
mechanism to account for the sudden appearance of self-compensation. Indeed,
the amphoteric nature of the Mg impurity leads to Fermi-level pinning and
accounts for the observed dropoff of the hole concentration of GaN samples at
high Mg doping. Our work suggests that current limitations in p-type doping of
GaN could be overcome by extrinsically controlling the Fermi energy during
growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08377</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08377</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Miceli</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Gironcoli</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquarello</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author></authors><title>Isobaric first-principles molecular dynamics of liquid water with
  nonlocal van der Waals interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 142, 034501 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4905333</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the structural properties of liquid water at near ambient
conditions using first-principles molecular dynamics simulations based on a
semilocal density functional augmented with nonlocal van der Waals
interactions. The adopted scheme offers the advantage of simulating liquid
water at essentially the same computational cost of standard semilocal
functionals. Applied to the water dimer and to ice Ih, we find that the
hydrogen-bond energy is only slightly enhanced compared to a standard semilocal
functional. We simulate liquid water through molecular dynamics in the NpH
statistical ensemble allowing for fluctuations of the system density. The
structure of the liquid departs from that found with a semilocal functional
leading to more compact structural arrangements. This indicates that the
directionality of the hydrogen-bond interaction has a diminished role as
compared to the overall attractions, as expected when dispersion interactions
are accounted for. This is substantiated through a detailed analysis comprising
the study of the partial radial distribution functions, various local order
indices, the hydrogen-bond network, and the selfdiffusion coefficient. The
explicit treatment of the van der Waals interactions leads to an overall
improved description of liquid water.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08491</id><created>2016-07-28</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Qi-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau-Zener-St\&quot;uckelberg Interferometry for Majorana Qubit</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stimulated by a very recent experiment observing successfully two
superconducting states with even- and odd-number of electrons in a nanowire
topological superconductor as expected from the existence of two end Majorana
quasiparticles (MQs) [Albrecht \textit{et al.}, Nature \textbf{531}, 206
(2016)], we propose a way to manipulate Majorana qubit exploiting quantum
tunneling effects. The prototype setup consists of two one-dimensional (1D)
topological superconductors coupled by a tunneling junction which can be
controlled by gate voltage. We show that, upon current injection, the time
evolution of superconducting phase difference at the junction induces an
oscillation in energy levels of the Majorana parity states, whereas the
level-crossing is avoided by a small coupling energy of MQs in the individual
1D superconductors. This results in a Landau-Zener-St\&quot;{u}ckelberg (LZS)
interference between the Majorana parity states. Adjusting the current pulse
and gate voltage, one can build a LZS interferometry which provides an
arbitrary manipulation of the Majorana qubit. The LZS rotation of Majorana
qubit can be monitored by the microwave radiated from the junction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08608</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Joffily</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novello</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology of a Heisenberg fluid</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a scenario in which the global geometry of the universe is driven
by non-linear fermions obeying Heisenberg dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08622</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Junwu</forenames></author><author><keyname>March-Russell</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified Maximally Natural Supersymmetry</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Maximally Natural Supersymmetry, an unusual weak-scale supersymmetric
extension of the Standard Model based upon the inherently higher-dimensional
mechanism of Scherk-Schwarz supersymmetry breaking (SSSB), possesses remarkably
good fine tuning given present LHC limits. Here we construct a version with
precision $SU(2)_{\rm L} \times U(1)_{\rm Y} $ unification: $\sin^2
\theta_W(M_Z) \simeq 0.231$ is predicted to $\pm 2\%$ by unifying $SU(2)_{\rm
L} \times U(1)_{\rm Y} $ into a 5D $SU(3)_{\rm EW}$ theory at a Kaluza-Klein
scale of $1/R_5 \sim 4.4\,{\rm TeV}$, where SSSB is simultaneously realised.
Full unification with $SU(3)_{\rm C}$ is accommodated by extending the 5D
theory to a $N=4$ supersymmetric $SU(6)$ gauge theory on a 6D rectangular
orbifold at $1/R_6 \sim 40 \,{\rm TeV}$. TeV-scale states beyond the SM include
exotic charged fermions implied by $SU(3)_{\rm EW}$ with masses lighter than
$\sim 1.2\,{\rm TeV}$, and squarks in the mass range $1.4\,{\rm TeV} -
2.3\,{\rm TeV}$, providing distinct signatures and discovery opportunities for
LHC run II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08625</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Weingartner</keyname><forenames>N. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pueblo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelton</keyname><forenames>K. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nussinov</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal collapse of the viscosity of supercooled fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  All liquids in nature can be supercooled to form a glass. Surprisingly,
although this phenomenon has been employed for millennia, it still remains
ill-understood. Perhaps the most puzzling feature of supercooled liquids is the
dramatic increase in their viscosity as the temperature ($T$) is lowered. This
precipitous rise has long posed a fundamental theoretical challenge. Numerous
approaches currently attempt to explain this phenomenon. When present, data
collapse points to an underlying simplicity in various branches of science. In
this Letter, we report on a 16 decade data collapse of the viscosity of 45
different liquids of all known types. Specifically, the viscosity of
supercooled liquids scaled by their value at their respective equilibrium
melting temperature ($\eta(T)/\eta(T_{melt}))$ is, for all temperatures
$T&lt;T_{melt}$, a universal function of $(T_{melt} - T)/(B T)$ where $B$ is a
constant that does not change significantly from one liquid to another. This
exceptionally plain behavior hints at a link between glassy dynamics and the
conventional equilibrium melting transition in all known supercooled fluids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08626</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Agarkov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burmistrov</keyname><forenames>I. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsybrov</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tartakovskii</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kharton</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bredikhin</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>In-situ Raman spectroscopy analysis of the interfaces between Ni-based
  SOFC anodes and stabilized zirconia electrolyte</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>ISSFIT-12 conference paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new experimental approach for in-situ Raman spectroscopy of the electrode |
solid electrolyte interfaces in controlled atmospheres, based on the use of
optically transparent single-crystal membranes of stabilized cubic zirconia,
has been proposed and validated. This technique makes it possible to directly
access the electrochemical reaction zone in SOFCs by passing the laser beam
through single-crystal electrolyte onto the interface, in combination with
simultaneous electrochemical measurements. The case study centered on the
analysis of NiO reduction in standard cermet anodes under open-circuit
conditions, demonstrated an excellent agreement between the observed kinetic
parameters and literature data on nickel oxide. The porous cermet reduction
kinetics at 400-600C in flowing H2-N2 gas mixture can be described by the
classical Avrami model, suggesting that the reaction rate is determined by the
metal nuclei growth limited by Ni diffusion. The advantages and limitations of
the new experimental approach were briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08629</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ariwahjoedi</keyname><forenames>Seramika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Astuti</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosasih</keyname><forenames>Jusak Sali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovelli</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zen</keyname><forenames>Freddy Permana</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical discrete geometry</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages, 16 figures, the information contained in this article was
  extracted from a doctoral thesis by the author</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following our earlier work, we construct statistical discrete geometry by
applying statistical mechanics to discrete (Regge) gravity. We propose a
coarse-graining method for discrete geometry under the assumptions of atomism
and background independence. To maintain these assumptions, restrictions are
given to the theory by introducing cut-offs, both in ultraviolet and infrared
regime. Having a well-defined statistical picture of discrete Regge geometry,
we take the infinite degrees of freedom (large n) limit. We argue that the
correct limit consistent with the restrictions and the background independence
concept is not the continuum limit of statistical mechanics, but the
thermodynamical limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08638</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Rjabchikov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>The Ancient Astronomy of Easter Island: Kirch's Comet</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>Archaeoastronomy; 4 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fragment of the folklore text &quot;Apai&quot; that was once put down on Easter
Island contains a report about astronomical observations of Kirch's Comet or
the Great Comet of 1680-1681 A.D. (C/1680 V1) and the partial solar eclipse of
March 19, 1681 A.D. Some astronomical aspects of the local cult of bird-men
have been discussed, too.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08642</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>H. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segurado</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina-Aldaregu&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LLorca</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A 3D dislocation dynamics analysis of the size effect on the strength of
  [111] LiF micropillars at 300K and 600K</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Modelling and Simulation in Materials Science and Engineering, 24
  (2016) 035009</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0965-0393/24/3/035009</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The mechanical behavior in compression of [111] LiF micropillars with
diameters in the range 0.5 $\mu$m to 2.0 $\mu$m was analyzed by means of
discrete dislocation dynamics at ambient and elevated temperature. The
dislocation velocity was obtained from the Peach-Koehler force acting on the
dislocation segments from a thermally-activated model that accounted for the
influence of temperature on the lattice resistance. A size effect of the type
&quot;smaller is stronger&quot; was predicted by the simulations, which was in
quantitative agreement with previous experimental results by the authors
\cite{SWC14}. The contribution of the different physical deformation mechanisms
to the size effect (namely, nucleation of dislocations, dislocation exhaustion
and forest hardening) could be ascertained from the simulations and the
dominant deformation mode could be assessed as a function of the specimen size
and temperature. These results shed light into the complex interaction among
size, lattice resistance and dislocation mobility in the mechanical behavior of
$\mu$m-sized single crystals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08661</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmid</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames><affiliation>ETH Zurich</affiliation></author></authors><title>Einstein's equations from Einstein's inertial motion and Newton's law
  for relative acceleration</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Einstein's $R^{\hat{0} \hat{0}}$ equation for nonrelativistic
matter and strong gravitational fields is identical with Newton's equation for
relative radial acceleration of neighbouring freefalling particles, spherically
averaged. These laws are explicitely identical with primary observer's (1)
space-time slicing by radial 4-geodesics, (2) radially parallel Local
Ortho-Normal Bases, LONBs, (3) Riemann normal 3-coordinates. Hats on indices
denote LONBs. General relativity follows from Newton's law of relative
acceleration, Einstein's inertial motion, Lorentz covariance, and
energy-momentum conservation combined with Bianchi identity. The gravitational
field equation of Newton-Gauss and Einstein's $R^{\hat{0} \hat{0}}$ equation
are identical and linear in gravitational field for an inertial primary
observer.---
  Einstein's equivalence between fictitious forces and gravitational forces is
formulated as equivalence theorem in the equations of motion. With this, the
gravitational field equation of 19th-century Newtonian physics and Einstein's
equation for $R^{\hat{0} \hat{0}}$ are identical and bilinear in the
gravitational forces for non-inertial primary observers.---
  $R^{\hat{0} \hat{0}} = - div \vec{E}_g$ and $2 R^{\hat{i} \hat{0}} = - (curl
\vec{B}_g)^{\hat{i}}$ hold exactly for inertial primary observers, if one uses
our LONB's. The gravitational $\vec{E}_g, \vec{B}_g $ are measured exactly with
quasistatic particles via $(d/dt) p_{\hat{i}}$ and $(d/dt) S_{\hat{i}}$ in
correspondence with the electromagnetic $\vec{E}$ and $\vec{B}$. The
$(\vec{E}_g, \vec{B}_g)$ are identical with the observer's Ricci connection
along his worldline, $(\omega_{\hat{a} \hat{b}})_{\hat{0}}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08683</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Aggarwal</keyname><forenames>Amol</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence of the Stochastic Six-Vertex Model to the ASEP</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we establish the convergence of the stochastic six-vertex model
to the one-dimensional asymmetric simple exclusion process, under a certain
limit regime recently predicted by Borodin-Corwin-Gorin. This convergence holds
for arbitrary initial data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08684</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Aggarwal</keyname><forenames>Amol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borodin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transitions in the ASEP and Stochastic Six-Vertex Model</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>64 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we consider two models in the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang (KPZ)
universality class, the asymmetric simple exclusion process (ASEP) and the
stochastic six-vertex model. We introduce a new class of initial data (which we
call {\itshape generalized step Bernoulli initial data}) for both of these
models that generalizes the step Bernoulli initial data studied in a number of
recent works on the ASEP. Under this class of initial data, we analyze the
current fluctuations of both the ASEP and stochastic six-vertex model and
establish the existence of a phase transition along a characteristic line,
across which the fluctuation exponent changes from $1 / 2$ to $1 / 3$. On the
characteristic line, the current fluctuations converge to the general (rank
$k$) Baik-Ben-Arous-P\'{e}ch\'{e} distribution for the law of the largest
eigenvalue of a critically spiked covariance matrix. For $k = 1$, this was
established for the ASEP by Tracy and Widom; for $k &gt; 1$ (and also $k = 1$, for
the stochastic six-vertex model), the appearance of these distributions in both
models is new.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08689</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sanjay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iyer</keyname><forenames>Kartik K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rayaprol</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paulose</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampathkumaran</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A rock-salt type Li-based oxide, Li3Ni2RuO6, exhibiting a chaotic
  ferrimagnetism with cluster spin-glass dynamics and thermally frozen charge
  carriers</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Scientific Reports (In press), 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The area of research to discover new Li containing materials and to
understand their physical properties has been of constant interest due to
applications potential for rechargeable batteries. Here, we present the results
of magnetic investigations on a Li compound, Li3Ni2RuO6, which was believed to
be a ferrimagnet below 80K. While our neutron diffraction (ND) and isothermal
magnetization (M) data support ferrimagnetism, more detailed magnetic studies
establish that this ferrimagnetic phase exhibits some features similar to
spin-glasses. In addition, we find another broad magnetic anomaly around 40-55
K in magnetic susceptibility, attributable to cluster spin-glass phenomenon.
Gradual dominance of cluster spin-glass dynamics with a decrease of temperature
(T) and the apparent spread in freezing temperature suggest that the
ferrimagnetism of this compound is a chaotic one. The absence of a unique
freezing temperature for a crystalline material is interesting. In addition,
pyroelectric current data reveals a feature in the range 40-50 K, attributable
to thermally stimulated depolarization current. We hope this finding motivates
future work to explore whether there is any intriguing correlation of such a
feature with spin-glass dynamics. We attribute these magnetic and electric
dipole anomalies to the crystallographic disorder intrinsic to this compound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08708</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08708</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>G S</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>J S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romh&#xe1;nyi</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szaller</keyname><forenames>D</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe9;zsm&#xe1;rki</keyname><forenames>I</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roessli</keyname><forenames>B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stuhr</keyname><forenames>U</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magrez</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groitl</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babkevich</keyname><forenames>P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>P</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17d;ivkovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>I</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf8;nnow</keyname><forenames>H M</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin excitations in the skymion host Cu2OSeO3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 54401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.054401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have used inelastic neutron scattering to measure the magnetic excitation
spectrum along the high-symmetry directions of the first Brillouin zone of the
magnetic skyrmion hosting compound Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$. The majority of our
scattering data are consistent with the expectations of a recently proposed
model for the magnetic excitations in Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$, and we report best-fit
parameters for the dominant exchange interactions. Important differences exist,
however, between our experimental findings and the model expectations. These
include the identification of two energy scales that likely arise due to
neglected anisotropic interactions. This feature of our work suggests that
anisotropy should be considered in future theoretical work aimed at the full
microscopic understanding of the emergence of the skyrmion state in this
material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08739</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bielewicz</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Eugen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinke</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>New ways to synthesize lead sulfide nanosheets - substituted alkanes
  direct the growth of 2D nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27 (2016) 355602</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/35/355602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional colloidal nanosheets represent very attractive optoelectronic
materials. They combine good lateral conductivity with solution-processability
and geometry-tunable electronic properties. In case of PbS nanosheets, so far
the synthesis was driven by the addition of chloroalkanes as coligands. Here,
we demonstrate how to synthesize two-dimensional lead sulfide nanostructures
using other halogen alkanes and primary amines. Further, we show that at a
reaction temperature of 170C a coligand is not even necessary, and the only
ligand, oleic acid, controls the anisotropic growth of the two-dimensional
structures and using thiourea as sulfide source, nanosheets with lateral
dimensions of over 10 microns are possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08752</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rohith</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>An investigation of nonclassical properties of light using an optical
  tomogram</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>PhD Thesis, IIST Thiruvananthapuram, February 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By analyzing the optical tomogram of a linear superposition of coherent
states, we show that distinctive signatures of the macroscopic superposition
states are displayed directly in the optical tomograms of the states. We also
study the effect of decoherence on the optical tomograms of the macroscopic
superposition states. Since the wave packet fractional revivals are associated
with the generation of macroscopic superposition states, these signatures help
in visualizing the revivals and fractional revivals occurring in a nonlinear
medium directly in the optical tomogram of the time-evolved state. We found
that the optical tomogram of the time-evolved state at the instants of
fractional revivals show structures with sinusoidal strands. Using a class of
initial superposed wave packets evolving in the Kerr-like medium, we further
show that the condition for the occurrence of fractional revival phenomenon
depends on the number of wave packets composing the initial superposition
state. In the case of a two-mode electromagnetic field, we investigate the
entanglement of the state directly using the optical tomogram. We have shown
that the signatures of entanglement can be observed directly in the single-mode
optical tomogram of the state without reconstructing the density matrix of the
system. We also analyze the effect of decoherence on the optical tomograms of
the entangled states. Further, we examine the optical tomograms of the
entangled states generated using a beam splitter with a Kerr medium placed into
one of its input modes. We have found the signatures of entanglement in the
optical tomogram for the entangled states generated at the instants of two- and
three-subpacket fractional revival times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08765</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Couturier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillaudin</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naraghi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riffard</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauzet</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribas</keyname><forenames>E. Ferrer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giomataris</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busto</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fouchez</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directional detection of Dark Matter with the MIcro-tpc MAtrix of
  Chambers</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO physics.ins-det</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure. Proceedings of the 51st Rencontres de Moriond:
  Cosmology, March 19-26, 2016, La Thuile, Italy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Particles weakly interacting with ordinary matter, with an associated mass of
the order of an atomic nucleus (WIMPs), are plausible candidates for Dark
Matter. The direct detection of an elastic collision of a target nuclei induced
by one of these WIMPs has to be discriminated from the signal produced by the
neutrons, which leaves the same signal in a detector. The MIMAC (MIcro-tpc
MAtrix of Chambers) collaboration has developed an original prototype detector
which combines a large pixelated Micromegas coupled with a fast,
self-triggering, electronics. Aspects of the two-chamber module in operation in
the Modane Underground Laboratory are presented: calibration, characterization
of the $^{222}$Rn progeny. A new test bench combining a MIMAC chamber with the
COMIMAC portable quenching line has been set up to characterize the 3D tracks
of low energy ions in the MIMAC gas mixture: the preliminary results thereof
are presented. Future steps are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08770</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Nesterenok</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakubovich</keyname><forenames>O. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Production of $^3$He in Rocks by Reactions Induced by Particles of the
  Nuclear-Active and Muon Components of Cosmic Rays: Geological and
  Petrological Implications</title><categories>astro-ph.EP physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Petrology, 2016, Vol. 24, No. 1, pp. 21-34</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0869591116010057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper presents data on the production of the $^3$He nuclide in rocks
under the effect of cosmic-ray particles. The origin of the nuclide in the
ground in neutron- and proton-induced spallation reactions, reactions induced
by high-energy muons, and negative muon capture reactions is analyzed. The
cross sections of reactions producing $^3$He and $^3$H are calculated by means
of numerical simulations with the GEANT4 simulation toolkit. The production
rate of the $^3$He nuclide in the ground is evaluated for the average level of
solar activity at high geomagnetic latitudes and at sea level. It is proved
that the production of $^3$He in near-surface ground layers by spallation
reactions induced by cosmic-ray protons may be approximately 10% of the total
production rate of cosmogenic $^3$He. At depths of 10-50 m.w.e., the
accumulation of $^3$He is significantly contributed by reactions induced by
cosmic-ray muons. Data presented in the paper make it possible to calculate the
accumulation rate of $^3$He in a rock depending on depth that is necessary for
the evaluation of the exposure time of the magmatic or metamorphic complex on
the Earth's surface ($^3$He dating).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08772</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Pietrobon</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallarino</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chuvilin</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casanova</keyname><forenames>F&#xe8;lix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hueso</keyname><forenames>Luis E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak de-localization in graphene on a ferromagnetic insulating film</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Small 11, 6295 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/smll.201502332</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene has been predicted to develop a magnetic moment by proximity effect
when placed on a ferromagnetic film, a promise that could open exciting
possibilities in the fields of spintronics and magnetic data recording. In this
work, we study in detail the interplay between the magnetoresistance of
graphene and the magnetization of an underlying ferromagnetic insulating film.
A clear correlation between both magnitudes is observed but we find, through a
careful modelling of the magnetization and the weak localization measurements,
that such correspondence can be explained by the effects of the magnetic stray
fields arising from the ferromagnetic insulator. Our results emphasize the
complexity arising at the interface between magnetic and two-dimensional
materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08789</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Biao</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson effect in spin-singlet superconductor/ferromagnetic
  insulator/spin-triplet superconductor junctions with helical $p$-wave states</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages,7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters, 113 (2016) 17007</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/113/17007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Josephson effect in spin-singlet superconductor/helical $p$-wave
superconductor junctions with a ferromagnetic barrier using the quasiclassical
Green function method. It is found that both $\sin{\phi}$-type and
$\cos{\phi}$-type current-phase relations always exist, irrespective of the gap
symmetries in superconductors. The indispensable condition for the
$\sin{\phi}$-type and $\cos{\phi}$-type current is that the magnetization must
have a component parallel to the crystallographic $a$ or $b$ axis, which is
distinct from the case of $p$-wave superconductor described by a
$\vect{d}$-vector with a uniform direction. The relation between the condition
and the symmetries of the gap functions is analysed. We investigate in detail
the symmetries and the sign reversal of the Josephson current when the
magnetization is rotated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08791</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jacobsen</keyname><forenames>Gunnar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazovsky</keyname><forenames>Leonid G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Tianhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friberg</keyname><forenames>Ari T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Noise Influence in Optical OFDM Systems employing RF Pilot Tone
  for Phase Noise Cancellation</title><categories>cs.OH cs.IT math.IT physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1607.04899</comments><msc-class>94A12</msc-class><acm-class>C.2.5</acm-class><journal-ref>Journal of Optical Communications, Vol.32(2), 141-145, 2011</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For coherent and direct-detection Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexed
(OFDM) systems employing radio frequency (RF) pilot tone phase noise
cancellation the influence of laser phase noise is evaluated. Novel analytical
results for the common phase error and for the (modulation dependent) inter
carrier interference are evaluated based upon Gaussian statistics for the laser
phase noise. In the evaluation it is accounted for that the laser phase noise
is filtered in the correlation signal detection. Numerical results are
presented for OFDM systems with 4 and 16 PSK modulation, 200 OFDM bins and baud
rate of 1 GS/s. It is found that about 225 km transmission is feasible for the
coherent 4PSK-OFDM system over normal (G.652) fiber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08796</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Mingliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jinliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiangzheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay Mode Solutions to Cylindrical KP Equation</title><categories>nlin.SI nlin.PS</categories><msc-class>35Q20, 35Q53</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A nonlinear transformation for the cylindrical KP(CKP) equation has been
derived by using the simplified homogeneous balance method (SHB). The 1-decay
mode and 2-decay mode solutions of the CKP equation have been obtained in terms
of the nonlinear transformation derived here. The results obtained in the paper
are different from those obtained in the previous literaturs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08824</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Vinante</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic detection of moduli dark matter</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scheme to detect light scalar moduli dark matter, based on
measuring the change of magnetization induced in a macroscopic hard
ferromagnet. Our method can probe moduli dark matter at the natural coupling to
the electron mass over several orders of magnitude in the moduli mass. The most
attracting feature of the proposed approach, compared to mechanical ones, is
that it relies on a nonresonant detection, allowing to probe a much wider
region of the parameter space. This is a crucial point, as long as the theory
is not able to predict the moduli mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08831</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ospina</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duque</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morell</keyname><forenames>Eric Su&#xe1;rez</forenames></author></authors><title>Twisted bilayer blue phosphorene: A direct band gap semiconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages 5 figures in Superlattice and Microstructures 2016</comments><doi>10.1016/j.spmi.2016.07.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report that two rotated layers of blue phosphorene behave as a direct band
gap semiconductor. The optical spectrum shows absorption peaks in the visible
region of the spectrum and in addition the energy of these peaks can be tuned
with the rotational angle. These findings makes twisted bilayer blue
phosphorene a strong candidate as a solar cell or photodetection device. Our
results are based on ab initio calculations of several rotated blue phosphorene
layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08844</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Kemper</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao-Geisler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>O. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The interstellar dust reservoir: SPICA's view on dust production and the
  interstellar medium in galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the proceedings of the &quot;SPICA Science
  Conference 2013, From Exoplanets to Distant Galaxies: SPICA's New Window on
  the Cool Universe&quot;, to be published in the ASP Conference Series</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Typical galaxies emit about one third of their energy in the infrared. The
origin of this emission reprocessed starlight absorbed by interstellar dust
grains and reradiated as thermal emission in the infrared. In particularly
dusty galaxies, such as starburst galaxies, the fraction of energy emitted in
the infrared can be as high as 90%. Dust emission is found to be an excellent
tracer of the beginning and end stages of a star's life, where dust is being
produced by post-main-sequence stars, subsequently added to the interstellar
dust reservoir, and eventually being consumed by star and planet formation.
This work reviews the current understanding of the size and properties of this
interstellar dust reservoir, by using the Large Magellanic Cloud as an example,
and what can be learned about the dust properties and star formation in
galaxies from this dust reservoir, using SPICA, building on previous work
performed with the Herschel and Spitzer Space Telescopes, as well as the
Infrared Space Observatory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08848</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08848</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bard</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Townsend</keyname><forenames>Richard H. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of a magnetic field on massive star winds I: mass-loss and
  velocity for a dipole field</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 12 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We generalize the Rigid-Field Hydrodynamic equations to accommodate arbitrary
magnetic field topologies, resulting in a new Arbitrary Rigid-Field
hydrodynamic (ARFHD) formalism. We undertake a critical point calculation of
the steady-state ARFHD equations with a CAK-type radiative acceleration and
determine the effects of a dipole magnetic field on the usual CAK mass-loss
rate and velocity structure. Enforcing the proper optically-thin limit for the
radiative line-acceleration is found to decrease both the mass-loss and wind
acceleration, while rotation boosts both properties. We define
optically-thin-correction and rotation parameters to quantify these effects on
the global mass-loss rate and develop scaling laws for the surface mass-flux as
a function of surface colatitude. These scaling laws are found to agree with
previous laws derived from magnetohydrodynamic simulations of magnetospheres.
The dipole magnetosphere velocity structure is found to differ from a global
beta-velocity law, which contradicts a central assumption of the
previously-developed XADM model of X-ray emission from magnetospheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08856</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Wirgin</keyname><forenames>Armand</forenames></author></authors><title>Earthquakes in cities revisited</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>37 pages, 19 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the last twenty years, a number of publications of
theoretical-numerical nature have appeared which come to the
apparently-reassuring conclusion that seismic motion on the ground in cities is
smaller than what this motion would be in the absence of the buildings (but for
the same underground and seismic load). Other than the fact that this finding
tells nothing about the motion within the buildings, it must be confronted with
the overwhelming empirical evidence (e.g, earthquakes in Sendai (2011),
Kathmandu (2015), Tainan City (2016), etc.) that shaking within buildings of a
city is often large enough to damage or even destroy these structures. I show,
on several examples, that theory can be reconciled with empirical evidence, and
suggest that the crucial subject of seismic response in cities is in need of
more thorough research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08859</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xing-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua-Zhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ren-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex Laser at Exceptional Point</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The optical vortices carrying orbital angular momentum (OAM) are commonly
generated by modulating the available conventional light beam. This article
shows that a micro-laser operates at the exceptional point (EP) of the
non-Hermitian quantum system can directly emit vortex laser with well-defined
OAM at will. Two gratings (the refractive index modulation and along azimuthal
direction and the grating protruding from the micro-ring cavity) modulate the
eigenmode of a micro-ring cavity to be a vortex laser mode. The phase-matching
condition ensures that we can tune the OAM of the vortex beam to be arbitrary
orders by changing the grating protruding from the micro-ring cavity while the
system is kept at EP. The results are obtained by analytical analysis and
confirmed by 3D full wave simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08872</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08872</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Hackstein</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazza</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brueggen</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigl</keyname><forenames>Guenter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dundovic</keyname><forenames>Andrej</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of Ultra High Energy Cosmic Rays in Extragalactic Magnetic
  Fields: A view from cosmological simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>13 pages, 20 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the CRPropa code to simulate the propagation of ultra high energy
cosmic rays (with energy $\geq 10^{18} \rm eV$ and pure proton composition)
through extragalactic magnetic fields that have been simulated with the
cosmological ENZO code.We test both primordial and astrophysical magnetogenesis
scenarios in order to investigate the impact of different magnetic field
strengths in clusters, filaments and voids on the deflection of cosmic rays
propagating across cosmological distances. We also study the effect of
different source distributions of cosmic rays around simulated Milky-Way like
observers. Our analysis shows that the arrival spectra and anisotropy of events
are rather insensitive to the distribution of extragalactic magnetic fields,
while they are more affected by the clustering of sources within a $\sim 50$
Mpc distance to observers. Finally, we find that in order to reproduce the
observed degree of isotropy of cosmic rays at $\sim $ EeV energies, the average
magnetic fields in cosmic voids must be $\sim 0.1 \rm \ nG$, providing limits
on the strength of primordial seed fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08874</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08874</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferrand</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>English</keyname><forenames>Jayanne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irani</keyname><forenames>Pourang</forenames></author></authors><title>3D visualization of astronomy data cubes using immersive displays</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cs.GR</categories><comments>presentation given at CASCA conference on 2016/06/01</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on an exploratory project aimed at performing immersive 3D
visualization of astronomical data, starting with spectral-line radio data
cubes from galaxies. This work is done as a collaboration between the
Department of Physics and Astronomy and the Department of Computer Science at
the University of Manitoba. We are building our prototype using the 3D engine
Unity, because of its ease of use for integration with advanced displays such
as a CAVE environment, a zSpace tabletop, or virtual reality headsets. We
address general issues regarding 3D visualization, such as: load and convert
astronomy data, perform volume rendering on the GPU, and produce physically
meaningful visualizations using principles of visual literacy. We discuss some
challenges to be met when designing a user interface that allows us to take
advantage of this new way of exploring data. We hope to lay the foundations for
an innovative framework useful for all astronomers who use spectral line data
cubes, and encourage interested parties to join our efforts. This pilot project
addresses the challenges presented by frontier astronomy experiments, such as
the Square Kilometre Array and its precursors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08875</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Levitt</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortner</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence and Cycling in Walker-type Saddle Search Algorithms</title><categories>math.NA math.OC physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Algorithms for computing local minima of smooth objective functions enjoy a
mature theory as well as robust and efficient implementations. By comparison,
the theory and practice of saddle search is destitute. In this paper we present
results for idealized versions of the dimer and gentlest ascent (GAD) saddle
search algorithms that show-case the limitations of what is theoretically
achievable within the current class of saddle search algorithms: (1) we present
an improved estimate on the region of attraction of saddles; and (2) we
construct quasi-periodic solutions which indicate that it is impossible to
obtain globally convergent variants of dimer and GAD type algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08890</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Pariente</keyname><forenames>Jose Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayat</keyname><forenames>Farzaneh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pecharom&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanco</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Cefe</forenames></author></authors><title>Percolation in photonic crystals revealed by Fano Resonance</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The understanding of how the arrangement of defects in photonic crystals
impacts its photonic properties is cru-cial for the design of functional
materials based thereon. By preparing photonic crystals with random missing
scatterers we create crystals where disorder is embodied as vacancies in an
otherwise perfect lattice rather than the usual positional or size disorder. We
show that the amount of defects not only determines the intensity but also the
nature of the light scattering. As the amount of defects varies, light
scattering undergoes a transition whereby the usual signatures of photonic gaps
(Bragg peak) suffer line-shape changes (Bragg dip) that can be readily
described with the Fano resonance q parameter. When the amount of vacancies
reaches the percolation threshold, q undergoes a sign change signaling the
transition from a crystal to a mosaic of microcrystals through a state where
scattering is maximum. Beyond that point the system reenters a state of low
scattering that ap-pears in the guise of normal Bragg diffraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08901</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ossola</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrand reduction beyond one-loop calculations</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures, to appear in the proceedings of Loops and Legs
  in Quantum Field Theory, 24-29 April 2016, Leipzig, Germany. arXiv admin
  note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1601.04590</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this presentation, we review the general features of integrand-reduction
techniques, with a particular focus on their generalization beyond one loop. We
start with a brief discussion of the one-loop scenario, a case in which
integrand-reduction algorithms are well established and played over the past
decade an important role in the development of automated tools for the
theoretical evaluation of physical observables. The generalization of
integrand-reduction techniques to all loops has been the subject of several
efforts in the recent past, thus providing a better understanding of the
universal properties of scattering amplitudes. The ultimate goal of these
studies is the development of efficient alternative computational techniques
for the evaluation of Feynman integrals beyond one loop.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
