<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:03:27Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-22" from="2016-08-22" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0806.0684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0806.0684</id><created>2008-06-03</created><updated>2012-12-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author></authors><title>A note on space dimensionality constraints relied on Anthropic
  arguments: methane structure and the origin of life</title><categories>physics.hist-ph astro-ph astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>7 pages, contribution to J.M.F. Bassalo's Festschrift</comments><journal-ref>Filardo Bassalo's Festschrift, S\~ao Paulo: Livraria da F\'isica,
  pp. 95-106, 2009</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general sketch of how the problem of space dimensionality depends on
Anthropic arguments is presented. A new argument in favor of a stable scenario
for space dimensionality for a time scale longer than that required for the
existence of human or another kind of highly-evolved life on Earth is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0907.3531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0907.3531</id><created>2009-07-20</created><updated>2015-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xavier</keyname><forenames>Roberto Moreira</forenames></author></authors><title>On Kant's first insight into the problem of space dimensionality and its
  physical foundations</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>Kant-Studien. Volume 106, Issue 4, Pages 547-560 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/kant-2015-0051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article it is shown that a careful analysis of Kant's &quot;Thoughts on
the True Estimation of Living Forces&quot; leads to a conclusion that does not match
the usually accepted interpretation of Kant's reasoning in 1747, according to
which the Young Kant supposedly establishes a relationship between the
tridimensionality of space and Newton's law of universal gravitation. Indeed,
it is argued that this text does not yield a satisfactory explanation of space
dimensionality, actually restricting itself to justify the tridimensionality of
extension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1104.0153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1104.0153</id><created>2011-04-01</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bornemann</keyname><forenames>Folkmar</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Scaling Limits of Determinantal Point Processes with Kernels
  Induced by Sturm-Liouville Operators</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 083, 20 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.083</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  By applying an idea of Borodin and Olshanski [J. Algebra 313 (2007), 40-60],
we study various scaling limits of determinantal point processes with trace
class projection kernels given by spectral projections of selfadjoint
Sturm-Liouville operators. Instead of studying the convergence of the kernels
as functions, the method directly addresses the strong convergence of the
induced integral operators. We show that, for this notion of convergence, the
Dyson, Airy, and Bessel kernels are universal in the bulk, soft-edge, and
hard-edge scaling limits. This result allows us to give a short and unified
derivation of the known formulae for the scaling limits of the classical random
matrix ensembles with unitary invariance, that is, the Gaussian unitary
ensemble (GUE), the Wishart or Laguerre unitary ensemble (LUE), and the MANOVA
(multivariate analysis of variance) or Jacobi unitary ensemble (JUE).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1203.1151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1203.1151</id><created>2012-03-06</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author></authors><title>All order covariant tubular expansion</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>27 pages. Corrected an error in a class of coefficients resulting
  from a typo. Integral theorem and all other results remain unchanged</comments><report-no>IMSc/2012/3/5</report-no><journal-ref>Reviews in Mathematical Physics, Vol. 26, No. 1 (2013) 1350019</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0129055X13500190</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider tubular neighborhood of an arbitrary submanifold embedded in a
(pseudo-)Riemannian manifold. This can be described by Fermi normal coordinates
(FNC) satisfying certain conditions as described by Florides and Synge in
\cite{FS}. By generalizing the work of Muller {\it et al} in \cite{muller} on
Riemann normal coordinate expansion, we derive all order FNC expansion of
vielbein in this neighborhood with closed form expressions for the curvature
expansion coefficients. Our result is shown to be consistent with certain
integral theorem for the metric proved in \cite{FS}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.4567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.4567</id><created>2013-05-20</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Talati</keyname><forenames>Daryoush</forenames></author></authors><title>On the classification of fifth-order integrable systems</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>This work updated with arXiv:1608.05125</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we classify the fifth-order integrable symmetrically coup led
systems of weight 0 that possess seventh-order symmetry. we obtained 2 new
integrable systems that related bi-Hamiltonian formulations are constructed
too.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.0815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.0815</id><created>2013-08-04</created><updated>2013-12-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oguri</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solving a two-electron quantum dot model in terms of polynomial
  solutions of a Biconfluent Heun Equation</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics v. 347, pp. 130-140 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2014.04.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects on the non-relativistic dynamics of a system compound by two
electrons interacting by a Coulomb potential and with an external harmonic
oscillator potential, confined to move in a two dimensional Euclidean space,
are investigated. In particular, it is shown that it is possible to determine
exactly and in a closed form a finite portion of the energy spectrum and the
associated eigeinfunctions for the Schr\&quot;odinger equation describing the
relative motion of the electrons, by putting it into the form of a biconfluent
Heun equation. In the same framework, another set of solutions of this type can
be straightforwardly obtained for the case when the two electrons are submitted
also to an external constant magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.5085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.5085</id><created>2013-09-19</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Charbonneau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dyer</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jaehoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yaida</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author></authors><title>Linking dynamical heterogeneity to static amorphous order</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures; v4: one cavity data point (T=0.51, R=3.2) added.
  Data relevant to this work can be accessed at
  http://dx.doi.org/10.7924/G8VD6WC5</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP-4496</report-no><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 074004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/074004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Glass-forming liquids grow dramatically sluggish upon cooling. This slowdown
has long been thought to be accompanied by a growing correlation length.
Characteristic dynamical and static length scales, however, have been observed
to grow at different rates, which perplexes the relationship between the two
and with the slowdown. Here, we show the existence of a direct link between
dynamical sluggishness and static point-to-set correlations, holding at the
local level as we probe different environments within a liquid. This link,
which is stronger and more general than that observed with locally preferred
structures, suggests the existence of an intimate relationship between
structure and dynamics in a broader range of glass-forming liquids than
previously thought.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.2550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.2550</id><created>2014-05-11</created><updated>2014-09-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;nchmeyer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandelt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Komatsu Spergel Wandelt estimator for oscillations in the cosmic
  microwave background bispectrum</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures. Updated to match published version (A&amp;A).
  References added</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 570, A94 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201424179</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oscillating shapes of the primordial bispectrum are present in many
inflationary models. The Planck experiment has recently published measurements
of oscillating shapes, which were however limited to the efficient frequency
range of the used analysis method. Here we study the KSW estimator for
oscillations in the CMB bispectrum, that allows to examine arbitrary
oscillation frequencies for separable oscillating bispectrum shapes. We study
the precision with which amplitude, phase and frequency can be determined with
our estimator. An examination of the 3-point function in real space gives
further insight into the estimator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.6308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.6308</id><created>2014-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Jasche</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leclercq</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandelt</keyname><forenames>Benjamin D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Past and present cosmic structure in the SDSS DR7 main sample</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>27 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01 (2015) 036</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/01/036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a chrono-cosmography project, aiming at the inference of the four
dimensional formation history of the observed large scale structure from its
origin to the present epoch. To do so, we perform a full-scale Bayesian
analysis of the northern galactic cap of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS)
Data Release 7 main galaxy sample, relying on a fully probabilistic, physical
model of the non-linearly evolved density field. Besides inferring initial
conditions from observations, our methodology naturally and accurately
reconstructs non-linear features at the present epoch, such as walls and
filaments, corresponding to high-order correlation functions generated by
late-time structure formation. Our inference framework self-consistently
accounts for typical observational systematic and statistical uncertainties
such as noise, survey geometry and selection effects. We further account for
luminosity dependent galaxy biases and automatic noise calibration within a
fully Bayesian approach. As a result, this analysis provides highly-detailed
and accurate reconstructions of the present density field on scales larger than
$\sim~3$ Mpc$/h$, constrained by SDSS observations. This approach also leads to
the first quantitative inference of plausible formation histories of the
dynamic large scale structure underlying the observed galaxy distribution. The
results described in this work constitute the first full Bayesian non-linear
analysis of the cosmic large scale structure with the demonstrated capability
of uncertainty quantification. Some of these results will be made publicly
available along with this work. The level of detail of inferred results and the
high degree of control on observational uncertainties pave the path towards
high precision chrono-cosmography, the subject of simultaneously studying the
dynamics and the morphology of the inhomogeneous Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4895</id><created>2014-11-18</created><updated>2015-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perlingeiro</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oguri</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Does Dirac equation for a generalized Coulomb-like potential in D+1
  dimensional flat spacetime admit any solution for $D\geq 4$?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 359, pp. 73-79 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2015.04.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relativistic hydrogen atom in an Euclidean space-time of arbitrary number
of space dimensions ($D$) plus one time dimension is revisited. In particular,
numerical solutions of the radial Dirac equation for a generalized Coulombian
potential proportional to $1/r^{(D-2)}$ are investigated. It is argued that one
could not find any physical solution for $D\geq 4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7471</id><created>2014-11-26</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Acosta-Hum&#xe1;nez</keyname><forenames>Primitivo B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machado-Higuera</keyname><forenames>Maximiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinitsyn</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A model of anaerobic digestion for biogas production using Abel
  equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><msc-class>12H05, 34A05, 34A34, 90B30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some time ago has been studied mathematical models for biogas production due
to its importance in the use of control and optimization of re\-new\-able
resources and clean energy. In this paper we combine two algebraic methods to
obtain solutions of Abel equation of first kind that arise from a mathematical
model to biogas production formulated in France on 2001. The aim of this paper
is obtain Liouvillian solutions of Abel's equations through Hamiltonian
Algebrization. As an illustration, we present graphics of solutions for Abel
equations and solutions for algebrized Abel equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.7768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.7768</id><created>2014-12-24</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramachandra</keyname><forenames>Nesar S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shandarin</keyname><forenames>Sergei F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-stream portrait of the Cosmic web</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 25 figures. Matches version accepted by MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society (2015) 452 (2):
  1643-1653</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1389</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results of the first study of the multi-stream environment of
dark matter haloes in cosmological N-body simulations in the LCDM cosmology.
The full dynamical state of dark matter can be described as a three-dimensional
sub-manifold in six dimensional phase space - the dark matter sheet. In our
study we use a Lagrangian sub-manifold x = x(q,t) (where x and q are co-moving
Eulerian and Lagrangian coordinates respectively), which is dynamically
equivalent to the dark matter sheet but is more convenient for numerical
analysis. Our major results can be summarized as follows. At the resolution of
the simulation i.e. without additional smoothing, the cosmic web represents a
hierarchical structure: each halo is embedded in the filamentary framework of
the web predominantly at the filament crossings, and each filament is embedded
in the wall like fabric of the web at the wall crossings. Locally, each halo or
sub-halo is a peak in the number of streams field. The number of streams in the
neighbouring filaments is higher than in the neighbouring walls. The walls are
regions where number of streams is equal to three or a few. Voids are uniquely
defined by the local condition requiring to be a single-stream flow region. The
shells of streams around haloes are quite thin and the closest void region is
typically within one and a half FOF radius from the center of the halo.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.05437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.05437</id><created>2015-01-22</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huitu</keyname><forenames>Katri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rindani</keyname><forenames>Saurabh D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Pankaj</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective fermion-Higgs interactions at an $e^+e^-$ collider with
  polarized beams</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 11 figures, 6 tables, Matches with the Published Version</comments><report-no>ADP-15-14/T903, HIP-2015-4/TH</report-no><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics B (2016), pp. 274-294</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.08.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the possibility of new physics giving rise to effective
interactions of the form $e^+e^-Hf \bar f$, where $f$ represents a charged
lepton $\ell$ or a (light) quark $q$, and $H$ the recently discovered Higgs
boson. Such vertices would give contributions beyond the standard model to the
Higgs production processes $e^+e^- \to H\ell^+\ell^-$ and $e^+e^- \to H q \bar
q$ at a future $e^+e^-$ collider. We write the most general form for these
vertices allowed by Lorentz symmetry. Assuming that such interactions
contribute in addition to the standard model production processes, where the
final-state fermion pair comes from the decay of the $Z$ boson, we obtain the
differential cross section for the processes $e^+e^- \to H\ell^+\ell^-$ and
$e^+e^- \to Hq\bar q$ to linear order in the effective interactions. We propose
several observables with differing CP and T properties which, if measured, can
be used to constrain the couplings occurring in interaction vertices. We derive
possible limits on these couplings that may be obtained at a collider with
centre-of-mass energy of 500 GeV and an integrated luminosity of 500 fb$^{-1}$.
We also carry out the analysis assuming that both the electron and positron
beams can be longitudinally polarized, and find that the sensitivity to the
couplings can be improved by a factor of 2-4 by a specific choice of the signs
of the polarizations of both the electron and positron beams for the same
integrated luminosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03964</id><created>2015-03-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Shunsuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hisakado</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactive Restless Multi-armed Bandit Game and Swarm Intelligence
  Effect</title><categories>cs.AI cs.LG physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>New generation computing, vol.34, No. 3, 291-306, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00354-016-0306-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain the conditions for the emergence of the swarm intelligence effect
in an interactive game of restless multi-armed bandit (rMAB). A player competes
with multiple agents. Each bandit has a payoff that changes with a probability
$p_{c}$ per round. The agents and player choose one of three options: (1)
Exploit (a good bandit), (2) Innovate (asocial learning for a good bandit among
$n_{I}$ randomly chosen bandits), and (3) Observe (social learning for a good
bandit). Each agent has two parameters $(c,p_{obs})$ to specify the decision:
(i) $c$, the threshold value for Exploit, and (ii) $p_{obs}$, the probability
for Observe in learning. The parameters $(c,p_{obs})$ are uniformly
distributed. We determine the optimal strategies for the player using complete
knowledge about the rMAB. We show whether or not social or asocial learning is
more optimal in the $(p_{c},n_{I})$ space and define the swarm intelligence
effect. We conduct a laboratory experiment (67 subjects) and observe the swarm
intelligence effect only if $(p_{c},n_{I})$ are chosen so that social learning
is far more optimal than asocial learning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04360</id><created>2015-05-17</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amano</keyname><forenames>Ken-ichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement theory of a density profile of colloid particles on a flat
  surface: Conversion of force acting on a colloidal probe into pressure on its
  surface element</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, we proposed a method that converts the force between two-large
colloids into the pressure on the surface element (FPSE conversion) in a system
of a colloidal solution. Using it, the density distribution of the small
colloids around the large colloid is calculated. In a similar manner, in this
letter, we propose a transform theory for colloidal probe atomic force
microscopy (colloidal probe AFM), which transforms the force acting on the
colloidal probe into the density distribution of the small colloids on a flat
surface. If measured condition is proper one, in our view, it is possible for
the transform theory to be applied for liquid AFM and obtain the liquid
structure. The transform theory we derived is briefly explained in this letter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07559</id><created>2015-06-24</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zobov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shatilov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milardi</keyname><forenames>Catia</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Santis</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drago</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallo</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of Crab Waist Collisions In DA{\Phi}NE With KLOE-2
  Interaction Region</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>5 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>FERMILAB-CONF-15-170-APC</report-no><doi>10.1109/TNS.2016.2536439</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After the successful completion of the SIDDHARTA experiment run with crab
waist collisions, the electron- positron collider DA{\Phi}NE has started
routine operations for the KLOE-2 detector. The new interaction region also
exploits the crab waist collision scheme, but features certain complications
including the experimental detector solenoid, compensating anti-solenoids, and
tilted quadrupole magnets. We have performed simulations of the beam-beam
collisions in the collider taking into account the real DA{\Phi}NE nonlinear
lattice. In particular, we have evaluated the effect of crab waist sextupoles
and beam-beam interactions on the DA{\Phi}NE dynamical aperture and energy
acceptance, and estimated the luminosity that can be potentially achieved with
and without crab waist sextupoles in the present working conditions. A
numerical analysis has been performed in order to propose possible steps for
further luminosity increase in DA{\Phi}NE such as a better working point
choice, crab sextupole strength optimization, correction of the phase advance
between the sextupoles and the interaction region. The proposed change of the
e- ring working point was implemented and resulted in a significant performance
increase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02172</id><created>2015-07-08</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Katrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Melanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melnikov</keyname><forenames>Ilarion V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robbins</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Royston</keyname><forenames>Andrew B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Some tree-level string amplitudes in the NSR formalism</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>40+8 pages; v2: references added; v3: additional field theory checks
  made; published version; v4: minor corrections; results unchanged</comments><report-no>MI-TH-1515</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 12 (2015) 010</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2015)010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate tree level scattering amplitudes for open strings using the NSR
formalism. We present a streamlined symmetry-based and pedagogical approach to
the computations, which we first develop by checking two-, three-, and
four-point functions involving bosons and fermions. We calculate the five-point
amplitude for massless gluons and find agreement with an earlier result by
Brandt, Machado and Medina. We then compute the five-point amplitudes involving
two and four fermions respectively, the general form of which has not been
previously obtained in the NSR formalism. The results nicely confirm
expectations from the supersymmetric $F^4$ effective action. Finally we use the
prescription of Kawai, Lewellen and Tye (KLT) to compute the amplitudes for the
closed string sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07910</id><created>2015-08-31</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lo</keyname><forenames>Hoi-kwong</forenames></author></authors><title>Blind Quantum Computing with Decoy States</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>The paper has been withdrawn by the author due to potential text
  overlap with another paper and is currently under revision</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the Universal Blind Quantum Computing (UBQC)
protocol, which allows a client to perform quantum computation on a remote
quantum server and the Remote Blind qubit state Preparation (RBSP) protocol
which allows the client to prepare single qubits on the server's location with
week coherent pulses. This RBSP protocol is inefficient for small $ T $,
because the required number of pulses for generating one single qubit scales as
$ \mbox{O}(1/T^4) $, where $ T $ is the transmittance of the quantum channe
between the client and the server.
  Our contribution in this paper is a modified RBSP protocol with decoy states.
This new protocol allows us to generate $ S $ single qubits simultaneously in a
single instance. With our new rotocol, we are able to reduce the number of weak
coherent pulses required for generating one single qubit from $ \mbox{O}(1/T^4)
$ to nearly $ \mbox{O}(1/T) $, significantly increasing the efficiency. For a
100 km standard telecom fiber of loss 0.2 dB/km, our method gives a six orders
of magnitude improvement in the speed, which is very significant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02227</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2015-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Assi</keyname><forenames>Hiba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaturvedi</keyname><forenames>Harshwardhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobramysl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pleimling</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tauber</keyname><forenames>Uwe C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disordered vortex matter out of equilibrium: a Langevin molecular
  dynamics study</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, to appear in Molecular Simulation for a special
  issue on &quot;Nonequilibrium Systems&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Molecular Simulation 42 (2016) 1401</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/08927022.2015.1119826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the use of Langevin molecular dynamics in the investigation of the
non-equilibrium properties of disordered vortex matter. Our special focus is
set on values of system parameters that are realistic for disordered high-$T_c$
superconductors such as YBCO. Using a discretized elastic line model, we study
different aspects of vortices far from thermal equilibrium. On the one hand we
investigate steady-state properties of driven magnetic flux lines in a
disordered environment, namely the current-voltage characteristics, the
gyration radius, and the pinning time statistics. On the other hand we study
the complex relaxation processes and glassy-like dynamics that emerge in
type-II superconductors due to the intricate competition between the long-range
vortex-vortex repulsion and flux pinning due to randomly placed point defects.
To this end we consider different types of sudden perturbations: temperature,
magnetic field, and external current quenches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04260</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-03-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Richartz</keyname><forenames>Maur&#xed;cio</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasinormal modes of extremal black holes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>v4: 16 pages, 9 figures. A mode stability analysis for extremal black
  holes has been included. Published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 064062 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.064062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The continued fraction method (also known as Leaver's method) is one of the
most effective techniques used to determine the quasinormal modes of a black
hole. For extremal black holes, however, the method does not work (since, in
such a case, the event horizon is an irregular singular point of the associated
wave equation). Fortunately, there exists a modified version of the method,
devised by Onozawa et al. [Phys. Rev. D 53, 7033 (1996)], which works for
neutral massless fields around an extremal Reissner-Nordstrom black hole. In
this paper, we generalize the ideas of Onozawa et al. to charged massless
perturbations around an extremal Reissner-Nordstrom black hole and to neutral
massless perturbations around an extremal Kerr black hole. Similarities and
differences between the results of the original continued fraction method for
near extremal black holes and the results of the new continued fraction method
for extremal black holes are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01196</id><created>2015-09-24</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kober</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>\&quot;Uber die Beziehung der begrifflichen Grundlagen der Quantentheorie und
  der Allgemeinen Relativit\&quot;atstheorie</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>179 pages, 4 figures, Dissertation (in German). Published by:
  Suedwestdeutscher Verlag fuer Hochschulschriften, Saarbruecken 2011 (main
  title: Die Konstituierung der Raum-Zeit in einer einheitlichen Naturtheorie)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this dissertation the question of the unification of quantum theory and
general relativity is treated. Based on the conceptual structure of these
theories and under incorporation of certain ideas from classical philosophy
there are formulated arguments for the assertion that these two fundamental
theories of nature can only be led to a unification in the framework of a
description, in which space-time is not presupposed but constituted by a more
fundamental physical reality. Under this precondition an own model to derive
the mathematical structure of general relativity from a unified quantum field
theory of spinors is developed. In addition the quantum theory of fundamental
binary logical alternatives, which has been conceived by Carl Friedrich von
Weizs\&quot;acker in the second half of the twentieth century and in which the
existence of physical space and his properties is a consequence of quantum
theory, is treated elaborately and considered with respect to the question of
the unification of quantum theory and general relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03496</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;tt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Locht</keyname><forenames>I. L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xe5;n&#xe4;s</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eriksson</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Marco</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic continuation by averaging Pad\'e approximants</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 075104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.075104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ill-posed analytic continuation problem for Green's functions and
self-energies is investigated by revisiting the Pad\'{e} approximants
technique. We propose to remedy the well-known problems of the Pad\'{e}
approximants by performing an average of several continuations, obtained by
varying the number of fitted input points and Pad\'{e} coefficients
independently. The suggested approach is then applied to several test cases,
including Sm and Pr atomic self-energies, the Green's functions of the Hubbard
model for a Bethe lattice and of the Haldane model for a nano-ribbon, as well
as two special test functions. The sensitivity to numerical noise and the
dependence on the precision of the numerical libraries are analysed in detail.
The present approach is compared to a number of other techniques, i.e. the
non-negative least-square method, the non-negative Tikhonov method and the
maximum entropy method, and is shown to perform well for the chosen test cases.
This conclusion holds even when the noise on the input data is increased to
reach values typical for quantum Monte Carlo simulations. The ability of the
algorithm to resolve fine structures is finally illustrated for two relevant
test functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04941</id><created>2015-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Wunderlich</keyname><forenames>Falk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampfer</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Imprints of a critical point on photon emission</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, contribution to the NICA White Paper</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 262</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16262-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The linear sigma model with linearized fluctuations of all involved fields
facilitates the onset of a sequence of first-order phase transitions at a
critical point. This phase structure has distinctive imprints on the photon
emission rates. We argue that analogously a critical point in the QCD phase
diagram manifests itself by peculiarities of the photon spectra, in particular
when the dynamical expansion path of matter crosses the phase transition curve
in the vicinity of the critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03515</id><created>2015-12-10</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tada</keyname><forenames>Yuichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Can massive primordial black holes be produced in mild waterfall hybrid
  inflation?</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>1+19 pages, 5 figures, JCAP accepted version with updated figures</comments><report-no>IPMU 15-0205</report-no><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We studied the possibility whether the massive primordial black holes (PBHs)
surviving today can be produced in hybrid inflation. Though it is of great
interest since such PBHs can be the candidate for dark matter or seeds of the
supermassive black holes in galaxies, there have not been quantitatively
complete works yet because of the non-perturbative behavior around the critical
point of hybrid inflation. Therefore, combining the stochastic and $\delta N$
formalism, we numerically calculated the curvature perturbations in a
non-perturbative way and found, without any specific assumption of the types of
hybrid inflation, PBHs are rather overproduced when the waterfall phase of
hybrid inflation continues so long that the PBH scale is well enlarged and the
corresponding PBH mass becomes sizable enough.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05021</id><created>2015-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ameen</keyname><forenames>Tarek A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilatikhameneh</keyname><forenames>Hesameddin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimeck</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>Rajib</forenames></author></authors><title>Few-layer Phosphorene: An Ideal 2D Material For Tunnel Transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Scientific reports 6 (2016): 28515</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep28515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  2D transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) have attracted a lot of attention
recently for energy-efficient tunneling-field-effect transistor (TFET)
applications due to their excellent gate control resulting from their
atomically thin dimensions. However, most TMDs have bandgaps (Eg) and effective
masses (m*) outside the optimum range needed for high performance. It is shown
here that the newly discovered 2D material, few-layer phosphorene, has several
properties ideally suited for TFET applications: 1) direct Eg in the optimum
range ~1.0-0.4 eV, 2) light transport m* (0.15m0), 3) anisotropic m* which
increases the density of states near the band edges, and 4) a high mobility.
These properties combine to provide phosphorene TFET outstanding ION 1 mA/um,
ON/OFF ratio~1e6, scalability to 6 nm channel length and 0.2 V supply voltage,
thereby significantly outperforming the best TMD-TFETs in energy-delay
products. Full-band atomistic quantum transport simulations establish
phosphorene TFETs as serious candidates for energy-eficient and scalable
replacements of MOSFETs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06472</id><created>2015-12-20</created><updated>2016-02-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shao-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>De-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>Charged scalar gravitational collapse in de Sitter spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>16pages, 8 figures. Accepted by PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 064036 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.064036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the charged scalar collapse in de Sitter spacetimes. With the
electric charge, there is one more competitor to join the competition of
dynamics in the gravitational collapse. We find that two factors can influence
the electric charge. If we just adjust the charge conjugation, the electric
charge effect is always perturbative at the black hole threshold. The electric
charge can also be influenced by the initial conditions of perturbations. These
initial parameters can be tuned to control the competition in dynamics and
present us new and rich physics in the process of gravitational collapse. We
give physical explanations on these phenomena found in dynamics. Furthermore we
show that the properties of the gravitational collapse are universal and do not
depend on spacetime dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08483</id><created>2015-12-28</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauly</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>On Korn's First Inequality for Mixed Tangential and Normal Boundary
  Conditions on Bounded Lipschitz-Domains in $\mathbb{R}^N$</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>49J40 / 82C40 / 76P05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that for bounded Lipschitz domains in $\mathbb{R}^N$ Korn's first
inequality holds for vector fields satisfying homogeneous mixed normal and
tangential boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01018</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>Fabiano M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>A. G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vicentini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Luz</keyname><forenames>M. G. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Green's function approach for quantum graphs: an overview</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>54 pages, 24 figures, 1 table. Two sections expanded + minor
  modifications. One appendix added. References added. To appear in Physics
  Reports</comments><journal-ref>Physics Reports 647, 1-46 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2016.07.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we review the many aspects and distinct phenomena associated to quantum
dynamics on general graph structures. For so, we discuss such class of systems
under the energy domain Green's function ($G$) framework. This approach is
particularly interesting because $G$ can be written as a sum over
classical-like paths, where local quantum effects are taking into account
through the scattering matrix amplitudes (basically, transmission and
reflection amplitudes) defined on each one of the graph vertices. Hence, the
{\em exact} $G$ has the functional form of a generalized semiclassical formula,
which through different calculation techniques (addressed in details here)
always can be cast into a closed analytic expression. It allows to solve
exactly arbitrary large (although finite) graphs in a recursive and fast way.
Using the Green's function method, we survey many properties for open and
closed quantum graphs as scattering solutions for the former and eigenspectrum
and eigenstates for the latter, also considering quasi-bound states. Concrete
examples, like cube, binary trees and Sierpi\'{n}ski-like topologies are
presented. Along the work, possible distinct applications using the Green's
function methods for quantum graphs are outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01603</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liechty</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Two Lax systems for the Painlev\'e II equation, and two related kernels
  in random matrix theory</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.CA math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>46 pages, 20 figures</comments><msc-class>34M55, 33E17, 30E20, 60B20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider two Lax systems for the homogeneous Painlev\'{e} II equation: one
of size $2\times 2$ studied by Flaschka and Newell in the early 1980's, and one
of size $4\times 4$ introduced by Delvaux-Kuijlaars-Zhang and Duits-Geudens in
the early 2010's. We prove that solutions to the $4\times 4$ system can be
derived from those to the $2\times 2$ system via an integral transform, and
consequently relate the Stokes multipliers for the two systems. As corollaries
we are able to express two kernels for determinantal processes as contour
integrals involving the Flaschka-Newell Lax system: the tacnode kernel arising
in models of nonintersecting paths, and a critical kernel arising in a
two-matrix model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04152</id><created>2016-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Stich</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rib&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Josep M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hochberg</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral autocatalysis: reaction noise, micro-reversibility and chiral
  inhibition in mirror symmetry breaking</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 Figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 074111 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Applying the constraints dictated by the principle of detailed balance, we
analyze a recent proposal for spontaneous mirror symmetry breaking (SMSB) based
on enantioselective autocatalysis coupled to a linear decay of the enantiomers
and in the presence of reaction noise. We find the racemic state is the final
stable outcome for both deterministic as well as for stochastic dynamics, and
for both well-mixed and small spatially-coupled systems. The racemic outcome
results even when the autocatalytic cycles are driven irreversibly by external
reagents, in manifestly non-equilibrium conditions. Our findings suggest that
first-order autocatalysis coupled to reactions involving \textit{non-linear}
heterochiral dynamics is a necessary pre-condition for any mechanism purporting
to lead to molecular homochirality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04700</id><created>2016-01-18</created><updated>2016-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mazharimousavi</keyname><forenames>S. Habib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halilsoy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Black holes from multiplets of scalar fields in 2+1- and 3+1-dimensions</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures, final version accepted for publication in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C, 76, 458 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4309-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain classes of black hole solutions constructed from multiplets of
scalar fields in 2+1 / 3+1 dimensions. The multi-component scalars don't
undergo a symmetry breaking so that only the isotropic modulus is effective.
The Lagrangian is supplemented by a self-interacting potential which plays
significant role in obtaining the exact solutions. In 2+1 / 3+1 dimensions
doublet / triplet of scalars is effective which enriches the available black
hole spacetimes and creates useful Liouville weighted field theoretic models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00046</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-05-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Topcu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derevianko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Possibility of triple magic trapping of clock and Rydberg states of
  divalent atoms in optical lattices</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. B 49, 144004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/14/144004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We predict the possibility of &quot;triply-magic&quot; optical lattice trapping of
neutral divalent atoms. In such a lattice, the ${^1}\!S_{0}$ and ${^3}\!P_{0}$
clock states and an additional Rydberg state experience identical optical
potentials, fully mitigating detrimental effects of the motional decoherence.
In particular, we show that this triply magic trapping condition can be
satisfied for Yb atom at optical wavelengths and for various other divalent
systems (Ca, Mg, Hg and Sr) in the UV region. We assess the quality of triple
magic trapping conditions by estimating the probability of excitation out of
the motional ground state as a result of the excitations between the clock and
the Rydberg states. We also calculate trapping laser-induced photoionization
rates of divalent Rydberg atoms at magic frequencies. We find that such rates
are below the radiative spontaneous-emission rates, due to the presence of
Cooper minima in photoionization cross-sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05308</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear optomechanics with gain and loss: amplifying higher-order
  sideband and group delay</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>Final version, accepted by New J. Phys</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 083034</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/8/083034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the nonlinear optomechanically-induced transparency (OMIT) with gain
and loss. We find that (i) for a single active cavity, significant enhancement
can be achieved for the higher-order sidebands, including the transmission rate
and the group delay; (ii) for active- passive-coupled cavities, hundreds of
microsecond of optical delay or advance are attainable for the nonlinear
sideband pulses in the parity-time-symmetric regime. The active higher-order
OMIT effects, as firstly revealed here, open up the way to make a low-power
optomechaical amplifier, which can amplify both the strength and group delay of
not only the probe light but also its higher-order sidebands.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05387</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vermeersch</keyname><forenames>Bjorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shakouri</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Limitations of generalised grey phonon models for quasiballistic thermal
  transport in time-periodic regimes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Suitably superimposed grey-medium solutions of the Boltzmann transport
equation (BTE) provide a simple yet accurate description of non-grey
quasiballistic heat conduction in transient thermal grating experiments. Recent
applications of similar strategies based on kinetic and
McKelvey-Schockley-Landauer theory to time-periodic transport predicted notable
conductivity suppression only at heating frequencies comparable to phonon
scattering rates, in contrast to lengthscale criteria observed by several prior
studies. Here we show that the frequency-integrated grey-medium approximation
(FIGMA) is ill suited to tackle temporally periodic quasiballistic transport.
Starting from first-principles phonon dispersions and scattering rates, we
obtain semi-analytic 1D BTE solutions for semi-infinite structures subjected to
sinusoidal surface heating and compare these to the approximate model
counterparts. We find FIGMA-based approaches to overestimate the semiconductor
surface temperature by up to one and characteristic heating frequencies for
onset of quasiballistic effects by up to three orders of magnitude
respectively. Our study reasserts that experimentally observed
heating-frequency dependent apparent conductivities originate in the overlap of
the characteristic length scale of the thermal gradient with phonon mean free
paths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05648</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okorokov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames><affiliation>National Research Nuclear University MEPhI</affiliation></author></authors><title>NICA fixed target mode: soft jet studies in the relative 4-velocity
  space</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, 1 table. Contribution to the Topical Issue &quot;NICA
  White Paper&quot;. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1308.2406</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A52, 256 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16256-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental results obtained by studying the properties of soft jets in the
4-velocity space at $\sqrt{s} \sim 2-20$ GeV are presented. The changes in the
mean distance from the jet axis to the jet particles, the mean kinetic energy
of these particles, and the cluster dimension in response to the growth of the
collision energy are consistent with the assumption that quark degrees of
freedom manifest themselves in processes of pion jet production at intermediate
energies. The energy at which quark degrees of freedom begin to manifest
themselves experimentally in the production of soft pion jets is estimated for
the first time. The estimated value of this energy is $2.8 \pm 0.6$ GeV. The
suggestions are made for future investigations on NICA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05653</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okorokov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames><affiliation>National Research Nuclear University MEPhI</affiliation></author></authors><title>NICA-MPD: azimuthal and femtoscopic particle correlations</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. Contribution to the Topical Issue &quot;NICA White
  Paper&quot;. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1301.0880</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A52, 255 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16255-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discussion is focused on the study of the fundamental symmetries
($\mathcal{P/CP}$) of QCD and geometry of the particle source. The combination
of correlators corresponding to the absolute asymmetry of distribution of
electrically charged particles with respect to the reaction plane in heavy ion
collisions is studied. A significant decrease of the absolute asymmetry is
observed in the intermediate energy range which can be considered as indication
of possible transition to predominance of hadronic states over quark-gluon
degrees of freedom in the mixed phase created in heavy ion collisions at
intermediate energies. For the investigation of the energy evolution of the
geometric properties of the particle source the use of femtoscopic radii scaled
on the averaged radius of colliding ions is suggested. This approach allows the
expansion of the set of interaction types, in particular, on the collisions of
non-symmetrical ion beams which can be studied within the framework of common
treatment. There is no sharp changing of femtoscopic parameter values with
increasing of the initial energy. The suggestions are made for future
advancement of these studies on NICA-MPD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05845</id><created>2016-02-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Laflamme</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budich</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalmonte</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium $8\pi$ Josephson Effect in Atomic Kitaev Wires</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 7, 12280 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12280</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study a Kitaev wire interrupted by an extra site which gives
rise to super exchange coupling between two Majorana bound states. We show that
this system hosts a tunable, non-equlibrium Josephson effect with a
characteristic $8\pi$ periodicity of the Josephson current. We elucidate the
physical mechanism deriving a minimal model for the junction and confirm its
quantitative accuracy by comparison to the numerical solution of the full
model. The visibility of the $8\pi$ periodicity of the Josephson current is
then studied using time-dependent simulations including the effects of
dephasing and particle losses. Our findings provide a novel signature of
Majorana quasi-particles which is qualitatively different form the behavior of
a conventional superconductor, and can be experimentally verified in cold atom
systems using alkaline-earth-like atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07384</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baxter</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clampitt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giannantonio</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodelson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huterer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleem</keyname><forenames>L. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efstathiou</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fosalba</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Story</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troxel</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbott</keyname><forenames>T. M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armstrong</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benoit-L&#xe9;vy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benson</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernstein</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernstein</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlstrom</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosell</keyname><forenames>A. Carnero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kind</keyname><forenames>M. Carrasco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretero</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chown</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crocce</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Costa</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>H. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evrard</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>A. Fausti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaugher</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frieman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruendl</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Haan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holder</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honscheid</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuropatkin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>March</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchior</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miquel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omori</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plazas</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichardt</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romer</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla-Noarbe</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheldon</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares-Santos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreira</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suchyta</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stark</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swanson</keyname><forenames>M. E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarle</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wechsler</keyname><forenames>R. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Joint Measurement of Lensing-Galaxy Correlations Using SPT and DES SV
  Data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. This version
  has been revised in response to referee comments</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (October 01, 2016) 461 (4): 4099-4114</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1584</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measure the correlation of galaxy lensing and cosmic microwave background
lensing with a set of galaxies expected to trace the matter density field. The
measurements are performed using pre-survey Dark Energy Survey (DES) Science
Verification optical imaging data and millimeter-wave data from the 2500 square
degree South Pole Telescope Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (SPT-SZ) survey. The two
lensing-galaxy correlations are jointly fit to extract constraints on
cosmological parameters, constraints on the redshift distribution of the lens
galaxies, and constraints on the absolute shear calibration of DES galaxy
lensing measurements. We show that an attractive feature of these fits is that
they are fairly insensitive to the clustering bias of the galaxies used as
matter tracers. The measurement presented in this work confirms that DES and
SPT data are consistent with each other and with the currently favored
$\Lambda$CDM cosmological model. It also demonstrates that joint lensing-galaxy
correlation measurement considered here contains a wealth of information that
can be extracted using current and future surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01409</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>L&#xf6;rch</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amitai</keyname><forenames>Ehud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunnenkamp</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruder</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Genuine quantum signatures in synchronization of anharmonic
  self-oscillators</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 073601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.073601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the synchronization of a van der Pol self-oscillator with Kerr
anharmonicity to an external drive. We demonstrate that the anharmonic,
discrete energy spectrum of the quantum oscillator leads to multiple resonances
in both phase locking and frequency entrainment not present in the
corresponding classical system. Strong driving close to these resonances leads
to nonclassical steady-state Wigner distributions. Experimental realizations of
these genuine quantum signatures can be implemented with current technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01492</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Massat</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karlsson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strobel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toulemonde</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Measson</keyname><forenames>M. -A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cazayous</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sacuto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasahara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibuachi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallais</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge induced nematicity in FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures + SI</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. (USA) 113 (33), 9177-9181 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1606562113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spontaneous appearance of nematicity, a state of matter that breaks
rotation but not translation symmetry, is one of the most intriguing property
of the iron based superconductors (Fe SC), and has relevance for the cuprates
as well. Establishing the critical electronic modes behind nematicity remains
however a challenge, because their associated susceptibilities are not easily
accessible by conventional probes. Here using FeSe as a model system, and
symmetry resolved electronic Raman scattering as a probe, we unravel the
presence of critical charge nematic fluctuations near the structural / nematic
transition temperature, T$_S\sim$ 90 K. The diverging behavior of the
associated nematic susceptibility foretells the presence of a Pomeranchuk
instability of the Fermi surface with d-wave symmetry. The excellent scaling
between the observed nematic susceptibility and elastic modulus data
demonstrates that the structural distortion is driven by this d-wave
Pomeranchuk transition. Our results make a strong case for charge induced
nematicity in FeSe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02082</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitchison</keyname><forenames>Mark T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prior</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Mischa P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plenio</keyname><forenames>Martin B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Realising a quantum absorption refrigerator with an atom-cavity system</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>13+4 pages. Updated to published version, replacing a previous
  submission titled &quot;Autonomous quantum thermal machines in atom-cavity
  systems&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology 1, 015001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/1/1/015001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An autonomous quantum thermal machine comprising a trapped atom or ion placed
inside an optical cavity is proposed and analysed. Such a machine can operate
as a heat engine whose working medium is the quantised atomic motion, or as an
absorption refrigerator which cools without any work input. Focusing on the
refrigerator mode, we predict that it is possible with state-of-the-art
technology to cool a trapped ion almost to its motional ground state using a
thermal light source such as sunlight. We nonetheless find that a laser or
similar reference system is necessary to stabilise the cavity frequencies.
Furthermore, we establish a direct and heretofore unacknowledged connection
between the abstract theory of quantum absorption refrigerators and practical
sideband cooling techniques. We also highlight and clarify some assumptions
underlying several recent theoretical studies on self-contained quantum engines
and refrigerators. Our work indicates that cavity quantum electrodynamics is a
promising and versatile experimental platform for the study of autonomous
thermal machines in the quantum domain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03188</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-05-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhigang</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluid dynamics: an emerging route for the scalable production of
  graphene in the last five years</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 figures</comments><journal-ref>RSC Adv., 2016,6, 72525-72536</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6RA15269D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bulk applications of graphene in fields such as advanced composites,
conductive ink, and energy storage require cheap and scalable graphene.
Fortunately, in the last decade, liquid-phase exfoliation of graphite to give
pristine graphene has been thought as a promising way to massive production of
graphene at high efficiency and low cost, in terms of the cheap and abundant
graphite source and a variety of cost-effective exfoliation techniques. Though
many exfoliation techniques are available so far, this article will highlight
the recent progress of fluid dynamics route which emerges as a promising
scalable and efficient way for graphene production in the last five years. The
emphasis is set on vortex fluidic devices and pressure- and mixer-driven fluid
dynamics, with our perspectives on the latest progress, exfoliation mechanism,
and some key issues that require further study in order to realize industrial
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03628</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hammar</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fransson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent spin and transport properties of a single-molecule magnet
  in a tunnel junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 15 figures; submitted</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 054311 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.054311</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In single-molecule magnets, the exchange between a localized spin moment and
the electronic background provides a suitable laboratory for studies of
dynamical aspects of both local spin and transport properties. Here we address
the time evolution of a localized spin moment coupled to an electronic level in
a molecular quantum dot embedded in a tunnel junction between metallic leads.
The interactions between the localized spin moment and the electronic level
generate an effective interaction between the spin moment at different
instances in time. Therefore, we show that, despite being a single-spin system,
there are effective contributions of isotropic Heisenberg, and anisotropic
Ising and Dzyaloshinski-Moriya character acting on the spin moment. The
interactions can be controlled by gate voltage, voltage bias, the spin
polarization in the leads, in addition to external magnetic fields. Signatures
of the spin dynamics are found in the transport properties of the tunneling
system, and we demonstrate that measurements of the spin current may be used
for read-out of the local spin moment orientation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09394</id><created>2016-03-30</created><updated>2016-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yichao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Size Effects in the Terahertz Nonlinear Response of Metallic
  Armchair Graphene Nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Quantum Electronics, VOL. 23,
  NO. 1, 5100108, Jan.-Feb. 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/JSTQE.2016.2564402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use time dependent perturbation theory to study quantum size effects on
the terahertz nonlinear response of metallic graphene armchair nanoribbons of
finite length under an applied electric field. Our work shows that quantization
due to the finite length of the nanoribbon, the applied field profile, and the
broadening of the graphene spectrum all play a significant role in the
resulting nonlinear conductances. In certain cases, these effects can
significantly enhance the nonlinearity over that for infinitely-long metallic
armchair graphene nanoribbon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09677</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09677</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Hongming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudo-Spin, Real-Spin and Spin Polarization of Photo-emitted Electrons</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 085123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we discuss the connections between pseudo spin, real spin of
electrons in material and spin polarization of photo-emitted electrons out of
material. By investigating these three spin textures for Bi$_2$Se$_3$ and
SmB$_6$ compounds, we find that the spin orientation of photo-electrons for
SmB$_6$ has different correspondence to pseudo spin and real spin compare to
Bi$_2$Se$_3$, due to the different symmetry properties of the photo-emission
matrix between initial and final states. We calculate the spin polarization and
circular dichroism spectra of photo-emitted electrons for both compounds, which
can be detected by spin-resolved and circular dichroism angle resolved
photo-emission spectroscopy experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03467</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ooshida</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of displacement correlation tensor indicating vortical
  cooperative motion in two-dimensional colloidal liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures; &quot;X&quot; in math intended as a capital &quot;chi&quot;;
  accepted by Phys. Rev. E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 022125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As an indicator of cooperative motion in a system of Brownian particles that
models two-dimensional colloidal liquids, displacement correlation tensor is
calculated analytically and compared with numerical results. The key idea for
the analytical calculation is to relate the displacement correlation tensor,
which is a kind of four-point space-time correlation, to the Lagrangian
two-time correlation of the deformation gradient tensor. Tensorial treatment of
the statistical quantities, including the displacement correlation itself,
allows capturing the vortical structure of the cooperative motion. The
calculated displacement correlation also implies a negative longtime tail in
the velocity autocorrelation, which is a manifestation of the cage effect. Both
the longitudinal and transverse components of the displacement correlation are
found to be expressible in terms of a similarity variable, suggesting that the
cages are nested to form a self-similar structure in the space-time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03914</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brod</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gea-Banacloche</keyname><forenames>Julio</forenames></author></authors><title>Two photons co- and counter-propagating through $N$ cross-Kerr sites</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages (+ appendix), 7 figures. V2: New author added. Content
  expanded with new results (Sec. VIII). V3: Closer to published version. See
  companion paper at http://arxiv.org/abs/1604.04278</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 023833 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.023833</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A cross-Kerr interaction produces a phase shift on two modes of light
proportional to the number of photons in both modes, and is sometimes called
cross-phase modulation. Cross-Kerr nonlinearities have many applications in
classical and quantum nonlinear optics, including the possibility of a
deterministic and all-optical controlled-phase gate. We calculate the one- and
two-photon S-matrix for fields propagating in a medium where the cross-Kerr
interaction is spatially distributed at discrete interaction sites comprised of
atoms. For the interactions considered, we analyze the cases where the photons
co-propagate and counter-propagate through the medium and give a physical
interpretation to the differences between the two cases. Finally, we obtain the
S-matrix in the limit of infinitely long chains, showing that it corresponds to
a perfect controlled-phase operation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04030</id><created>2016-04-14</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yugui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shengyuan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicted Unusual Magnetoresponse in Type-II Weyl Semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 077202 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.077202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show several distinct signatures in the magneto-response of type-II Weyl
semimetals. The energy tilt tends to squeeze the Landau levels (LLs), and for a
type-II Weyl node, there always exists a critical angle between the B-fileld
and the tilt, at which the LL spectrum collapses, regardless of the fileld
strength. Before collapse, signatures also appear in the magneto-optical
spectrum, including the invariable presence of intraband peaks, the absence of
absorption tails, and the special anisotropic fileld dependence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04278</id><created>2016-04-14</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brod</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author></authors><title>A passive CPHASE gate via cross-Kerr nonlinearities</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages (+ appendix), 4 figures. See companion paper
  http://arxiv.org/abs/1604.03914 . v3: Closer to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 080502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.080502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental and open question is whether cross-Kerr nonlinearities can be
used to construct a controlled-phase (CPHASE) gate. Here we propose a gate
constructed from a discrete set of atom-mediated cross-Kerr interaction sites
with counter-propagating photons. We show that the average gate fidelity $F$
between a CPHASE and our proposed gate increases as the number of interaction
sites increases and the spectral width of the photon decreases, e.g. with 12
sites we find $F &gt; 99\%$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05007</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>SK Firoz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benjamin</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author></authors><title>Topologically induced fractional Hall steps in the integer quantum Hall
  regime of $MoS_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in Nanotechnology
  (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 385203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/38/385203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum magnetotransport properties of a monolayer of molybdenum
disulfide are derived using linear response theory. Especially, the effect of
topological terms on longitudinal and Hall conductivity is analyzed. The Hall
conductivity exhibits fractional steps in the integer quantum Hall regime.
Further complete spin and valley polarization of the longitudinal conductivity
is seen in presence of these topological terms. Finally, the Shubnikov-de Hass
oscillations are suppressed or enhanced contingent on the sign of these
topological terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05763</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Veldhorst</keyname><forenames>Arno A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf8;der</keyname><forenames>Thomas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dyre</keyname><forenames>Jeppe C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A pair potential that reproduces the shape of isochrones in molecular
  liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. B 120, 7970-7974 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcb.6b04424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many liquids have curves (isomorphs) in their phase diagrams along which
structure, dynamics, and some thermodynamic quantities are invariant in reduced
units. A substantial part of their phase diagrams is thus effectively one
dimensional. The shape of these isomorphs is described by a material-dependent
function of density $h(\rho)$, which for real liquids is well approximated by a
power law $\rho^\gamma$. However, in simulations, a power law is not adequate
when density changes are large; typical models such as the Lennard-Jones liquid
show that $\gamma(\rho) \equiv \mathrm{d} \ln h(\rho)/\mathrm{d} \ln \rho$ is a
decreasing function of density. This paper presents results from computer
simulations using a new pair potential that diverges at a nonzero distance and
can be tuned to give a more realistic shape of $\gamma(\rho)$. Our results
indicate that the finite size of molecules is an important factor to take into
account when modeling liquids over a large density range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06374</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gartside</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burn</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Branford</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A novel method for the injection and manipulation of magnetic charge
  states in nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>in Scientific Reports (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Realising the promise of next-generation magnetic nanotechnologies is
contingent on the development of novel methods for controlling magnetic states
at the nanoscale. There is currently demand for simple and flexible techniques
to access exotic magnetisation states without convoluted fabrication and
application processes. 360 degree domain walls (metastable twists in
magnetisation separating two domains with parallel magnetisation) are one such
state, which is currently of great interest in data storage and magnonics.
Here, we demonstrate a straightforward and powerful process whereby a moving
magnetic charge, provided experimentally by a magnetic force microscope tip,
can write and manipulate magnetic charge states in ferromagnetic nanowires. The
method is applicable to a wide range of nanowire architectures with
considerable benefits over existing techniques. We confirm the method's
efficacy via the injection and spatial manipulation of 360 degree domain walls
in Py and Co nanowires. Experimental results are supported by micromagnetic
simulations of the tip-nanowire interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06415</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Endres</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Hees</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleicher</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy, centrality and momentum dependence of dielectron production at
  collider energies in a coarse-grained transport approach</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 024912 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024912</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dilepton production in heavy-ion collisions at collider energies - i.e., for
the Relativistic Heavy-Ion Collider (RHIC) and the Large Hadron Collider (LHC)
- is studied within an approach that uses coarse-grained transport simulations
to calculate thermal dilepton emission applying in-medium spectral functions
from hadronic many-body theory and partonic production rates based on lattice
calculations. The microscopic output from the Ultra-relativistic Quantum
Molecular Dynamics (UrQMD) model is hereby put on a grid of space-time cells
which allows to extract the local temperature and chemical potential in each
cell via an equation of state. The resulting dilepton spectra are in good
agreement with the experimental results for the range of RHIC energies,
$\sqrt{s_{NN}}=19.6 - 200$ GeV. The comparison of data and model outcome shows
that the newest measurements by the PHENIX and STAR collaborations are
consistent and that the low-mass spectra can be described by a cocktail of
hadronic decay contributions together with thermal emission from broadened
vector-meson spectral functions and from the Quark-Gluon Plasma phase.
Predictions for dilepton results at LHC energies show no significant change of
the spectra as compared to RHIC, but a higher fraction of thermal contribution
and harder slopes of the transverse momentum distributions due to the higher
temperatures and flow obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06432</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klimchitskaya</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostepanenko</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Lifshitz-Matsubara sum formula for the Casimir pressure
  between magnetic metallic mirrors&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>3 pages; minor additions have been made in accordance to the version
  to appear in Phys. Rev. E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E, v.94, 026101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.026101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently Guerout et al. [Phys. Rev. E, v.93, 022108 (2016)] advocated that
the lossless plasma model has to be redefined as the limit of the Drude model
when the relaxation parameter goes to zero. It was claimed that the previously
used plasma model cannot correctly describe the Casimir pressure between two
plates made of both nonmagnetic and magnetic metals and has to be replaced with
the redefined one. We show that the suggested redefinition does not satisfy
necessary physical requirements imposed on the dielectric permittivity. We also
present a plausible explanation to the fact that the lossless plasma model
describes the Casimir pressure correctly even though it does not match the
optical and electrical properties of metals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02369</id><created>2016-05-08</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lehner</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liebling</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palenzuela</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motl</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>The $m=1$ instability \&amp; gravitational wave signal in binary neutron
  star mergers</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures. Update to match published version; in particular
  the previous version used an incorrect noise curve which affected slightly
  the conclusions. This is now fixed</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 043003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.043003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the development and detectability of the $m=1$ instability in the
remnant of binary neutron star mergers. The detection of the gravitational mode
associated with the $m=1$ degree of freedom could potentially reveal details of
the equation of state. We analyze the post-merger epoch of simulations of both
equal and non-equal mass neutron star mergers using three realistic,
microphysical equations of state and neutrino cooling. Our studies show such an
instability develops generically and within a short dynamical time to strengths
that are comparable or stronger than the $m=2$ mode which is the strongest
during the early post-merger stage. We estimate the signal to noise ratio that
might be obtained for the $m=1$ mode and discuss the prospects for observing
this signal with available Earth-based detectors. Because the $m=1$ occurs at
roughly half the frequency of the more powerful $m=2$ signal and because it can
potentially be long-lived, targeted searches could be devised to observe it. We
estimate that with constant amplitude direct detection of the mode could occur
up to a distance of roughly $14\,\mathrm{Mpc}$ whereas a search triggered by
the inspiral signal could extend this distance to roughly $100\,\mathrm{Mpc}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02519</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kyono</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Kentaroh</forenames></author></authors><title>Supercoset construction of Yang-Baxter deformed AdS$_5\times$S$^5$
  backgrounds</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>32 pages, v2: typos corrected, presentation improved, v3: further
  typos corrected, accepted in PTEP, v4: further typos corrected</comments><report-no>KUNS-2624</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We proceed to study Yang-Baxter deformations of the AdS$_5\times$S$^5$
superstring with the classical Yang-Baxter equation. We make a general argument
on the supercoset construction and present the master formula to describe the
dilaton in terms of classical $r$-matrices. The supercoset construction is
explicitly performed for some classical $r$-matrices and the full backgrounds
including the Ramond-Ramond (R-R) sector and dilaton are derived. Within the
class of abelian $r$-matrices, the perfect agreement is shown for well-known
examples including gravity duals of non-commutative gauge theories,
$\gamma$-deformations of S$^5$ and Schr\&quot;odinger spacetimes. It would be
remarkable that the supercoset construction works well, even if the resulting
backgrounds are not maximally supersymmetric. In particular, three-parameter
$\gamma$-deformations of S$^5$ and Schr\&quot;odinger spacetimes do not preserve any
supersymmetries. As for non-abelian $r$-matrices, we will focus upon a specific
example. The resulting background does not satisfy the equation of motion of
the Neveu-Schwarz-Neveu-Schwarz (NS-NS) two-form because the R-R three-form is
not closed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03954</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>Jonah E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreland</keyname><forenames>J. Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bass</keyname><forenames>Steffen A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Applying Bayesian parameter estimation to relativistic heavy-ion
  collisions: simultaneous characterization of the initial state and
  quark-gluon plasma medium</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures. This version includes minor clarifications in
  the description of the model and several updated references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 024907 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024907</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We quantitatively estimate properties of the quark-gluon plasma created in
ultra-relativistic heavy-ion collisions utilizing Bayesian statistics and a
multi-parameter model-to-data comparison. The study is performed using a
recently developed parametric initial condition model, TRENTO, which
interpolates among a general class of particle production schemes, and a modern
hybrid model which couples viscous hydrodynamics to a hadronic cascade. We
calibrate the model to multiplicity, transverse momentum, and flow data and
report constraints on the parametrized initial conditions and the
temperature-dependent transport coefficients of the quark-gluon plasma. We show
that initial entropy deposition is consistent with a saturation-based picture,
extract a relation between the minimum value and slope of the
temperature-dependent specific shear viscosity, and find a clear signal for a
nonzero bulk viscosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08654</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alhaidari</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ifidon</keyname><forenames>E. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taiwo</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic Limit of Continuous Dual Hahn Polynomial</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Using Darboux method, we obtain an asymptotic limit for Continuous Dual Hahn
Polynomial.The basic concept is to construct a comparison function which is the
singular part of the generating function; then expand the comparison function.
With little simplification and modification,the asymptotic limit is achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09419</id><created>2016-05-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Atanov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baranov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colao</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cordelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corradi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dane`</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>Y. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flood</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovannella</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glagolev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Happacher</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hitlin</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miscetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyashita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morescalchi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pezzullo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saputi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarra</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soleti</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tassielli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tereshchenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy and time resolution for a LYSO matrix prototype of the Mu2e
  experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>2 pages, 3 figures, 13th Pisa Meeting on Advanced Detectors</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Instr. Meth. A 824 (2016) 684</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2015.09.051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the performances of a LYSO crystal matrix prototype tested
with electron and photon beams in the energy range 60$-$450 MeV. This study has
been carried out to determine the achievable energy and time resolutions for
the calorimeter of the Mu2e experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00392</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmad</keyname><forenames>Zeeshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viswanathan</keyname><forenames>Venkatasubramanian</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantification of uncertainty in first-principles predicted mechanical
  properties of solids: Application to solid ion conductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Computationally-guided material discovery is being increasingly employed
using a descriptor-based screening through the calculation of a few properties
of interest. A precise understanding of the uncertainty associated with first
principles density functional theory calculated property values is important
for the success of descriptor-based screening. Bayesian error estimation
approach has been built-in to several recently developed exchange-correlation
functionals, which allows an estimate of the uncertainty associated with
properties related to the ground state energy, for e.g. adsorption energies.
Here, we propose a robust and computationally efficient method for quantifying
uncertainty in mechanical properties, which depends on the derivatives of the
energy. The procedure involves calculating the energy around the equilibrium
cell volume with different strains and fitting the obtained energies to the
corresponding energy-strain relationship. At each strain, we use instead of a
single energy, an ensemble of energies, giving us an ensemble of fits and
thereby, an ensemble of mechanical properties associated with each fit, whose
spread can be used to quantify its uncertainty. The generation of ensemble of
energies is only a post-processing step involving a perturbation of parameters
of the exchange-correlation functional and solving for the energy non-self
consistently. The proposed method is computationally efficient and provides a
more robust uncertainty estimate compared to the approach of self-consistent
calculations employing several different exchange-correlation functionals. We
demonstrate the method by calculating the uncertainty bounds for Si using the
developed method. We show that the calculated uncertainty bounds the property
values obtained using three different GGA functionals: PBE, PBEsol and RPBE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00590</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-08-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhaduri</keyname><forenames>Susmita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Dipak</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of Void Probability Scaling of Singly Charged Particles Produced
  in Ultrarelativistic Nuclear Collision in Fractal Scenario</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics,Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  6848197, 5 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/6848197</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the fractality of void probability distribution
measured in $^{32}$S-Ag/Br interaction at an incident energy of $200$ GeV per
nucleon. A radically different and rigorous method called \textit{Visibility
Graph} analysis is used. This method is shown to reveal a strong scaling
character of void probability distribution in all pseurorapidity regions. The
scaling exponent, called the Power of the Scale-freeness in Visibility
Graph(PSVG), a quantitative parameter related to Hurst exponent, is strongly
found to be dependent on the rapidity window size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04517</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2016-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dev</keyname><forenames>P. S. Bhupal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazanas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohapatra</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teplitz</keyname><forenames>V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yongchao</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy right-handed neutrino dark matter and PeV neutrinos at IceCube</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures, minor corrections, version for publication in
  JCAP</comments><report-no>ULB-TH/16-10</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 1608, 034 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a simple non-supersymmetric model based on the electroweak gauge
group $SU(2)_L\times SU(2)^\prime\times U(1)_{B-L}$ where the lightest of the
right-handed neutrinos, which are part of the leptonic doublet of
$SU(2)^\prime$, play the role of a long-lived unstable dark matter with mass in
the multi-PeV range. We use a resonant $s$-channel annihilation to obtain the
correct thermal relic density and relax the unitarity bound on dark matter
mass. In this model, there exists a 3-body dark matter decay mode producing tau
leptons and neutrinos, which could be the source for the PeV cascade events
observed in the IceCube experiment. The model can be tested with more precise
flavor information of the highest-energy neutrino events in future data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05239</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guevara</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pais</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanelli</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Contents of Unconventional Supersymmetry</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.other</categories><comments>17 pages. Accepted version for publication in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP (2016) 2016: 85</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)085</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac Hamiltonian formalism is applied to a system in $(2+1)$-dimensions
consisting of a Dirac field $\psi$ minimally coupled to Chern-Simons $U(1)$ and
$SO(2,1)$ connections, $A$ and $\omega$, respectively. This theory is connected
to a supersymmetric Chern-Simons form in which the gravitino has been projected
out (unconventional supersymmetry) and, in the case of a flat background,
corresponds to the low energy limit of graphene. The separation between
first-class and second-class constraints is performed explicitly, and both the
field equations and gauge symmetries of the Lagrangian formalism are fully
recovered. The degrees of freedom of the theory in generic sectors shows that
the propagating states correspond to fermionic modes in the background
determined by the geometry of the graphene sheet and the nondynamical
electromagnetic field. This is shown for the following canonical sectors: i) a
conformally invariant generic description where the spinor field and the
dreibein are locally rescaled; ii) a specific configuration for the Dirac
fermion consistent with its spin, where Weyl symmetry is exchanged by time
reparametrizations; iii) the vacuum sector $\psi=0$, which is of interest for
perturbation theory. For the latter the analysis is adapted to the case of
manifolds with boundary, and the corresponding Dirac brackets together with the
centrally extended charge algebra are found. Finally, the $SU(2)$
generalization of the gauge group is briefly treated, yielding analogous
conclusions for the degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06100</id><created>2016-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaturvedi</keyname><forenames>Harshwardhan</forenames><affiliation>Virginia Tech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Assi</keyname><forenames>Hiba</forenames><affiliation>Virginia Tech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dobramysl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames><affiliation>Gurdon Institute, University of Cambridge</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pleimling</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames><affiliation>Virginia Tech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>T&#xe4;uber</keyname><forenames>Uwe C.</forenames><affiliation>Virginia Tech</affiliation></author></authors><title>Flux line relaxation kinetics following current quenches in disordered
  type-II superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 083301</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/08/083301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the relaxation dynamics of magnetic vortex lines in type-II
superconductors following rapid changes of the external driving current by
means of an elastic line model simulated with Langevin molecular dynamics. A
system of flux vortices in a sample with randomly distributed point-like
defects is subjected to an external current of appropriate strength for a
sufficient period of time so as to be in a moving non-equilibrium steady state.
The current is then instantaneously lowered to a value that pertains to either
the moving or pinned regime. The ensuing relaxation of the flux lines is
studied via one-time observables such as their mean velocity and radius of
gyration. We have in addition measured the two-time flux line height
autocorrelation function to investigate dynamical scaling and aging behavior in
the system, which in particular emerge after quenches into the glassy pinned
state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06758</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leclercq</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavaux</keyname><forenames>Guilhem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jasche</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandelt</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing cosmic web classifiers using information theory</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM stat.AP</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures, 6 tables. Matches JCAP published version. Public
  data available from the first author's website (currently
  http://icg.port.ac.uk/~leclercq/)</comments><journal-ref>JCAP08 (2016) 027</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a decision scheme for optimally choosing a classifier, which
segments the cosmic web into different structure types (voids, sheets,
filaments, and clusters). Our framework, based on information theory, accounts
for the design aims of different classes of possible applications: (i)
parameter inference, (ii) model selection, and (iii) prediction of new
observations. As an illustration, we use cosmographic maps of web-types in the
Sloan Digital Sky Survey to assess the relative performance of the classifiers
T-web, DIVA and ORIGAMI for: (i) analyzing the morphology of the cosmic web,
(ii) discriminating dark energy models, and (iii) predicting galaxy colors. Our
study substantiates a data-supported connection between cosmic web analysis and
information theory, and paves the path towards principled design of analysis
procedures for the next generation of galaxy surveys. We have made the cosmic
web maps, galaxy catalog, and analysis scripts used in this work publicly
available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07453</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Holmes</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tubman</keyname><forenames>Norm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umrigar</keyname><forenames>Cyrus</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat-bath Configuration Interaction: An efficient selected CI algorithm
  inspired by heat-bath sampling</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new selected configuration interaction plus perturbation
theory algorithm that is based on a deterministic analog of our recent
efficient heat-bath sampling algorithm. This Heat-bath Configuration
Interaction (HCI) algorithm makes use of two parameters that control the
tradeoff between speed and accuracy, one which controls the selection of
determinants to add to a variational wavefunction, and one which controls the
the selection of determinants used to compute the perturbative correction to
the variational energy. We show that HCI provides an accurate treatment of both
static and dynamic correlation by computing the potential energy curve of the
multireference carbon dimer in the cc-pVDZ basis. We then demonstrate the speed
and accuracy of HCI by recovering the full configuration interaction energy of
both the carbon dimer in the cc-pVTZ basis and the strongly-correlated chromium
dimer in the Ahlrichs VDZ basis, correlating all electrons, to an accuracy of
better than 1 mHa, in just a few minutes on a single core. These systems have
full variational spaces of 3x10^14 and 2x10^22 determinants respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07791</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Voss</keyname><forenames>Henning U.</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple predictor based on delay-induced negative group delay</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>Changes to version 2: Corrections, extensions, new discussion</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A very simple linear signal predictor that uses past predicted values rather
than past signal values for prediction is presented. Man-made or natural
systems utilizing this predictor would not require a memory of input signal
values but only of already predicted, internalized states. This delay-induced
negative group delay (DINGD) predictor affords real-time prediction of signals
without the need for a specific signal model. Its properties are derived
analytically and are numerically tested on various types of broadband input
data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01099</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cossu</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukaya</keyname><forenames>Hidenori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>Shoji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noaki</keyname><forenames>Jun-Ichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic calculation of the Dirac spectrum on the lattice and a
  determination of chiral condensate in 2+1-flavor QCD</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures, a revised version to appear in PTEP</comments><report-no>KEK-CP-346, OU-HET-898</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the chiral condensate in 2+1-flavor QCD through the spectrum of
low-lying eigenmodes of Dirac operator. The number of eigenvalues of the Dirac
operator is evaluated using a stochastic method with an eigenvalue filtering
technique on the background gauge configurations generated by lattice QCD
simulations including the effects of dynamical up, down and strange quarks
described by the Mobius domain-wall fermion formulation. The low-lying spectrum
is related to the chiral condensate, which is one of the leading order
low-energy constants in chiral effective theory, as dictated by the
Banks-Casher relation. The spectrum shape and its dependence on the sea quark
masses calculated in numerical simulations are consistent with the expectation
from one-loop chiral perturbation theory. After taking the chiral limit as well
as the continuum limit using the data at three lattice spacings ranging
0.080-0.045 fm, we obtain $\Sigma^{1/3}$(2 GeV) = 270.0(4.9) MeV, with the
error combining those from statistical and from various sources of systematic
errors. Finite volume effect is confirmed to be under control by a direct
comparison of the results from two different volumes at the lightest available
sea quarks corresponding to 230 MeV pions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04172</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>Richard L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saad</keyname><forenames>Nasser</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact and approximate solutions of Schr\&quot;odinger's equation with
  hyperbolic double-well potentials</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><report-no>CUQM - 156</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131:277</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16277-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analytic and approximate solutions for the energy eigenvalues generated by
the hyperbolic potentials
$V_m(x)=-U_0\sinh^{2m}(x/d)/\cosh^{2m+2}(x/d),\,m=0,1,2,\dots$ are constructed.
A byproduct of this work is the construction of polynomial solutions for the
confluent Heun equation along with necessary and sufficient conditions for the
existence of such solutions based on the evaluation of a three-term recurrence
relation. Very accurate approximate solutions for the general problem with
arbitrary potential parameters are found by use of the {\it asymptotic
iteration method}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05708</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05708</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rauscher</keyname><forenames>Bernard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canavan</keyname><forenames>Edgar R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moseley</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadleir</keyname><forenames>John E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevenson</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Detectors and cooling technology for direct spectroscopic biosignature
  characterization</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures, and 4 tables. Submitted to the Journal of
  Astronomical Telescopes, Instruments, and Systems</comments><journal-ref>JATIS, 2(4), 041212 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.2.4.041212</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct spectroscopic biosignature characterization (hereafter &quot;biosignature
characterization&quot;) will be a major focus for future space observatories
equipped with coronagraphs or starshades. Our aim in this article is to provide
an introduction to potential detector and cooling technologies for biosignature
characterization. We begin by reviewing the needs. These include nearly
noiseless photon detection at flux levels as low as
$&lt;0.001~\textrm{photons}~s^{-1}~\textrm{pixel}^{-1}$ in the visible and
near-IR. We then discuss potential areas for further testing and/or development
to meet these needs using non-cryogenic detectors (EMCCD, HgCdTe array, HgCdTe
APD array), and cryogenic single photon detectors (MKID arrays and TES
microcalorimeter arrays). Non-cryogenic detectors are compatible with the
passive cooling that is strongly preferred by coronagraphic missions, but would
add non-negligible noise. Cryogenic detectors would require active cooling, but
in return deliver nearly quantum limited performance. Based on the flight
dynamics of past NASA missions, we discuss reasonable vibration expectations
for a large UV-Optical-IR space telescope (LUVOIR) and preliminary cooling
concepts that could potentially fit into a vibration budget without being the
largest element. We believe that a cooler that meets the stringent vibration
needs of a LUVOIR is also likely to meet those of a starshade-based Habitable
Exoplanet Imaging Mission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00448</id><created>2016-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bezerra</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimchitskaya</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostepanenko</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining axion coupling constants from measuring the Casimir
  interaction between polarized test bodies</title><categories>hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures; to appear in Phes. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D, v.94, 035011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.035011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an experiment for measuring the effective Casimir pressure between
two parallel SiC plates with aligned nuclear spins. The prospective constraints
on an axion-neutron coupling constant for both hadronic and GUT axions are
calculated using the process of one-axion exchange. For this purpose, a general
expression for the additional pressure arising between two polarized plates due
to the exchange of one axion between their constituent fermions is derived. We
demonstrate that only the polarization component perpendicular to the plates
contribute to the pressure. The obtained pressure can be both repulsive and
attractive depending on whether the polarizations of both plates are
unidirectional or directed in opposite directions. It is shown that although
the constraints on an axion-electron coupling obtained in the case of
magnetized plates are not competitive, the constraints on an axion-neutron
coupling found for plates with polarized nuclear spins are of the same order of
magnitude of those obtained previously for the GUT axions alone using the
process of two-axion exchange. The proposed experiment allows also to
strengthen the presently known constraints on the axion-neutron coupling
constants of GUT axions by using both processes of one- and two-axion exchange.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03300</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Galteland</keyname><forenames>Peder N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudb&#xf8;</keyname><forenames>Asle</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing interactions in population-imbalanced two-component
  Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>15 pages, 14 figures. Accepted for publication in Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 054510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.054510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a two-component Bose-Einstein condensate with and without
synthetic &quot;spin-orbit&quot; interactions in two dimensions. Density- and
phase-fluctuations of the condensate are included, allowing us to study the
impact of thermal fluctuations and density-density interactions on the physics
originating with spin-orbit interactions. In the absence of spin-orbit
interactions, we find that inter-component density interactions deplete the
minority condensate. The thermally driven phase transition is driven by coupled
density and phase-fluctuations, but is nevertheless shown to be a
phase-transition in the Kosterlitz-Thouless universality class with close to
universal amplitude ratios irrespective of whether both the minority- and
majority condensates exist in the ground state, or only one condensate exists.
In the presence of spin-orbit interactions we observe three separate phases,
depending on the strength of the spin-orbit coupling and inter-component
density-density interactions: a phase-modulated phase with uniform amplitudes
for small intercomponent interactions, a completely imbalanced, effectively
single-component, condensate for intermediate spin-orbit coupling strength and
suficciently large inter-component interactions, and a phase-modulated
\textit{and} amplitude-modulated phase for sufficiently large values of both
the spin-orbit coupling and the inter-component density-density interactions.
The phase which is modulated by a single $\bv q$-vector only is observed to
transition into an isoptropic liquid through a strong de-pinning transition
with periodic boundary conditions, which weakens with open boundaries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04381</id><created>2016-08-13</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naeemi</keyname><forenames>Maitham D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alessio</keyname><forenames>Adam M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roychowdhury</keyname><forenames>Sohini</forenames></author></authors><title>Automated Selection of Uniform Regions for CT Image Quality Detection</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.CV</categories><comments>5 pages, 8 figures, Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and
  Computers</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CT images are widely used in pathology detection and follow-up treatment
procedures. Accurate identification of pathological features requires
diagnostic quality CT images with minimal noise and artifact variation. In this
work, a novel Fourier-transform based metric for image quality (IQ) estimation
is presented that correlates to additive CT image noise. In the proposed
method, two windowed CT image subset regions are analyzed together to identify
the extent of variation in the corresponding Fourier-domain spectrum. The two
square windows are chosen such that their center pixels coincide and one window
is a subset of the other. The Fourier-domain spectral difference between these
two sub-sampled windows is then used to isolate spatial regions-of-interest
(ROI) with low signal variation (ROI-LV) and high signal variation (ROI-HV),
respectively. Finally, the spatial variance ($var$), standard deviation
($std$), coefficient of variance ($cov$) and the fraction of abdominal ROI
pixels in ROI-LV ($\nu'(q)$), are analyzed with respect to CT image noise. For
the phantom CT images, $var$ and $std$ correlate to CT image noise ($|r|&gt;0.76$
($p\ll0.001$)), though not as well as $\nu'(q)$ ($r=0.96$ ($p\ll0.001$)).
However, for the combined phantom and patient CT images, $var$ and $std$ do not
correlate well with CT image noise ($|r|&lt;0.46$ ($p\ll0.001$)) as compared to
$\nu'(q)$ ($r=0.95$ ($p\ll0.001$)). Thus, the proposed method and the metric,
$\nu'(q)$, can be useful to quantitatively estimate CT image noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05229</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Swapan</forenames></author></authors><title>Semihadronic and hadronic decays of $\rho^0$ and $\omega$ mesons
  coherently photoproduced in the isoscalar nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94 (2016) 025204</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.025204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interference of the $\rho^0$ and $\omega$ mesons has been studied in the
hadronic and leptonic decay channels, i.e., dipion and dilepton decay channels
respectively, but this interference is not studied yet in the semihadronic or
semileptonic decay channel, e.g., $V \to \pi^0\gamma$. $V$ denotes either
$\rho^0$ or $\omega$ meson. To look for the quoted interference in the
$\pi^0\gamma$ decay channel as well as the contribution of $\rho$ meson to the
cross section, the correlated $\pi^0\gamma$ invariant mass distribution spectra
are calculated in the photonuclear reaction in the multi-GeV region. It is
assumed that these bosons arise in the final state due to the decay of $\rho^0$
and $\omega$ mesons which are photoproduced coherently in the isoscalar
nucleus. The elementary reaction in the nucleus is considered to proceed as
$\gamma N \to VN$; $V \to \pi^0\gamma$. The forward propagation of the $\rho$
and $\omega$ mesons and the near forward emission of pion are considered, so
that they can be described by the eikonal form. The meson nucleus interactions
are evaluated using $t\varrho$ approximation. Replacing the decay vertex $V \to
\pi^0\gamma$ by $V \to \pi^+\pi^-$ in the above formalism, it is also used to
study the $\rho-\omega$ interference in the $\pi^+\pi^-$ decay channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05259</id><created>2016-08-07</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Raptis</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unitary Cellular Automata and Convolution Algebras</title><categories>nlin.CG</categories><comments>23 p., 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The original local, discrete example of Linear Unitary Cellular Automata
(LUCA) is analyzed in terms of a new representation previously introduced in
[1] for classical CA. Several important underlying symmetries are reviewed and
their tight relationship with both signal and coding theory as well as with
combinatorics is underlined. A class of analog implementations in the form of
Linear Transmission Line Networks (LTLN) is described as possible emulators of
this type of dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05408</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>von der Wense</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seiferle</keyname><forenames>Benedict</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laatiaoui</keyname><forenames>Mustapha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thirolf</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the extraction efficiency for $^{233}$U source
  $\alpha$-recoil ions from the MLL buffer-gas stopping cell</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2015) 51:29</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2015-15029-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following the $\alpha$ decay of $^{233}$U, $^{229}$Th recoil ions are shown
to be extracted in a significant amount from the MLL buffer-gas stopping cell.
The produced recoil ions and subsequent daughter nuclei are mass purified with
the help of a customized quadrupole mass spectrometer. The combined extraction
and mass-purification efficiency for $^{229}$Th$^{3+}$ is determined via
MCP-based measurements and via the direct detection of the $^{229}$Th $\alpha$
decay. A large value of $(10\pm2)$\% for the combined extraction and
mass-purification efficiency of $^{229}$Th$^{3+}$ is obtained at a mass
resolution of about 1 u/e. In addition to $^{229}$Th, also other
$\alpha$-recoil ions of the $^{233,232}$U decay chains are addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05420</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaudet</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallas</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maharaj</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buhariwalla</keyname><forenames>C. R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kermarrec</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butch</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Munsie</keyname><forenames>T. J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabkowska</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luke</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaulin</keyname><forenames>B. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic dilution and domain selection in the XY pyrochlore
  antiferromagnet Er$_{2}$Ti$_2$O$_7$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages,7 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B. 94(R), 060407 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.060407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Below $T_N = 1.1$K, the XY pyrochlore Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ orders into a $k=0$
non-collinear, antiferromagnetic structure referred to as the $\psi_2$ state.
The magnetic order in Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ is known to obey conventional three
dimensional (3D) percolation in the presence of magnetic dilution, and in that
sense is robust to disorder. Recently, however, two theoretical studies have
predicted that the $\psi_2$ structure should be unstable to the formation of a
related $\psi_3$ magnetic structure in the presence of magnetic vacancies. To
investigate these theories, we have carried out systematic elastic and
inelastic neutron scattering studies of three single crystals of
Er$_{2-x}$Y$_x$Ti$_2$O$_7$ with $x=0$ (pure), 0.2 (10$\%$-Y) and 0.4
(20$\%$-Y), where magnetic Er$^{3+}$ is substituted by non-magnetic Y$^{3+}$.
We find that the $\psi_2$ ground state of pure Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ is
significantly affected by magnetic dilution. The characteristic domain
selection associated with the $\psi_2$ state, and the corresponding energy gap
separating $\psi_2$ from $\psi_3$, vanish for Y$^{3+}$ substitutions between
10$\%$-Y and 20$\%$-Y, far removed from the 3D percolation threshold of
$\sim$60$\%$-Y. The resulting ground state for Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ with magnetic
dilutions from 20$\%$-Y up to the percolation threshold is naturally
interpreted as a frozen mosaic of $\psi_2$ and $\psi_3$ domains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05424</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yongchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Bingcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuanhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Xumin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jialei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hongbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yongjin</forenames></author></authors><title>Full duplex communication using visible light</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we propose, fabricate and characterize a full duplex
communication system using visible light on a single chip. Both the suspended
p-n junction InGaN/GaN multiple quantum well (MQW) devices and the suspended
waveguides are obtained on a GaN-on-silicon platform by wafer-level processing.
Two suspended p-n junction InGaN/GaN MQW devices that can both emit and detect
light simultaneously are connected using suspended waveguides to form an
in-plane visible light communication (VLC) system. The light that is emitted
from one suspended p-n junction InGaN/GaN MQW device can induce a current in
the device located at the other end of the waveguide via in-plane light
coupling, thus leading to full duplex communication using visible light. This
proof-of-concept in-plane VLC system paves the way towards the implementation
of a full duplex communications system operating at the same frequency using
visible light on a single chip.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05425</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Hanel</keyname><forenames>Rudolf A.</forenames></author></authors><title>An action principle of classical irreversible thermodynamics -
  Irreversible thermodynamic cycles and embodied bits of information</title><categories>physics.class-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite its simplicity, it seems to my best of knowledge that the possibly
simplest approach towards deriving equations governing irreversible
thermodynamics from gas-kinetic considerations within the framework of
classical mechanics has never been pursued. In this paper we address this
omission and derive the equations describing the irreversible thermodynamics of
a gas in a piston and associated thermodynamic cycles performed in finite time.
What we find is a thermodynamic action principle: The irreversible work we
require for performing a thermodynamic cycle in finite time times the time we
require to run through the cycle, a isothermal compression/decompression cycle
for instance, will always be larger or equal to a lower bound given by a system
specific constant with the dimension of an action. This process specific action
constants can take values of the order of Plank's constant for microscopic
processes, such as displacing a Hydrogen atom by one atom diameter. For
macroscopic processes (e.g. a bicycle pump) also the action constant takes
macroscopically observable values. We discuss the finite time Carnot cycle, and
estimate the lower bound for irreversible work required when rewriting
physically embodied bits of information and compare the resulting values with
Landauer's bond, the irreversible amount of energy that needs to be dissipated
for re-writing a bit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05433</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsekouras</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riedel</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabizon</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marqusee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Press&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustamante</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Enhanced Diffusion of Enzymes that Catalyze Exothermic
  Reactions&quot; by R.Golestanian</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We (Riedel et al. Nature 2015), as well as others, have showed that some
enzymes exhibit enhanced diffusion when active. In a recent PRL, (Golestanian,
PRL 2015, arXiv:1508.03219) R.Golestanian theoretically examines a number of
possible explanations for this phenomenon and concludes that &quot;collective
heating&quot; is the best candidate to account for the observed diffusion
coefficient increase. Here we present evidence showing that collective heating
cannot possibly apply to our experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05434</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gregory</keyname><forenames>Scott G.</forenames><affiliation>University of St Andrews</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>Fred C.</forenames><affiliation>University of Michigan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Claire L.</forenames><affiliation>University of Exeter</affiliation></author></authors><title>The coronal evolution of pre-main-sequence stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Proceedings of Cool Stars 19, Uppsala, Sweden, June 2016. 7 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The bulk of X-ray emission from pre-main-sequence (PMS) stars is coronal in
origin. We demonstrate herein that stars on Henyey tracks in the
Hertzsprung-Russell diagram have lower $\log(L_X/L_\ast)$, on average, than
stars on Hayashi tracks. This effect is driven by the decay of $L_X$ once stars
develop radiative cores. $L_X$ decays faster with age for intermediate mass PMS
stars, the progenitors of main sequence A-type stars, compared to those of
lower mass. As almost all main sequence A-type stars show no detectable X-ray
emission, we may already be observing the loss of their coronae during their
PMS evolution. Although there is no direct link between the size or mass of the
radiative core and $L_X$, the longer stars have spent with partially convective
interiors, the weaker their X-ray emission becomes. This conference paper is a
synopsis of Gregory, Adams and Davies (2016).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05436</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Okada</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curceanu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doriese</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fowler</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gard</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gustafsson</keyname><forenames>F. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayano</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirenzaki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hays-Wehle</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilton</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeno</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iliescu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishimoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itahashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koike</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuwabara</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noda</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Neil</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Outa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reintsema</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swetz</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatsuno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uhlig</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ullom</keyname><forenames>J. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widmann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamagata-Sekihara</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmeskal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>First application of superconducting transition-edge-sensor
  microcalorimeters to hadronic-atom x-ray spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex nucl-th physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, submitted to PTEP</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-resolution pionic-atom x-ray spectroscopy was performed with an x-ray
spectrometer based on a 240-pixel array of superconducting
transition-edge-sensor (TES) microcalorimeters at the piM1 beam line of the
Paul Scherrer Institute. X-rays emitted by pionic carbon via the 4f-&gt;3d
transition and the parallel 4d-&gt;3p transition were observed with a
full-width-at-half-maximum energy resolution of 6.8 eV at 6.4 keV. Measured
x-ray energies are consistent with calculated electromagnetic values which
considered the strong-interaction effect assessed via the Seki-Masutani
potential for the 3p energy level, and favor the electronic population of two
filled 1s electrons in the K-shell. Absolute energy calibration with an
uncertainty of 0.1 eV was demonstrated under a high-rate hadron beam condition
of 1.45 MHz. This is the first application of a TES spectrometer to
hadronic-atom x-ray spectroscopy and is an important milestone towards
next-generation high-resolution kaonic-atom x-ray spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05439</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schadschneider</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Evacuation dynamics of asymmetrically coupled pedestrian pairs</title><categories>physics.soc-ph nlin.CG</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, to be published in Traffic and Granular Flow '15
  (Springer, in press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and analyze extended floor field cellular automaton models for
evacuation dynamics of inhomogeneous pedestrian pairs which are coupled by
asymmetric group interactions. Such pairs consist of a leader, who mainly
determines the couple's motion and a follower, who has a defined tendency to
follow the leader. Examples for such pairs are mother and child or two siblings
of different age. We examine the system properties and compare them to the case
of a homogeneous crowd. We find a strong impact on evacuation times for the
regime of strong pair coupling due to the occurrence of a clogging phenomenon.
In addition we obtain a non-trivial dependence of evacuation times on the
followers' coupling to the static floor field, which carries the information of
the shortest way to the exit location. In particular we find that systems with
fully passive followers, who are solely coupled to their leaders, show lower
evacuation times than homogeneous systems where all pedestrians have an equal
tendency to move towards the exit. We compare the results of computer
simulations with recently performed experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05451</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Omnarayani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meixner</keyname><forenames>Margaret</forenames></author><author><keyname>Indebetouw</keyname><forenames>Remy</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Marchi</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koekemoer</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagia</keyname><forenames>Nino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabbi</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying Relation Between Star Formation and Molecular Clumps on
  Subparsec Scales in 30 Doradus</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted by ApJ, 65 pages, 17 figures, 6 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present $\mathrm{^{12}CO}$ and $\mathrm{^{13}CO}$ molecular gas data
observed by ALMA, massive early stage young stellar objects identified by
applying color-magnitude cuts to \textit{Spitzer} and \textit{Herschel}
photometry, and low-mass late stage young stellar objects identified via
H$\mathrm{\alpha}$ excess. Using dendrograms, we derive properties for the
molecular cloud structures. This is the first time a dendrogram analysis has
been applied to extragalactic clouds. The majority of clumps have a virial
parameter equal to unity or less. The size-linewidth relations of
$\mathrm{^{12}CO}$ and $\mathrm{^{13}CO}$ show the clumps in this study have a
larger linewidth for a given size (by factor of 3.8 and 2.5, respectively) in
comparison to several, but not all, previous studies. The larger linewidths in
30 Doradus compared to typical Milky Way quiescent clumps are probably due to
the highly energetic environmental conditions of 30 Doradus. The slope of the
size-linewidth relations of $\mathrm{^{12}CO}$, 0.65 $\pm$ 0.04, and
$\mathrm{^{13}CO}$, 0.97 $\pm$ 0.12, are on the higher end but consistent
within 3$\mathrm{\sigma}$ of previous studies. Massive star formation occurs in
clumps with high masses ($&gt; 1.83 \times 10^{2}\;\mathrm{M_{\odot}}$), high
linewidths (v $&gt; 1.18\;\mathrm{km/s}$), and high mass densities ($&gt; 6.67 \times
10^{2}\;\mathrm{M_{\odot}\;pc^{-2}}$). The majority of embedded, massive young
stellar objects are associated with a clump. However the majority of more
evolved, low-mass young stellar objects are not associated with a clump.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05456</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Galitzki</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angile</keyname><forenames>Francesco E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashton</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Austermann</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billings</keyname><forenames>Tashalee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Che</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Hsiao-Mei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Kristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devlin</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dicker</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dober</keyname><forenames>Bradley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fissel</keyname><forenames>Laura M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Yasuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Jiansong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groppi</keyname><forenames>Christopher E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillbrand</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilton</keyname><forenames>Gene C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubmayr</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Kent D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Dale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lourie</keyname><forenames>Nathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lowe</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mani</keyname><forenames>Hamdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKenney</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nati</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novak</keyname><forenames>Giles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascale</keyname><forenames>Enzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisano</keyname><forenames>Giampaolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fabio P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Douglas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soler</keyname><forenames>Juan D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Carole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Underhill</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vissers</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Instrumental performance and results from testing of the BLAST-TNG
  receiver, submillimeter optics, and MKID arrays</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Presented at SPIE Millimeter, Submillimeter, and Far-Infrared
  Detectors and Instrumentation for Astronomy VIII, June 29th, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9914, Millimeter, Submillimeter, and Far-Infrared
  Detectors and Instrumentation for Astronomy VIII, 99140J (July 19, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2231167</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarized thermal emission from interstellar dust grains can be used to map
magnetic fields in star forming molecular clouds and the diffuse interstellar
medium (ISM). The Balloon-borne Large Aperture Submillimeter Telescope for
Polarimetry (BLASTPol) flew from Antarctica in 2010 and 2012 and produced
degree-scale polarization maps of several nearby molecular clouds with
arcminute resolution. The success of BLASTPol has motivated a next-generation
instrument, BLAST-TNG, which will use more than 3000 linear polarization
sensitive microwave kinetic inductance detectors (MKIDs) combined with a 2.5m
diameter carbon fiber primary mirror to make diffraction-limited observations
at 250, 350, and 500 $\mu$m. With 16 times the mapping speed of BLASTPol,
sub-arcminute resolution, and a longer flight time, BLAST-TNG will be able to
examine nearby molecular clouds and the diffuse galactic dust polarization
spectrum in unprecedented detail. The 250 $\mu$m detector array has been
integrated into the new cryogenic receiver, and is undergoing testing to
establish the optical and polarization characteristics of the instrument.
BLAST-TNG will demonstrate the effectiveness of kilo-pixel MKID arrays for
applications in submillimeter astronomy. BLAST-TNG is scheduled to fly from
Antarctica in December 2017 for 28 days and will be the first balloon-borne
telescope to offer a quarter of the flight for &quot;shared risk&quot; observing by the
community.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05464</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing the thermoelectric performance of a HfS2 monolayer through
  valley engineering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic, phonon, and thermoelectric properties of a two-dimensional
HfS2 monolayer are investigated by using the first-principles calculations
combined with the Boltzmann transport theory. The band valleys of the HfS2
monolayer can be effectively tuned by the applied biaxial strain. The Seebeck
coefficient and therefore the peak value of the power factor (with the
relaxation time inserted) increase when the degeneracy of the band valleys is
increased by the strain. When no strain is applied, the HfS2 monolayer is an
excellent n-type thermoelectric material, while the thermoelectric performance
of the p-type doped one is poor. The applied tensile strain of 6% can increase
the room-temperature ZT value of the p-type doped system to 3.67, which is five
times larger than that of the unstrained one. The much more balanced ZT values
of the p- and n-type doping are favorable for fabrication of both p- and n-legs
of thermoelectric modules. Our results indicate that the thermoelectric
performance of the HfS2 monolayer can be greatly improved by the valley
engineering through the method of strain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05472</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bystrenko</keyname><forenames>Oleksiy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kartuzov</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author></authors><title>Computer simulations of the interface zone structure in binary eutectic</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular dynamics simulations of the interface structure in binary AgCu
eutectic were performed by using the realistic EAM potential. In simulations,
we examined such quantities as the time dependence of the total energy in the
process of equilibration, the probability distributions, the composition
profiles for the components, and the component diffusivities within the
interface zone. It is shown that the equilibrium in the solid state associated
with the complete phase separation in binary eutectic is accompanied by
formation of the steady disordered diffusion zone at the boundary of the
crystalline components. At higher temperatures, closer to the eutectic point,
the increase in the width of the steady diffusion zone is observed. The
particle diffusivities grow therewith to the numbers typical for the liquid
phase. Above the eutectic point, the steady zone does not form, instead, the
complete contact melting in the system occurs. The results of simulations
indicate that during the temperature increase the phenomenon of contact melting
is preceded by the similar process spatially localized in the vicinity of the
interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05476</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Beukman</keyname><forenames>Arjan J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Fanming</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Ken W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Loren N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kouwenhoven</keyname><forenames>Leo P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A non-invasive method for nanoscale electrostatic gating of pristine
  materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>25 pages including Supporting Information</comments><journal-ref>Nano Letters, 2015, 15, 6883</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b02800</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrostatic gating is essential for defining and control of semiconducting
devices. However, nano-fabrication processes required for depositing gates
inevitably degrade the pristine quality of the material of interest. Examples
of materials that suffer from such degradation include ultra-high mobility
GaAs/AlGaAs two-dimensional electron gases (2DEGs), graphene, topological
insulators, and nanowires. To preserve the pristine material properties, we
have developed a flip-chip setup where gates are separated from the material by
a vacuum, which allows nanoscale electrostatic gating of the material without
exposing it to invasive nano-processing. An additional benefit is the vacuum
between gates and material, which, unlike gate dielectrics, is free from charge
traps. We demonstrate the operation and feasibility of the flip-chip setup by
achieving quantum interference at integer quantum Hall states in a
Fabry-P\'erot interferometer based on a GaAs/AlGaAs 2DEG. Our results pave the
way for the study of exotic phenomena including fragile fractional quantum Hall
states by preserving the high quality of the material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05486</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Hossein-Babaei</keyname><forenames>Faramarz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirkoohi</keyname><forenames>Hamid Reza Sefidi</forenames></author></authors><title>Defect-free nanocrystals are at thermodynamic equilibrium at room
  temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Crystal defect statistics is developed by minimizing the Gibbs free energy of
defect formation, which is commonly converted to a crystallite size-independent
equation by applying Stirling's approximation. Solutions of this equation
forecast Arrhenius-like temperature dependence for the concentrations of all
defect types, and higher defect populations for nanocrystals due to the smaller
formation free energies involved. Here, we improve the accuracy in the
mathematical processing of the equation describing the defect population at
thermodynamic equilibrium and show that this equation is intrinsically
size-dependent. The new model predicts lower defect concentrations for smaller
crystallites, and shows that vacancy-free crystallites smaller than a
determinable critical size are thermodynamically stable at elevated
temperatures. Our findings describe the previously reported data on the
mechanical properties of a number of nanocrystals and lead to a revised and
deeper understanding of many morphological occurrences in micro- and
nanocrystals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05504</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gautham</keyname><forenames>Chitra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steger</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snoke</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Loren</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-resolved two-photon excitation of long-lifetime polaritons</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies of two-photon excitation of exciton-polaritons in
microcavities have considered the possibility of an allowed absorption process
into the $2p$-state of the excitons which participate in the polariton effect.
Here we report time-resolved measurements of two-photon excitation directly
into the lower polariton states invoking the $1s$ state of the excitons.
Although this process is forbidden by symmetry for light at normal incidence,
it is allowed at non-zero angle of incidence due to state mixing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05516</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hod</keyname><forenames>Shahar</forenames></author></authors><title>A quantum bound on the thermodynamic description of gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The seminal works of Bekenstein and Hawking have revealed that black holes
have a well-defined thermodynamic description. In particular, it is often
stated in the physical literature that black holes, like mundane physical
systems, obey the first law of thermodynamics: $\Delta S=\Delta
E/T_{\text{BH}}$, where $T_{\text{BH}}$ is the Bekenstein-Hawking temperature
of the black hole. In the present work we test the regime of validity of the
thermodynamic description of gravity. In particular, we provide compelling
evidence that, due to quantum effects, the first law of thermodynamics breaks
down in the low-temperature regime $T_{\text{BH}}\times r_{\text{H}}\lesssim
({{\hbar}/{r_{\text{H}}}})^2$ of near-extremal black holes (here $r_{\text{H}}$
is the radius of the black-hole horizon).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05519</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Lindell</keyname><forenames>Ismo V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sihvola</keyname><forenames>Ari</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic Boundaries with PEC/PMC Equivalence</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><journal-ref>Progress in Electromagnetics Research Letters, Vol. 61, 119-123,
  2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most general electromagnetic boundary, defined by linear and local
boundary conditions, is defined in terms of conditions which can be called
generalized impedance boundary conditions. Requiring that the boundary be
equivalent to PEC and PMC boundaries for its two eigen-plane waves, which
property is known to exist for many of its special cases, it is shown that the
recently introduced Generalized Soft-and-Hard/DB (GSHDB) boundary is the most
general boundary satisfying this property.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05536</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bemporad</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Susino</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frassati</keyname><forenames>Federica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fineschi</keyname><forenames>Silvano</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring coronal magnetic fields with remote sensing observations of
  shock waves</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Frontiers in Astronomy and Space Sciences, Volume 3, id.17 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3389/fspas.2016.00017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent works demonstrated that remote sensing observations of shock waves
propagating into the corona and associated with major solar eruptions can be
used to derive the strength of coronal magnetic fields met by the shock over a
very large interval of heliocentric distances and latitudes. This opinion
article will summarize most recent results obtained on this topic and will
discuss the weaknesses and strengths of these techniques to open a constructive
discussion with the scientific community.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05539</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Forgan</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilee</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cyganowski</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brogan</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunter</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-gravitating disc candidates around massive young stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>9 pages, 20 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1917</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There have been several recent detections of candidate Keplerian discs around
massive young protostars. Given the relatively large disc-to-star mass ratios
in these systems, and their young ages, it is worth investigating their
propensity to becoming self-gravitating. To this end, we compute
self-consistent, semi-analytic models of putative self-gravitating discs for
five candidate disc systems. Our aim is not to fit exactly the observations,
but to demonstrate that the expected dust continuum emission from marginally
unstable self-gravitating discs can be quite weak, due to high optical depth at
the midplane even at millimetre wavelengths. In the best cases, the models
produce &quot;observable&quot; disc masses within a factor of &lt;1.5 of those observed,
with midplane dust temperatures comparable to measured temperatures from
molecular line emission. We find in two cases that a self-gravitating disc
model compares well with observations. If these discs are self-gravitating,
they satisfy the conditions for disc fragmentation in their outer regions.
These systems may hence have as-yet-unresolved low mass stellar companions, and
are thus promising targets for future high angular resolution observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05551</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prucnal</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;bner</keyname><forenames>R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skorupa</keyname><forenames>W</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helm</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Shengqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppressing the cellular breakdown in silicon supersaturated with
  titanium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 49, 245104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0022-3727/49/24/245104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hyper doping Si with up to 6 at.% Ti in solid solution was performed by ion
implantation followed by pulsed laser annealing and flash lamp annealing. In
both cases, the implanted Si layer can be well recrystallized by liquid phase
epitaxy and solid phase epitaxy, respectively. Cross-sectional transmission
electron microscopy of Ti-implanted Si after liquid phase epitaxy shows the
so-called growth interface breakdown or cellular breakdown owing to the
occurrence of constitutional supercooling in the melt. The appearance of
cellular breakdown prevents further recrystallization. However, the
out-diffusion and cellular breakdown can be effectively suppressed by solid
phase epitaxy during flash lamp annealing due to the high velocity of
amorphous-crystalline interface and the low diffusion velocity for Ti in the
solid phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05556</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Verstraelen</keyname><forenames>Toon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandenbrande</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heidar-Zadeh</keyname><forenames>Farnaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanduyfhuys</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Speybroeck</keyname><forenames>Veronique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waroquier</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayers</keyname><forenames>Paul W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimal Basis Iterative Stockholder: Atoms in Molecules for Force-Field
  Development</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.atm-clus physics.atom-ph physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>61 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Theory Comput., 2016, 12 (8), pp 3894--3912</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00456</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Atomic partial charges appear in the Coulomb term of many force-field models
and can be derived from electronic structure calculations with a myriad of
atoms-in-molecules (AIM) methods. More advanced models have also been proposed,
using the distributed nature of the electron cloud and atomic multipoles. In
this work, an electrostatic force field is defined through a concise
approximation of the electron density, for which the Coulomb interaction is
trivially evaluated. This approximate &quot;pro-density&quot; is expanded in a minimal
basis of atom-centered s-type Slater density functions, whose parameters are
optimized by minimizing the Kullback-Leibler divergence of the pro-density from
a reference electron density, e.g. obtained from an electronic structure
calculation. The proposed method, Minimal Basis Iterative Stockholder (MBIS),
is a variant of the Hirshfeld AIM method but it can also be used as a
density-fitting technique. An iterative algorithm to refine the pro-density is
easily implemented with a linear-scaling computational cost, enabling
applications to supramolecular systems. The benefits of the MBIS method are
demonstrated with systematic applications to molecular databases and extended
models of condensed phases. A comparison to 14 other AIM methods shows its
effectiveness when modeling electrostatic interactions. MBIS is also suitable
for rescaling atomic polarizabilities in the Tkatchenko-Sheffler scheme for
dispersion interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05561</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ilee</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cyganowski</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazari</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunter</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brogan</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forgan</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>G11.92-0.61 MM1: A Keplerian disc around a massive young proto-O star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures. Accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1912</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation process of massive stars is not well understood, and
advancement in our understanding benefits from high resolution observations and
modelling of the gas and dust surrounding individual high-mass (proto)stars.
Here we report sub-arcsecond (&lt;1550 au) resolution observations of the young
massive star G11.92-0.61 MM1 with the SMA and VLA. Our 1.3 mm SMA observations
reveal consistent velocity gradients in compact molecular line emission from
species such as CH$_3$CN, CH$_3$OH, OCS, HNCO, H$_2$CO, DCN and CH$_3$CH$_2$CN,
oriented perpendicular to the previously reported bipolar molecular outflow
from MM1. Modelling of the compact gas kinematics suggests a structure
undergoing rotation around the peak of the dust continuum emission. The
rotational profile can be well fit by a model of a Keplerian disc, including
infall, surrounding an enclosed mass of 30-60M$_{\odot}$, of which
2-3M$_{\odot}$ is attributed to the disc. From modelling the CH$_3$CN emission,
we determine that two temperature components, of 150 K and 230 K, are required
to adequately reproduce the spectra. Our 0.9 and 3.0cm VLA continuum data
exhibit an excess above the level expected from dust emission; the full
centimetre-submillimetre wavelength spectral energy distribution of MM1 is well
reproduced by a model including dust emission, an unresolved hypercompact
H{\i}{\i} region, and a compact ionised jet. In combination, our results
suggest that MM1 is an example of a massive proto-O star forming via disc
accretion, in a similar way to that of lower mass stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05574</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ellis</keyname><forenames>R. Keith</forenames></author></authors><title>Guido Altarelli and the evolution of QCD</title><categories>physics.hist-ph hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><report-no>IPPP/16/77</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I describe the contributions of Guido Altarelli to the development of Quantum
Chromodynamics from the discovery of asymptotic freedom until the end of the
S$p\bar{p}$S collider era, 1973-1985.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05579</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kompan</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>The giant frequency shift of intramolecular O-H vibration band in the
  raman spectra of water on the silver surface</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The giant frequency shift was observed in Raman spectra for inramolecular O-H
vibration band. The effect was observed in SERS-condition experiment, when
exciting light was focused by short-focus objective on the Ag-surface, merged
in water. The shift was detected relatively to the regularl position of band,
measured from the bulk of water under the same other conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05587</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Salac</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Vesicles in magnetic fields</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Liposome vesicles tend to align with an applied magnetic field. This is due
to the directional magnetic susceptibility difference of the lipids which form
the membrane of these vesicles. In this work a model of liposome vesicles
exposed to magnetic field is presented. Starting from the base energy of a
lipid membrane in a magnetic field, the force applied to the surrounding fluids
is derived. This force is then used to investigate the dynamics of vesicle in
the presence of magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05611</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicoletti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalleri</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear light-matter interaction at terahertz frequencies</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>55 pages, 34 figures</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Optics and Photonics Vol. 8, Issue 3, pp. 401-464
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/AOP.8.000401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong optical pulses at mid-infrared and terahertz frequencies have recently
emerged as a powerful tool to manipulate and control the solid state and
especially complex condensed matter systems with strongly correlated electrons.
The recent developments in high-power sources in the 0.1-30 THz frequency
range, both from table-top laser systems and Free-Electron Lasers, has provided
access to excitations of molecules and solids, which can be stimulated at their
resonance frequencies. Amongst these, we discuss free electrons in metals,
superconducting gaps and Josephson plasmons in layered superconductors,
vibrational modes of the crystal lattice (phonons), as well as magnetic
excitations. This Review provides an overview and illustrative examples of how
intense THz transients can be used to resonantly control matter, with
particular focus on strongly correlated electron systems and high-temperature
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05624</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanderson</keyname><forenames>Robyn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vera-Ciro</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helmi</keyname><forenames>Amina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heit</keyname><forenames>Joren</forenames></author></authors><title>Stream-subhalo interactions in the Aquarius simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>A&amp;A subm</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform the first self-consistent measurement of the rate of interactions
between stellar tidal streams created by disrupting satellites and dark
subhalos in a cosmological simulation of a Milky-Way-mass galaxy. Using a
retagged version of the Aquarius A dark-matter-only simulation, we selected 18
streams of tagged star particles that appear thin at the present day and
followed them from the point their progenitors accrete onto the main halo,
recording in each snapshot the characteristics of all dark-matter subhalos
passing within several distance thresholds of any tagged star particle in each
stream. We considered distance thresholds corresponding to constant impact
parameters (1, 2, and 5 kpc), as well as those proportional to the region of
influence of each subhalo (one and two times its half-mass radius $r_{1/2}$).
We then measured the age and present-day, phase-unwrapped length of each stream
in order to compute the interaction rate in different mass bins and for
different thresholds, and compared these to analytic predictions from the
literature. We measure a median rate of $1.5^{+3.0}_{-1.1}\
(9.1^{+17.5}_{-7.1},\ 61.8^{+211}_{-40.6})$ interactions within 1 (2, 5) kpc of
the stream per 10 kpc of stream length per 10 Gyr. Resolution effects (both
time and particle number) affect these estimated rates by lowering them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05625</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>Rupert L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Phan Th&#xe0;nh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosch</keyname><forenames>Hanne Van Den</forenames></author></authors><title>The maximal excess charge in M\&quot;uller density-matrix-functional theory</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an atom described by M\&quot;uller theory, which is similar to
Hartree-Fock theory, but with a modified exchange term. We prove that a nucleus
of charge Z can bind at most Z+C electrons, where C is a universal constant.
Our proof proceeds by comparison with Thomas-Fermi theory and a key ingredient
is a novel bound on the number of electrons far from the nucleus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05626</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shao-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venkataraman</keyname><forenames>Dhandapani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramasubramaniam</keyname><forenames>Ashwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Activation of new Raman modes by inversion symmetry breaking in type II
  Weyl semimetal candidate T'-MoTe2</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Incorporates earlier results presented in arXiv:1602.03566 entitled
  as Inversion-symmetry-breaking-activated shear Raman bands in T'-MoTe2</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b02666</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We synthesized distorted octahedral(T') molybdenum ditelluride (MoTe2) and
investigated its vibrational properties with Raman spectroscopy, density
functional theory and symmetry analysis. Compared to the results from high
temperature centrosymmetric monoclinic (T'mo) phase, four new Raman bands
emerge in the low temperature orthorhombic (T'or) phase, which was recently
predicted to be a type II Weyl semimetal. Crystal-angle-dependent,
light-polarization-resolved measurements indicate that all the observed Raman
peaks belong to two categories: those vibrating along the zigzag Mo atomic
chain (z-mode) and those vibrating in the mirror plane (m-mode) perpendicular
to the zigzag chain. Interestingly the low energy shear z-mode and shear
m-mode, absent from the T'mo spectra, become activated when sample cooling
induces a phase transition to the T'or crystal structure. We interpret this
observation as a consequence of inversion-symmetry breaking, which is crucial
for the existence of Weyl fermions in the layered crystal. Our temperature
dependent Raman measurements further show that both the high energy m-mode at
130 cm-1 and the low energy shear m-mode at 12 cm-1 provide useful gauges for
monitoring the broken inversion symmetry in the crystal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05638</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Cataldo</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Lieto</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maccarrone</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paffuti</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements and analysis of current-voltage characteristic of a pn
  diode for an undergraduate physics laboratory</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that in a simple experiment at undergraduate level, suitable to be
performed in classes of science and engineering students, it is possible to
test accurately, on a popular 1N4148 p-n diode, the range of the junction
currents where the Shockley equation model can be considered satisfactory. The
experiment benefits from a system of temperature control and data collection
driven in a LabVIEW environment. With these tools a large quantity of data can
be recorded in the temporal frame of a lab session. Significant deviations of
the experimental I-V with respect to the ideal behaviour curve predicted by the
Shockley equation are observed, both at low and high current. A better
agreement over the entire range is obtained introducing, as is customary, a
four parameters model, including a parallel and a series resistance. A new
iterative fitting procedure is presented which treats the I-V data of different
regimes on the same level, and allows a simultaneous determination of the four
parameters for each temperature selected. Moreover, the knowledge of the
temperature dependence of saturation current is used to estimate the energy gap
of silicon. The connection of a macroscopic measure with a microscopic quantity
is another valuable feature of this experiment, from an educational point of
view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05640</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Poyraz</keyname><forenames>Deniz</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the top quark properties in the production and decays of
  top anti-top pair events at CMS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 6 figures. Proceedings of the DIS 2016 XXIV International
  Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects</comments><report-no>CMS CR-2016/179</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of several top-quark properties obtained from CMS data collected
at various centre-of-mass energies are presented. The results include
measurements of the top pair charge asymmetry, $\textrm{t}\bar{\textrm{t}}$
spin correlation, CP violation and the cross section of
$\textrm{t}\bar{\textrm{t}}$ events produced in association with a W or a Z
boson. The results are compared with predictions from the standard model as
well as new physics models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05646</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zypman</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vibration of a Cantilever Beam in Ambient Fluid</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we obtain analytical expressions for the frequency response of a
cantilever beam in the presence of ambient fluid. The advantage of our
approach, besides its simplicity of use, is that it explicitly contains the
viscosity and the density of the ambient fluid. Thus, if measuring the
frequency spectrum, the expression can be used in the design of viscometers.
Conversely, if the ambient fluid is known, the expression can be used in the
design of force gauges such as in Atomic Force Microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05648</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Parihar</keyname><forenames>Abhinav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>Nikhil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jerry</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Suman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raychowdhury</keyname><forenames>Arijit</forenames></author></authors><title>Computing with Dynamical Systems Based on Insulator-Metal-Transition
  Oscillators</title><categories>cs.ET cond-mat.mes-hall math.DS</categories><comments>Submitted to Journal of Nanophotonics for review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we review recent work on novel computing paradigms using
coupled oscillatory dynamical systems. We explore systems of relaxation
oscillators based on linear state transitioning devices, which switch between
two discrete states with hysteresis. By harnessing the dynamics of complex,
connected systems we embrace the philosophy of &quot;let physics do the computing&quot;
and demonstrate how complex phase and frequency dynamics of such systems can be
controlled, programmed and observed to solve computationally hard problems.
Although our discussion in this paper is limited to Insulator-to-Metallic (IMT)
state transition devices, the general philosophy of such computing paradigms
can be translated to other mediums including optical systems. We present the
necessary mathematical treatments necessary to understand the time evolution of
these systems and demonstrate through recent experimental results the potential
of such computational primitives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05649</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Agsten</keyname><forenames>Britte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pursiainen</keyname><forenames>Sampsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolters</keyname><forenames>Carsten H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Advanced boundary electrode modeling for tES and parallel tES/EEG</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>83C50, 65M60, 92C55</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper explores advanced electrode modeling in the context of separate
and parallel transcranial electrical stimulation (tES) and
electroencephalography (EEG) measurements. We focus on boundary condition based
approaches that do not necessitate adding auxiliary elements, e.g. sponges, to
the computational domain. In particular, we investigate the complete electrode
model (CEM) which incorporates a detailed description of the skin-electrode
interface including its contact surface, impedance and normal current
distribution. The CEM can be applied for both tES and EEG electrodes which is
advantageous when a parallel system is used. In comparison to the CEM, we test
two important reduced approaches: the gap model (GAP) and the point electrode
model (PEM). We aim to find out the differences of these approaches for a
realistic numerical setting based on the stimulation of the auditory cortex.
The results obtained suggest, among other things, that GAP and GAP/PEM are
sufficiently accurate for the practical application of tES and parallel
tES/EEG, respectively. Differences between CEM and GAP were observed mainly in
the skin compartment, where only CEM explains the heating effects
characteristic to tES.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05652</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author></authors><title>On direct and inverse spectral problems for sloshing of a two-layer
  fluid in an open container</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study direct and inverse eigenvalue problems for a pair of harmonic
functions with a spectral parameter in boundary and coupling conditions. The
direct problem is relevant to sloshing frequencies of free oscillations of a
two-layer fluid in a container. The upper fluid occupies a layer bounded above
by a free surface and below by a layer of fluid of greater density. Both fluids
are assumed to be inviscid, incompressible, and heavy, whereas the free surface
and the interface between fluids are supposed to be bounded.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05663</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ion Beam radiation and temperature effect on Co/Si and CoO/Co/Si thin
  films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physics Procedia, 54, 2014, 87-89</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Co and CoO thin films were deposited by magnetron sputtering in the form of
multilayers. They were irradiated with Ar and Si ion beams of different
energies and fluences. The magnetic properties were investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05667</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanocomposite si-c-n coatings</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Summary of PhD thesis awarded by Department of Metallurgy and
  Materials Engineering, Jadavpur University, Kolkata 2009</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coatings of ternary nanocomposite Si-C-N ceramic coatings have shown newer
and improved mechanical and functional properties over the coarser and
monolithic coatings. Properties like high hardness, wear resistance, oxidation
resistance, tunable band gap and chemical inertness have been observed for
Si-C-N which makes its potential for numerous applications. Although lot of
research has taken place in Si-C-N coatings, proper understanding of the effect
of different parameters on the coating properties are still not resolved. The
changes occurring in fraction of Si, C and N and the phases forming in the
coatings with variation in deposition conditions require investigations. This
research paper gives a systematic study of the role of different deposition
parameters like substrate temperature, pressure, power on the nucleation and
growth, structure, microstructural bonding and mechanical properties of the
film deposited by magnetron sputtering which adds significantly to the
fundamental knowledge of nanocomposite Si-C-N coatings as well as its
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05671</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Boudourides</keyname><forenames>Moses A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenis</keyname><forenames>Sergios T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dominating sets and ego-centered decompositions in social networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Special Topics 225, 1293-1310 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-02673-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our aim here is to address the problem of decomposing a whole network into a
minimal number of ego-centered subnetworks. For this purpose, the network egos
are picked out as the members of a minimum dominating set of the network.
However, to find such an efficient dominating ego-centered construction, we
need to be able to detect all the minimum dominating sets and to compare all
the corresponding dominating ego-centered decompositions of the network. To
find all the minimum dominating sets of the network, we are developing a
computational heuristic, which is based on the partition of the set of nodes of
a graph into three subsets, the always dominant vertices, the possible dominant
vertices and the never dominant vertices, when the domination number of the
network is known. To compare the ensuing dominating ego-centered decompositions
of the network, we are introducing a number of structural measures that count
the number of nodes and links inside and across the ego-centered subnetworks.
Furthermore, we are applying the techniques of graph domination and
ego=centered decomposition for six empirical social networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05672</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoherent histories approach to the cosmological measure problem</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages, plain TeX</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The method of decoherent histories allows probabilities to be assigned to
sequences of quantum events in systems, such as the universe as a whole, where
there is no external observer to make measurements. This paper applies the
method of decoherent histories to address cosmological questions. Using a
series of simple examples, beginning with the harmonic oscillator, we show that
systems in a stationary state such as an energy eigenstate or thermal state can
exhibit decoherent histories with non-trivial dynamics. We then examine
decoherent histories in a universe that undergoes eternal inflation. Decoherent
histories that assign probabilities to sequences of events in the vicinity of a
timelike geodesic supply a natural cosmological measure. Under reasonable
conditions, such sequences of events do not suffer from the presence of
unlikely statistical fluctuations that mimic reality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05686</id><created>2016-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Brian E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horrom</keyname><forenames>Travis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Kevin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lett</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of input phase modulation to a phase-sensitive optical
  amplifier</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express, 24(17), 19871-19880 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.019871</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many optical applications depend on amplitude modulating optical beams using
devices such as acousto-optical modulators (AOMs) or optical choppers. Methods
to add amplitude modulation (AM) often inadvertently impart phase modulation
(PM) onto the light as well. While this PM is of no consequence to many
phase-insensitive applications, phase-sensitive processes can be affected. Here
we study the effects of input phase and amplitude modulation on the output of a
quantum-noise limited phase-sensitive optical amplifier (PSA) realized in hot
$^{85}$Rb vapor. We investigate the dependence of PM on AOM alignment and
demonstrate a novel approach to quantifying PM by using the PSA as a diagnostic
tool. We then use this method to measure the alignment-dependent PM of an
optical chopper which arises due to diffraction effects as the chopper blade
passes through the optical beam.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0411013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0411013</id><created>2004-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Hyun</keyname><forenames>Seungjoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Kyungho</forenames></author></authors><title>Open-Closed String Duality from Orbifolded Conifolds</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:hep-th/0105066 by other
  authors</comments><journal-ref>J.Geom.Phys. 56 (2006) 405-417</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.geomphys.2005.02.009</doi><abstract>  We study large N dualities for a class of ${\cal N} = 1$ theories realized on
type IIB D5 branes wrapping 2-cycles of local Calabi-Yau threefolds which is
obtained from resolving orbifolded conifolds or as effective field theories on
D4 branes in type IIA brane configurations. The field theory is $\mathcal{N}
=1$ supersymmetric $\prod U(N_{ij})$ Yang-Mills gauge theory. Strong coupling
effects are analyzed in the deformed geometry. We propose open-closed string
duality via a geometric transition in toric geometry. The T-dual type IIA
picture and M-theory lifting are also considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
