<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:54:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-18" from="2016-08-18" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1003.3327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1003.3327</id><created>2010-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Pranav</keyname><forenames>Pratyush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jog</keyname><forenames>Chanda J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Response of a galactic disc to vertical perturbations : Strong
  dependence on density distribution</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS.</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 406,
  Issue 1, pp. 576-585, 2010</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2010.16695.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the self-consistent, linear response of a galactic disc to
non-axisymmetric perturbations in the vertical direction as due to a tidal
encounter, and show that the density distribution near the disc mid-plane has a
strong impact on the radius beyond which distortions like warps develop. The
self-gravity of the disc resists distortion in the inner parts. Applying this
approach to a galactic disc with an exponential vertical profile, Saha &amp; Jog
showed that warps develop beyond 4-6 disc scalelengths, which could hence be
only seen in HI. The real galactic discs, however, have less steep vertical
density distributions that lie between a sech and an exponential profile. Here
we calculate the disc response for such a general sech^(2/n) density
distribution, and show that the warps develop from a smaller radius of 2-4 disc
scalelengths. This naturally explains why most galaxies show stellar warps that
start within the optical radius. Thus a qualitatively different picture of
ubiquitous optical warps emerges for the observed less-steep density profiles.
The surprisingly strong dependence on the density profile is due to the fact
that the disc self-gravity depends crucially on its mass distribution close to
the mid-plane. General results for the radius of onset of warps, obtained as a
function of the disc scalelength and the vertical scaleheight, are presented as
contour plots which can be applied to any galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1102.3326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1102.3326</id><created>2011-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Hugouvieux</keyname><forenames>Virginie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Axelos</keyname><forenames>Monique A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolb</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>Micelle formation, gelation and phase separation of amphiphilic
  multiblock copolymers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>14 pages, 14 figures; Soft Matter (2011)</comments><doi>10.1039/C0SM01018A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phase behaviour of amphiphilic multiblock copolymers with a large number
of blocks in semidilute solutions is studied by lattice Monte Carlo
simulations. The influence on the resulting structures of the concentration,
the solvent quality and the ratio of hydrophobic to hydrophilic monomers in the
chains has been assessed explicitely. Several distinct regimes are put in
evidence. For poorly substituted (mainly hydrophilic) copolymers formation of
micelles is observed, either isolated or connected by the hydrophilic moieties,
depending on concentration and chain length. For more highly substituted chains
larger tubular hydrophobic structures appear which, at higher concentration,
join to form extended hydrophobic cores. For both substitution ratios gelation
is observed, but with a very different gel network structure. For the poorly
substituted chains the gel consists of micelles cross-linked by hydrophilic
blocks whereas for the highly substituted copolymers the extended hydrophobic
cores form the gelling network. The interplay between gelation and phase
separation clearly appears in the phase diagram. In particular, for poorly
substituted copolymers and in a narrow concentration range, we observe a
sol-gel transition followed by an inverse gel-sol transition when increasing
the interaction energy. The simulation results are discussed in the context of
the experimentally observed phase properties of methylcellulose, a
hydrophobically substituted polysaccharide.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1211.2446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1211.2446</id><created>2012-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Addington</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>D-brane probes, branched double covers, and noncommutative resolutions</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>61 pages, LaTeX</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Theor. Math. Phys. 18(6):1369-1436, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/ATMP.2014.v18.n6.a5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes D-brane probes of theories arising in abelian gauged
linear sigma models (GLSMs) describing branched double covers and
noncommutative resolutions thereof, via nonperturbative effects rather than as
the critical locus of a superpotential. As these theories can be described as
IR limits of Landau-Ginzburg models, technically this paper is an exercise in
utilizing (sheafy) matrix factorizations. For Landau-Ginzburg models which are
believed to flow in the IR to smooth branched double covers, our D-brane probes
recover the structure of the branched double cover (and flat nontrivial B
fields), verifying previous results. In addition to smooth branched double
covers, the same class of Landau-Ginzburg models is also believed to sometimes
flow to `noncommutative resolutions' of singular spaces. These noncommutative
resolutions are abstract conformal field theories without a global geometric
description, but D-brane probes perceive them as non-Kahler small resolutions
of a singular Calabi-Yau. We conjecture that such non-Kahler small resolutions
are typical in D-brane probes of such theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.0236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.0236</id><created>2013-03-31</created><updated>2016-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fiorenza</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>Christopher L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiber</keyname><forenames>Urs</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher U(1)-gerbe connections in geometric prequantization</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.AT math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>Title changed. Exposition revised. 55 pages</comments><msc-class>81T70, 53D50, 53D17, 55N30</msc-class><journal-ref>Rev. Math. Phys., Vol. 28, Issue 06, 1650012 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0129055X16500124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We promote geometric prequantization to higher geometry (higher stacks),
where a prequantization is given by a higher principal connection (a higher
gerbe with connection). We show fairly generally how there is canonically a
tower of higher gauge groupoids and Courant groupoids assigned to a higher
prequantization, and establish the corresponding Atiyah sequence as an
integrated Kostant-Souriau infinity-group extension of higher Hamiltonian
symplectomorphisms by higher quantomorphisms. We also exhibit the
infinity-group cocycle which classifies this extension and discuss how its
restrictions along Hamiltonian infinity-actions yield higher Heisenberg
cocycles. In the special case of higher differential geometry over smooth
manifolds we find the L-infinity-algebra extension of Hamiltonian vector fields
-- which is the higher Poisson bracket of local observables -- and show that it
is equivalent to the construction proposed by the second author in n-plectic
geometry. Finally we indicate a list of examples of applications of higher
prequantization in the extended geometric quantization of local quantum field
theories and specifically in string geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.5767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.5767</id><created>2013-05-24</created><updated>2013-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Addington</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspinwall</keyname><forenames>Paul S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Categories of Massless D-Branes and del Pezzo Surfaces</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>LaTeX, 40 pages, refs added</comments><journal-ref>J. High Energy Phys. 7(176):39pp., 2013</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2013)176</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In analogy with the physical concept of a massless D-brane, we define a
notion of &quot;Q-masslessness&quot; for objects in the derived category. This is defined
in terms of monodromy around singularities in the stringy Kahler moduli space
and is relatively easy to study using spherical functors. We consider several
examples in which del Pezzo surfaces and other rational surfaces in Calabi-Yau
threefolds are contracted. For precisely the del Pezzo surfaces that can be
written as hypersurfaces in weighted P3, the category of Q-massless objects is
a &quot;fractional Calabi-Yau&quot; category of graded matrix factorizations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.4848</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.4848</id><created>2013-07-18</created><updated>2014-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Si-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Li-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>General monogamy property of global quantum discord and the application</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 348, 256 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2014.05.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a family of general monogamy inequalities for global quantum
discord (GQD), which can be considered as an extension of the usual discord
monogamy inequality. It can be shown that those inequalities are satisfied
under the similar condition for the holding of usual monogamy relation. We find
that there is an intrinsic connection among them. Furthermore, we present a
different type of monogamy inequality and prove that it holds under the
condition that the bipartite GQDs do not increase when tracing out some
subsystems. We also study the residual GQD based on the second type of monogamy
inequality. As applications of those quantities, we investigate the GQDs and
residual GQD in characterizing the quantum phase transition in the transverse
field Ising model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.3159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.3159</id><created>2013-10-11</created><updated>2016-08-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rachel</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum phase transitions of topological insulators without gap closing</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>v3: 15 pages, 5 figures; refs. added - final version</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 405502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/40/405502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider two-dimensional Chern insulators and time-reversal invariant
topological insulators and discuss the effect of perturbations breaking either
particle-number conservation or time-reversal symmetry. The appearance of
trivial mass terms is expected to cause quantum phase transitions into trivial
phases when such a perturbation overweights the topological term. These phase
transitions are usually associated with a bulk-gap closing. In contrast, the
chiral Chern insulator is unaffected by particle-number breaking perturbations.
Moreover, the $\mathbb{Z}_2$ topological insulator undergoes phase transitions
into topologically trivial phases without bulk-gap closing in the presence of
any of such perturbations. In certain cases, these phase transitions can be
circumvented and the protection restored by another U(1) symmetry, e.g. due to
spin conservation. These findings are discussed in the context of interacting
topological insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.3661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.3661</id><created>2014-01-15</created><updated>2014-11-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Addington</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donovan</keyname><forenames>Will</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segal</keyname><forenames>Ed</forenames></author></authors><title>The Pfaffian-Grassmannian equivalence revisited</title><categories>math.AG hep-th</categories><comments>Improved exposition, minor corrections. 32 pages</comments><msc-class>Primary 14F05, 14J32, 18E30, 81T30, Secondary 14M15</msc-class><journal-ref>Alg. Geom. 2(3):332-364, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.14231/AG-2015-015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a new proof of the 'Pfaffian-Grassmannian' derived equivalence
between certain pairs of non-birational Calabi-Yau threefolds. Our proof
follows the physical constructions of Hori and Tong, and we factor the
equivalence into three steps by passing through some intermediate categories of
(global) matrix factorizations. The first step is global Knoerrer periodicity,
the second comes from a birational map between Landau-Ginzburg B-models, and
for the third we develop some new techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.5012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.5012</id><created>2014-04-20</created><updated>2016-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ching-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Min-Hsiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Hsiao-feng</forenames></author></authors><title>On the MacWilliams Identity for Classical and Quantum Convolutional
  Codes</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT quant-ph</categories><comments>Part of this work was in Proceedings of IEEE Intl. Symp. Inf. Theory
  2014, and part of this work was in Proceedings of IEEE Information Theory
  Workshop 2014. 11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Communications, vol. 64, no. 8, pp.
  3148-3159, Aug 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TCOMM.2016.2585641</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The weight generating functions associated with convolutional codes (CCs) are
based on state space realizations or the weight adjacency matrices (WAMs). The
MacWilliams identity for CCs on the WAMs was first established by Gluesing-
Luerssen and Schneider in the case of minimal encoders, and generalized by
Forney. We consider this problem in the viewpoint of constraint codes and
obtain a simple and direct proof of this MacWilliams identity in the case of
minimal encoders. For our purpose, we choose a different representation for the
exact weight generating function (EWGF) of a block code, by defining it as a
linear combination of orthonormal vectors in Dirac bra-ket notation. This
representation provides great flexibility so that general split weight
generating functions and their MacWilliams identities can be easily obtained
from the MacWilliams identity for EWGFs. As a result, we also obtain the
MacWilliams identity for the input-parity weight adjacency matrices of a
systematic convolutional code and its dual. Finally, paralleling the
development of the classical case, we establish the MacWilliams identity for
quantum convolutional codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.4965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.4965</id><created>2014-05-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Si-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Global quantum discord and quantum phase transition in XY model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 362,805 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2015.09.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the relationship between the behavior of global quantum correlations
and quantum phase transitions in XY model. We find that the two kinds of phase
transitions in the studied model can be characterized by the features of global
quantum discord (GQD) and the corresponding quantum correlations. We
demonstrate that the maximum of the sum of all the nearest neighbor bipartite
GQDs is effective and accurate for signaling the Ising quantum phase
transition, in contrast, the sudden change of GQD is very suitable for
characterizing another phase transition in the XY model. This may shed lights
on the study of properties of quantum correlations in different quantum phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.4423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.4423</id><created>2014-06-17</created><updated>2014-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Breier</keyname><forenames>Rebekka E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selinger</keyname><forenames>Robin L. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciccotti</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herminghaus</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazza</keyname><forenames>Marco G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous chiral symmetry breaking in model bacterial suspensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.022410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chiral symmetry breaking is ubiquitous in biological systems, from DNA to
bacterial suspensions. A key unresolved problem is how chiral structures may
spontaneously emerge from achiral interactions. We study a simple model of
bacterial suspensions in three dimensions that effectively incorporates active
motion and hydrodynamic interactions. We perform large-scale molecular dynamics
simulations (up to $10^6$ particles) and describe stable (or long-lived
metastable) collective states that exhibit chiral organization although the
interactions are achiral. We elucidate under which conditions these chiral
states will emerge and grow to large scales. We also study a related
equilibrium model that clarifies the role of orientational fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.3012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.3012</id><created>2014-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Si-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipartite distribution property of one way discord beyond measurement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 354, 157 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2014.12.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the distribution property of one way discord in multipartite
system by introducing the concept of polygamy deficit for one way discord. The
difference between one way discord and quantum discord is analogue to the
difference between entanglement of assistance and entanglement of formation.
For tripartite pure states, two kinds of polygamy deficits are presented with
the equivalent expressions and physical interpretations regardless of
measurement. For four-partite pure states, we provide a condition which makes
one way discord polygamy being satisfied. Those results can be applicable to
multipartite quantum systems and are complementary to our understanding of the
shareability of quantum correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7755</id><created>2014-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Vinjanampathy</keyname><forenames>Sai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modi</keyname><forenames>Kavan</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlations, operations and the second law of thermodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.class-ph</categories><journal-ref>Int. J. Quantum Inf. 14, 1640033 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749916400335</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Completely positive trace preserving maps are essential for the formulation
of the second law of thermodynamics. The dynamics of quantum systems,
correlated with their environments, are in general not described by such maps.
We explore how this issue can be fixed by describing the classical analogue of
this problem. We consider correlated probability distributions, whose
subsequent system dynamics is ill-described by stochastic maps, and prescribe
the correct way to describe the dynamics. We use this prescription to discuss
the classical version of the second law, valid for correlated probability
distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02987</id><created>2015-02-10</created><updated>2016-04-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Runyao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Severini</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>On zero-error communication via quantum channels in the presence of
  noiseless feedback</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.CO math.IT</categories><comments>34 pages, 1 figure; v2 has improved presentation, numerous typos
  corrected and many more references; v3 equivalent to final, accepted journal
  version (IEEE Trans Inf Theory)</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory, vol. 62, no. 9, pp. 5260-5277 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2016.2562580</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We initiate the study of zero-error communication via quantum channels when
the receiver and sender have at their disposal a noiseless feedback channel of
unlimited quantum capacity, generalizing Shannon's zero-error communication
theory with instantaneous feedback.
  We first show that this capacity is a function only of the linear span of
Choi-Kraus operators of the channel, which generalizes the bipartite
equivocation graph of a classical channel, and which we dub &quot;non-commutative
bipartite graph&quot;. Then we go on to show that the feedback-assisted capacity is
non-zero (with constant activating noiseless communication) if and only if the
non-commutative bipartite graph is non-trivial, and give a number of equivalent
characterizations. This result involves a far-reaching extension of the
&quot;conclusive exclusion&quot; of quantum states [Pusey/Barrett/Rudolph, Nature Phys.
8:475-478].
  We then present an upper bound on the feedback-assisted zero-error capacity,
motivated by a conjecture originally made by Shannon and proved later by
Ahlswede. We demonstrate this bound to have many good properties, including
being additive and given by a minimax formula. We also prove that this quantity
is the entanglement-assisted capacity against an adversarially chosen channel
from the set of all channels with the same Choi-Kraus span, which can also be
interpreted as the feedback-assisted unambiguous capacity. The proof relies on
a generalization of the &quot;Postselection Lemma&quot; [Christandl/Koenig/Renner, PRL
102:020504] that allows to reflect additional constraints, and which we believe
to be of independent interest.
  We illustrate our ideas with a number of examples, including
classical-quantum channels and Weyl diagonal channels, and close with an
extensive discussion of open questions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03379</id><created>2015-03-11</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schneck</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabrera</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerdeno</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandic</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>H. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agnese</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakishiyeva</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakur</keyname><forenames>R. Basu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billard</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgland</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldwell</keyname><forenames>D. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calkins</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chagani</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooley</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornell</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crewdson</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cushman</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daal</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Stefano</keyname><forenames>P. C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doughty</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esteban</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallows</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Figueroa-Feliciano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godfrey</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golwala</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>H. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofer</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holmgren</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jardin</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jastram</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamaev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kara</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelsey</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennedy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leder</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asamar</keyname><forenames>E. Lopez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukens</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahapatra</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirabolfathi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moffatt</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendoza</keyname><forenames>J. D. Morales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oser</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Page</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Page</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Partridge</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phipps</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pyle</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redl</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reisetter</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saab</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadoulet</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sander</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnee</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scorza</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serfass</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shank</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Speller</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toback</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyayula</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villano</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Welliver</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yellin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yen</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter effective field theory scattering in direct detection
  experiments</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>Newest version includes erratum</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 91, 092004 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.092004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the consequences of the effective field theory (EFT) of dark
matter-nucleon scattering for current and proposed direct detection
experiments. Exclusion limits on EFT coupling constants computed using the
optimum interval method are presented for SuperCDMS Soudan, CDMS II, and LUX,
and the necessity of combining results from multiple experiments in order to
determine dark matter parameters is discussed. We demonstrate that spectral
differences between the standard dark matter model and a general EFT
interaction can produce a bias when calculating exclusion limits and when
developing signal models for likelihood and machine learning techniques. We
also discuss the implications of the EFT for the next-generation (G2) direct
detection experiments and point out regions of complementarity in the EFT
parameter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04702</id><created>2015-03-16</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cattan&#xe9;o</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdrix</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimum Degree up to Local Complementation: Bounds, Parameterized
  Complexity, and Exact Algorithms</title><categories>cs.DM math.CO quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>ISAAC 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-662-48971-0_23</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The local minimum degree of a graph is the minimum degree that can be reached
by means of local complementation. For any n, there exist graphs of order n
which have a local minimum degree at least 0.189n, or at least 0.110n when
restricted to bipartite graphs. Regarding the upper bound, we show that for any
graph of order n, its local minimum degree is at most 3n/8+o(n) and n/4+o(n)
for bipartite graphs, improving the known n/2 upper bound. We also prove that
the local minimum degree is smaller than half of the vertex cover number (up to
a logarithmic term). The local minimum degree problem is NP-Complete and hard
to approximate. We show that this problem, even when restricted to bipartite
graphs, is in W[2] and FPT-equivalent to the EvenSet problem, which
W[1]-hardness is a long standing open question. Finally, we show that the local
minimum degree is computed by a O*(1.938^n)-algorithm, and a
O*(1.466^n)-algorithm for the bipartite graphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04755</id><created>2015-06-15</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>van de Meent</keyname><forenames>Maarten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>Abhay G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Metric perturbations produced by eccentric equatorial orbits around a
  Kerr black hole</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Fix typo in eq 17</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 064025 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.064025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first numerical calculation of the (local) metric perturbation
produced by a small compact object moving on an eccentric equatorial geodesic
around a Kerr black hole, accurate to first order in the mass ratio. The
procedure starts by first solving the Teukolsky equation to obtain the Weyl
scalar $\psi_4$ using semi-analytical methods. The metric perturbation is then
reconstructed from $\psi_4$ in an (outgoing) radiation gauge, adding the
appropriate non-radiative contributions arising from the shifts in mass and
angular momentum of the spacetime.
  As a demonstration we calculate the generalized redshift $U$ as a function of
the orbital frequencies $\Omega_r$ and $\Omega_\phi$ to linear order in the
mass ratio, a gauge invariant measure of the conservative corrections to the
orbit due to self-interactions. In Schwarzschild, the results surpass the
existing result in the literature in accuracy, and we find new estimates for
some of the unknown 4PN and 5PN terms in the post-Newtonian expansion of $U$.
In Kerr, we provide completely novel values of $U$ for eccentric equatorial
orbits. Calculation of the full self-force will appear in a forthcoming paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07557</id><created>2015-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fiorenza</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sati</keyname><forenames>Hisham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiber</keyname><forenames>Urs</forenames></author></authors><title>The WZW term of the M5-brane and differential cohomotopy</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.AT math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 56, 102301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4932618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We combine rational homotopy theory and higher Lie theory to describe the WZW
term in the M5-brane sigma model. We observe that this term admits a natural
interpretation as a twisted 7-cocycle on super-Minkowski spacetime with
coefficients in the rational 4-sphere. This exhibits the WZW term as an element
in twisted cohomology, with the twist given by the cocycle of the M2-brane. We
consider integration of this rational situation to differential cohomology and
differential cohomotopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01012</id><created>2015-07-03</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bergeron</keyname><forenames>Dominic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>A. -M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Algorithms for optimized maximum entropy and diagnostic tools for
  analytic continuation</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 023303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.023303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analytic continuation of numerical data obtained in imaginary time or
frequency has become an essential part of many branches of quantum
computational physics. It is, however, an ill-conditioned procedure and thus a
hard numerical problem. The maximum-entropy approach, based on bayesian
inference, is the most widely used method to tackle that problem. Although the
approach is well established and among the most reliable and efficient ones,
useful developments of the method and of its implementation are still possible.
In addition, while a few free software implementations are available, a
well-documented, optimized, general purpose and user-friendly software
dedicated to that specific task is still lacking. Here we analyze all aspects
of the implementation that are critical for accuracy and speed, and present a
highly optimized approach to maximum-entropy. Original algorithmic and
conceptual contributions include (1) numerical approximations that yield a
computational complexity that is almost independent of temperature and spectrum
shape (including sharp Drude peaks in broad background for example) while
ensuring quantitative accuracy of the result whenever precision of the data is
sufficient, (2) a robust method of choosing the entropy weight $\alpha$ that
follows from a simple consistency condition of the approach and the observation
that information- and noise-fitting regimes can be identified clearly from the
behavior of $\chi^2$ with respect to $\alpha$, and (3) several diagnostics to
assess the reliability of the result. Benchmarks with test spectral functions
of different complexity and an example with an actual physical simulation are
presented. Our implementation, which covers most typical cases for fermions,
bosons and response functions, is available as an open source, user friendly
software.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02653</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ebrahimi</keyname><forenames>Zanyar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karami</keyname><forenames>Kayoomars</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant absorption of kink magnetohydrodynamic waves by a magnetic
  twist in coronal loops</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, matched to published version</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 462, 1002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1677</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is ample evidence of twisted magnetic structures in the solar corona.
This motivates us to consider the magnetic twist as the cause of Alfven
frequency continuum in the coronal loops, which can support the resonant
absorption as a rapid damping mechanism for the observed coronal kink
magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) oscillations. We model a coronal loop with a straight
cylindrical magnetic flux tube which has constant but different densities in
the interior and exterior regions. The magnetic field is assumed to be constant
and aligned with the cylinder axis everywhere except a thin layer near the
boundary of the flux tube which has an additional small magnetic field twist.
Then, we investigate a number of possible instabilities that may arise in our
model. In the thin tube thin boundary approximation, we derive the dispersion
relation and solve it analytically to obtain the frequencies and damping rates
of the fundamental (l=1) and first/second overtone (l=2,3) kink (m=1) MHD
modes. We conclude that the resonant absorption by the magnetic twist can
justify the rapid damping of kink MHD waves observed in coronal loops.
Furthermore, the magnetic twist in the inhomogeneous layer can cause deviations
from P1/P2=2 and P1/P3=3 which are comparable with the observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00747</id><created>2015-08-04</created><updated>2015-10-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ritacco</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adam</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adane</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andr&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beelen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belier</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beno&#xee;t</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bideaud</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billot</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourrion</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catalano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coiffard</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Comis</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Addabbo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xe9;sert</keyname><forenames>F. -X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doyle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goupy</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leclercq</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mac&#xed;as-P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martino</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maury</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monfardini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pajot</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascale</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perotto</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisano</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponthieu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebolo-Iglesias</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xe9;veret</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sievers</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thum</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triqueneaux</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zylka</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>First polarised light with the NIKA camera</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages, Proceeding for Journal of Low Temperature Physics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Low Temperature Physics, Volume 184, Issue 3-4, pp.
  724-732, 08/2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-015-1340-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NIKA is a dual-band camera operating with 315 frequency multiplexed LEKIDs
cooled at 100 mK. NIKA is designed to observe the sky in intensity and
polarisation at 150 and 260 GHz from the IRAM 30-m telescope. It is a
test-bench for the final NIKA2 camera. The incoming linear polarisation is
modulated at four times the mechanical rotation frequency by a warm rotating
multi-layer Half Wave Plate. Then, the signal is analysed by a wire grid and
finally absorbed by the LEKIDs. The small time constant (&lt; 1ms ) of the LEKID
detectors combined with the modulation of the HWP enables the
quasi-simultaneous measurement of the three Stokes parameters I, Q, U,
representing linear polarisation. In this paper we present results of recent
observational campaigns demonstrating the good performance of NIKA in detecting
polarisation at mm wavelength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04997</id><created>2015-08-20</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Junpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Kangjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yupeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Bethe States of the integrable spin-s chain with generic open boundaries</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, no figure, published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 014001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/1/014001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the inhomogeneous T-Q relation and the associated Bethe Ansatz
equations obtained via the off-diagonal Bethe Ansatz, we construct the
Bethe-type eigenstates of the SU(2)-invariant spin-s chain with generic
non-diagonal boundaries by employing certain orthogonal basis of the Hilbert
space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02838</id><created>2015-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Zhenjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hu</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of highly reactive oxygen species by co-adsorption of oxygen
  and water on metal-supported MgO(100) thinfilms</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. , 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP03236B</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation of highly reactive oxygen species (ROS) on metal oxide surfaces
have attracted considerable interest due to their diverse applications. In this
work, we have performed densi-ty-functional theory calculations to investigate
the co-adsorption of oxygen and water on ul-trathin MgO(100) films deposited on
Mo(100) substrate. We reveal that the molecular oxygen can be stepwise
decomposed completely with the assistance of water. Consequently, a series of
highly ROS including superoxide, hydroperoxide, hydroxyl and single oxygen
adatom are formed on Mo(100) supported MgO(100) thinfilms. The reaction
barriers accompanied by the generation of ROS are reported, and the influence
of the thickness of MgO(100) films is also discussed. The most promising routes
to produce these fascinating species provide valuable information to understand
the importance of synergistic effect, namely the substrate, the co-adorbed
species, and the film thickness, in multiphase catalyst design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03576</id><created>2015-09-11</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jin-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence susceptibility as a probe of quantum phase transitions</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 022112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.022112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a coherence susceptibility method, based on the fact that it
signals quantum fluctuations, for identifying quantum phase transitions, which
are induced by quantum fluctuations. This method requires no prior knowledge of
order parameter, and there is no need for careful considerations concerning the
choice of a bipartition of the system. It can identify different types of
quantum phase transition points exactly. At finite temperatures, where quantum
criticality is influenced by thermal fluctuations, our method can pinpoint the
temperature frame of quantum criticality, which perfectly coincides with recent
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04641</id><created>2015-09-15</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinert</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Designing substrates for silicene and germanene: First-principles
  calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a guideline for exploring substrates that stabilize the monolayer
honeycomb structure of silicene and germanene while simultaneously preserve the
Dirac states: in addition to have a strong binding energy to the monolayer, a
suitable substrate should be a large-gap semiconductor with a proper
workfunction such that the Dirac point lies in the gap and far from the
substrate states when their bands align. We illustrate our idea by performing
first-principles calculations for silicene and germanene on the Al-terminated
(0001) surface of Al2O3 . The overlaid monolayers on Al-terminated Al2O3(0001)
retain the main structural profile of the low-buckled honeycomb structure via a
binding energy comparable to the one between silicene and Ag(111). Unfolded
band structure derived from the k-projection method reveals that gapped Dirac
cone is formed at the K point due to the structural distortion and the
interaction with the substrate. The gaps of 0.4 eV and 0.3 eV respectively for
the supported silicene and germanene suggest that they may have potential
applications in nanoelectronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06480</id><created>2015-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Rauw</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naze</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray emission from interacting massive binaries: a review of 15 years
  of progress</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in a special issue of Advances in Space
  Research on X-ray Emission from Hot Stars and their Winds</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Space Research, 58, 761-781 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.asr.2015.09.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous generations of X-ray observatories revealed a group of massive
binaries that were relatively bright X-ray emitters. This was attributed to
emission of shock-heated plasma in the wind-wind interaction zone located
between the stars. With the advent of the current generation of X-ray
observatories, the phenomenon could be studied in much more detail. In this
review, we highlight the progress that has been achieved in our understanding
of the phenomenon over the last 15 years, both on theoretical and observational
grounds. All these studies have paved the way for future investigations using
the next generation of X-ray satellites that will provide crucial information
on the X-ray emission formed in the innermost part of the wind-wind
interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06482</id><created>2015-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>ud-Doula</keyname><forenames>Asif</forenames><affiliation>Penn State Worth. Scranton</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Naze</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames><affiliation>ULg</affiliation></author></authors><title>Magnetically Confined Wind Shocks in X-rays - a Review</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>accepted for publication by Advances in Space Research (special issue
  &quot;X-ray emission from hot stars and their winds&quot;)</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Space Research, 58, 680-693 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.asr.2015.09.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A subset (~ 10%) of massive stars present strong, globally ordered (mostly
dipolar) magnetic fields. The trapping and channeling of their stellar winds in
closed magnetic loops leads to magnetically confined wind shocks (MCWS), with
pre-shock flow speeds that are some fraction of the wind terminal speed. These
shocks generate hot plasma, a source of X-rays. In the last decade, several
developments took place, notably the determination of the hot plasma properties
for a large sample of objects using XMM-Newton and Chandra, as well as fully
self-consistent MHD modelling and the identification of shock retreat effects
in weak winds. Despite a few exceptions, the combination of magnetic
confinement, shock retreat and rotation effects seems to be able to account for
X-ray emission in massive OB stars. Here we review these new observational and
theoretical aspects of this X-ray emission and envisage some perspectives for
the next generation of X-ray observatories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07958</id><created>2015-09-26</created><updated>2016-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zi-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherednychek</keyname><forenames>Mykyta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pukhov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Wavebreaking-associated transmitted emission of attosecond
  extreme-ultraviolet pulses from laser-driven overdense plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 18, 063014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/6/063014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new mechanism of attosecond extreme-ultraviolet (XUV) pulses
generation from a relativistic laser-driven overdense plasma surfaces in the
wavebreaking regime. Through particle-in-cell simulations and analysis, we
demonstrate that the observed ultrashort XUV emission for the parameters we
considered is predominantly due to a strong plasma-density oscillation
subsequent to wavebreaking. The coupling of the strong density variation and
the transverse fields in the front surface layer gives rise to the transmitted
emission with frequencies mainly around the local plasma frequency. This
mechanism provides new insights into the scenarios of XUV generation from solid
surfaces and the dynamics of laser-plasma interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07115</id><created>2015-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Si-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quan</keyname><forenames>Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jin-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagram of quantum critical system via local convertibility of
  ground state</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6,29175 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29175</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the relationship between two kinds of ground-state local
convertibility and quantum phase transitions in XY model. The local operations
and classical communications (LOCC) convertibility is examined by the
majorization relations and the entanglement-assisted local operations and
classical communications (E- LOCC) via Renyi entropy interception. In the phase
diagram of XY model, LOCC convertibility and ELOCC convertibility of
ground-states are presented and compared. It is shown that different phases in
the phase dia- gram of XY model can have different LOCC or ELOCC
convertibility, which can be used to detect the quantum phase transition. This
study will enlighten extensive studies of quantum phase transitions from the
perspective of local convertibility, e.g., finite-temperature phase transitions
and other quantum many-body models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01277</id><created>2015-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jiaming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Melo</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Le</forenames></author></authors><title>Parametric cooling of a degenerate Fermi gas in an optical trap</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 041401(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.041401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a novel technique for cooling a degenerate Fermi gas in a
crossed-beam optical dipole trap, where high-energy atoms can be selectively
removed from the trap by modulating the stiffness of the trapping potential
with anharmonic trapping frequencies. We measure the dependence of the cooling
effect on the frequency and amplitude of the parametric modulations. It is
found that the large anharmonicity along the axial trapping potential allows to
generate a degenerate Fermi gas with anisotropic energy distribution, in which
the cloud energy in the axial direction can be reduced to the ground state
value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02660</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Wei-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Laura H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent Progress of Point Contact Spectroscopy as a Probe of Correlated
  Electron States</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>25 pages, 8 figures, an invited review for a special issue on
  strongly correlated electron systems in Rep. Prog. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 79, 094502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/79/9/094502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review recent progress in point contact spectroscopy (PCS) to extract
spectroscopic information out of correlated electron materials, with the
emphasis on non-superconducting states. PCS has been used to detect bosonic
excitations in normal metals, where signatures (e.g. phonons) are usually less
than 1$\%$ of the measured conductance. In the superconducting state, point
contact Andreev reflection (PCAR) has been widely used to study properties of
the superconducting gap in various superconductors. In the last decade, there
have been more and more experimental results suggesting that the point contact
conductance could reveal new features associated with the unusual single
electron dynamics in non-superconducting states, shedding a new light on
exploring the nature of the competing phases in correlated materials. We will
summarize the theories for point contact spectroscopy developed from different
approaches and highlight these conceptual differences distinguishing point
contact spectroscopy from tunneling-based probes. Moreover, we will show how
the Schwinger-Kadanoff-Baym-Keldysh (SKBK) formalism together with the
appropriate modeling of the nano-scale point contacts randomly distributed
across the junction leads to the conclusion that the point contact conductance
is proportional to the {\it effective density of states}, a physical quantity
that can be computed if the electron self energy is known. The experimental
data on iron based superconductors and heavy fermion compounds will be analyzed
in this framework. These recent developments have extended the applicability of
point contact spectroscopy to correlated materials, which will help us achieve
a deeper understanding of the single electron dynamics in strongly correlated
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05255</id><created>2015-12-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Boschi</keyname><forenames>Cristian Degli Esposti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montorsi</keyname><forenames>Arianna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roncaglia</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Brane parity orders in the insulating state of Hubbard ladders</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Main article: 5 pages, 1 figure. Supplementary information: 4 pages,
  8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 085119 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Mott insulating state of the Hubbard model at half-filling could be
depicted as a spin liquid of singly occupied sites with holon-doublon quantum
fluctuations localized in pairs. In one dimension the behavior is captured by a
finite value of the charge parity string correlator, which fails to remain
finite when generalized to higher dimensions. We recover a definition of parity
brane correlator which may remain nonvanishing in presence of interchain
coupling, by assigning an appropriate fractional phase to the parity breaking
fluctuations. In case of Hubbard ladders at half-filling, we find that the
charge parity brane is non-zero at any repulsive value of interaction. The spin
parity brane instead becomes nonvanishing in the even-leg case, in
correspondence to the onset of the spin gapped D-Mott phase, which is absent in
the odd-leg case. The behavior of the parity correlators is also analyzed by
means of a numerical DMRG analysis of the one- and two-leg ladder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07322</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryan</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher Order Fermionic and Bosonic Operators</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.CV math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper studies a particular class of higher order conformally invariant
dif- ferential operators and related integral operators acting on functions
taking values in particular finite dimensional irreducible representations of
the Spin group. The differential operators can be seen as a generalization to
higher spin spaces of kth- powers of the Euclidean Dirac operator. To construct
these operators, we use the framework of higher spin theory in Clifford
analysis, in which irreducible represen- tations of the Spin group are realized
as polynomial spaces satisfying a particular system of differential equations.
As a consequence, these operators act on functions taking values in the space
of homogeneous harmonic or monogenic polynomials de- pending on the order.
Moreover, we classify these operators in analogy with the quantization of
angular momentum in quantum mechanics to unify the terminology used in studying
higher order higher spin conformally invariant operators: for integer and
half-integer spin, these are respectively bosonic and fermionic operators.
Fundamental solutions and their conformal invariance are presented here.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00467</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rehemanjiang</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allgaier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joyner</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sieber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhl</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xf6;ckmann</keyname><forenames>H. -J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A microwave realization of the Gaussian symplectic ensemble</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.CD</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 064101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.064101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following an idea by Joyner et al. [Europhys. Lett. 107, 50004 (2014)] a
microwave graph with an antiunitary symmetry T obeying T^2=-1 is realized. The
Kramers doublets expected for such systems are clearly identified and can be
lifted by a perturbation which breaks the antiunitary symmetry. The observed
spectral level spacings distribution of the Kramers doublets is in agreement
with the predictions from the Gaussian symplectic ensemble expected for chaotic
systems with such a symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04389</id><created>2016-01-17</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Junpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guang-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Kangjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yupeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solution of an su(n) spin torus</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, no figure, published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 073104</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/073104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The trigonometric su(n) spin chain with anti-periodic boundary condition
(su(n) spin torus) is demonstrated to be Yang-Baxter integrable. Based on some
intrinsic properties of the R-matrix, certain operator product identities of
the transfer matrix are derived. These identities and the asymptotic behavior
of the transfer matrix together allow us to obtain the exact eigenvalues in
terms of an inhomogeneous T-Q relation via the off-diagonal Bethe Ansatz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05923</id><created>2016-01-22</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zi-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pukhov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Bright high-order harmonic generation with controllable polarization
  from a relativistic plasma mirror</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12515 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrafast extreme ultraviolet (XUV) sources with a controllable polarization
state are powerful tools for investigating the structural and electronic as
well as the magnetic properties of materials. However, such light sources are
still limited to only a few free-electron laser facilities and, very recently,
to high-order harmonic generation from noble gases. Here we propose and
numerically demonstrate a laser-plasma scheme to generate bright XUV pulses
with fully controlled polarization. In this scheme, an elliptically-polarized
laser pulse is obliquely incident on a plasma surface, and the reflected
radiation contains pulse trains and isolated circularly- or
highly-elliptically-polarized attosecond XUV pulses. The harmonic polarization
state is fully controlled by the laser-plasma parameters. The mechanism can be
explained within the relativistically oscillating mirror model. This scheme
opens a practical and promising route to generate bright attosecond XUV pulses
with desirable ellipticities in a straightforward and efficient way for a
number of applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06611</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-04-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>&quot;Pretty strong&quot; converse for the private capacity of degraded quantum
  wiretap channels</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, IEEEtran.cls. V2 final (conference) version,
  accepted for ISIT 2016 (Barcelona, 10-15 July 2016)</comments><journal-ref>Proc. ISIT 2016 (Barcelona, 10-15 July 2016), pp. 2858-2862</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ISIT.2016.7541821</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the vein of the recent &quot;pretty strong&quot; converse for the quantum and
private capacity of degradable quantum channels [Morgan/Winter, IEEE Trans.
Inf. Theory 60(1):317-333, 2014], we use the same techniques, in particular the
calculus of min-entropies, to show a pretty strong converse for the private
capacity of degraded classical-quantum-quantum (cqq-)wiretap channels, which
generalize Wyner's model of the degraded classical wiretap channel.
  While the result is not completely tight, leaving some gap between the region
of error and privacy parameters for which the converse bound holds, and a
larger no-go region, it represents a further step towards an understanding of
strong converses of wiretap channels [cf. Hayashi/Tyagi/Watanabe,
arXiv:1410.0443 for the classical case].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07088</id><created>2016-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaipurath</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietrzyk</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspani</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roger</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clerici</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizza</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciattoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Falco</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faccio</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optically induced metal-to-dielectric transition in Epsilon-Near-Zero
  metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 27700 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep27700</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Epsilon-Near-Zero materials exhibit a transition in the real part of the
dielectric permittivity from positive to negative value as a function of
wavelength. Here we study metal-dielectric layered metamaterials in the
homogenised regime (each layer has strongly subwavelength thickness) with zero
real part of the permittivity in the near-infrared region. By optically pumping
the metamaterial we experimentally show that close to the Epsilon-Equal-to-Zero
(EEZ) wavelength the permittivity exhibits a marked transition from metallic
(negative permittivity) to dielectric (positive permittivity) as a function of
the optical power. Remarkably, this transition is linear as a function of pump
power and occurs on time scales of the order of the 100 fs pump pulse that need
not be tuned to a specific wavelength. The linearity of the permittivity
increase allows us to express the response of the metamaterial in terms of a
standard third order optical nonlinearity: this shows a clear inversion of the
roles of the real and imaginary parts in crossing the EEZ wavelength, further
supporting an optically induced change in the physical behaviour of the
metamaterial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07138</id><created>2016-01-23</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kiss</keyname><forenames>Miklos</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron Capture Nucleosynthesis</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1502.03763</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the international conference Teaching Physics
  Innovatively (TPI-15) New Learning Environments and Methods in Physics
  Education Budapest, 17-19 August, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.13140/RG.2.2.14220.51849</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heavy elements (beyond iron) are formed in neutron capture nucleosynthesis
processes. We have proposed a simple unified model to investigate the neutron
capture nucleosynthesis in arbitrary neutron density environment. We have also
investigated what neutron density is required to reproduce the measured
abundance of nuclei assuming equilibrium processes. We found both of these that
the medium neutron density has a particularly important role at neutron capture
nucleosynthesis. About these results most of the nuclei can formed at medium
neutron capture density environment e.g. in some kind of AGB stars. Besides
these observations our model is capable to use educational purpose.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08249</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamase</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bejas</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmon excitations in layered high-Tc cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures; Authors names corrected in arXiv's metadata;
  Added one figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075139 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the recent resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS) experiment
for the electron-doped cuprates Nd_{2-x}Ce_{x}CuO_{4} with x around 0.15, we
compute the density-density correlation function in the t-J model on a square
lattice by including interlayer hopping and the long-range Coulomb interaction.
We find that collective charge excitations are realized not inside the
particle-hole continuum, but above the continuum as plasmons. The plasmon mode
has a rather flat dispersion near the in-plane momentum q=(0,0) with a typical
excitation energy of the order of the intralayer hopping t when the
out-of-plane momentum qz is zero. However, when qz becomes finite, the plasmon
dispersion changes drastically near q=(0,0), leading to a strong dispersive
feature with an excitation gap scaled by the interlayer hopping tz. We discuss
that the mode recently observed by RIXS near q=(0,0) can be associated with the
plasmon mode with a finite qz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02314</id><created>2016-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Cruz</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuch</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castanos</keyname><forenames>Octavio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosas-Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-evolution of quantum systems via a complex nonlinear Riccati
  equation II. Dissipative systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 373 (2016) 609-630</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.07.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our former contribution [Ann. Phys. 360 (2015) 44], we have shown the
sensitivity to the choice of initial conditions in the evolution of Gaussian
wave packets via the nonlinear Riccati equation. The formalism developed in the
previous work is extended to effective approaches for the description of
dissipative quantum systems. By means of simple examples we show the effects of
the environment on the quantum uncertainties, correlation function, quantum
energy contribution and tunneling currents. We prove that the environmental
parameter $\gamma$ is strongly related with the sensitivity to the choice of
initial conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03744</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolocan</keyname><forenames>Voicu</forenames></author></authors><title>The question of charge and of mass</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are two long-range forces in the Universe, electromagnetism and
gravity.We have found a general expression for the energy of interaction in
these cases alphaXhbarXc/r, where alpha is the fine structure constant and r is
the distance between the two particles.In the case of the electromagnetic
interaction we have alphaxhbarxc=e^2/4pixepsilon, where e is the gauge charge,
which is the elementary electron charge. In the case of the gravitational
interaction alphaxhbarxc=GxM^2where M=1.85x10^(-9) kg is the gauge mass of the
particle.This is a giant particle. A system of like charged giant particles,
would be a charged superfluid. By spontaneous breaking of a gauge symmetry are
generated the Higgs masive bosons.The unitary gauge assure generation of the
neutral massive particles. The perturbation from the unitary gauge generates
charged massive particles. Also, the Higgs boson decays into charged and
neutral particles.The Tesla coil is the user of the excitations of the vacuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04202</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author></authors><title>Third Order Fermionic and Fourth Order Bosonic Operators</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.CV math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1512.07322</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper continues the work of our previous paper [8], where we generalize
kth-powers of the Euclidean Dirac operator D_x to higher spin spaces in the
case the target space is a degree one homogeneous polynomial space. In this
paper, we reconsider the generalizations of D_x^3 and D_x^4 to higher spin
spaces in the case the target space is a degree k homogeneous polynomial space.
Constructions of 3rd and 4th order conformally invariant operators in higher
spin spaces are given; these are the 3rd order fermionic and 4th order bosonic
operators. Fundamental solutions and intertwining operators of both operators
are also presented here. These results can be easily generalized to cylinders
and Hopf manifolds as in [7].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07529</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Katsutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>A distribution of energies of a charged black hole</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to the complete
  misunderstanding</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We proposed a gravitational energy momentum tensor in previous paper. By
using it, we evaluate an electric and a gravitational energies in and out of an
event horizon of a charged black hole. There is no gravitational energy in the
event horizon as well as Schwarzschild black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00765</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for direct pair production of supersymmetric top quarks decaying
  to all-hadronic final states in pp collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SUS-13-023/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-SUS-13-023, CERN-EP-2016-040</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 460</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4292-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Results are reported from a search for the pair production of top squarks,
the supersymmetric partners of top quarks, in final states with jets and
missing transverse momentum. The data sample used in this search was collected
by the CMS detector and corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 18.9 inverse
femtobarns of proton-proton collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV
produced by the LHC. The search features novel background suppression and
prediction methods, including a dedicated top quark pair reconstruction
algorithm. The data are found to be in agreement with the predicted
backgrounds. Exclusion limits are set in simplified supersymmetry models with
the top squark decaying to jets and an undetected neutralino, either via a top
quark or through a bottom quark and chargino. Models with the top squark
decaying via a top quark are excluded for top squark masses up to 755 GeV in
the case of neutralino masses below 200 GeV. For decays via a chargino, top
squark masses up to 620 GeV are excluded, depending on the masses of the
chargino and neutralino.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02115</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zingl</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Assmann</keyname><forenames>Elias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seth</keyname><forenames>Priyanka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivenko</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aichhorn</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Importance of effective dimensionality in manganese pnictides</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045130 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate the two manganese pnictides BaMn$_2$As$_2$ and
LaMnAsO, using fully charge self-consistent density functional plus dynamical
mean-field theory calculations. These systems have a nominally half-filled d
shell, and as a consequence, electronic correlations are strong, placing these
compounds at the verge of a metal-insulator transition. Although their crystal
structure is composed of similar building blocks, our analysis shows that the
two materials exhibit a very different effective dimensionality, LaMnAsO being
a quasi-two-dimensional material in contrast to the much more three-dimensional
BaMn$_2$As$_2$. We demonstrate that the experimentally observed differences in
the N\'eel temperature, the band gap, and the optical properties of the
manganese compounds under consideration can be traced back to exactly this
effective dimensionality. Our calculations show excellent agreement with
measured optical spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05967</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nyshadham</keyname><forenames>Chandramouli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oses</keyname><forenames>Corey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Jacob E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Ichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curtarolo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hart</keyname><forenames>Gus L. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A computational high-throughput search for new ternary superalloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 Tables, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2006, a novel cobalt-based superalloy was discovered [1] with mechanical
properties better than some conventional nickel-based superalloys. As with
conventional superalloys, its high performance arises from the
precipitate-hardening effect of a coherent L1$_2$ phase, which is in two-phase
equilibrium with the fcc matrix. Inspired by this unexpected discovery of an
L1$_2$ ternary phase, we performed a first-principles search through 2224
ternary metallic systems for analogous precipitate-hardening phases of the form
$X_{3}$[$A_{0.5}, B_{0.5}$], where $X$ = Ni, Co, or Fe, and [$A,B$] = Li, Be,
Mg, Al, Si, Ca, Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn Ga, Sr, Y, Zr, Nb, Mo,
Tc, Ru, Rh, Pd, Ag, Cd, In, Sn, Sb, Hf, Ta, W, Re, Os, Ir, Pt, Au, Hg, or Tl.
We found 102 systems that have a smaller decomposition energy and a lower
formation enthalpy than the Co$_{3}$(Al, W) superalloy. They have a stable
two-phase equilibrium with the host matrix within the concentration range
$0&lt;x&lt;1$ ($X_{3}$[$A_{x}, B_{1-x}$]) and have a relative lattice mismatch with
the host matrix of less than or equal to 5%. These new candidates, narrowed
from 2224 systems, suggest possible experimental exploration for identifying
new superalloys. Of these 102 systems, 37 are new; they have no reported phase
diagrams in standard databases. Based on cost, experimental difficulty, and
toxicity, we limit these 37 to a shorter list of six promising candidates of
immediate interest. Our calculations are consistent with current experimental
literature where data exists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00022</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pisarski</keyname><forenames>Robert D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skokov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral matrix model of the semi-Quark Gluon Plasma in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>69 pages, 22 figures; version published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 034015 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.034015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A chiral matrix model applicable to QCD with 2+1 flavors is developed. This
requires adding a SU(3)_L x SU(3)_R x Z(3)_A nonet of scalar fields, with both
parities, and coupling these to quarks through a Yukawa coupling, y. Treating
the scalar fields in mean field approximation, the effective Lagrangian is
computed by integrating out quarks to one loop order. In addition to the usual
symmetry breaking term, linear in the current quark mass m_qk, at a nonzero
temperature T it is necessary to add a new term, ~ m_qk T^2. The parameters of
the gluon part of the matrix model are identical to that for the pure glue
theory without quarks. The parameters in the chiral matrix model are fixed by
the values, at zero temperature, of the pion decay constant and the masses of
the pions, kaons, eta, and eta'. The temperature for the chiral crossover at
T_chi = 155 MeV is determined by adjusting the Yukawa coupling y. We find
reasonable agreement with the results of numerical simulations on the lattice
for the pressure and related quantities. In the chiral limit, besides the
divergence in the chiral susceptibility there is also a milder divergence in
the susceptibility between the Polyakov loop and the chiral order parameter,
with critical exponent beta - 1. We compute derivatives with respect to a quark
chemical potential to determine the susceptibilities for baryon number, the
chi_2n. Especially sensitive tests are provided by chi_4 - chi_2 and by chi_6,
which changes in sign about T_chi. The behavior of the susceptibilities in the
chiral matrix model strongly suggests that as the temperature increases from
T_chi, that the transition to deconfinement is significantly quicker than
indicated by the measurements of the (renormalized) Polyakov loop on the
lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02315</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dabrowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippert</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avila</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baringhaus</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colambo</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedkov</keyname><forenames>Yu. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herziger</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupina</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maultzsch</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaffus</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schroeder</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sowinska</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tegenkamp</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignaud</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asensio</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct growth of low-doped graphene on Ge/Si(001) surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>text and 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 31639 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep31639</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The practical difficulties to use graphene in microelectronics and
optoelectronics is that the available methods to grow graphene are not easily
integrated in the mainstream technologies. A growth method that could overcome
at least some of these problems is chemical vapour deposition (CVD) of graphene
directly on semiconducting (Si or Ge) substrates. Here we report on the
comparison of the CVD and molecular beam epitaxy (MBE) growth of graphene on
the technologically relevant Ge(001)/Si(001) substrate from ethene (C$_2$H$_4$)
precursor and describe the physical properties of the films as well as we
discuss the surface reaction and diffusion processes that may be responsible
for the observed behavior. Using nano angle resolved photoemission (nanoARPES)
complemented by transport studies and Raman spectroscopy, we report the direct
observation of massless Dirac particles in monolayer graphene, providing a
comprehensive mapping of their low-hole doped Dirac electron bands. The
micrometric graphene flakes are oriented along two predominant directions
rotated by $30^\circ$ with respect to each other. The growth mode is attributed
to the mechanism when small graphene &quot;molecules&quot; nucleate on the Ge(001)
surface and it is found that hydrogen plays a significant role in this process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03805</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuchment</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terzioglu</keyname><forenames>Fatma</forenames></author></authors><title>3D Image Reconstruction from Compton camera data</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>V3 expanded</comments><msc-class>44A12, 53C65, 92C55</msc-class><acm-class>I.4.5; I.2.1</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we address analytically and numerically the inversion of the
integral transform (\emph{cone} or \emph{Compton} transform) that maps a
function on $\mathbb{R}^3$ to its integrals over conical surfaces. It arises in
a variety of imaging techniques, e.g. in astronomy, optical imaging, and
homeland security imaging, especially when the so called Compton cameras are
involved.
  Several inversion formulas are developed and implemented numerically in $3D$
(the much simpler $2D$ case was considered in a previous publication). An
admissibility condition on detectors geometry is formulated, under which all
these inversion techniques will work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05097</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05097</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-06-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Habibi</keyname><forenames>Hojat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeuthen</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghanaatshoar</keyname><forenames>Majid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerer</keyname><forenames>Klemens</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Feedback Cooling of a Mechanical Oscillator Using Variational
  Measurements:Tweaking Heisenberg's Microscope</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Article submitted to the special issue on Nano-optomechanics edited
  by I. Wilson-Rae and J. Sanckey in Journal of Optics</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. 18 084004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/8/084004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the problem of preparing a mechanical oscillator in the vicinity
of its quantum-mechanical ground state by means of feedback cooling based on
continuous optical detection of the oscillator position. In the parameter
regime relevant to ground state cooling, the optical back-action and
imprecision noise set the bottleneck of achievable cooling and must be
carefully balanced. This can be achieved by adapting the phase of the local
oscillator in the homodyne detection realizing a so-called variational
measurement. The trade-off between accurate position measurement and minimal
disturbance can be understood in terms of Heisenberg's microscope and becomes
particularly relevant when the measurement and feedback processes happen to be
fast within the quantum coherence time of the system to be cooled. This
corresponds to the regime of large quantum cooperativity
$C_{\text{q}}\gtrsim1$, which was achieved in recent experiments on feedback
cooling. Our method provides a simple path to further pushing the limits of
current state-of-the-art experiments in quantum optomechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05332</id><created>2016-04-15</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Saehanseul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morsch</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loizides</keyname><forenames>Constantin</forenames></author></authors><title>Correction methods for finite-acceptance effects in two-particle
  correlation analyses</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures, version accepted by EPJ Plus</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus 131 (2016) 278</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16278-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-particle angular correlations have been widely used as a tool to explore
particle production mechanisms in heavy-ion collisions. The mixed-event
technique is generally used as a standard method to correct for
finite-acceptance effects. We demonstrate that event mixing only provides an
approximate acceptance correction, and propose new methods for
finite-acceptance corrections. Starting from discussions about 2-dimensional
correction procedures, new methods are derived for specific assumptions on the
properties of the signal, such as uniform signal distribution or
$\delta$-function-like trigger particle distribution, and suitable for
two-particle correlation analyses from particles at mid-rapidity and jet-hadron
or high $p_{\text{T}}$-triggered hadron-hadron correlations. Per-trigger
associated particle yields from the mixed-event method and the new methods are
compared through Monte Carlo simulations containing well-defined correlation
signals. Significant differences are observed at large pseudorapidity
differences in general and especially for asymmetric particle distribution like
that produced in proton--nucleus collisions. The applicability and validity of
the new methods are discussed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06895</id><created>2016-04-23</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Double Chooz collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abrah&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almazan</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alt</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Appel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baussan</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bekman</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergevin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezerra</keyname><forenames>T. J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezrukov</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blucher</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brugi&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buck</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busenitz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabrera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camilleri</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carr</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerrada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauveau</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chimenti</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collin</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conover</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crespo-Anad&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>J. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crum</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cucoanes</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damon</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Kerret</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhooghe</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djurcic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anjos</keyname><forenames>J. C. dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dracos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Etenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallot</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felde</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furuta</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gil-Botella</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giot</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;ger-Neff</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>L. F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodenough</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodman</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haag</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haser</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hellwig</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horton-Smith</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hourlier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishitsuka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jim&#xe9;nez</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jochum</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jollet</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaether</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalousis</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamyshkov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaplan</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemp</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kryn</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuze</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lachenmaier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lane</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasserre</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Letourneau</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lhuillier</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Casta&#xf1;o</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LoSecco</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubsandorzhiev</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucht</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maeda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maricic</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martino</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsubara</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mention</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meregaglia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miletic</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milincic</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minotti</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagasaka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navas-Nicol&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunokawa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberauer</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Obolensky</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onillon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osborn</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palomares</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepe</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perasso</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pronost</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichenbacher</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinhold</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;hling</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roncin</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybolt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santorelli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schilithz</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nert</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoppmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaevitz</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharankova</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shrestha</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sibille</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skorokhvatov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soiron</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spitz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stahl</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stancu</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stokes</keyname><forenames>L. F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strait</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suekane</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhotin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumiyoshi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svoboda</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terao</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonazzo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thi</keyname><forenames>H. H. Trinh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valdiviesso</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vassilopoulos</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veyssiere</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vivier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Feilitzsch</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebusch</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurm</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yermia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmer</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of the Spontaneous Light Emission of the PMTs used in
  the Double Chooz Experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>24 pages, 24 figures. Minor revision to be published in the Journal
  of Instrumentation (JINST), Corresponding author: R. Santorelli</comments><journal-ref>JINST 11 (2016) no.08, P08001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/08/P08001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the commissioning of the first of the two detectors of the Double
Chooz experiment, an unexpected and dominant background caused by the emission
of light inside the optical volume has been observed. A specific study of the
ensemble of phenomena called &quot;Light Noise&quot; has been carried out in-situ, and in
an external laboratory, in order to characterize the signals and to identify
the possible processes underlying the effect. Some mechanisms of instrumental
noise originating from the PMTs were identified and it has been found that the
leading one arises from the light emission localized on the photomultiplier
base and produced by the combined effect of heat and high voltage across the
transparent epoxy resin covering the electric components. The correlation of
the rate and the amplitude of the signal with the temperature has been
observed. For the first detector in operation the induced background has been
mitigated using online and offline analysis selections based on timing and
light pattern of the signals, while a modification of the photomultiplier
assembly has been implemented for the second detector in order to blacken the
PMT bases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07401</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schaal</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springel</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakmor</keyname><forenames>R&#xfc;diger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfrommer</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Dylan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsberger</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genel</keyname><forenames>Shy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pillepich</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sijacki</keyname><forenames>Debora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernquist</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>Shock finding on a moving-mesh: II. Hydrodynamic shocks in the Illustris
  universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>26 pages, 15 figures, 1 movie, published in mnras</comments><journal-ref>MRNAS 461, 4441-4465 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1587</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrodynamical shocks are a manifestation of the non-linearity of the Euler
equations and play a fundamental role in cosmological gas dynamics. In this
work, we identify and analyse shocks in the Illustris simulation, and contrast
the results with those of non-radiative runs. We show that simulations with
more comprehensive physical models of galaxy formation pose new challenges for
shock finding algorithms due to radiative cooling and star-forming processes,
prompting us to develop a number of methodology improvements. We find in
Illustris a total shock surface area which is about 1.4 times larger at the
present epoch compared to non-radiative runs, and an energy dissipation rate at
shocks which is higher by a factor of around 7. Remarkably, shocks with Mach
numbers above and below $\mathcal{M}\approx10$ contribute about equally to the
total dissipation across cosmic time. This is in sharp contrast to
non-radiative simulations, and we demonstrate that a large part of the
difference arises due to strong black hole radio-mode feedback in Illustris. We
also provide an overview of the large diversity of shock morphologies, which
includes complex networks of halo-internal shocks, shocks on to cosmic sheets,
feedback shocks due to black holes and galactic winds, as well as ubiquitous
accretion shocks. In high redshift systems more massive than
$10^{12}\,\mathrm{M}_\odot$ we discover the existence of a double accretion
shock pattern in haloes. They are created when gas streams along filaments
without being shocked at the outer accretion shock, but then forms a second,
roughly spherical accretion shock further inside.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03211</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03211</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burdick</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lev</keyname><forenames>Benjamin L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A long-lived spin-orbit-coupled degenerate dipolar Fermi gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, one appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 031022 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.031022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the creation of a long-lived spin-orbit-coupled gas of quantum
degenerate atoms using the most magnetic fermionic element, dysprosium.
Spin-orbit-coupling arises from a synthetic gauge field created by the
adiabatic following of degenerate dressed states comprised of optically coupled
components of an atomic spin. Because of dysprosium's large electronic orbital
angular momentum and large magnetic moment, the lifetime of the gas is limited
not by spontaneous emission from the light-matter coupling, as for gases of
alkali-metal atoms, but by dipolar relaxation of the spin. This relaxation is
suppressed at large magnetic fields due to Fermi statistics. We observe
lifetimes up to 400 ms, which exceeds that of spin-orbit-coupled fermionic
alkali atoms by a factor of 10-100, and is close to the value obtained from a
theoretical model. Elastic dipolar interactions are also observed to influence
the Rabi evolution of the spin, revealing an interacting fermionic system. The
long lifetime of this weakly interacting spin-orbit-coupled degenerate Fermi
gas will facilitate the study of quantum many-body phenomena manifest at longer
timescales, with exciting implications for the exploration of exotic
topological quantum liquids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04431</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meerburg</keyname><forenames>P. Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>The holiest grail</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Based on a presentation given at the cosmology session of Rencontres
  de Moriond L (50) and arXiv:1603.02243. This version: updated refs</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I will discuss to what degree the cosmic microwave background (CMB) can be
used to constrain primordial non-Gaussianity involving one tensor and two
scalar fluctuations, focusing on the correlation of one $B$-mode polarization
fluctuation with two temperature fluctuations (BTT). In the simplest models of
inflation, the tensor-scalar-scalar primordial bispectrum is non-vanishing and
is of the same order in slow-roll parameters as the scalar-scalar-scalar
bispectrum. I will show that constraints from an experiment like CMB-Stage IV
using this observable are more than an order of magnitude better than those on
the same primordial coupling obtained from temperature measurements alone. I
will argue that $B$-mode non-Gaussianity opens up an as-yet-unexplored window
into the early Universe, demonstrating that significant information on
primordial physics remains to be harvested from CMB anisotropies. BTT presents
a measure of both primordial tensors and primordial non-Gaussianity, two of the
most sought after signatures of the inflationary paradigm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04482</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakama</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suyama</keyname><forenames>Teruaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Primordial black holes as a novel probe of primordial gravitational
  waves. II: Detailed analysis</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>31 pages, accepted in PRD, this paper presents detailed derivations
  of the results shown in our recent work 1506.05228</comments><report-no>RESCEU-19/16</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 043507 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.043507</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently we have proposed a novel method to probe primordial gravitational
waves from upper bounds on the abundance of primordial black holes (PBHs). When
the amplitude of primordial tensor perturbations generated in the early
Universe is fairly large, they induce substantial scalar perturbations due to
their second-order effects. If these induced scalar perturbations are too large
when they reenter the horizon, then PBHs are overproduced, their abundance
exceeding observational upper limits. That is, primordial tensor perturbations
on superhorizon scales can be constrained from the absence of PBHs. In our
recent paper we have only shown simple estimations of these new constraints,
and hence in this paper, we present detailed derivations, solving the Einstein
equations for scalar perturbations induced at second order in tensor
perturbations. We also derive an approximate formula for the probability
density function of induced density perturbations, necessary to relate the
abundance of PBHs to the primordial tensor power spectrum, assuming primordial
tensor perturbations follow Gaussian distributions. Our new upper bounds from
PBHs are compared with other existing bounds obtained from big bang
nucleosynthesis, cosmic microwave background, LIGO/Virgo and pulsar timing
arrays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05471</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koole</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frisenda</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrus</keyname><forenames>Michiel L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrin</keyname><forenames>Mickael L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>Herre S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dingemans</keyname><forenames>Theo J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge Transport through Conjugated Azomethine-based Single Molecules
  for Optoelectronic Applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Organic Electronics, 34(2016), 38-41</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.orgel.2016.03.043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The single-molecule conductance of a 3-ring, conjugated azomethine was
studied using the mechanically controlled breakjunction technique. Charge
transport properties are found to be comparable to vinyl-based analogues;
findings are supported with density functional calculations. The simple
preparation and good transport properties make azomethine-based molecules an
attractive class for use in polymer and single-molecule organic electronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05513</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhaoyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Tianyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Depict noise-driven nonlinear dynamic networks from output data by using
  high-order correlations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many practical systems can be described by dynamic networks, for which modern
technique can measure their output signals, and accumulate extremely rich data.
Nevertheless, the network structures producing these data are often deeply
hidden in these data. Depicting network structures by analysing the available
data, i.e., the inverse problems turns to be of great significant. On one hand,
dynamics are often driven by various unknown facts, called noises. On the other
hand, network structures of practical systems are commonly nonlinear, and
different nonlinearities can provide rich dynamic features and meaningful
functions of realistic networks. So far, no method, both theoretically or
numerically, has been found to systematically treat the both difficulties
together. Here we propose to use high-order correlation computations (HOCC) to
treat nonlinear dynamics; use two-time correlations to treat noise effects; and
use suitable basis and correlator vectors to unifiedly depict all dynamic
nonlinearities and topological interaction links and noise statistical
structures. All the above theoretical frameworks are constructed in a closed
form and numerical simulations fully verify the validity of theoretical
predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09435</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>McKague</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-testing high dimensional states using the generalized magic square
  game</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Withdrawn by the author due to errors in section 5 which make the
  magic square self-test invalid</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To date all self-tests for high dimensional systems are confined to
many-qubit states. This is due to two restrictions in the literature: the
standard techniques for proving self-testing results apply only to qubits, and
there are few suitable non-local games that are known to require high
dimensional non-qubit states to achieve their optimal quantum value. In this
paper we address these two problems. Specifically, we generalize the usual
self-testing framework to q$d$its and then apply it to a generalization of the
magic square game, giving a self-test for two maximally entangled pairs of
q$d$its. This self-test has two parties, perfect completeness for honest
quantum players, and requires only a constant number of measurement settings,
regardless of the dimension $d$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09563</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wolschin</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond the thermal model in relativistic heavy-ion collisions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 024911 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024911</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deviations from thermal distribution functions of produced particles in
relativistic heavy-ion collisions are discussed as indicators for
nonequilibrium processes. The focus is on rapidity distributions of produced
charged hadrons as functions of collision energy and centrality which are used
to infer the fraction of produced particles from a central fireball as compared
to the one from the fragmentation sources that are out of equilibrium with the
rest of the system. Overall thermal equilibrium would only be reached for large
times t -&gt; infinity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01602</id><created>2016-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bancal</keyname><forenames>Jean-Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Jacquiline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarani</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author></authors><title>A new device-independent dimension witness and its experimental
  implementation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, Volume 49,
  Number 30, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/30/305301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A dimension witness is a criterion that sets a lower bound on the dimension
needed to reproduce the observed data. Three types of dimension witnesses can
be found in the literature: device-dependent ones, in which the bound is
obtained assuming some knowledge on the state and the measurements;
device-independent prepare-and-measure ones, that can be applied to any system
including classical ones; and device-independent Bell-based ones, that certify
the minimal dimension of some entangled systems. Here we consider the
Collins-Gisin-Linden-Massar-Popescu (CGLMP) Bell-type inequality for four
outcomes. We show that a sufficiently high violation of this inequality
witnesses $d \geq 4$ and present a proof-of-principle experimental observation
of such a violation. This presents a first experimental violation of the third
type of dimension witness beyond qutrits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03710</id><created>2016-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kutsenko</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramenko</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using SDO/HMI magnetograms as a source of the solar mean magnetic field
  data</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Kutsenko, A.S. &amp; Abramenko, V.I. Sol Phys (2016) 291: 1613</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-0940-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The solar mean magnetic field (SMMF) provided by the Wilcox Solar Observatory
(WSO) is compared with the SMMF acquired by the \textit{Helioseismic and
Magnetic Imager} (HMI) onboard the \textit{Solar Dynamic Observatory} (SDO). We
found that despite the different spectral lines and measurement techniques used
in both instruments the Pearson correlation coefficient between these two
datasets equals 0.86 while the conversion factor is very close to unity: B(HMI)
= 0.99(2)B(WSO). We also discuss artifacts of the SDO/HMI magnetic field
measurements, namely the 12 and 24-hour oscillations in SMMF and in sunspots
magnetic fields that might be caused by orbital motions of the spacecraft. The
artificial harmonics of SMMF reveal significant changes in amplitude and the
nearly stable phase. The connection between the 24-hour harmonic amplitude of
SMMF and the presence of sunspots is examined. We also found that opposite
phase artificial 12 and/or 24-hour oscillations exist in sunspots of opposite
polarities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04641</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-07-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bimonte</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emig</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaffe</keyname><forenames>Robert L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kardar</keyname><forenames>Mehran</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic Probe of the van der Waals Interaction between Polar
  Molecules and a Curved Surface</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, version accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 022509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.022509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the shift of rotational levels of a diatomic polar molecule due to
its van der Waals (vdW) interaction with a gently curved dielectric surface at
temperature $T$, and submicron separations. The molecule is assumed to be in
its electronic and vibrational ground state, and the rotational degrees are
described by a rigid rotor model. We show that under these conditions
retardation effects and surface dispersion can be neglected. The level shifts
are found to be independent of $T$, and given by the quantum state averaged
classical electrostatic interaction of the dipole with its image on the
surface. We use a derivative expansion for the static Green's function to
express the shifts in terms of surface curvature. We argue that the curvature
induced line splitting is experimentally observable, and not obscured by
natural line widths and thermal broadening.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06474</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06474</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rastelli</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Born-Jordan and Weyl Quantizations of the 2D Anisotropic Harmonic
  Oscillator</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><msc-class>81S05 (Primary), 81S30 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 081, 7 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.081</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the Born-Jordan and Weyl quantization formulas for polynomials in
canonical coordinates to the constants of motion of some examples of the
superintegrable 2D anisotropic harmonic oscillator. Our aim is to study the
behaviour of the algebra of the constants of motion after the different
quantization procedures. In the examples considered, we have that the Weyl
formula always preserves the original superintegrable structure of the system,
while the Born-Jordan formula, when producing different operators than the
Weyl's one, does not.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08851</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blennow</keyname><forenames>Mattias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choubey</keyname><forenames>Sandhya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohlsson</keyname><forenames>Tommy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Dipyaman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raut</keyname><forenames>Sushant K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A combined study of source, detector and matter non-standard neutrino
  interactions at DUNE</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 7 figures. Version accepted for publication in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 08 (2016) 090</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We simultaneously investigate source, detector and matter non-standard
neutrino interactions at the proposed DUNE experiment. Our analysis is
performed using a Markov Chain Monte Carlo exploring the full parameter space.
We find that the sensitivity of DUNE to the standard oscillation parameters is
worsened due to the presence of non-standard neutrino interactions. In
particular, there are degenerate solutions in the leptonic mixing angle
$\theta_{23}$ and the Dirac CP-violating phase $\delta$. We also compute the
expected sensitivities at DUNE to the non-standard interaction parameters. We
find that the sensitivities to the matter non-standard interaction parameters
are substantially stronger than the current bounds (up to a factor of about
15). Furthermore, we discuss correlations between the source/detector and
matter non-standard interaction parameters and find a degenerate solution in
$\theta_{23}$. Finally, we explore the effect of statistics on our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02471</id><created>2016-07-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Z. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smidman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>H. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple quantum phase transitions and superconductivity in Ce-based
  heavy fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>To appear in Reports on Progress in Physics: Special issue on
  strongly correlated electron systems, 24 pages, 22 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 79 094503 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/79/9/094503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heavy fermions have served as prototype examples of strongly-correlated
electron systems. The occurrence of unconventional superconductivity in close
proximity to the electronic instabilities associated with various degrees of
freedom points to an intricate relationship between superconductivity and other
electronic states, which is unique but also shares some common features with
high temperature superconductivity. The magnetic order in heavy fermion
compounds can be continuously suppressed by tuning external parameters to a
quantum critical point, and the role of quantum criticality in determining the
properties of heavy fermion systems is an important unresolved issue. Here we
review the recent progress of studies on Ce based heavy fermion
superconductors, with an emphasis on the superconductivity emerging on the edge
of magnetic and charge instabilities as well as the quantum phase transitions
which occur by tuning different parameters, such as pressure, magnetic field
and doping. We discuss systems where multiple quantum critical points occur and
whether they can be classified in a unified manner, in particular in terms of
the evolution of the Fermi surface topology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03487</id><created>2016-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tollerud</keyname><forenames>Erik J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geha</keyname><forenames>Marla C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grcevich</keyname><forenames>Jana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putman</keyname><forenames>Mary E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weisz</keyname><forenames>Daniel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolphin</keyname><forenames>Andrew E.</forenames></author></authors><title>HST Imaging of the Local Volume Dwarf Galaxies Pisces A&amp;B: Prototypes
  for Local Group Dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted to ApJ, 14 pages. 3D version of Figure 12 at
  http://bit.ly/piscdwarfs_3d_fig12, MCMC chains at
  http://dx.doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.51375</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/827/2/89</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present observations of the Pisces A and B galaxies with the Advanced
Camera for Surveys on the Hubble Space Telescope. Photometry from these images
clearly resolve a Red Giant Branch for both objects, demonstrating that they
are nearby dwarf galaxies. We describe a Bayesian inferential approach to
determining the distance to these galaxies using the magnitude of the tip of
the RGB, and then apply this approach to these galaxies. We also provide the
full probability distributions for parameters derived using this approach. This
reveals the distance to these galaxies as $5.64^{+0.13}_{-0.15} \, {\rm Mpc}$
and $8.89^{+0.75}_{-0.85} \, {\rm Mpc}$ for Pisces A and B, respectively,
placing both within the Local Volume but not the Local Group. We estimate the
star formation histories of these galaxies, which suggests that they have
recently undergone an increase in their star formation rates. Together these
yield luminosities for Pisces A and B of $M_V=-11.57^{+0.06}_{-0.05}$ and
$-12.9 \pm 0.2$, respectively, and estimated stellar masses of
$\log(M_*/M_{\odot})= 7.0^{+0.4}_{-1.7}$ and $7.5^{+0.3}_{-1.8}$. We further
show that these galaxies are likely at the boundary between nearby voids and
higher-density filamentary structure. This suggests that they are entering a
higher-density region from voids, where they would have experienced delayed
evolution, consistent with their recent increased star formation rates. If this
is indeed the case, they are useful for study as proxies of the galaxies that
later evolved into typical Local Group satellite galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04806</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04806</id><created>2016-07-16</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Yeon Ui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozerov</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bedu</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Ji Su</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fages</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jeong Weon</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin- and orbital-Hall effect in cyclic group symmetric metasurface</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light possesses both spin and orbital angular momentum (AM). While spin AM is
determined by helicity of circular-polarization, orbital AM is characterized by
topological charge of vortex beam. Interaction of AM with optical beam orbit
leads to optical spin Hall or orbital Hall effect, exhibited as spin-dependent
or topological charge-dependent transverse shift of optical beam. Conservation
of AM enables spin-to-orbital AM conversion, where circular-polarized Gaussian
beam is converted to opposite-helicity circular-polarized vortex beam with
topological charge $\pm 2$, an example of controlling spatial beam profiling by
spin flip. However, the resultant vortex beam has the beam center of gravity
unchanged, the same as that of incident Gaussian beam, meaning a null
transverse shift. Here we introduce a cyclic group symmetric metasurface to
demonstrate generation of vortex beam exhibiting spin-dependent transverse
shift, namely, spin- and orbital-Hall effect, attributed to an alteration of
dynamical phase of scattered beam according to the order $n$ of cyclic group
while keeping geometric phase constant. Capability of spin-controlled spatial
beam profiling with a transverse shift via spin- and orbital-Hall effect has
important implications for spatial demultiplexing in optical communication
utilizing orbital AM mode division multiplexing as well as for optical vortex
tweezer and signal processing involving vortex beams.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07478</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dreiner</keyname><forenames>Herbi K.</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Borzyszkowski</keyname><forenames>Mikolaj</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fa&#xdf;bender</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hampel</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Maike</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hebecker</keyname><forenames>Dustin</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U. and Berlin, Humboldt U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Heepenstrick</keyname><forenames>Timo</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hortmanns</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jost</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kortmann</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kruckow</keyname><forenames>Matthias U.</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leuteritz</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;tz</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mahlberg</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;llers</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Opferkuch</keyname><forenames>Toby</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pauli</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rossbach</keyname><forenames>Merlin</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schaepe</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schiffer</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Jan F.</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;ller-Ruhl</keyname><forenames>Jana</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ubaldi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames><affiliation>Bonn U. and Tel Aviv U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wagner-Carena</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames><affiliation>Harvard U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>&quot;What's (the) Matter?&quot;, A Show on Elementary Particle Physics with 28
  Demonstration Experiments</title><categories>physics.pop-ph hep-ex hep-ph hep-th physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>113 pages, 88 figures. An up to date version of the paper with high
  resolution pictures can be found at
  http://www.th.physik.uni-bonn.de/People/dreiner/Downloads/. In v2 the
  acknowledgements and a citation are corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the screenplay of a physics show on particle physics, by the
Physikshow of Bonn University. The show is addressed at non-physicists aged 14+
and communicates basic concepts of elementary particle physics including the
discovery of the Higgs boson in an entertaining fashion. It is also
demonstrates a successful outreach activity heavily relying on the university
physics students. This paper is addressed at anybody interested in particle
physics and/or show physics. This paper is also addressed at fellow physicists
working in outreach, maybe the experiments and our choice of simple
explanations will be helpful. Furthermore, we are very interested in related
activities elsewhere, in particular also demonstration experiments relevant to
particle physics, as often little of this work is published.
  Our show involves 28 live demonstration experiments. These are presented in
an extensive appendix, including photos and technical details. The show is set
up as a quest, where 2 students from Bonn with the aid of a caretaker travel
back in time to understand the fundamental nature of matter. They visit
Rutherford and Geiger in Manchester around 1911, who recount their famous
experiment on the nucleus and show how particle detectors work. They travel
forward in time to meet Lawrence at Berkeley around 1950, teaching them about
the how and why of accelerators. Next, they visit Wu at DESY, Hamburg, around
1980, who explains the strong force. They end up in the LHC tunnel at CERN,
Geneva, Switzerland in 2012. Two experimentalists tell them about colliders and
our heroes watch live as the Higgs boson is produced and decays. The show was
presented in English at Oxford University and University College London, as
well as Padua University and ICTP Trieste. It was 1st performed in German at
the Deutsche Museum, Bonn (5/'14). The show has eleven speaking parts and
involves in total 20 people.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00586</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Minardi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacour</keyname><forenames>Sylvestre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labadie</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>Robert R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haniff</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Beam combination schemes and technologies for the Planet Formation
  Imager (PFI)</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures, Proceedings of SPIE 2016</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2232656</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Planet Formation Imager (PFI) initiative aims at developing the next
generation large scale facility for imaging astronomical optical interferometry
operating in the mid-infrared. Here we report on the progress of the Planet
Formation Imager Technical Working Group on the beam-combination instruments.
We will discuss various available options for the science and fringe-tracker
beam combination instruments, ranging from direct imaging, to non-redundant
fiber arrays, to integrated optics solutions. Besides considering basic
characteristics of the schemes, we will investigate the maturity of the
available technological platforms at near- and mid-infrared wavelengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00587</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mozurkewich</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Practical Beam Transport for the Planet Formation Imager (PFI)</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures, Proceedings of SPIE 2016</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2232382</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Planet Formation Imager (PFI) is a future kilometric-baseline infrared
interferometer to image the complex physical processes of planet formation.
Technologies that could be used to transport starlight to a central
beam-combining laboratory in PFI include free-space propagation in air or
vacuum, and optical fibres. This paper addresses the design and cost issues
associated with free-space propagation in vacuum pipes. The signal losses due
to diffraction over long differential paths are evaluated, and conceptual beam
transport designs employing pupil management to ameliorate these losses are
presented and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04459</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiribella</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scandolo</keyname><forenames>Carlo Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement as an axiomatic foundation for statistical mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>19+10 pages, no figures. See also the related work by Krumm,Barnum,
  Barrett, and Mueller on arXiv:1608.04461</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose four information-theoretic axioms for the foundations of
statistical mechanics in general physical theories. The axioms---Causality,
Purity Preservation, Pure Sharpness, and Purification---identify a class of
theories where every mixed state can be modelled as the marginal of a pure
entangled state and where every unsharp measurement can be modelled as a sharp
measurement on a composite system. This class of theories, called sharp
theories with purification, includes quantum theory both with complex and real
amplitudes, as well as a suitable extension of classical probability theory
where classical systems can be entangled with other, non-classical systems.
Theories satisfying our axioms support well-behaved notions of majorization,
entropy, and Gibbs states, allowing for an information-theoretic derivation of
Landauer's principle. We conjecture that every theory admitting a sensible
thermodynamics must be extendable to a sharp theory with purification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04548</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Postnov</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames><affiliation>SAI MSU and ITEP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kuranov</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames><affiliation>SAI MSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kolesnikov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames><affiliation>SAI MSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames><affiliation>SAI MSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Porayko</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames><affiliation>SAI MSU, ITEP, MPIfR</affiliation></author></authors><title>Rapidly rotating neutron star progenitors</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rotating proto-neutron stars can be important sources of gravitational waves
to be searched for by present-day and future interferometric detectors. It was
demonstrated by Imshennik that in extreme cases the rapid rotation of a
collapsing stellar core may lead to fission and formation of a binary
proto-neutron star which subsequently merges due to gravitational wave
emission. In the present paper, we show that such dynamically unstable
collapsing stellar cores may be the product of a former merger process of two
stellar cores in a common envelope. We applied population synthesis
calculations to assess the expected fraction of such rapidly rotating stellar
cores which may lead to fission and formation of a pair of proto-neutron stars.
We have used the BSE population synthesis code supplemented with a new
treatment of stellar core rotation during the evolution via effective
core-envelope coupling, characterized by the coupling time, $\tau_c$. The
validity of this approach is checked by direct MESA calculations of the
evolution of a rotating 15 $M_\odot$ star. From comparison of the calculated
spin distribution of young neutron stars with the observed one, reported by
Popov and Turolla, we infer the value $\tau_c \simeq 5 \times 10^5$ years. We
show that merging of stellar cores in common envelopes can lead to collapses
with dynamically unstable proto-neutron stars, with their formation rate being
$\sim 0.1-1\%$ of the total core collapses, depending on the common envelope
efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04616</id><created>2016-08-16</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frazin</keyname><forenames>Richard A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finding the Dark Hole with the Lights On: A New Approach to Focal Plane
  Wavefront Sensing</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In direct imaging of exoplanets from space, achieving the required dynamic
range (i.e., planet-to-star contrast in brightness) currently relies on
coronagraphic technology combined with active control of one or more deformable
mirrors (DMs) to create a dark region in the image plane, sometimes called a
&quot;dark hole.&quot; While many algorithms have been proposed for this purpose, all of
them employ focal plane wavefront sensing (FPWS) in order to calculate the
optimal DM configuration to create the desired dark hole. All current
algorithms are limited by their own success in that, as the dark hole is
achieved, the FPWS procedure becomes shot-noise limited due to he low intensity
in the dark hole. This article proposes a FPWS procedure that allows
determination of the optimal DM configuration without relying on information
obtained when the DM is near the optimal configuration. This article gives
regression procedures for FPWS that do not assume the DM step size is small,
which should allow two important improvements to the control loop: 1)
performing informative FPWS observations with DM configurations that are
sufficiently distant from the optimal dark hole configuration to mitigate
shot-noise limitations, and 2) more accurately predicting the DM configuration
that will achieve the desired objective in the dark hole control loop. In order
to treat this more challenging FPWS problem, two different representations are
presented. The first of these, is called the empirical Green's function (EGF),
is easy to implement, and has a block-diagonal matrix structure that is
well-suited to parallel processing. The other representation, based on an
explicit aberration expansion (EAE) requires the regression to estimate a
smaller number of parameters than the EGF, but leads to a dense matrix
structure. The EGF and EAE methods both simultaneously estimate the planetary
image.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04758</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Reasenberg</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandler</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colmenares</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>N. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling and Analysis of the APOLLO Lunar Laser Ranging Data</title><categories>astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Earth-Moon-Sun system has traditionally provided the best laboratory for
testing the strong equivalence principle. For a decade, the Apache Point
Observatory Lunar Laser-ranging Operation (APOLLO) has been producing the
world's best lunar laser ranging data. At present, a single observing session
of about an hour yields a distance measurement with uncertainty of about 2~mm,
an order of magnitude advance over the best pre-APOLLO lunar laser ranging
data. However, these superb data have not yet yielded scientific results
commensurate with their accuracy, number, and temporal distribution. There are
two reasons for this. First, even in the relatively clean environment of the
Earth-Moon system, a large number of effects modify the measured distance
importantly and thus need to be included in the analysis model. The second
reason is more complicated. The traditional problem with the analysis of
solar-system metric data is that the physical model must be truncated to avoid
extra parameters that would increase the condition number of the estimator.
Even in a typical APOLLO analysis that does not include parameters of gravity
physics, the condition number is very high: $8 \times 10^{10}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04770</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Farhat</keyname><forenames>Aseel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunasin</keyname><forenames>Evelyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Titi</keyname><forenames>Edriss S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Charney Conjecture of Data Assimilation Employing Temperature
  Measurements Alone: The Paradigm of 3D Planetary Geostrophic Model</title><categories>math.AP physics.ao-ph physics.flu-dyn physics.geo-ph</categories><msc-class>35Q30, 93C20, 37C50, 76B75, 34D06</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analyzing the validity and success of a data assimilation algorithm when some
state variable observations are not available is an important problem in
meteorology and engineering. We present an improved data assimilation algorithm
for recovering the exact full reference solution (i.e. the velocity and
temperature) of the 3D Planetary Geostrophic model, at an exponential rate in
time, by employing coarse spatial mesh observations of the temperature alone.
This provides, in the case of this paradigm, a rigorous justification to an
earlier conjecture of Charney which states that temperature history of the
atmosphere, for certain simple atmospheric models, determines all other state
variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04774</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Grigoryev</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yugov</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eliseev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efimov</keyname><forenames>Yu. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lovtcius</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapega</keyname><forenames>V. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ignatiev</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inversion of Zeeman splitting of exciton states in InGaAs quantum wells</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 205425, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.205425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zeeman splitting of quantum-confined states of excitons in InGaAs quantum
wells (QWs) is experimentally found to depend strongly on quantization energy.
Moreover, it changes sign when the quantization energy increases with a
decrease in the QW width. In the 87-nm QW, the sign change is observed for the
excited quantum-confined states, which are above the ground state only by a few
meV. A two-step approach for the numerical solution of the two-particle
Schroedinger equation, taking into account the Coulomb interaction and
valence-band coupling, is used for a theoretical justification of the observed
phenomenon. The calculated variation of the g-factor convincingly follows the
dependencies obtained in the experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04778</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Felfli</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Msezane</keyname><forenames>A. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolovski</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative ion formation in lanthanide atoms: Many-body effects</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigations of low-energy electron-scattering of the lanthanide atoms Eu,
Nd, Tb, Tm demonstrate that electron-correlation effects and core polarization
are the dominant fundamental many-body effects responsible for the formation of
metastable states of negative ions. Ramsauer Townsend minima, shape resonances
and binding energies of the resultant anions are identified and extracted from
the elastic total cross sections calculated using the complex angular momentum
method. The large discrepancy between the recently measured electron affinity
of 0.116 and the previously measured value of 1.053 eV for Eu is resolved.
Also, the previously measured electron affinities for Nd, Tb and Tm are
reconciled and new values are extracted from the calculated total cross
sections. The large electron affinities found here for these atoms, should be
useful in negative ion nanocatalysis, including methane conversion to methanol
without CO2 emission, with significant environmental impact.. The powerful
complex angular momentum method which requires only a few poles, yields
reliable binding energies for the metastable states of negative ions with no a
priori knowledge of experimental or other theoretical data and should be
applicable to other complex systems for the fundamental understanding of their
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04779</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattarai</keyname><forenames>Khagendra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jiangfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Talbayev</keyname><forenames>Diyar</forenames></author></authors><title>Thin InSb layers with metallic gratings: a novel platform for
  spectrally-selective THz plasmonic sensing</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>Copyright 2016 Optical Society of America. One print or electronic
  copy may be made for personal use only. Systematic reproduction and
  distribution, duplication of any material in this paper for a fee or for
  commercial purposes, or modifications of the content of this paper are
  prohibited. Online abstract link: http://dx.doi.org/10.1364/OE.24.019448</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 19448 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.019448</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a computational study of terahertz optical properties of a
grating-coupled plasmonic structure based on micrometer-thin InSb layers. We
find two strong absorption resonances that we interpret as standing surface
plasmon modes and investigate their dispersion relations, dependence on InSb
thickness, and the spatial distribution of the electric field. The observed
surface plasmon modes are well described by a simple theory of the air/InSb/air
trilayer. The plasmonic response of the grating/InSb structure is highly
sensitive to the dielectric environment and the presence of an analyte (e.g.,
lactose) at the InSb interface, which is promising for terahertz plasmonic
sensor applications. We determine the sensor sensitivity to be 7200 nm per
refractive index unit (or 0.06 THz per refractive index unit). The lower
surface plasmon mode also exhibits a splitting when tuned in resonance with the
vibrational mode of lactose at 1.37 THz. We propose that such interaction
between surface plasmon and vibrational modes can be used as the basis for a
new sensing modality that allows the detection of terahertz vibrational
fingerprints of an analyte.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04792</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Florez</keyname><forenames>Jorge Eduar Cardona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franklin</keyname><forenames>Erick de Moraes</forenames></author></authors><title>The formation and migration of sand ripples in closed conduits:
  experiments with turbulent water flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>This manuscript version is made available under the CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0
  license http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</comments><journal-ref>Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science, v. 71, p. 95-102, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2015.10.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transport of solid particles by a fluid flow is frequently found in
nature and industry. Some examples are the transport of sand in rivers and
hydrocarbon pipelines. When the shear stresses exerted by a fluid flow on a
granular bed remain moderate, some grains are set in motion without fluidizing
the bed; the moving grains form a layer, known as bed load, that moves while
maintaining contact with the fixed part of the bed. Under bed load conditions,
the granular bed may become unstable, generating ripples and dunes. Sand
ripples are commonly observed in closed conduits and pipes such as in petroleum
pipelines, sewer systems, and dredging lines. Although of importance for many
scientific domains and industrial applications, the formation of ripples in
closed conduits is not well understood, and the problem is still open. This
paper presents an experimental study on the formation and migration of sand
ripples under a turbulent closed-conduit flow and bed-load conditions. In our
experiments, fully-developed turbulent water flows were imposed over a granular
bed of known granulometry in a transparent channel, and bed load took place.
For different water flow rates and grain diameters, the growth and migration of
bedforms were filmed by a high-definition camera, and a numerical code was
developed to determine the wavelength and celerity of the bedforms from the
acquired images. The obtained results are compared with published stability
analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04793</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicholson</keyname><forenames>Amy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berkowitz</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Chia Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joo</keyname><forenames>Balint</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurth</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rinaldi</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiburzi</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vranas</keyname><forenames>Pavlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker-Loud</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrinoless double beta decay from lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Plenary talk given at the 34th International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory, Southampton, UK, 24-30 July 2016</comments><report-no>LLNL-PROC-700398</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While the discovery of non-zero neutrino masses is one of the most important
accomplishments by physicists in the past century, it is still unknown how and
in what form these masses arise. Lepton number-violating neutrinoless double
beta decay is a natural consequence of Majorana neutrinos and many BSM
theories, and many experimental efforts are involved in the search for these
processes. Understanding how neutrinoless double beta decay would manifest in
nuclear environments is key for understanding any observed signals. In these
proceedings we present an overview of a set of one- and two-body matrix
elements relevant for experimental searches for neutrinoless double beta decay,
describe the role of lattice QCD calculations, and present preliminary lattice
QCD results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04806</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04806</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Roberto L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velasco</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colodro-Conde</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valdivia</keyname><forenames>Juan J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puga</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oscoz</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebolo</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackay</keyname><forenames>Craig</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Garrido</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Ramos</keyname><forenames>Luis Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Ramos</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labadie</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muthusubramanian</keyname><forenames>Balaji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Coira</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author></authors><title>An instrumental puzzle: the modular integration of AOLI</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures, Proc. SPIE 9908, Ground-based and Airborne
  Instrumentation for Astronomy VI, 99082Z (August 9, 2016)</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9908, 99082Z (August 9, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2231980</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Adaptive Optics Lucky Imager, AOLI, is an instrument developed to deliver
the highest spatial resolution ever obtained in the visible, 20 mas, from
ground-based telescopes. In AOLI a new philosophy of instrumental prototyping
has been applied, based on the modularization of the subsystems. This modular
concept offers maximum flexibility regarding the instrument, telescope or the
addition of future developments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04807</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Velasco</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Etxegarai</keyname><forenames>Urtats</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oscoz</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Roberto L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puga</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murga</keyname><forenames>Gaizka</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Garrido</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pall&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Enric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayuso</keyname><forenames>Ismael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>M&#xf3;nica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truant</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Commissioning and First Observations with Wide FastCam at the Telescopio
  Carlos S\'anchez</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures, Proc. SPIE. 9908, Ground-based and Airborne
  Instrumentation for Astronomy VI, 99082O. (August 09, 2016)</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9908, Ground-based and Airborne Instrumentation for
  Astronomy VI, 99082O (August 9, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2233023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The FastCam instrument platform, jointly developed by the IAC and the UPCT,
allows, in real-time, acquisition, selection and storage of images with a
resolution that reaches the diffraction limit of medium-sized telescopes.
FastCam incorporates a specially designed software package to analyse series of
tens of thousands of images in parallel with the data acquisition at the
telescope. Wide FastCam is a new instrument that, using the same software for
data acquisition, does not look for lucky imaging but fast observations in a
much larger field of view. Here we describe the commissioning process and first
observations with Wide FastCam at the Telescopio Carlos S\'anchez (TCS) in the
Observatorio del Teide.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04821</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaban</keyname><forenames>Vitaly V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Isomerism in Quantum Dots: Geometries, Band Gaps, Dipole Moments,
  Ionization Energies and Heats of Formation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum dots (QDs) are applied in a variety of fields ranging from
photovoltaics to biomedical imaging. Even the smallest QDs present a
complicated potential energy surface characterized by a large set of stationary
points. Each local minimum is an isomer of QD of given composition. An
established theoretical methodology is hereby employed to obtain geometries of
the QD isomers (Cd16Se16, Cd16Se16, Zn16S16, Zn16Se16) and predict their
fundamental electronic and thermodynamic properties. Significantly scattered
heats of formation, with an amplitude up to 1304 kcal mol-1 in Cd16S16, were
found for the most and the least thermodynamically stable isomers of QDs. The
most shallow transition points can unlikely be observed in the experiments at
finite temperature, since they are able to transform into more stable isomers
upon thermal motion. Dipole moment is the most sensitive property to the QD
isomer geometry. A global energy search technique was demonstrated to be an
efficient tool to systematically identify isomers of QDs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04823</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chi</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jiansen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Lingqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belcher</keyname><forenames>John W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Cui</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasma heating inside ICMEs by Alfvenic fluctuations dissipation</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear cascade of low-frequency Alfvenic fluctuations (AFs) is regarded as
one candidate of the energy sources to heat plasma during the non-adiabatic
expansion of interplanetary coronal mass ejections (ICMEs). However, AFs inside
ICMEs were seldom reported in the literature. In this study, we investigate AFs
inside ICMEs using observations from Voyager 2 between 1 and 6 au. It is found
that AFs with high degree of Alfvenicity frequently occurred inside ICMEs, for
almost all the identified ICMEs (30 out of 33 ICMEs), and 12.6% of ICME time
interval. As ICMEs expand and move outward, the percentage of AF duration
decays linearly in general. The occurrence rate of AFs inside ICMEs is much
less than that in ambient solar wind, especially within 4 au. AFs inside ICMEs
are more frequently presented in the center and at the boundaries of ICMEs. In
addition, the proton temperature inside ICME has a similar distribution. These
findings suggest significant contribution of AFs on local plasma heating inside
ICMEs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04829</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Morimae</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Merlin-Arthur with noisy channel</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  What happens if in QMA the quantum channel between Merlin and Arthur is
noisy? It is not difficult to show that such a modification does not change the
computational power as long as the noise is not too strong so that errors are
correctable with high probability, since if Merlin encodes the witness state in
a quantum error-correction code and sends it to Arthur, Arthur can correct the
error caused by the noisy channel. If we further assume that Arthur can do only
single-qubit measurements, however, the problem becomes nontrivial, since in
this case Arthur cannot do the universal quantum computation by himself. In
this paper, we show that such a restricted complexity class is still equivalent
to QMA. To show it, we use measurement-based quantum computing: honest Merlin
sends the graph state to Arthur, and Arthur does fault-tolerant
measurement-based quantum computing on the noisy graph state with only
single-qubit measurements. By measuring stabilizer operators, Arthur also
checks the correctness of the graph state. Although this idea itself was
already used in several previous papers, these results cannot be directly used
to the present case, since the test that checks the graph state used in these
papers is so strict that even honest Merlin is rejected with high probability
if the channel is noisy. We therefore introduce a more relaxed test that can
accept not only the ideal graph state but also noisy graph states that are
error-correctable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04849</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jin-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou</forenames></author></authors><title>Dressed-state scheme for a fast CNOT gate</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1607.02696</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A highly feasible dressed-state scheme, which greatly speeds up the adiabatic
population transfer of a quantum system, is applied for implementing a fast
CNOT gate in a cavity QED system. The cavity QED system consists of two
identical five-level atoms which are respectively trapped in two optical
cavities connected by a fiber. With the help of quantum Zeno dynamics, the CNOT
gate is constructed by three steps with six pulses. Because the adiabatic
condition is not necessary to be considered and all of the pulses are smoothly
turned on and off, the scheme is fast and feasible in experiment. Numerical
simulations indicate that the average fidelity for constructing the CNOT gate
is quite high and the gate operation time is relatively short. Moreover, the
effects on the fidelity of the atomic spontaneous emission and the photon
leakages from the cavities are discussed by the master equation and the result
shows the scheme is robust against the decoherence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04850</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Bao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiu</keyname><forenames>Guozhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Sliding control for single-degree-of-freedom fractional oscillators</title><categories>math.DS nlin.CD</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proposes fractional sliding control designs for
single-degree-of-freedom fractional oscillators respectively of the
Kelvin-Voigt type, the modified Kelvin-Voigt type and D\&quot;{u}ffing type, whose
dynamical behaviors are described by second-order differential equations
involving fractional derivatives. Firstly, the differential equations of motion
are transformed into non-commensurate fractional state equations by introducing
state variables with physical significance. Secondly, fractional sliding
manifolds are constructed and stability of the corresponding sliding dynamics
is addressed via the infinite state approach and Lyapunov stability theory.
Thirdly, sliding control laws and adaptive sliding laws are designed for
fractional oscillators respectively in cases that the bound of the external
exciting force is known or unknown. Finally, numerical simulations are carried
out to validate the above control designs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04869</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>John A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunningham</keyname><forenames>Maria R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Paul A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>Jonathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bronfman</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lo</keyname><forenames>Nadia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Chemistry and Kinematics of Two Molecular Clouds near Sagittarius A*</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS, on the 5th of August 2016. 39
  pages (including online supplementary material). Main manuscript is 27 pages,
  containing 12 figures and 16 tables. The last 12 pages are the online
  supplementary material, containing 36 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1975</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analysed the chemical and kinematic properties of the 20 and 50 km
s$^{-1}$ molecular clouds in the Central Molecular Zone of the Milky Way
Galaxy, as well as those of the molecular ridge bridging these two clouds. Our
work has utilized 37 molecular transitions in the 0.65, 3 and 7-mm wavebands,
from the Mopra and NANTEN2 telescopes. The 0.65-mm NANTEN2 data highlights a
dense condensation of emission within the western part of the 20 km s$^{-1}$
cloud, visible in only four other transitions, which are 3-mm H$^{13}$CN
(1--0), H$^{13}$CO$^{+}$ (1--0), HNC (1--0) and N$_{2}$H$^{+}$ (1--0),
suggesting that the condensation is moderately optically thick and cold. We
find that while the relative chemical abundances between both clouds are alike
in many transitions, suggesting little variation in the chemistry between both
clouds; the 20 km s$^{-1}$, cold cloud is brighter than the 50 km s$^{-1}$
cloud in shock and high density tracers. The spatial distribution of enhanced
emission is widespread in the 20 km s$^{-1}$ cloud, as shown via line ratio
maps. The position velocity diagrams across both clouds indicate that the gas
is well mixed. We show that the molecular ridge is most likely part of the 20
km s$^{-1}$ cloud and that both of them may possibly extend to include the 50
km s$^{-1}$ cloud, as part of one larger cloud. Furthermore, we expect that the
20 km s$^{-1}$ cloud is being tidally sheared as a result of the gravitational
potential from Sgr A*.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04888</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04888</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lippa</keyname><forenames>Magdalena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillessen</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blind</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kok</keyname><forenames>Yipting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazici</keyname><forenames>Senol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfuhl</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haug</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kellner</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieprecht</keyname><forenames>Ekkehard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenhauer</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genzel</keyname><forenames>Reinhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hans</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haussmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kratschmann</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plattner</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sturm</keyname><forenames>Eckhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waisberg</keyname><forenames>Idel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiezorrek</keyname><forenames>Erich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrin</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perraut</keyname><forenames>Karine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandner</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straubmeier</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amorim</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>The metrology system of the VLTI instrument GRAVITY</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9907, Optical and Infrared Interferometry and Imaging
  V, 990722 (August 4, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2232272</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The VLTI instrument GRAVITY combines the beams from four telescopes and
provides phase-referenced imaging as well as precision-astrometry of order 10
microarcseconds by observing two celestial objects in dual-field mode. Their
angular separation can be determined from their differential OPD (dOPD) when
the internal dOPDs in the interferometer are known. Here, we present the
general overview of the novel metrology system which performs these
measurements. The metrology consists of a three-beam laser system and a
homodyne detection scheme for three-beam interference using phase-shifting
interferometry in combination with lock-in amplifiers. Via this approach the
metrology system measures dOPDs on a nanometer-level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04897</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Buck</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeh</keyname><forenames>Minfang</forenames></author></authors><title>Metal-loaded organic scintillators for neutrino physics</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>46 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 43 (2016) 093001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/9/093001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Organic liquid scintillators are used in many neutrino physics experiments of
the past and present. In particular for low energy neutrinos when realtime and
energy information are required, liquid scintillators have several advantages
compared to other technologies. In many cases the organic liquid needs to be
loaded with metal to enhance the neutrino signal over background events.
Several metal loaded scintillators of the past suffered from chemical and
optical instabilities, limiting the performance of these neutrino detectors.
Different ways of metal loading are described in the article with a focus on
recent techniques providing metal loaded scintillators that can be used under
stable conditions for many years even in ton scale experiments. Applications of
metal loaded scintillators in neutrino experiments are reviewed and the
performance as well as the prospects of different scintillator types are
compared.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04901</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Debashree</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolutionary algorithm based configuration interaction approach</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A stochastic configuration interaction method based on evolutionary algorithm
is designed as an affordable approximation to full configuration interaction
(FCI). The algorithm comprises of initiation, propagation and termination
steps, where the propagation step is performed with cloning, mutation and
cross-over, taking inspiration from genetic algorithm. We have tested its
accuracy in 1D Hubbard problem and a molecular system (symmetric bond breaking
of water molecule). We have tested two different fitness functions based on
energy of the determinants and the CI coefficients of determinants. We find
that the absolute value of CI coefficients is a more suitable fitness function
when combined with a fixed selection scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04903</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Serrano</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tebi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiespointner-Baumgarthuber</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;llegger</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Reinhold</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic-scale sensor for charge- and atomic-lattice-dynamics on surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present here a powerful method providing simultaneous atomic spatial and
nanosecond temporal resolution for investigating dynamics and structure on the
atomic scale, in general. We reveal the dynamic reorganization of surface
(ad)atoms induced by radio frequency alternating charging and decharging of a
metal. Our method utilizes taylor-made nano-fabricated two-dimensional islands
of physisorbed argon atoms, acting as motion sensors, probed by a radio
frequency low-temperature scanning tunneling microscope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04925</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kadlecov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>Hedvika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimo</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korn</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational wave generation by interaction of high power lasers with
  matter. Part II: Ablation and Piston models</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 32 images. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1602.08904</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze theoretical models of gravitational waves generation in the
interaction of high intensity laser with matter, namely ablation and piston
models. We analyse the generated gravitational waves in linear approximation of
gravitational theory. We derive the analytical formulas and estimates for the
metric perturbations and the radiated power of generated gravitational waves.
Furthermore we investigate the characteristics of polarization and the
behaviour of test particles in the presence of gravitational wave which will be
important for the detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04926</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kudryashov</keyname><forenames>Nikolai A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinelshchikov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry I.</forenames></author></authors><title>New non-standard Lagrangians for the Li\'enard-type equations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>To appear in Applied Mathematics Letters</comments><doi>10.1016/j.aml.2016.07.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Li\'enard-type equations are used for the description of various phenomena in
physics and other fields of science. Here we find a new family of the
Li\'enard-type equations which admits a non-standard autonomous Lagrangian. As
a by-product we obtain autonomous first integrals for each member of this
family of equations. We also show that some of the previously known conditions
for the existence of a non-standard Lagrangian for the Li\'enard-type equations
follow from the linearizability of the corresponding equation via nonlocal
transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04940</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Dvornikov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames><affiliation>IZMIRAN, Tomsk State University, University of Hamburg</affiliation></author></authors><title>Role of particle masses in the magnetic field generation driven by the
  parity violating interaction</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages in pdflatex, Elsevier latex style</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 760, 406-410 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently the new model for the generation of strong large scale magnetic
fields in neutron stars, driven by the parity violating interaction, was
proposed. In this model, the magnetic field instability results from the
modification of the chiral magnetic effect in presence of the electroweak
interaction between ultrarelativistic electrons and nucleons. In the present
work we study how a nonzero mass of charged particles, which are degenerate
relativistic electrons and nonrelativistic protons, influences the generation
of the magnetic field in frames of this approach. For this purpose we calculate
the induced electric current of these charged particles, electroweakly
interacting with background neutrons and an external magnetic field, exactly
accounting for the particle mass. This current is calculated by two methods:
using the exact solution of the Dirac equation for a charged particle in
external fields and computing the polarization operator of a photon in matter
composed of background neutrons. We show that the induced current is vanishing
in both approaches leading to the zero contribution of massive particles to the
generated magnetic field. We discuss the implication of our results for the
problem of the magnetic field generation in compact stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04954</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kulchitsky</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the underlying-event properties with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, on behalf of the ATLAS collaboration, The 24th
  Low-x Meeting, 6-11 June 2016, Hungary</comments><report-no>ATL-PHYS-PROC-2016-098</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  A correct modelling of the underlying event in proton-proton collisions is
important for the proper simulation of kinematic distributions of high-energy
collisions. The ATLAS collaboration extended previous studies at 7 TeV with a
leading track or jet or Z boson by a new study of Drell-Yan events in 1.1 1/fb
of data collected at a center-of-mass energy of 7 TeV. In this new study the
distributions of several topological event-shape variables based on charged
particles are measured, both integrated and differential in the transverse
momentum of the Drell-Yan lepton pair. These measurements are sensitive to the
underlying-event as well as the onset of hard emissions. The results have been
compared with the predictions of several state-of-the-art MC generators. The
collaboration has also performed a first study of the number and transverse
momentum sum of charged particles as a function of transverse momentum and
azimuthal angle in a special data set taken with low beam currents at a
center-of-mass energy of 13 TeV. The results are compared to predictions of
several MC generators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04956</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorbatsevich</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shubin</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>PT-Symmetry Breaking and Catastrophes in Dissipationless Resonant
  Tunneling Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the phenomenon of spontaneous symmetry breaking in dissipationless
resonant tunneling heterostructures (RTS). To describe the quantum transport in
this system we apply both the nonequilibrium Green function formalism based on
a tight-binding model and a numerical solution of the Schroedinger equation
within the envelope wavefunction formalism. An auxiliary non-Hermitian
Hamiltonian is introduced. Its eigenvalues determine exactly the transparency
peak positions. We present a procedure how to construct a family of
non-Hermitian Hamiltonians with real eigenvalues. In general these Hamiltonians
do not have PT-symmetry. In spatially symmetric RTS the corresponding auxiliary
non-Hermitian Hamiltonian becomes PT-symmetric and possesses real eigenvalues,
which can coalesce at exceptional points (EP) of Hamiltonian. A coalescence of
the auxiliary non-Hermitian Hamiltonian eigenvalues means a coalescence of
resonances in RTS, which is accompanied be symmetry breaking of the electron
wavefunction probability distribution (at a given direction of the particle
flow). We construct a classification of different types of the peak coalescence
in terms of the catastrophe theory and investigate the impact of dissipation
and asymmetry on these phenomena. Possible applications include sensors and
broad-band filters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04965</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Manoj</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Megeath</keyname><forenames>S. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames><suffix>II</suffix></author><author><keyname>Stutz</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobin</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furlan</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The evolution of far-infrared CO emission from protostars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the evolution of far-IR CO emission from protostars observed
with Herschel/PACS for 50 sources from the combined sample of HOPS and DIGIT
Herschel key programs. From the uniformly sampled spectral energy
distributions, we computed $L_{\rm{bol}}$, $T_{\rm{bol}}$ and $L_{\rm
{bol}}/L_{\rm {smm}}$ for these sources to search for correlations between
far-IR CO emission and protostellar properties. We find a strong and tight
correlation between far-IR CO luminosity ($L^{\rm fir}_{\rm CO}$) and the
bolometric luminosity ($L_{\rm{bol}}$) of the protostars with $L^{\rm fir}_{\rm
CO}$ $\propto$ $L_{\rm{bol}}^{0.7}$. We, however, do not find a strong
correlation between $L^{\rm fir}_{\rm CO}$ and protostellar evolutionary
indicators, $T_{\rm{bol}}$ and $L_{\rm {bol}}/L_{\rm {smm}}$. FIR CO emission
from protostars traces the currently shocked gas by jets/outflows, and $L^{\rm
fir}_{\rm CO}$ is proportional to the instantaneous mass loss rate,
$\dot{M}_{\rm{out}}$. The correlation between $L^{\rm fir}_{\rm CO}$ and
$L_{\rm{bol}}$ is indicative of instantaneous $\dot{M}_{\rm{out}}$ tracking
instantaneous $\dot{M}_{\rm{acc}}$. The lack of correlation between $L^{\rm
fir}_{\rm CO}$ and evolutionary indicators $T_{\rm{bol}}$ and $L_{\rm
{bol}}/L_{\rm {smm}}$ suggests that $\dot{M}_{\rm{out}}$ and, therefore,
$\dot{M}_{\rm{acc}}$ do not show any clear evolutionary trend. These results
are consistent with mass accretion/ejection in protostars being episodic. Taken
together with the previous finding that the time-averaged mass
ejection/accretion rate declines during the protostellar phase (e.g., Bontemps
et al. 1996), our results suggest that the instantaneous accretion/ejection
rate of protostars is highly time variable and episodic, but the amplitude
and/or frequency of this variability decreases with time such that the time
averaged accretion/ejection rate declines with system age.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04970</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lamichhane</keyname><forenames>Madan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newman</keyname><forenames>Kathie E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gezelter</keyname><forenames>J. Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Real space electrostatics for multipoles. III. Dielectric Properties</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 074108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4960957</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the first two papers in this series, we developed new shifted potential
(SP), gradient shifted force (GSF), and Taylor shifted force (TSF) real-space
methods for multipole interactions in condensed phase simulations. Here, we
discuss the dielectric properties of fluids that emerge from simulations using
these methods. Most electrostatic methods (including the Ewald sum) require
correction to the conducting boundary fluctuation formula for the static
dielectric constants, and we discuss the derivation of these corrections for
the new real space methods. For quadrupolar fluids, the analogous material
property is the quadrupolar susceptibility. As in the dipolar case, the
fluctuation formula for the quadrupolar susceptibility has corrections that
depend on the electrostatic method being utilized. One of the most important
effects measured by both the static dielectric and quadrupolar susceptibility
is the ability to screen charges embedded in the fluid. We use potentials of
mean force between solvated ions to discuss how geometric factors can lead to
distance-dependent screening in both quadrupolar and dipolar fluids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04971</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Helbing</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Dept. of Physics, University of Wuppertal</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Dept. of Physics, University of Wuppertal</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Naumann</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames><affiliation>Dept. of Physics, University of Wuppertal</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eliseev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>III. Physikalisches Institut, RWTH Aachen University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Heinen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>III. Physikalisches Institut, RWTH Aachen University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Scholz</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>III. Physikalisches Institut, RWTH Aachen University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wiebusch</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>III. Physikalisches Institut, RWTH Aachen University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zierke</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>III. Physikalisches Institut, RWTH Aachen University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Acoustic properties of glacial ice for neutrino detection and the
  Enceladus Explorer</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>7 pages, 12 figures, ICRC 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra high energy neutrinos may be observed in ice by the emission of
acoustic signals. The SPATS detector has investigated the possibility of
observing GZK-neutrinos in the clear ice near the South Pole at the IceCube
detector site. To explore other potential detection sites glacial ice in the
Alps and in Antarctica has been surveyed for its acoustical properties. The
purpose of the Enceladus Explorer (EnEx), on the other hand, is the search for
extraterrestrial life on the Saturn moon Enceladus. Here acoustics is used to
maneuver a subsurface probe inside the ice by trilateration of signals. A
system of acoustic transducers has been developed to study both applications.
In the south polar region of the moon Enceladus there are secluded crevasses.
These are filled with liquid water, probably heated by tidal forces due to the
short distance to Saturn. We intend to take a sample of water from these
crevasses by using a combination of a melt down and steering probe called
IceMole (IM). Maneuvering IM requires a good understanding of ice properties
such as the speed of sound, the attenuation of acoustic signals in ice, their
directional dependencies and their dependence on different frequencies. The
technology developed for this positioning system could also contribute to the
design of future large scale acoustic neutrino detectors. We present our
analysis methods and the findings on attenuation, sound speed, and frequency
response obtained at several sites in the Alps and Antarctica.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04975</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kovacevic</keyname><forenames>Dejan</forenames></author></authors><title>Incompressible Navier-Stokes Equations: Example of no solution at $R^3$
  and $t=0$</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>76D05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide an example of a smooth, divergence-free $\nabla \cdot
\vec{u}(\vec{x})=0$ velocity vector field $\vec{u}(\vec{x})$ for incompressible
fluid occupying all of $R^{3}$ space, and smooth vector field $\vec{f}(\vec{x},
t)$ for which the Navier-Stokes equation for incompressible fluid does not have
a solution for any position in space $\vec{x}\in R^{3} $ at $t=0$. The velocity
vector field $u_{i} (\vec{x})=2\frac{x_{h(i-1)} -x_{h(i+1)} }{\left(1+\sum
_{j=1}^{3}x_{j}^{2} \right)^{2} }$ ; $i=\{ 1,2,3\} $ where
$h(l)=\left\{\begin{array}{ccc} {l} &amp; {;1\le l\le 3} &amp; {} \\ {1} &amp; {;l=4} &amp; {}
\\ {3} &amp; {;l=0} &amp; {} \end{array}\right.$ is smooth, divergence-free,
continuously differentiable $u(\vec{x})\in C^{\infty }$, has bounded energy
$\int _{R^{3} }\left|\vec{u}\right|^{2} dx=\pi ^{2}$, zero velocity at
coordinate origin, and velocity converges to zero for $\left|\vec{x}\right|\to
\infty$. The vector field $\vec{f}(\vec{x},t)=(0,0,\frac{1}{1+t^{2} (\sum
_{j=1}^{3}x_{j} )^{2} )} $ is smooth, continuously differentiable
$f(\vec{x},t)\in C^{\infty }$, converging to zero for $\left|\vec{x}\right|\to
\infty$. Applying $\vec{u}(\vec{x})$ and $\vec{f}(\vec{x}, t)$ in the
Navier-Stokes equation for incompressible fluid results with three mutually
different solutions for pressure $p(\vec{x}, t)$, one of which includes zero
division with zero $\frac{0}{0}$ term at $t=0$, which is indeterminate for all
positions $\vec{x} \in R^{3}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04984</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Svozil</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author></authors><title>A note on the statistical sampling aspect of delayed choice entanglement
  swapping</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum and classical models for delayed choice entanglement swapping by
postselection of measurements are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04986</id><created>2016-08-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Iurato</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>On the history of Levi-Civita's parallel transport</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>A case-study in history of mathematical physics and theoretical
  physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this historical note, we wish to highlight the crucial conceptual role
played by the principle of virtual work of analytical mechanics, in working out
the fundamental notion of parallel transport on a Riemannian manifold, which
opened the way to the theory of connections and gauge theories. Moreover, after
a detailed historical-technical reconstruction of the original Levi-Civita's
argument, a further historiographical deepening and a related critical
discussion of the question, are pursued.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04992</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Fioretti</keyname><forenames>Valentina</forenames><affiliation>the CTA Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bulgarelli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames><affiliation>the CTA Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schussler</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames><affiliation>the CTA Consortium</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Cherenkov Telescope Array On-Site integral sensitivity: observing
  the Crab</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9906, Ground-based and Airborne Telescopes VI, 99063O
  (July 27, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2231398</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA) is the future large observatory in the
very high energy (VHE) domain. Operating from 20 GeV to 300 TeV, it will be
composed of tens of Imaging Air Cherenkov Telescopes (IACTs) displaced in a
large area of a few square kilometers in both the southern and northern
hemispheres. The CTA/DATA On-Site Analysis (OSA) is the system devoted to the
development of dedicated pipelines and algorithms to be used at the CTA site
for the reconstruction, data quality monitoring, science monitoring and
realtime science alerting during observations. The OSA integral sensitivity is
computed here for the most studied source at Gamma-rays, the Crab Nebula, for a
set of exposures ranging from 1000 seconds to 50 hours, using the full CTA
Southern array. The reason for the Crab Nebula selection as the first example
of OSA integral sensitivity is twofold: (i) this source is characterized by a
broad spectrum covering the entire CTA energy range; (ii) it represents, at the
time of writing, the standard candle in VHE and it is often used as unit for
the IACTs sensitivity. The effect of different Crab Nebula emission models on
the CTA integral sensitivity is evaluated, to emphasize the need for
representative spectra of the CTA science targets in the evaluation of the OSA
use cases. Using the most complete model as input to the OSA integral
sensitivity, we obtain a significant detection of the Crab nebula (about 10% of
flux) even for a 1000 second exposure, for an energy threshold less than 10
TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05016</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Harvey</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redman</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boumis</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopsacheili</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akras</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurkic</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The circumstellar environment of pre-SN Ia systems</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>3 Pages, 1 Figure, Supernova Remnants Conference, Chania, Greece,
  June 6-11</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we explore the possible preexisting circumstellar debris of supernova
type Ia systems. Classical, symbiotic and recurrent novae all accrete onto
roughly solar mass white dwarfs from main sequence or Mira type companions and
result in thermonuclear runaways and expulsion of the accreted material at high
velocity. The expelled material forms a fast moving shell that eventually slows
to planetary nebula expansion velocities within several hundred years. All such
systems are recurrent and thousands of shells (each of about 0.001 Mo) snow
plough into the environment. As these systems involve common envelope binaries
the material is distributed in a non-spherical shell. These systems could be
progenitors of some SN Ia and thus explode into environments with large amounts
of accumulated gas and dust distributed in thin non-spherical shells. Such
shells should be observable around 100 years after a SN Ia event in a radio
flash as the SN Ia debris meets that of the ejected material of the systems
previous incarnation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05018</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lopez-Bezanilla</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Littlewood</keyname><forenames>Peter B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic properties of 8-Pmmn borophene</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 241405(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.241405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First-principles calculations on monolayer 8-{\it Pmmn} borophene are
reported to reveal unprecedented electronic properties in a two-dimensional
material. Based on a Born effective charge analysis, 8-{\it Pmmn} borophene is
the first single-element based monolayered material exhibiting two sublattices
with substantial ionic features. The observed Dirac cones are actually formed
by the p$_z$ orbitals of one of the inequivalent sublattices composed of
uniquely four atoms, yielding an underlying hexagonal network topologically
equivalent to distorted graphene. A significant physical outcome of this effect
includes the possibility of converting metallic 8-{\it Pmmn} borophene into an
indirect band gap semiconductor by means of external shear stress. The
stability of the strained structures are supported by a phonon frequency
analysis. The Dirac cones are sensitive to the formation of vacancies only in
the inequivalent sublattice electronically active at the Fermi level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05020</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ignat'ev</keyname><forenames>Yurii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agathonov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ignatyev</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Cosmological Fermion Systems With Interparticle Fantom
  Scalar Interaction</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>67 pages, 71 figures, 43 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The article represents a research of the cosmological evolution of fermion
statistical systems with fantom scalar interaction where &quot;kinetic&quot; term's
contribution to the total energy of a scalar field is negative. As a result of
analytical and numerical simulation of such systems it has been revealed a
existence of four possible scenarios depending on parameters of the system and
initial conditions. Among these scenarios there are scenarios with an early,
intermediate and late non-relativistic stages of the cosmological evolution,
all of which also have necessary inflation stage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05021</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Asuquo</keyname><forenames>Cletus C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McArthur</keyname><forenames>Danielle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowles</keyname><forenames>Richard K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Competitive Heterogeneous Nucleation onto a Microscopic Impurity in a
  Potts Model</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 Figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 064511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4960650</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many metastable systems can nucleate to multiple competing stable or
intermediate metastable states. In this work, a Potts model, subject to
external fields, is used to study the competitive nucleation of two phases
attempting to grow on a microscopic impurity. Monte Carlo simulations are used
to calculate the free energy surfaces for the system under different
conditions, where the relative stability of the phases is adjusted by changing
the interaction parameters, and the nucleation rates obtained using
multicomponent transition state theory are compared with the rates measured
using the survival probability method. We find that the two methods predict
similar nucleation rates when the free energy barrier used in the transition
state theory is defined as the work required to form a critical embryo from the
metastable phase. An analysis of the free energy surfaces also reveals that the
competition between the nucleating phases leads to an effective drying of the
impurity which slows down the nucleation rate compared to the single phase
case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05022</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sheckelton</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neilson</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic tunability of the frustrated triangular-lattice cluster
  magnet LiZn$_{2-x}$Mo$_3$O$_8$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mater. Horiz. 2, 76-80 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C4MH00166D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  LiZn$_2$Mo$_3$O$_8$ is an electrically insulating geometrically frustrated
antiferromagnet in which inorganic Mo$_3$O$_{13}$ clusters each behaves as a
single $S = 1/2$ unit, with the clusters arranged on a two-dimensional
triangular lattice. Prior results have shown that LiZn$_2$Mo$_3$O$_8$ does not
exhibit static magnetic order down to at least $T = 0.05\,K$, and instead
possesses a valence bond ground state. Here, we show that LiZn$_2$Mo$_3$O$_8$
can be hole doped by oxidation with $\mathrm{I}_2$ and subsequent removal of
$\mathrm{Zn}^{2+}$ cations to access the entire range of electron count, from
one to zero unpaired electrons per site on the triangular lattice. Contrary to
expectations, no metallic state is induced; instead, the primary effect is to
suppress the number of sites contributing to the condensed valence-bond state.
Further, diffraction and pair-distribution function analysis show no evidence
for local Jahn-Teller distortions or other deviations from the parent trigonal
symmetry as a function of doping or temperature. Taken together, the data and
density functional theory calculations indicate that removal of electrons from
the magnetic layers favors Anderson localization of the resulting hole and an
increase in the electrical band-gap over the formation of a metallic and
superconducting state. These results put strong constraints on the chemical
conditions necessary to realize metallic states from parent insulating
geometrically frustrated antiferromagnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05038</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Levy</keyname><forenames>Michael Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electoral Stability and Rigidity</title><categories>q-fin.EC physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>34 pages (body = 28, appendix = 6), 3 Figures, 3 tables, includes 2
  apendices</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some argue that political stability is best served through a two-party
system. This study refutes this. The author mathematically defines the
stability and rigidity of electoral systems comprised of any quantity of
electors and parties. In fact, stability is a function of the quantity of
electors - i.e., the number of occupied seats at the table. As the number of
electors increases, the properties of an electorate are increasingly well
resolved, and well described by those of an electorate that is least excessive
-- that is to say an electorate that is closest to equilibrium. Further,
electoral rigidity is a function of the quantity of parties and their
probabilities of representation. An absolutely rigid system admits no
fluctuations -- whatever happens to one elector will happen to all electors. As
the quantity of parties increases so does the number of party lines, and with
it the quantity of alternatives with which to respond to an external stimulus.
Rigidity is significant in a social system that places high value on party
loyalty. In conclusion, (i) electoral stability is best served by increasing
the quantity of electors; (ii) electoral rigidity is best served by decreasing
the quantity of parties, and by increasing the representation of some parties
at the expense of others; and (iii) the less stable a branch of government, the
more concern is placed on those who would hold those offices for the people.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05044</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Cardinot</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibbons</keyname><forenames>Maud</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Riordan</keyname><forenames>Colm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffith</keyname><forenames>Josephine</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of an Optional Strategy in the Prisoner's Dilemma in Spatial
  and Non-spatial Environments</title><categories>cs.GT cs.MA cs.NE nlin.AO</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures. International Conference on the Simulation of
  Adaptive Behavior</comments><journal-ref>From Animals to Animats 14 (pp. 145-156). Springer International
  Publishing, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-43488-9_14</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents research comparing the effects of different environments
on the outcome of an extended Prisoner's Dilemma, in which agents have the
option to abstain from playing the game. We consider three different pure
strategies: cooperation, defection and abstinence. We adopt an evolutionary
game theoretic approach and consider two different environments: the first
which imposes no spatial constraints and the second in which agents are placed
on a lattice grid. We analyse the performance of the three strategies as we
vary the loner's payoff in both structured and unstructured environments.
Furthermore we also present the results of simulations which identify scenarios
in which cooperative clusters of agents emerge and persist in both
environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05049</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Francica</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montangero</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paternostro</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plastina</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>The driven Dicke Model: time-dependent mean field and quantum
  fluctuations in a non-equilibrium quantum many-body system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish a new theoretical framework, based on a time-dependent mean
field approach, to address the dynamics of the driven Dicke model. The joint
evolution of both mean fields and quantum fluctuations gives rise to a rich and
generally non-linear dynamics, featuring a normal (stable) regime and an
unstable, super-radiant one. Various dynamical phenomena emerge, such as the
spontaneous amplification of vacuum fluctuations, or the appearance of special
points around which the mean-field amplitudes rotate during driven time
evolution, signalling a dynamical symmetry breaking. We also provide a
characterization of the driving-induced photon production in terms of the work
done by the driving agent, of the non-adiabaticity of the process and of the
entanglement generated between the atomic system and the cavity mode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05051</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pendharker</keyname><forenames>Sarang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>Zubin</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Zero Conductivity Condition for Optical Absorption</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Harnessing information and energy from light within a nanoscale mode volume
is a fundamental challenge for nanophotonic applications ranging from solar
photovoltaics to single photon detectors. Here, we show the existence of a
universal condition in materials that sheds light on fundamental limits of
electromagnetic to matter energy conversion (transduction). We show that the
upper limit of absorption rate (transduction rate) in any nanoscale absorber
converting light to matter degrees of freedom is revealed by the zero of
optical conductivity at complex frequencies ($\sigma(\omega^\prime +
i\omega^{\prime\prime})= 0$). We trace the origin of this universal zero
conductivity condition to causality requirements on any passive linear response
function and propose an experiment of absorption resonances using plasmonic
nanoparticles to experimentally verify this universal zero conductivity
condition. Our work is widely applicable to linear systems across the
electromagnetic spectrum and allows for systematic optimization of optical
absorption in single photon detectors, solar cells, Coherent Perfect Absorbers
and SPASERS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0703363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0703363</id><created>2007-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hugouvieux</keyname><forenames>Virginie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farhi</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Mark R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juranyi</keyname><forenames>Fanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourges</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kob</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure and dynamics of l-Ge: Neutron scattering experiments and ab
  initio molecular dynamics simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>11 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 75, 104208 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.75.104208</doi><abstract>  We report the first measurements of the dynamics of liquid germanium (l-Ge)
by quasi-elastic neutron scattering on time-of-flight and triple-axis
spectrometers. These results are compared with simulation data of the structure
and dynamics of l-Ge which have been obtained with ab initio density functional
theory methods. The simulations accurately reproduce previous results from
elastic and inelastic scattering experiments, as well as the q-dependence of
the width of the quasi-elastic signal of the new experimental data. In order to
understand some special features of the structure of the liquid we have also
simulated amorphous Ge. Overall we find that the atomistic model represents
accurately the average structure of real l-Ge as well as the time dependent
structural fluctuations. The new quasi-elastic neutron scattering data allows
us to investigate to what extent simple theoretical models can be used to
describe diffusion in l-Ge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
