<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:59:05Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-12" from="2017-05-12" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0807.2509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0807.2509</id><created>2008-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Baohua</keyname><forenames>Sun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jie</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author></authors><title>Challenge on the Astrophysical R-process Calculation with Nuclear Mass
  Models</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. Lett. 25 (2008) 2429</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0256-307X/25/7/027</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  Our understanding of the rapid neutron capture nucleosynthesis process in
universe depends on the reliability of nuclear mass predictions. Initiated by
the newly developed mass table in the relativistic mean field theory (RMF), in
this paper the influence of mass models on the $r$-process calculations is
investigated assuming the same astrophysical conditions. The different model
predictions on the so far unreachable nuclei lead to significant deviations in
the calculated r-process abundances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.5223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.5223</id><created>2010-12-23</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kozameh</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreschi</keyname><forenames>Osvaldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Regular isolated black holes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA hep-th</categories><comments>published version</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4756825</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define a family of spacetimes representing isolated black holes exhibiting
remarkable universal properties which are natural generalizations from
stationary spacetimes. They admit a well defined notion of surface gravity k_H.
This generalized surface gravity mediates an exponential relation between a
regular null coordinate w near the horizon and an asymptotic Bondi null
coordinate u defined in the vicinity of future null infinity. Our construction
provides a framework for the study of gravitational collapse of an isolated
system in its late stage of evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.0475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.0475</id><created>2013-05-02</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arraut</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>The Astrophysical Scales Set by the Cosmological Constant, Black-Hole
  Thermodynamics and Non-Linear Massive Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Published version. 24 pages. Significant changes in order to match
  the published version</comments><journal-ref>Universe 2017, 3, 45</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/universe3020045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate explicitly the black-hole temperature for the Schwarzschild
de-Sitter solution inside massive gravity by defining the Killing-vector in the
direction of the St\&quot;uckelberg function. We then consider the conditions which
an observer in massive gravity has to obey in order to agree with the standard
results of General Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.2434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.2434</id><created>2013-05-10</created><updated>2014-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datchev</keyname><forenames>Kiril R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Daniel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kessler</keyname><forenames>Andre P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nontrapping surfaces of revolution with long living resonances</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mathematical Research Letters. Vol. 22, No. 1, pp. 23-42, 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study resonances of surfaces of revolution obtained by removing a disk
from a cone and attaching a hyperbolic cusp in its place. These surfaces
include ones with nontrapping geodesic flow (every maximally extended
non-reflected geodesic is unbounded) and yet infinitely many long living
resonances (resonances with uniformly bounded imaginary part, i.e. decay rate).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.1112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.1112</id><created>2013-09-04</created><updated>2014-04-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datchev</keyname><forenames>Kiril</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative limiting absorption principle in the semiclassical limit</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Geometric and Functional Analysis. Vol. 24, No. 3, pp. 740-747,
  2014</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an elementary proof of Burq's resolvent bounds for long range
semiclassical Schroedinger operators. Globally, the resolvent norm grows
exponentially in the inverse semiclassical parameter, and near infinity it
grows linearly. We also weaken the regularity assumptions on the potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.5804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.5804</id><created>2014-06-22</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jin-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yong-Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jian-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Ming-Qiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral symmetry-breaking corrections to strong decays of D*s0(2317) and
  D's1(2460) in HH\c{hi}PT</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 3figures, LaTeX</comments><msc-class>81V05</msc-class><acm-class>J.2.9</acm-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The strong decays of two narrow mesons $D_{s0}^{*}(2317)$ and
$D_{s1}^{'}(2460)$ are studied within the framework of heavy hadron chiral
perturbation theory. Up to next-to-leading order in $1/\Lambda_{\chi}$, by a
fit to the experimental widths of their nonstrange partners, the chiral
symmetry-breaking coupling constants are extracted. The single-pion decay
widths are estimated to be $\Gamma(D_{s0}^{*}(2317)\to
D_{s}^{+}\pi^{0})=9.2\pm2.3$ KeV and $\Gamma(D_{s1}^{'}(2460)\to
D_{s}^{*+}\pi^{0})=9.0\pm2.1$ KeV, respectively, which are consistent with the
experimental constraints and comparable with other theoretical predictions. The
numerical analysis shows that chiral-symmetry corrections to the decay widths
are significant. Applications and predictions for the corresponding beauty
mesons are also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.0414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.0414</id><created>2014-09-01</created><updated>2016-11-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jho</keyname><forenames>Yong-Soo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jae-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Ki-Seok</forenames></author></authors><title>A topological Fermi-liquid theory for interacting Weyl metals with time
  reversal symmetry breaking</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205113 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Introducing both Berry curvature and chiral anomaly into Landau's
Fermi-liquid theory, we construct a topological Fermi-liquid theory, applicable
to interacting Weyl metals in the absence of time reversal symmetry. Following
the Landau's Fermi-liquid theory, we obtain an effective free-energy functional
in terms of the density field of chiral fermions. The density field of chiral
fermions is determined by a self-consistent equation, minimizing the effective
free-energy functional with respect to the order-parameter field. Beyond these
thermodynamic properties, we construct Boltzmann transport theory to encode
both the Berry curvature and the chiral anomaly in the presence of forward
scattering of a Fermi-liquid state, essential for understanding dynamic
correlations in interacting Weyl metals. This generalizes the Boltzmann
transport theory for the Landau's Fermi-liquid state in the respect of
incorporating the topological structure and extends that for noninteracting
Weyl metals in the sense of introducing the forward scattering. Finally, we
justify this topological Fermi-liquid theory, generalizing the
first-quantization description for noninteracting Weyl metals into the
second-quantization representation for interacting Weyl metals. First, we
derive a topological Fermi-gas theory, integrating over high-energy electronic
degrees of freedom deep inside a pair of chiral Fermi surfaces. As a result, we
reproduce a topological Drude model with both the Berry curvature and the
chiral anomaly. Second, we take into account interactions between such
low-energy chiral fermions on the pair of chiral Fermi surfaces. We perform the
renormalization group analysis, and find that only forward scattering turns out
to be marginal above possible superconducting transition temperatures,
justifying the topological Fermi-liquid theory of interacting Weyl metals with
time reversal symmetry breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0416</id><created>2014-11-03</created><updated>2015-11-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>Leonhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;hle</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Epidemic Phenomena Using the R Package
  surveillance</title><categories>stat.CO cs.CE physics.data-an stat.AP</categories><comments>53 pages, 20 figures, package homepage:
  http://surveillance.r-forge.r-project.org/</comments><msc-class>62-04</msc-class><acm-class>G.3</acm-class><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Software (2017); 77 (11): 1-55</journal-ref><doi>10.18637/jss.v077.i11</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The availability of geocoded health data and the inherent temporal structure
of communicable diseases have led to an increased interest in statistical
models and software for spatio-temporal data with epidemic features. The open
source R package surveillance can handle various levels of aggregation at which
infective events have been recorded: individual-level time-stamped
geo-referenced data (case reports) in either continuous space or discrete
space, as well as counts aggregated by period and region. For each of these
data types, the surveillance package implements tools for visualization,
likelihoood inference and simulation from recently developed statistical
regression frameworks capturing endemic and epidemic dynamics. Altogether, this
paper is a guide to the spatio-temporal modeling of epidemic phenomena,
exemplified by analyses of public health surveillance data on measles and
invasive meningococcal disease.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.2563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.2563</id><created>2014-11-10</created><updated>2015-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>Louise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Electric-magnetic Duality of Abelian Gauge Theory on the Four-torus,
  from the Fivebrane on T2 x T4, via their Partition Functions</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>41 pages, published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2015)134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the partition function of four-dimensional abelian gauge theory on
a general four-torus T4 with flat metric using Dirac quantization. In addition
to an SL(4, Z) symmetry, it possesses SL(2,Z) symmetry that is electromagnetic
S-duality. We show explicitly how this SL(2, Z) S-duality of the 4d abelian
gauge theory has its origin in symmetries of the 6d (2,0) tensor theory, by
computing the partition function of a single fivebrane compactified on T2 x T4,
which has SL(2,Z) x SL(4,Z) symmetry. If we identify the couplings of the
abelian gauge theory \tau = {\theta\over 2\pi} + i{4\pi\over e^2} with the
complex modulus of the T2 torus, \tau = \beta^2 + i {R_1\over R_2}, then in the
small T2 limit, the partition function of the fivebrane tensor field can be
factorized, and contains the partition function of the 4d gauge theory. In this
way the SL(2,Z) symmetry of the 6d tensor partition function is identified with
the S-duality symmetry of the 4d gauge partition function. Each partition
function is the product of zero mode and oscillator contributions, where the
SL(2,Z) acts suitably. For the 4d gauge theory, which has a Lagrangian, this
product redistributes when using path integral quantization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04719</id><created>2015-03-16</created><updated>2015-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nekrasov</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge-exchange reactions from the standpoint of the parton model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures; version to appear in EPJA</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2015) 51:148</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2015-15148-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using simple arguments, we show that charge-exchange reactions at high
energies go through the hard scattering of fast quarks. On this basis we
describe $\pi^- p \to M^0 n$ and $K^- p \to M^0 \Lambda$, $M^0 =\pi^0, \eta,
\eta'$, in a combined approach which defines hard contributions in the parton
model and soft ones in Regge phenomenology. The disappearance of a dip
according to recent GAMS-4$\pi$ data in the differential cross-section $K^- p
\to \eta\Lambda$ at $|t| \approx$ 0.4--0.5 (GeV$\!$/c)$^2$ at transition to
relatively high momenta, is explained as a manifestation of a mode change of
summation of hard contributions from coherent to incoherent. Other
manifestations of the mentioned mode change are discussed. Constraints on the
$\eta$--$\eta'$ mixing and gluonium admixture in $\eta'$ are obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01065</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>Leonhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Incorporating social contact data in spatio-temporal models for
  infectious disease spread</title><categories>stat.ME physics.soc-ph q-bio.PE stat.AP</categories><comments>accepted manuscript; 14 pages, including 4 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Biostatistics (2017); 18(2):338-351</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/biostatistics/kxw051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Routine public health surveillance of notifiable infectious diseases gives
rise to weekly counts of reported cases -- possibly stratified by region and/or
age group. We investigate how an age-structured social contact matrix can be
incorporated into a spatio-temporal endemic-epidemic model for infectious
disease counts. To illustrate the approach, we analyze the spread of norovirus
gastroenteritis over 6 age groups within the 12 districts of Berlin, 2011-2015,
using contact data from the POLYMOD study. The proposed age-structured model
outperforms alternative scenarios with homogeneous or no mixing between age
groups. An extended contact model suggests a power transformation of the
survey-based contact matrix towards more within-group transmission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04915</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mannheim</keyname><forenames>Philip D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antilinearity Rather than Hermiticity as a Guiding Principle for Quantum
  Theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>41 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1506.08432. Majorana spinor quantization scheme constructed in which
  all spin zero fermion multilinears are real. Charge conjugation and the C
  operator of PT theory are compared and contrasted. Discussion on causality
  included. Text rewritten, with no change in physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Currently there is much interest in Hamiltonians that are not Hermitian but
instead possess an antilinear $PT$ symmetry, since such Hamiltonians can still
lead to the time-independent evolution of scalar products, and can still have
an entirely real energy spectrum. However, such theories can also admit of
energy spectra in which energies come in complex conjugate pairs, and can even
admit of Hamiltonians that cannot be diagonalized at all. Hermiticity is just a
particular realization of $PT$ symmetry, with $PT$ symmetry being the more
general. These $PT$ theories are themselves part of an even broader class of
theories, theories that can be characterized by possessing some general
antilinear symmetry, as that requirement alone is a both necessary and
sufficient condition for the time-independent evolution of scalar products,
with all the different realizations of the $PT$ symmetry program then being
obtained. Use of complex Lorentz invariance allows us to show that the
antilinear symmetry is uniquely specified to be $CPT$, with the $CPT$ theorem
thus being extended to the non-Hermitian case. For theories that are separately
charge conjugation invariant, the results of the $PT$-symmetry program then
follow. We show that in order to construct the correct classical action needed
for a path integral quantization one must impose $CPT$ symmetry on each
classical path, a requirement that has no counterpart in any Hermiticity
condition since Hermiticity of a Hamiltonian is only definable after the
quantization has been performed and the quantum Hilbert space has been
constructed. We show that whether or not a $CPT$-invariant Hamiltonian is
Hermitian is a property of the solutions to the theory and not of the
Hamiltonian itself. Thus Hermiticity never needs to be postulated at all.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05988</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gambhir</keyname><forenames>Arjun Singh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stathopoulos</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orginos</keyname><forenames>Kostas</forenames></author></authors><title>Deflation as a Method of Variance Reduction for Estimating the Trace of
  a Matrix Inverse</title><categories>hep-lat cs.NA</categories><comments>21 pages, 24 figures</comments><journal-ref>SIAM J. Sci. Comput., 39(2), A532 to A558, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/16M1066361</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many fields require computing the trace of the inverse of a large, sparse
matrix. The typical method used for such computations is the Hutchinson method
which is a Monte Carlo (MC) averaging over matrix quadratures. To improve its
convergence, several variance reductions techniques have been proposed. In this
paper, we study the effects of deflating the near null singular value space. We
make two main contributions.
  First, we analyze the variance of the Hutchinson method as a function of the
deflated singular values and vectors. Although this provides good intuition in
general, by assuming additionally that the singular vectors are random unitary
matrices, we arrive at concise formulas for the deflated variance that include
only the variance and mean of the singular values. We make the remarkable
observation that deflation may increase variance for Hermitian matrices but not
for non-Hermitian ones. This is a rare, if not unique, property where
non-Hermitian matrices outperform Hermitian ones. The theory can be used as a
model for predicting the benefits of deflation.
  Second, we use deflation in the context of a large scale application of
&quot;disconnected diagrams&quot; in Lattice QCD. On lattices, Hierarchical Probing (HP)
has previously provided an order of magnitude of variance reduction over MC by
removing &quot;error&quot; from neighboring nodes of increasing distance in the lattice.
Although deflation used directly on MC yields a limited improvement of 30% in
our problem, when combined with HP they reduce variance by a factor of over 60
compared to MC. For this, we pre-computated 1000 smallest singular values of an
ill-conditioned matrix of size 25 million. Using PRIMME and a domain-specific
Algebraic Multigrid preconditioner, we perform one of the largest eigenvalue
computations in Lattice QCD at a fraction of the cost of our trace computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04885</id><created>2016-04-17</created><updated>2017-01-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agundez</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>Charles D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollenberg</keyname><forenames>Lloyd C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogge</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaauboer</keyname><forenames>Miriam</forenames></author></authors><title>Superadiabatic quantum state transfer in spin chains</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>Final accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012317 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter we propose a superadiabatic protocol where quantum state
transfer can be achieved with arbitrarily high accuracy and minimal control
across long spin chains with an odd number of spins. The quantum state transfer
protocol only requires the control of the couplings between the qubits on the
edge and the spin chain. We predict fidelities above 0.99 for an evolution of
nanoseconds using typical spin exchange coupling values of {\mu}eV.
Furthermore, by building a superadiabatic formalism on top of this protocol, we
propose a effective superadiabatic protocol that retains the minimal control
over the spin chain and improves the fidelity by up to 20%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00841</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Illingworth</keyname><forenames>Garth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magee</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouwens</keyname><forenames>Rychard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oesch</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labbe</keyname><forenames>Ivo</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dokkum</keyname><forenames>Pieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitaker</keyname><forenames>Katherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holden</keyname><forenames>Bradford</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franx</keyname><forenames>Marijn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Valentino</forenames></author></authors><title>The Hubble Legacy Fields (HLF-GOODS-S) v1.5 Data Products: Combining
  2442 Orbits of GOODS-S/CDF-S Region ACS and WFC3/IR Images</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Version 1.5 release data can be found at:
  https://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/hlf/ 9 pages, 3 figures - minor update in
  number of orbits/exposures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have submitted to MAST the 1.5 version data release of the Hubble Legacy
Fields (HLF) project covering a 25 x 25 arcmin area over the GOODS-S (ECDF-S)
region from the HST archival program AR-13252. The release combines exposures
from Hubble's two main cameras, the Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS/WFC) and
the Wide Field Camera 3 (WFC3/IR), taken over more than a decade between
mid-2002 to the end of 2016. The HLF includes essentially all optical (ACS/WFC
F435W, F606W, F775W, F814W and F850LP filters) and infrared (WFC3/ IR F098M,
F105W, F125W, F140W and F160W filters) data taken by Hubble over the original
CDF-S region including the GOODS-S, ERS, CANDELS and many other programs (31 in
total). The data has been released at https://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/hlf/ as
images with a common astrometric reference frame, with corresponding inverse
variance weight maps. We provide one image per filter of WFC3/IR images at 60
mas per pixel resolution and two ACS/WFC images per filter, at both 30 and 60
mas per pixel. Since this comprehensive dataset combines data from 31 programs
on the GOODS-S/CDF-S, the AR proposal identified the MAST products by the
global name &quot;Hubble Legacy Field&quot;, with this region being identified by
&quot;HLF-GOODS-S&quot;. This dataset complements that of the Frontier Fields program.
The total incorporated in the HLF-GOODS-S is 5.8 Msec in 7211 exposures from
2442 orbits. This is ~70% of a HST full cycle!
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09090</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Mew-Bing</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of magnetic field topology in black hole-neutron star mergers:
  Long-term simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 17 figures. Version to appear in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 104013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.104013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report long-term simulations of black hole-neutron star binary mergers
where the neutron star possesses an asymmetric magnetic field dipole. Focusing
on the scenario where the neutron star is tidally disrupted by the black hole,
we track the evolution of the binary up to $\approx 100$ms after the merger. We
uncover more than one episode of thermally driven winds being launched along a
funnel wall in all these cases beginning from $\approx 25$ms after the merger.
On the other hand, we are unable to conclude presently whether the amount of
ejected mass increases with the \it{degree} of asymmetry. A large-scale
magnetic field configuration in the poloidal direction is formed along the
funnel wall accompanied by the generation of a large Poynting flux. The
magnetic field in the accretion disk around the black hole remnant is amplified
by the nonaxisymmetric magnetorotational instability (MRI). The MRI growth is
estimated to be in the ideal magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) regime and thus would
be free from significant effects induced by potential neutrino radiation.
However, the asymmetry in the magnetic field leads to increased turbulence,
which causes the vertical magnetic field in the accretion disk to grow largely
in a nonlinear manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00642</id><created>2016-07-03</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>W. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice Defects and the Mechanical Anisotropy of Borophene</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry C 121, 10224-10232, (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b02582</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using density functional theory combined with a semi-empirical van der Waals
dispersion correction, we have investigated the stability of lattice defects
including boron vacancy, substitutional and interstitial X (X=H, C, B, N, O)
and $\Sigma$5 tilt grain boundaries in borophene and their influence on the
anisotropic mechanical properties of this two-dimensional system. The pristine
borophene has significant in-plane Young's moduli and Poisson's ratio
anisotropy due to its strong and highly coordinated B-B bonds. The
concentration of B vacancy and $\Sigma$5 grain boundary could be rather high
given that their formation energies are as low as 0.10 eV and 0.06 eV/$\AA$
respectively. In addition, our results also suggest that borophene can react
easily with H$_2$, O$_2$ and N$_2$ when exposed to these molecules. We find
that the mechanical properties of borophene are remarkably degraded by these
defects. The anisotropy in Poisson's ratio, however, can be tuned by some of
them. Furthermore, the adsorbed H or substitutional C may induce remarkably
negative Poisson's ratio in borophene, and the substitutional C or N can
significantly increase the Poisson's ratio by contrast.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02811</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>Eric J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Fangzhao Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gadway</keyname><forenames>Bryce</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of the topological soliton state in the Su-Schrieffer-Heeger
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 13986 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13986</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH) model, which captures the most striking
transport properties of the conductive organic polymer $trans$-polyacetylene,
provides perhaps the most basic model system supporting topological
excitations. The alternating bond pattern of polyacetylene chains is captured
by the bipartite sublattice structure of the SSH model, emblematic of
one-dimensional chiral symmetric topological insulators. This structure
supports two distinct nontrivial topological phases, which, when interfaced
with one another or with a topologically trivial phase, give rise to
topologically-protected, dispersionless boundary states. Using $^{87}$Rb atoms
in a momentum-space lattice, we realize fully-tunable condensed matter
Hamiltonians, allowing us to probe the dynamics and equilibrium properties of
the SSH model. We report on the experimental quantum simulation of this model
and observation of the localized topological soliton state through quench
dynamics, phase-sensitive injection, and adiabatic preparation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08083</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pironneau</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames><affiliation>LJLL</affiliation></author></authors><title>An Energy stable Monolithic Eulerian Fluid-Structure Numerical Scheme *</title><categories>cs.CE cs.NA math.NA physics.flu-dyn</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conservation laws of continuum mechanic written in an Eulerian frame make
no difference between fluids and solids except in the expression of the stress
tensors, usually with Newton's hypothesis for the fluids and Helmholtz
potentials of energy for hyperelastic solids. By taking the velocities as
unknown , monolithic methods for fluid structure interactions (FSI) are built.
In this article such a formulation is analyzed when the fluid is compressible
and the fluid is incompressible. The idea is not new but the progress of mesh
generators and numerical schemes like the Characteristics-Galerkin method
render this approach feasible and reasonably robust. In this article the method
and its discretization are presented, stability is discussed by through an
energy estimate. A numerical section discusses implementation issues and
presents a few simple tests.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08866</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Navas-Portella</keyname><forenames>V&#xed;ctor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corral</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vives</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author></authors><title>Avalanches and force drops in displacement-driven compression of porous
  glasses</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E, 94 033005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.033005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Similarities between force-driven compression experiments of porous materials
and earthquakes have been recently proposed. In this manuscript, we measure the
acoustic emission during displacement-driven compression of a porous glass. The
energy of acoustic-emission events shows that the failure process exhibits
avalanche scale-invariance and therefore follows the Gutenberg-Richter law. The
resulting exponents do not exhibit significant differences with respect the
force-driven case. Furthermore, the force exhibits an avalanche-type behaviour
for which the force drops are power-law distributed and correlated with the
acoustic emission events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01070</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Uchino</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Transport in the Superfluid Fluctuation Regime</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 105303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.105303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by a recent experiment in ultracold atoms [ S. Krinner et al.,
Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A 113, 8144 (2016)], we analyze transport of
attractively interacting fermions through a one-dimensional wire near the
superfluid transition. We show that in a ballistic regime where the conductance
is quantized in the absence of interaction, the conductance is renormalized by
superfluid fluctuations in reservoirs. In particular, the particle conductance
is strongly enhanced and the plateau is blurred by emergent bosonic pair
transport. For spin transport, in addition to the contact resistance the wire
itself is resistive, leading to a suppression of the measured spin conductance.
Our results are qualitatively consistent with the experimental observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01914</id><created>2016-08-05</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Ruihua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Huitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author></authors><title>Out-of-Time-Order Correlation for Many-Body Localization</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Science Bulletin, 62 (10), 707-711 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.scib.2017.04.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we first compute the out-of-time-order correlators (OTOC) for
both a phenomenological model and a random-field XXZ model in the many-body
localized phase. We show that the OTOC decreases in power law in a many-body
localized system at the scrambling time. We also find that the OTOC can also be
used to distinguish a many-body localized phase from an Anderson localized
phase, while a normal correlator cannot. Furthermore, we prove an exact theorem
that relates the growth of the second R\'enyi entropy in the quench dynamics to
the decay of the OTOC in equilibrium. This theorem works for a generic quantum
system. We discuss various implications of this theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02473</id><created>2016-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Aramendia</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Handsteiner</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziarkash</keyname><forenames>Abdul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinlechner</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheidl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuentes</keyname><forenames>Ivette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pienaar</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ralph</keyname><forenames>Tim C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ursin</keyname><forenames>Rupert</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental test of photonic entanglement in accelerated reference
  frames</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/ncomms15304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantization of the electromagnetic field has successfully paved the way
for the development of the Standard Model of Particle Physics and has
established the basis for quantum technologies. Gravity, however, continues to
hold out against physicists' efforts of including it into the framework of
quantum theory. Experimental techniques in quantum optics have only recently
reached the precision and maturity required for the investigation of quantum
systems under the influence of gravitational fields. Here, we report on
experiments in which a genuine quantum state of an entangled photon pair was
exposed to a series of different accelerations. We measure an entanglement
witness for $g$ values ranging from 30 mg to up to 30 g - under free-fall as
well on a spinning centrifuge - and have thus derived an upper bound on the
effects of uniform acceleration on photonic entanglement. Our work represents
the first quantum optics experiment in which entanglement is systematically
tested in geodesic motion as well as in accelerated reference frames with
acceleration a&gt;&gt;g = 9.81 m/s^2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01076</id><created>2016-09-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Berman</keyname><forenames>O. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kezerashvili</keyname><forenames>R. Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lozovik</keyname><forenames>Y. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziegler</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensitive linear response of an electron-hole superfluid in a periodic
  potential</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 92, 1 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2017.05.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider excitons in a two-dimensional periodic potential and study the
linear response of the excitonic superfluid to an electromagnetic wave at low
and high densities. It turns out that the static structure factor for small
wavevectors is very sensitive to a change of density and temperature. It is a
consequence of the fact that thermal fluctuations play a crucial role at small
wavevectors, since exchanging the order of the two limits, zero temperature and
vanishing wavevector, leads to different results for the structure factor. This
effect could be used for high accuracy measurements in the superfluid exciton
phase, which might be realized by a gated electron-hole gas. The transition of
the exciton system from the superfluid state to a non-superfluid state and its
manifestation by light scattering are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03520</id><created>2016-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kurtev</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gromadzki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beamin</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Folkes</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez</keyname><forenames>K. Pena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>V. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borissova</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villanueva</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minniti</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>P. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinfield</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhn</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>H. R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yip</keyname><forenames>A. K. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>VVV High proper motion stars I. The catalogue of bright Ks &lt; 13.5 stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, accepted in the MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2357</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Knowledge of the stellar content near the Sun is important for a broad range
of topics ranging from the search for planets to the study of Milky Way
structure. The most powerful method for identifying potentially nearby stars is
proper motion (PM) surveys. All old optical surveys avoid, or are at least
substantially incomplete, near the Galactic plane. The depth and breadth of the
&quot;Vista Variables in Via Lactea&quot; (VVV) near-IR survey significantly improves
this situation. Taking advantage of the VVV survey database, we have measured
PMs in the densest regions of the MW bulge and southern plane in order to
complete the census of nearby objects. We have developed a custom PM pipeline
based on VVV catalogues from the Cambridge Astronomy Survey Unit (CASU), by
comparing the first epoch of JHKs with the multi-epoch Ks-bands acquired later.
Taking advantage of the large time baseline between the 2MASS and the VVV
observations, we also obtained 2MASS-VVV PMs. We present a near-IR proper
motion catalogue for the whole area of the VVV survey, which includes 3003
moving stellar sources. All of these have been visually inspected and are real
PM objects. Our catalogue is in very good agreement with the proper motion data
supplied in IR catalogues outside the densest zone of the MW. The majority of
the PM objects in our catalogue are nearby M-dwarfs, as expected. This new
database allow us to identify 57 common proper motion binary candidates, among
which are two new systems within ~30pc of the Sun.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04372</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aumont</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banfi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battistelli</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ba&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe9;lier</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernard</keyname><forenames>J. Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bersanelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bigot-Sazy</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleurvacq</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordier</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brossard</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunn</keyname><forenames>E. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzzelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cammilleri</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavaliere</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chanial</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapron</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coppi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coppolecchia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couchot</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Agostino</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Alessandro</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Bernardis</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Gasperis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Petris</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decourcelle</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Torto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumoulin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Etchegoyen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franceschet</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gault</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gayer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gervasi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghribi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giard</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giraud-H&#xe9;raud</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradziel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandsire</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamilton</keyname><forenames>J. Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harari</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haynes</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henrot-Versill&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holtzer</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaplan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamagna</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lande</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loucatos</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lowitz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukovic</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maffei</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marnieros</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martino</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>May</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCulloch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melhuish</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mennella</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montier</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xe9;el</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Sullivan</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paiella</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pajot</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passerini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelosi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perbost</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdereau</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piacentini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piat</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piccirillo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisano</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pr&#xea;le</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puddu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rambaud</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigaut</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salatino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schillaci</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scully</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolpovskiy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suarez</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tartari</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timbie</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tristram</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vigan&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittori</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zullo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>QUBIC Technical Design Report</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>139 pages ; high resolution version can be found on the qubic website
  (http://qubic.in2p3.fr/QUBIC/Home.html) minor changes : update author list &amp;
  affiliations ; correct title</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  QUBIC is an instrument aiming at measuring the B mode polarisation
anisotropies at medium scales angular scales (30-200 multipoles). The search
for the primordial CMB B-mode polarization signal is challenging, because of
many difficulties: smallness of the expected signal, instrumental systematics
that could possibly induce polarization leakage from the large E signal into B,
brighter than anticipated polarized foregrounds (dust) reducing to zero the
initial hope of finding sky regions clean enough to have a direct primordial
B-modes observation. The QUBIC instrument is designed to address all aspects of
this challenge with a novel kind of instrument, a Bolometric Interferometer,
combining the background-limited sensitivity of Transition-Edge-Sensors and the
control of systematics allowed by the observation of interference fringe
patterns, while operating at two frequencies to disentangle polarized
foregrounds from primordial B mode polarization. Its characteristics are
described in details in this Technological Design Report.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05039</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Couzens</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric AdS$_{5}$ solutions of type IIB supergravity without D3
  branes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages; v2 references added, minor change to conclusion</comments><report-no>KCL-MTH-16-06</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 01 (2017) 041</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the most general bosonic supersymmetric solutions of type IIB
supergravity whose metrics are warped products of five-dimensional anti-de
Sitter space (AdS$_5$) with a five-dimensional Riemannian manifold $M_{5}$,
where the five-form flux vanishes, while all remaining fluxes are allowed to be
non-vanishing consistent with SO(4,2) symmetry. This completes the program of
classifying all supersymmetric solutions of ten and eleven-dimensional
supergravity with an AdS$_5$ factor. We investigate the supersymmetry
conditions in some special cases, and demonstrate how these are satisfied by a
solution originally found in arXiv:1410.2650[hep-th], utilising the method of
non-Abelian T-duality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05910</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Korzekwa</keyname><forenames>Kamil</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of the thermodynamic arrow of time in classical and quantum
  theories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures. Published version. Expanded discussion and a
  new section on history erasure process added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 052318 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052318</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we analyse the structure of the thermodynamic arrow of time,
defined by transformations that leave the thermal equilibrium state unchanged,
in classical (incoherent) and quantum (coherent) regimes. We note that in the
infinite-temperature limit the thermodynamic ordering of states in both regimes
exhibits a lattice structure. This means that when energy does not matter and
the only thermodynamic resource is given by information, the thermodynamic
arrow of time has a very specific structure. Namely, for any two states at
present there exists a unique state in the past consistent with them and with
all possible joint pasts. Similarly, there also exists a unique state in the
future consistent with those states and with all possible joint futures. We
also show that the lattice structure in the classical regime is broken at
finite temperatures, i.e., when energy is a relevant thermodynamic resource.
Surprisingly, however, we prove that in the simplest quantum scenario of a
two-dimensional system, this structure is preserved at finite temperatures. We
provide the physical interpretation of these results by introducing and
analysing the history erasure process, and point out that quantum coherence may
be a necessary resource for the existence of an optimal erasure process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07774</id><created>2016-09-25</created><updated>2017-02-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wootton</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Demonstrating non-Abelian braiding of surface code defects in a five
  qubit experiment</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, Volume 2, Number 1 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa5c73</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Currently, the mainstream approach to quantum computing is through surface
codes. One way to store and manipulate quantum information with these to create
defects in the codes which can be moved and used as if they were particles.
Specifically, they simulate the behaviour of exotic particles known as
Majoranas, which are a kind of non-Abelian anyon. By exchanging these
particles, important gates for quantum computation can be implemented. Here we
investigate the simplest possible exchange operation for two surface code
Majoranas. This is found to act non-trivially on only five qubits. The system
is then truncated to these five qubits, so that the exchange process can be run
on the IBM 5Q processor. The results demonstrate the expected effect of the
exchange. This paper has been written in a style that should hopefully be
accessible to both professional and amateur scientists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08104</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2016-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Gil-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Ko-Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efetov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Di S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hart</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yacoby</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author></authors><title>Inducing Superconducting Correlation in Quantum Hall Edge States</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/nphys4084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum Hall (QH) effect supports a set of chiral edge states at the
boundary of a 2-dimensional electron gas (2DEG) system. A superconductor (SC)
contacting these states induces correlation of the quasi-particles in the
dissipationless 1D chiral QH edge states. If the superconducting electrode is
narrower than the superconducting coherence length, the incoming electron are
correlated to outgoing hole along the chiral edge state by the Andreev process.
In order to realize this crossed Andreev conversion (CAC), it is necessary to
fabricate highly transparent and nanometer-scale superconducting junctions to
QH system. Here we report the observation of CAC in a graphene QH system
contacted with a nanostructured NbN superconducting electrode. The chemical
potential of the edge states across the superconducting electrode exhibits a
sign reversal, providing direct evidence of CAC. This hybrid SC/QH system is a
novel route to create isolated non-Abelian anyonic zero modes, in resonance
with the chiral QH edge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09064</id><created>2016-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Wen-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Bao-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Liu-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Wei-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanihata</keyname><forenames>Isao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Guang-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xue-Heng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Li-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Li-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Rong-Jiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chen-Gui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Pei-Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Li-Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shi-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Duo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Plastic scintillation detectors for precision time-of-flight
  measurements of relativistic heavy ions</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C 41 (2017) 066001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/6/066001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plastic scintillation detectors for Time-of-Flight (TOF) measurements are
almost essential for event-by-event identification of relativistic rare
isotopes. In this work, a pair of plastic scintillation detectors of 50
$\times$ 50 $\times$ 3$^{t}$ mm$^3$ and 80 $\times$ 100 $\times$ 3$^{t}$ mm$^3$
have been set up at the external target facility (ETF), Institute of Modern
Physics. Their time, energy and position responses are measured with $^{18}$O
primary beam at 400 MeV/nucleon. After the off-line walk-effect and position
corrections, the time resolution of the two detectors are determined to be 27
ps ($\sigma$) and 36 ps ($\sigma$), respectively. Both detectors have nearly
the same energy resolution of 3$\%$ ($\sigma$) and position resolution of 2 mm
($\sigma$). The detectors have been used successfully in nuclear reaction cross
section measurements, and will be be employed for upgrading RIBLL2 beam line at
IMP as well as for the high energy branch at HIAF.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02783</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Ahmad R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shemesh</keyname><forenames>Noam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lund</keyname><forenames>Torben E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangill</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eskildsen</keyname><forenames>Simon F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd8;stergaard</keyname><forenames>Leif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jespersen</keyname><forenames>Sune N.</forenames></author></authors><title>White matter biomarkers from fast protocols using axially symmetric
  diffusion kurtosis imaging</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, 8 figures, 1 table, 3 supplementary figures</comments><doi>10.1002/nbm.3741</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  White matter tract integrity (WMTI) can characterize brain microstructure in
areas with highly aligned fiber bundles. Several WMTI biomarkers have now been
validated against microscopy and provided promising results in studies of brain
development and aging, and in a number of brain disorders. Currently, WMTI is
mostly used in dedicated animal studies and clinical studies of slowly
progressing diseases but has not yet emerged as a routine clinical tool. To
this end, a less data intensive experimental method would be beneficial by
enabling high resolution validation studies, and ease clinical applications by
speeding up data acquisition compared to typical diffusion kurtosis imaging
(DKI) protocols utilized as part of WMTI imaging. Here, we evaluate WMTI based
on recently introduced axially symmetric DKI which has lower data demand than
conventional DKI. We compare WMTI parameters derived from conventional DKI to
those calculated analytically from axially symmetric DKI. We employ numerical
simulations, as well as data from fixed rat spinal cord (1) and in vivo human
(3) and rat brain (4). Our analysis shows that analytical WMTI based on axially
symmetric DKI with sparse data sets (19 images) produces WMTI metrics that
correlate strongly with estimates based on traditional DKI data sets (60 images
or more). We demonstrate the preclinical potential of the proposed WMTI
technique in in vivo rat brain (300 {\mu}m isotropic resolution with whole
brain coverage). WMTI parameter estimates are subject to a duality leading to
two solution branches dependent on a sign choice which is currently debated.
Results from both of these branches are presented and discussed throughout our
analysis. The proposed fast WMTI approach may be useful for preclinical
research and e.g. clinical evaluation of patients with traumatic white matter
injuries or symptoms of neurovascular or neuroinflammatory disorders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02969</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Wenda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jeongwoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Hugh S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gary</keyname><forenames>Dale E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jiasheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Haimin</forenames></author></authors><title>Flare differentially rotates sunspot on Sun's surface</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures, published in Nature Communications under a
  Creative Commons license; typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7, 13104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sunspots are concentrations of magnetic field visible on the solar surface
(photosphere). It was considered implausible that solar flares, as resulted
from magnetic reconnection in the tenuous corona, would cause a direct
perturbation of the dense photosphere involving bulk motion. Here we report the
sudden flare-induced rotation of a sunspot using the unprecedented
spatiotemporal resolution of the 1.6 m New Solar Telescope, supplemented by
magnetic data from the Solar Dynamics Observatory. It is clearly observed that
the rotation is non-uniform over the sunspot: as the flare ribbon sweeps
across, its different portions accelerate (up to 50 deg per hr) at different
times corresponding to peaks of flare hard X-ray emission. The rotation may be
driven by the surface Lorentz-force change due to the back reaction of coronal
magnetic restructuring and is accompanied by a downward Poynting flux. These
results have direct consequences for our understanding of energy and momentum
transportation in the flare-related phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04512</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>K. Rama Koteswara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suter</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Dynamics of a two-level system of a single spin driven beyond
  the rotating-wave approximation</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053804 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum systems driven by strong oscillating fields are the source of many
interesting physical phenomena. In this work, we experimentally study the
dynamics of a two-level system of a single spin driven in the strong-driving
regime where the rotating-wave approximation is not valid. This two-level
system is a subsystem of a single Nitrogen-Vacancy center coupled to a
first-shell $^{13}$C nuclear spin in diamond at a level anti-crossing point
that occurs in the $m_{s}=\pm1$ manifold when the energy level splitting
between the $m_{s}$ = $+1$ and $-1$ spin states due to the static magnetic
field is $\approx$ 127 MHz, which is roughly equal to the spectral splitting
due to the $^{13}$C hyperfine interaction. The transition frequency of this
electron spin two-level system in a static magnetic field of 28.9 G is 1.7 MHz
and it can be driven only by the $z$-component of the RF field. Electron spin
Rabi frequencies in this system can reach tens of MHz even for moderate RF
powers. The simple sinusoidal Rabi oscillations that occur when the amplitude
of the driving field is much smaller than the transition frequency become
complex when the driving field strength is comparable or greater than the
energy level splitting. We observe that the system oscillates faster than the
amplitude of the driving field and the response of the system shows multiple
frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05048</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodkin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goryaev</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibb</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slemzin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shugay</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veselovsky</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackay</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin and Ion Charge State Evolution of Solar Wind Transients during 4
  -- 7 August 2011</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Title and abstract changed, figure 4c modified, figures' and tables'
  captions changed, Equations 5-7 modified, proofread was made, text revised
  (p.2,3,4,5,7,8,24,26). The final publication is available at Springer</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-017-1109-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present study of the complex event consisting of several solar wind
transients detected by Advanced Composition Explorer (ACE) on 4 -- 7 August
2011, that caused a geomagnetic storm with Dst$=-$110 nT. The supposed coronal
sources -- three flares and coronal mass ejections (CMEs) occurred on 2 -- 4
August 2011 in the active region (AR) 11261. To investigate the solar origin
and formation of these transients we studied kinematic and thermodynamic
properties of the expanding coronal structures using the Solar Dynamics
Observatory/Atmospheric Imaging Assembly (SDO/AIA) EUV images and the
differential emission measure (DEM) diagnostics. The Helioseismic and Magnetic
Imager (HMI) magnetic field maps were used as the input data for the 3D
magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) model to describe the flux rope ejection. We
characterize the early phase of the flux rope ejection in the corona, where the
usual three-component CME structure formed. The flux rope ejected with a speed
of about 200~km~s$^{-1}$ to the height of 0.25~R$_{\odot}$. The kinematics of
the modeled CME front agrees well with the Solar Terrestrial Relations
Observatory (STEREO) EUV measurements. Using the results of the plasma
diagnostics and MHD modeling, we calculated the ion charge ratios of carbon and
oxygen as well as the mean charge state of iron ions of the 2 August 2011 CME,
taking into account the processes of heating, cooling, expansion, ionization,
and recombination of the moving plasma in the corona up to the frozen-in
region. We estimated a probable heating rate of the CME plasma in the low
corona by matching the calculated ion composition parameters of the CME with
those measured in situ for the solar wind transients. We also consider the
similarities and discrepancies between the results of the MHD simulation and
the observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06124</id><created>2016-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Rougemont</keyname><forenames>Romulo</forenames><affiliation>Sao Paulo U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Holographic black hole engineering at finite baryon chemical potential</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, contribution to the proceedings of Hot Quarks
  2016 conference at South Padre Island, TX, USA</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 832 (2017) no.1, 012048</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/832/1/012048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a contribution for the Proceedings of the Conference Hot Quarks 2016,
held at South Padre Island, Texas, USA, 12-17 September 2016. I briefly review
some thermodynamic and baryon transport results obtained from a bottom-up
Einstein-Maxwell-Dilaton holographic model engineered to describe the physics
of the quark-gluon plasma at finite temperature and baryon density. The results
for the equation of state, baryon susceptibilities, and the curvature of the
crossover band are in quantitative agreement with the corresponding lattice QCD
results with $2+1$ flavors and physical quark masses. Baryon diffusion is
predicted to be suppressed by increasing the baryon chemical potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07006</id><created>2016-10-22</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Woo</keyname><forenames>Seungchan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>Hongki</forenames></author></authors><title>Large negative transconductance in multilayer graphene: The role of
  intersubband scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4, 025090 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa6e33</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the transport properties of multilayer graphene, considering the
effect of multisubband scattering in a high density regime, where higher
subbands are occupied by charge carriers. To calculate the conductivity of
multilayer graphene, we use the coupled multiband Boltzmann transport theory
while fully incorporating the multiband scattering effects. We show that the
allowed scattering channels, screening effects, chiral nature of the electronic
structure, and type of impurity scatterings determine the transport behavior of
multilayer graphene. We find that the conductivity of multilayer graphene shows
a sudden change when the carriers begin to occupy the higher subbands, and
therefore a large negative transconductance (NTC) appears as the carrier
density varies. These phenomena arise mostly from the intersubband scattering
and the change in the density of states at the band touching density. Based on
our results, it is possible to build novel devices utilizing the large NTC in
multilayer graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07069</id><created>2016-10-22</created><updated>2017-02-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;vg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking radiation of scalar and vector particles from 5D Myers-Perry
  black holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, Accepted for publication in International Journal of
  Theoretical Physics</comments><journal-ref>Int J Theor Phys (2017) 56: 1725</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-017-3317-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper we explore the Hawking radiation as a quantum tunneling
effect from a rotating 5 dimensional Myers-Perry black hole (5D-MPBH) with two
independent angular momentum components. First, we investigate the Hawking
temperature by considering the tunneling of massive scalar particles and spin-1
vector particles from the 5D-MPBH in the Painlev\'{e} coordinates and then in
the corotating frames. More specifically, we solve the Klein-Gordon and Proca
equations by applying the WKB method and Hamilton-Jacobi equation in both
cases. Finally, we recover the Hawking temperature and show that coordinates
systems do not affect the Hawking temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08240</id><created>2016-10-26</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kesaev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiselev</keyname><forenames>Alexei D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pozhidaev</keyname><forenames>Evgeny P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation of unpolarized light in planar aligned subwavelength-pitch
  deformed-helix ferroelectric liquid crystals</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures, revised version. arXiv admin note: text overlap
  with arXiv:1508.04964</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 032705 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.032705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the electro-optic properties of subwavelength-pitch deformed-helix
ferroelectric liquid crystals (DHFLC) illuminated with unpolarized light. In
the experimental setup based on the Mach-Zehnder interferometer, it was
observed that the reference and the sample beams being both unpolarized produce
the interference pattern which is insensitive to rotation of in-plane optical
axes of the DHFLC cell. We find that the field-induced shift of the
interference fringes can be described in terms of the electrically dependent
Pancharatnam relative phase determined by the averaged phase shift, whereas the
visibility of the fringes is solely dictated by the phase retardation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08707</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tajahmad</keyname><forenames>Behzad</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solutions of an anisotropic universe in a modified teleparallel
  gravity model via the Noether and B.N.S. approaches</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1610.08099</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present the Noether symmetries of locally rotationally
symmetric Bianchi type I (LRS BI), an anisotropic model, in the context of the
teleparallel gravity. We study a certain modified teleparallel theory based on
the action that, in particular, contains a coupling between the scalar field
and field strength (magnetism part). We derive the symmetry generators and show
that, by means of cyclic variables approach, we can not obtain a suitable
solution for field equations. Hence by the use of B.N.S. approach, we solve the
equations which carry Noether currents as well. By data analysis of the
obtained results, we show compatible results with observational data at the
last half the age of universe which is accelerating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09551</id><created>2016-10-29</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the mass difference between top quark and antiquark in pp
  collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference. All
  figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/TOP-12-031/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-TOP-12-031, CERN-EP-2016-249</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 770 (2017) 50</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The invariance of the standard model (SM) under the CPT transformation
predicts equality of particle and antiparticle masses. This prediction is
tested by measuring the mass difference between the top quark and antiquark
(Delta m[t] = m[t] - m[t-bar]) that are produced in pp collisions at a
center-of-mass energy of 8 TeV, using events with a muon or an electron and at
least four jets in the final state. The analysis is based on data corresponding
to an integrated luminosity of 19.6 inverse femtobarns collected by the CMS
experiment at the LHC, and yields a value of Delta m[t] = -0.15 +/- 0.19 (stat)
+/- 0.09 (syst) GeV, which is consistent with the SM expectation. This result
is significantly more precise than previously reported measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00773</id><created>2016-11-02</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barger</keyname><forenames>Vernon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basso</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keung</keyname><forenames>Wai-Yee</forenames></author></authors><title>PeV Neutrino Events at IceCube from Single Top-Quark Production</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>A final updated version in parallel with the one published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 093002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.093002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deep inelastic scattering of very high-energy neutrinos can potentially be
enhanced by the production of a single top quark or charm quark via the
interaction of a virtual $W$-boson exchange with a $b$-quark or $s$-quark
parton in the nucleon. The single top contribution shows a sharp rise at
neutrino energies above 0.5 PeV and gives a cross-section contribution of order
5 percent at 10 PeV, while single charm has a low energy threshold and
contributes about 25 percent. Semi-leptonic decays of top and charm give
di-muon events whose kinematic characteristics are shown. The angular
separation of the di-muons from heavy quark production in the IceCube detector
can reach up to one degree. Top quark production has a unique, but rare, three
muon signal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06707</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-05-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schaefer</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tal-Ezer</keyname><forenames>Hillel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosloff</keyname><forenames>Ronnie</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-global approach for propagation of the time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger
  equation for time-dependent and nonlinear problems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>76 pages</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2017.04.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed exposition of highly efficient and accurate method for the
propagation of the time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation is presented. The
method is readily generalized to solve an arbitrary set of ODE's. The
propagation is based on a global approach, in which large time-intervals are
treated as a whole, replacing the local considerations of the common
propagators. The new method is suitable for various classes of problems,
including problems with a time-dependent Hamiltonian, nonlinear problems,
non-Hermitian problems and problems with an inhomogeneous source term. In this
paper, a thorough presentation of the basic principles of the propagator is
given. We give also a special emphasis on the details of the numerical
implementation of the method. For the first time, we present the application
for a non-Hermitian problem by a numerical example of a one-dimensional atom
under the influence of an intense laser field. The efficiency of the method is
demonstrated by a comparison with the common Runge-Kutta approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07263</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-04-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Puhr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buividovich</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A numerical study of non-perturbative corrections to the Chiral
  Separation Effect in quenched finite-density QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>6 + 2 pages, 3 figures, 1 table, REVTeX style, conclusion changed due
  to results from simulations with larger lattices, accepted for publication in
  PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 192003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.192003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the non-renormalization of the Chiral Separation Effect (CSE)
in quenched finite-density QCD in both confinement and deconfinement phases
using a recently developed numerical method which allows, for the first time,
to address the transport properties of exactly chiral, dense lattice fermions.
This finding suggests that CSE can be used to fix renormalization constants for
axial current density. Explaining the suppression of the CSE which we observe
for topologically nontrivial gauge field configurations on small lattices, we
also argue that CSE vanishes for self-dual non-Abelian fields inside instanton
cores.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07969</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mrozinski</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buachalla</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;amonn &#xd3;</forenames></author></authors><title>A Borel-Weil Theorem for the Quantum Grassmannians</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish a noncommutative generalisation of the Borel-Weil theorem for
the Heckenberger-Kolb calculus of the quantum Grassmannians. The result is
presented in the framework of noncommutative complex and holomorphic structures
and generalises previous work of a number of authors on quantum projective
space. As a direct consequence we get a novel holomorphic presentation of the
twisted Grassmannian coordinate ring studied in noncommutative algebraic
geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00112</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stanley</keyname><forenames>Jacob T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewandowski</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recommendations for the use of notebooks in upper-division physics lab
  courses</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The use of lab notebooks for scientific documentation is a ubiquitous part of
physics research. However, it is common for undergraduate physics laboratory
courses not to emphasize the development of documentation skills, despite the
fact that such courses are some of the earliest opportunities for students to
start engaging in this practice. One potential impediment to the inclusion of
explicit documentation training is that it may be unclear to instructors which
features of authentic documentation practice are efficacious to teach and how
to incorporate these features into the lab class environment. In this work, we
outline some of the salient features of authentic documentation, informed by
interviews with physics researchers, and provide recommendations for how these
can be incorporated into the lab curriculum. We do not focus on structural
details or templates for notebooks. Instead, we address holistic considerations
for the purpose of scientific documentation that can guide students to develop
their own documentation style. Taking into consideration all the aspects that
can help improve students' documentation, it is also important to consider the
design of the lab activities themselves. Students should have experience with
implementing these authentic features of documentation during lab activities in
order for them to find practice with documentation beneficial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01644</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Primulando</keyname><forenames>Reinard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uttayarat</keyname><forenames>Patipan</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Lepton Flavor Violation at the 13 TeV LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>29 + 3 pages, 23 figures. Version 2 expanded discussion of low energy
  constraints and added more references. Matched the JHEP version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the bounds on tau-mu lepton flavor violation (LFV). Our main
focus is on the collider constrains on tau-mu LFV. We use the Type-III
Two-Higgs-Doublet-Model (2HDM) as a set up for our study. While the LFV
branching fraction of the 125 GeV is well constrained by current LHC searches,
the heavier neutral states could have a large branching fraction to tau and
muon. We estimate the LHC reach for the 13 TeV center of mass energy with 300
$\text{fb}^{-1}$ luminosity for a neutral boson decaying into a tau and a muon.
We identify parts of the LFV parameter space where the searches for heavy
scalar and pseudoscalar decaying into a tau and a muon are more sensitive than
the similar search for the 125 GeV boson.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04852</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>Andrew K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Kim G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hedegaard</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paaske</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>Kondo blockade due to quantum interference in single-molecule junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages with 5 figures + supplementary information (11 pages with 2
  figures)</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV CMT 2017</report-no><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 8, 15210 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15210</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular electronics offers unique scientific and technological
possibilities, resulting from both the nanometre scale of the devices and their
reproducible chemical complexity. Two fundamental yet different effects, with
no classical analogue, have been demonstrated experimentally in single-molecule
junctions: quantum interference due to competing electron transport pathways,
and the Kondo effect due to entanglement from strong electronic interactions.
Here we unify these phenomena, showing that transport through a spin-degenerate
molecule can be either enhanced or blocked by Kondo correlations, depending on
molecular structure, contacting geometry and applied gate voltages. An exact
framework is developed, in terms of which the quantum interference properties
of interacting molecular junctions can be systematically studied and
understood. We prove that an exact Kondo-mediated conductance node results from
destructive interference in exchange-cotunneling. Nonstandard temperature
dependences and gate-tunable conductance peaks/nodes are demonstrated for
prototypical molecular junctions, illustrating the intricate interplay of
quantum effects beyond the single-orbital paradigm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05075</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yunan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engquist</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junzhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Froese</keyname><forenames>Brittany D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of Optimal Transport and the Quadratic Wasserstein Metric to
  Full-Waveform Inversion</title><categories>physics.geo-ph math.NA</categories><comments>30 pages, 51 figures, 2nd version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conventional full-waveform inversion (FWI) using the least-squares norm
($L^2$) as a misfit function is known to suffer from cycle skipping. This
increases the risk of computing a local rather than the global minimum of the
misfit. In our previous work, we proposed the quadratic Wasserstein metric
($W_2$) as a new misfit function for FWI. The $W_2$ metric has been proved to
have many ideal properties with regards to convexity and insensitivity to
noise. When the observed and predicted seismic data are regarded as two density
functions, the quadratic Wasserstein metric corresponds to the optimal cost of
rearranging one density into the other, where the transportation cost is
quadratic in distance. The difficulty of transforming seismic signals into
nonnegative density functions is discussed. Unlike the $L^2$ norm, $W_2$
measures not only amplitude differences, but also global phase shifts, which
helps to avoid cycle skipping issues. In this work, we build on our earlier
method to cover more realistic high-resolution applications by embedding the
$W_2$ technique into the framework of the adjoint-state method and applying it
to seismic relevant 2D examples: the Camembert, the Marmousi, and the 2004 BP
models. We propose a new way of using the $W_2$ metric trace-by-trace in FWI
and compare it to global $W_2$ via the solution of the Monge-Amp\`ere equation.
With corresponding adjoint source, the velocity model can be updated using the
l-BFGS method. Numerical results show the effectiveness of $W_2$ for
alleviating cycle skipping issues and sensitivity to noise. Both mathematical
theory and numerical examples demonstrate that the quadratic Wasserstein metric
is a good candidate for a misfit function in seismic inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05825</id><created>2016-12-17</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jianyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakurathi</keyname><forenames>Manisha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Manish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Diptiman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density functional theory of the fractional quantum Hall effect</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 196802 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.196802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A conceptual difficulty in formulating the density functional theory of the
fractional quantum Hall effect is that while in the standard approach the
Kohn-Sham orbitals are either fully occupied or unoccupied, the physics of the
fractional quantum Hall effect calls for fractionally occupied Kohn-Sham
orbitals. This has necessitated averaging over an ensemble of Slater
determinants to obtain meaningful results. We develop an alternative approach
in which we express and minimize the grand canonical potential in terms of the
composite fermion variables. This provides a natural resolution of the
fractional-occupation problem because the fully occupied orbitals of composite
fermions automatically correspond to fractionally occupied orbitals of
electrons. We demonstrate the quantitative validity of our approach by
evaluating the density profile of fractional Hall edge as a function of
temperature and the distance from the delta dopant layer and showing that it
reproduces edge reconstruction in the expected parameter region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08294</id><created>2016-12-25</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Conde</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Pujian</forenames></author></authors><title>BMS Supertranslations and Not So Soft Gravitons</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>v2: 26 pages, moderate revision with corrections and clarifications,
  refs added</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 05 (2017) 060</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous article, we have argued that Low's sub-leading soft photon
theorem can be recovered as a Ward identity associated to the same large gauge
transformations that control the leading piece of the theorem. The key for that
was to link the energy expansion displayed in the soft theorem to a
$\frac{1}{r}$ expansion that we can perform in the associated asymptotic
charge. We expect this idea to be valid in general, and here we provide
compelling evidence for it by showing how the same method works in the case of
Einstein-Hilbert gravity. More precisely, we are able to derive the three
orders of the tree-level soft graviton theorem simply from the BMS
supertranslation charge, known to give rise to the leading soft graviton
theorem. In particular, we do not need to invoke superrotations (nor extended
superrotations) at any point of the argument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02175</id><created>2017-01-09</created><updated>2017-01-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Lauren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation leptogenesis, isocurvature perturbations, and the cosmic
  infrared background</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>35 pages, 16 figures; Improved calculation of baryon density
  contrast. Added Appendix B</comments><report-no>UMN-TH-3615/16, FTPI-MINN-16/35</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 103006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.103006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observations of cosmic infrared background (CIB) radiation exhibit
significant fluctuations on small angular scales. A number of explanations have
been put forth, but there is currently no consensus on the origin of these
large fluctuations. We consider the possibility that small-scale fluctuations
in matter-antimatter asymmetry could lead to variations in star formation rates
which are responsible for the CIB fluctuations. We show that the recently
proposed Higgs relaxation leptogenesis mechanism can produce such small-scale
baryonic isocurvature perturbations which can explain the observed excess in
the CIB fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04844</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Dong-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiaopeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>S. Das</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Entanglement in Neural Network States</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures. Version published in Phys. Rev. X</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Machine learning, one of today's most rapidly growing interdisciplinary
fields, promises an unprecedented perspective for solving intricate quantum
many-body problems. Understanding the physical aspects of the representative
artificial neural-network states is recently becoming highly desirable in the
applications of machine learning techniques to quantum many-body physics. Here,
we study the quantum entanglement properties of neural-network states, with a
focus on the restricted-Boltzmann-machine (RBM) architecture. We prove that the
entanglement of all short-range RBM states satisfies an area law for arbitrary
dimensions and bipartition geometry. For long-range RBM states we show by using
an exact construction that such states could exhibit volume-law entanglement,
implying a notable capability of RBM in representing efficiently quantum states
with massive entanglement. We further examine generic RBM states with random
weight parameters. We find that their averaged entanglement entropy obeys
volume-law scaling and meantime strongly deviates from the Page-entropy of the
completely random pure states. We show that their entanglement spectrum has no
universal part associated with random matrix theory and bears a Poisson-type
level statistics. Using reinforcement learning, we demonstrate that RBM is
capable of finding the ground state (with power-law entanglement) of a model
Hamiltonian with long-range interaction. In addition, we show, through a
concrete example of the one-dimensional symmetry-protected topological cluster
states, that the RBM representation may also be used as a tool to analytically
compute the entanglement spectrum. Our results uncover the unparalleled power
of artificial neural networks in representing quantum many-body states, which
paves a novel way to bridge computer science based machine learning techniques
to outstanding quantum condensed matter physics problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05263</id><created>2017-01-18</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fuks</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comprehensive Framework for Studying $W'$ and $Z'$ Bosons at Hadron
  Colliders with Automated Jet Veto Resummation</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Journal version (very minor changes and updated references).
  FeynRules files available from:
  http://feynrules.irmp.ucl.ac.be/wiki/WZPrimeAtNLO</comments><report-no>IPPP/17/1</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 05 (2017) 032</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of high-mass, color-singlet particles in hadron colliders is
universally accompanied by initial state QCD radiation that is predominantly
soft with respect to the hard process scale $Q$ and/or collinear with respect
to the beam axis. At TeV-scale colliders, this is in contrast to top quark and
multijet processes, which, by definition, are hard and central. Consequently,
vetoing events with jets possessing transverse momenta above $p_T^{\rm Veto}$
in searches for new color-singlet states can efficiently reduce non-singlet
backgrounds, thereby increasing experimental sensitivity. To quantify this
generic observation, we investigate the production and leptonic decay of a
Sequential Standard Model $W'$ boson at the 13 TeV LHC. We systematically
consider signal and background processes at next-to-leading-order (NLO) in QCD
with parton shower (PS) matching; for color-singlet channels, we resum Sudakov
logarithms of the form $\alpha_s^j(p_T^{\rm Veto})\log^k(Q/p_T^{\rm Veto})$ up
to next-to-next-to-leading logarithmic accuracy (NNLL) with NLO matching. We
obtain our results using the MadGraph5aMC@NLO and MadGraph5aMC@NLO-SCET
frameworks, respectively. Associated FeynRules model files capable of handling
NLO+PS- and NLO+NNLL-accurate computations are publicly available. We find that
within their given uncertainties, both the NLO+PS and NLO+NNLL(veto)
calculations give accurate and consistent predictions. Consequently, jet vetoes
applied to color-singlet processes can be reliably modeled at the NLO+PS level.
With respect to a $b$-jet veto of $p_{T}^{\rm Veto} = 30$ GeV, flavor-agnostic
vetoes of $p_{T}^{\rm Veto} = 30-40$ GeV can further reduce single top and
$t\overline{t}$ rates by a factor of 2-50 at a mild cost of the signal rate.
Jet vetoes can increase signal-to-noise ratios by roughly 10\% for light $W'$
boson masses of 30-50 GeV and 25\%-250\% for masses of 300-800 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05883</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pappalardi</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russomanno</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>Rosario</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipartite entanglement after a quantum quench</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures, un-copyedited version of the article published
  in Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 053104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa6809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the multipartite entanglement of a quantum many-body system
undergoing a quantum quench. We quantify multipartite entanglement through the
quantum Fisher information (QFI) density and we are able to express it after a
quench in terms of a generalized response function. For pure state initial
conditions and in the thermodynamic limit, we can express the QFI as the
fluctuations of an observable computed in the so-called diagonal ensemble. We
apply the formalism to the dynamics of a quantum Ising chain after a quench in
the transverse field. In this model the asymptotic state is, in almost all
cases, more than two-partite entangled. Moreover, starting from the
ferromagnetic phase, we find a divergence of multipartite entanglement for
small quenches closely connected to a corresponding divergence of the
correlation length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05906</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorek</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dragan</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omar</keyname><forenames>Yasser</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of acceleration on localized fermionic Gaussian states: from
  vacuum entanglement to maximally entangled states</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>Published version (minor typos fixed)</comments><report-no>LMU-ASC 03/17</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 076004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.076004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of acceleration on fermionic Gaussian states of
localized modes of a Dirac field. We consider two wave-packets in a Gaussian
state and transform these to an accelerated frame of reference. In particular,
we formulate the action of this transformation as a fermionic quantum channel.
Having developed the general framework for fermions, we then investigate the
entanglement of the vacuum, as well as the entanglement in Bell states. We find
that with increasing acceleration vacuum entanglement increases, while the
entanglement of Bell states decreases. Notably, our results have an immediate
operational meaning given the localization of the modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08620</id><created>2017-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bowman</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harte</keyname><forenames>T. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chardonnet</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Groot</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denny</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goc</keyname><forenames>G. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cassettari</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruce</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-fidelity phase and amplitude control of phase-only computer
  generated holograms using conjugate gradient minimisation</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Opt. Express 25,11692-11700 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.011692</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate simultaneous control of both the phase and amplitude of light
using a conjugate gradient minimisation-based hologram calculation technique
and a single phase-only spatial light modulator (SLM). A cost function which
incorporates the inner product of the light field with a chosen target field
within a defined measure region is efficiently minimised to create high
fidelity patterns in the Fourier plane of the SLM. A fidelity of $F=0.999997$
is achieved for a pattern resembling an $LG^{0}_{1}$ mode with a calculated
light-usage efficiency of $41.5\%$. Possible applications of our method in
optical trapping and ultracold atoms are presented and we show uncorrected
experimental realisation of our patterns with $F = 0.97$ and $7.8\%$ light
efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01709</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bomben</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire et de Hautes &#xc9;nergies</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ducourthial</keyname><forenames>Audrey</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire et de Hautes &#xc9;nergies</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bagolini</keyname><forenames>Alvise</forenames><affiliation>Fondazione Bruno Kessler, Centro per i Materiali e i Microsistemi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boscardin</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames><affiliation>Fondazione Bruno Kessler, Centro per i Materiali e i Microsistemi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bosisio</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames><affiliation>Universit&#xe0; di Trieste, Dipartimento di Fisica and INFN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Calderini</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire et de Hautes &#xc9;nergies</affiliation></author><author><keyname>D'Eramo</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire et de Hautes &#xc9;nergies</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Giacomini</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames><affiliation>Brookhaven National Laboratory, Instrumentation Division 535B, with Fondazione Bruno Kessler, Centro per i Materiali e i Microsistemi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Marchiori</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames><affiliation>Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire et de Hautes &#xc9;nergies</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames><affiliation>Fondazione Bruno Kessler, Centro per i Materiali e i Microsistemi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rummler</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames><affiliation>LAPP, CNRS/IN2P3 and Universit&#xe9; Savoie Mont Blanc</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Weingarten</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames><affiliation>II Physikalisches Institut</affiliation></author></authors><title>Performance of active edge pixel sensors</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>JINST 12 P05006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/12/05/P05006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To cope with the High Luminosity LHC harsh conditions, the ATLAS inner
tracker has to be upgraded to meet requirements in terms of radiation hardness,
pile up and geometrical acceptance. The active edge technology allows to reduce
the insensitive area at the border of the sensor thanks to an ion etched trench
which avoids the crystal damage produced by the standard mechanical dicing
process. Thin planar n-on-p pixel sensors with active edge have been designed
and produced by LPNHE and FBK foundry. Two detector module prototypes,
consisting of pixel sensors connected to FE-I4B readout chips, have been tested
with beams at CERN and DESY. In this paper the performance of these modules are
reported. In particular the lateral extension of the detection volume, beyond
the pixel region, is investigated and the results show high hit-efficiency also
at the detector edge, even in presence of guard rings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03286</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armano</keyname><forenames>Giuliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Javarone</keyname><forenames>Marco Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>The Beneficial Role of Mobility for the Emergence of Innovation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 1781 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-01955-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Innovation is a key ingredient for the evolution of several systems,
including social and biological ones. Focused investigations and lateral
thinking may lead to innovation, as well as serendipity and other random
discovery processes. Some individuals are talented at proposing innovation (say
innovators), while others at deeply exploring proposed novelties, at getting
further insights on a theory, or at developing products, services, and so on
(say developers). This separation in terms of innovators and developers raises
an issue of paramount importance: under which conditions a system is able to
maintain innovators? According to a simple model, this work investigates the
evolutionary dynamics that characterize the emergence of innovation. In
particular, we consider a population of innovators and developers, in which
agents form small groups whose composition is crucial for their payoff. The
latter depends on the heterogeneity of the formed groups, on the amount of
innovators they include, and on an award-factor that represents the policy of
the system for promoting innovation. Under the hypothesis that a &quot;mobility&quot;
effect may support the emergence of innovation, we compare the equilibria
reached by our population in different cases. Results confirm the beneficial
role of &quot;mobility&quot;, and the emergence of further interesting phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05039</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Hanley</keyname><forenames>Ryan K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bounds</keyname><forenames>Alistair D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huillery</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keegan</keyname><forenames>Niamh C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faoro</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bridge</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weatherill</keyname><forenames>Kevin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Matthew P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing interactions of thermal Sr Rydberg atoms using simultaneous
  optical and ion detection</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa6e79</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a method for probing interaction effects in a thermal beam of
strontium atoms using simultaneous measurements of Rydberg EIT and
spontaneously created ions or electrons. We present a Doppler-averaged optical
Bloch equation model that reproduces the optical signals and allows us to
connect the optical coherences and the populations. We use this to determine
that the spontaneous ionization process in our system occurs due to collisions
between Rydberg and ground state atoms in the EIT regime. We measure the cross
section of this process to be 0.6 $\pm$ 0.2 $\sigma_{\rm{geo}}$, where
$\sigma_{\rm{geo}}$ is the geometrical cross section of the Rydberg atom. This
results adds complementary insight to a range of recent studies of interacting
thermal Rydberg ensembles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06274</id><created>2017-02-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Davi R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Everschor-Sitte</keyname><forenames>Karin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretiakov</keyname><forenames>Oleg A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinova</keyname><forenames>Jairo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abanov</keyname><forenames>Ar.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin texture motion in antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 174408 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.174408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a Hamiltonian dynamics formalism for the current and magnetic
field driven dynamics of ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic domain walls in
one dimensional systems. To demonstrate the power of this formalism, we derive
Hamilton equations of motion via Poisson brackets based on the
Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert phenomenology, and add dissipative dynamics via the
evolution of the energy. We use this approach to study current induced domain
wall motion and compute the drift velocity. For the antiferromagnetic case, we
show that a nonzero magnetic moment is induced in the domain wall, which
indicates that an additional application of a magnetic field would influence
the antiferromagnetic domain-wall dynamics. We consider both cases of the
magnetic field being parallel and transverse to the N{\'e}el field. Based on
this formalism, we predict an orientation switch mechanism for
antiferromagnetic domain walls which can be tested with the recently discovered
N{\'e}el spin orbit torques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06804</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sakaue</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Jean-Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlon</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanderzande</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovian dynamics of reaction coordinate in polymer folding</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, submitted</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2017, Vol.13, p.317</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c7sm00395a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a theoretical description of the critical zipping dynamics of a
self-folding polymer. We use tension propagation theory and the formalism of
the generalized Langevin equation applied to a polymer that contains two
complementary parts which can bind to each other. At the critical temperature,
the (un)zipping is unbiased and the two strands open and close as a zipper. The
number of closed base pairs $n(t)$ displays a subdiffusive motion characterized
by a variance growing as $\langle \Delta n^2(t) \rangle \sim t^\alpha$ with
$\alpha &lt; 1$ at long times. Our theory provides an estimate of both the
asymptotic anomalous exponent $\alpha$ and of the subleading correction term,
which are both in excellent agreement with numerical simulations. The results
indicate that the tension propagation theory captures the relevant features of
the dynamics and shed some new insights on related polymer problems
characterized by anomalous dynamical behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08161</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hosotani</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author></authors><title>New dimensions from gauge-Higgs unification</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages. To appear in the Proceedings of &quot;Corfu Summer Institute
  2016&quot;, and in the Proceedings of &quot;6th CST-MISC Joint Symposium on Particle
  Physics -- from Spacetime Dynamics to Phenomenology --'. 6 figures are
  included</comments><report-no>OU-HET 925</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Higgs boson is unified with gauge fields in the gauge-Higgs unification.
The $SO(5) \times U(1)$ gauge-Higgs electroweak unification in the
Randall-Sundrum warped space yields almost the same phenomenology at low
energies as the standard model, and gives many predictions for the Higgs
couplings and new $W', Z'$ bosons around $6 \sim 8$ TeV, which can be tested at
14 TeV LHC. The gauge-Higgs grand unification is achieved in $SO(11)$ gauge
theory. It suggests the existence of the sixth dimension (GUT dimension) in
addition to the fifth dimension (electroweak dimension). The proton decay is
naturally suppressed in the gauge-Higgs grand unification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08485</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08485</id><created>2017-02-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Epps</keyname><forenames>Seth D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Weak Lensing Masses of Filaments between Luminous Red Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>MNRAS, in press</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 468, 2605 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the standard model of non-linear structure formation, a cosmic web of
dark-matter dominated filaments connects dark matter halos. In this paper, we
stack the weak lensing signal of an ensemble of filaments between groups and
clusters of galaxies. Specifically, we detect the weak lensing signal, using
CFHTLenS galaxy ellipticities, from stacked filaments between SDSS-III/BOSS
luminous red galaxies (LRGs). As a control, we compare the physical LRG pairs
with projected LRG pairs that are more widely separated in redshift space. We
detect the excess filament mass density in the projected pairs at the $5\sigma$
level, finding a mass of $(1.6 \pm 0.3) \times 10^{13} M_{\odot}$ for a stacked
filament region 7.1 $h^{-1}$ Mpc long and 2.5 $h^{-1}$ Mpc wide. This filament
signal is compared with a model based on the three-point
galaxy-galaxy-convergence correlation function, as developed in Clampitt, Jain
&amp; Takada (2014), yielding reasonable agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01173</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tempelaar</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichman</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vibronic exciton theory of singlet fission. I. Linear absorption and the
  anatomy of the correlated triplet pair state</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 174703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4982362</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent time-resolved spectroscopic experiments have indicated that vibronic
coupling plays a vital role in facilitating the process of singlet fission. In
this work, which forms the first article of a series, we set out to unravel the
mechanisms underlying singlet fission through a vibronic exciton theory. We
formulate a model in which both electronic and vibrational degrees of freedom
are treated microscopically and non-perturbatively. Using pentacene as a
prototypical material for singlet fission, we subject our theory to comparison
with measurements on polarization-resolved absorption of single crystals, and
employ our model to characterize the excited states underlying the absorption
band. Special attention is given to convergence of photophysical observables
with respect to the basis size employed, through which we determine the optimal
basis for more expensive calculations to be presented in subsequent work. We
furthermore evaluate the energetic separation between the optically prepared
singlet excited state and the correlated triplet pair state, as well as provide
a real-space characterization of the latter, both of which are of key
importance in the discussion of fission dynamics. We discuss our results in the
context of recent experimental studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01174</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tempelaar</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichman</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vibronic exciton theory of singlet fission. II. Two-dimensional
  spectroscopic detection of the correlated triplet pair state</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 174704 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4982359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Singlet fission, the molecular process through which photons are effectively
converted into pairs of lower energy triplet excitons, holds promise as a means
of boosting photovoltaic device efficiencies. In the preceding article of this
series, we formulated a vibronic theory of singlet fission, inspired by
previous experimental and theoretical studies suggesting that vibronic coupling
plays an important role in fission dynamics. Here, we extend our model in order
to simulate two-dimensional electronic spectra, through which the theory is
further validated based on a comparison to recent measurements on pentacene
crystals. Moreover, by means of such spectral simulations, we provide new
insights into the nature of the correlated triplet pair state, the first
product intermediate in the fission process. In particular, we address a
disagreement in the literature regarding the identification, energies, and
transition dipole moments of its optical transitions towards higher-lying
triplet states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01568</id><created>2017-03-05</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Dawoo</forenames><affiliation>Seoul National University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Chunglee</forenames><affiliation>Korea Astronomy and Space Science Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hyung Mok</forenames><affiliation>Seoul National University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bae</keyname><forenames>Yeong-Bok</forenames><affiliation>Korea Astronomy and Space Science Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Belczynski</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames><affiliation>University of Warsaw</affiliation></author></authors><title>Black Hole Binaries Dynamically Formed in Globular Clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 tables, 8 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS
  after minor revisions</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate properties of black hole (BH) binaries formed in globular
clusters via dynamical processes, using direct N-body simulations. We pay
attention to effects of BH mass function on the total mass and mass ratio
distributions of BH binaries ejected from clusters. Firstly, we consider BH
populations with two different masses in order to learn basic differences from
models with single-mass BHs only. Secondly, we consider continuous BH mass
functions adapted from recent studies on massive star evolution in a low
metallicity environment, where globular clusters are formed. In this work, we
consider only binaries that are formed by three-body processes and ignore
stellar evolution and primordial binaries for simplicity. Our results imply
that most BH binary mergers take place after they get ejected from the cluster.
Also, mass ratios of dynamically formed binaries should be close to one or
likely to be less than 2:1. Since the binary formation efficiency is larger for
higher-mass BHs, it is likely that a BH mass function sampled by
gravitational-wave observations would be weighed toward higher masses than the
mass function of single BHs for a dynamically formed population. Applying
conservative assumptions regarding globular cluster populations such as small
BH mass fraction and no primordial binaries, the merger rate of BH binaries
originated from globular clusters is estimated to be at least 6.5 per yr per
Gpc^3. Actual rate can be up to more than several times of our conservative
estimate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01705</id><created>2017-03-05</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Zhou</forenames></author></authors><title>Chirality, extended MHD statistics and solar wind turbulence</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>uncorrected version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We unite the one-flow-dominated-state (OFDS) argument of
\citet{MeyrandGaltierPRL12} with the one-chiral-sector-dominated-state (OCSCS)
one \citep[][]{hydrochirality} to form a nonlinear
extended-magnetohydrodynamics (XMHD) theory for the solar wind turbulence
(SWT), \textbf{ranging from the MHD- to subproton-, and even to
subelectron-scale regimes} \citep[modifying the theory
of][]{AbdelhamidLingamMahajanAPJ16}. Degenerate chiral states in
\citet{MiloshevichLingamMorrisonNJP17}'s XMHD absolute equilibria are exposed
with helical representation, to offer the basis of replacing the linear wave
(of infinitesimal or arbitrarily finite amplitudes) arguments of previous
theories with OCSDS. Possible connection of the OFDS-plus-OCSDS theory with the
local minimal-energy/stability principle is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02892</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-03-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;na</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weyers</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abgrall</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebing</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerginov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenbusch</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bize</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipphardt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denker</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quintin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raupach</keyname><forenames>S. M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolodi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiodo</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koke</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhl</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiotte</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meynadier</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camisard</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chardonnet</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coq</keyname><forenames>Y. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lours</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santarelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amy-Klein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Targat</keyname><forenames>R. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pottie</keyname><forenames>P. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosche</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>First international comparison of fountain primary frequency standards
  via a long distance optical fiber link</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Metrologia 54 (2017) 348</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1681-7575/aa65fe</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the first comparison of distant caesium fountain primary
frequency standards (PFSs) via an optical fiber link. The 1415 km long optical
link connects two PFSs at LNE-SYRTE (Laboratoire National de m\'{e}trologie et
d'Essais - SYst\`{e}me de R\'{e}f\'{e}rences Temps-Espace) in Paris (France)
with two at PTB (Physikalisch-Technische Bundesanstalt) in Braunschweig
(Germany). For a long time, these PFSs have been major contributors to accuracy
of the International Atomic Time (TAI), with stated accuracies of around
$3\times 10^{-16}$. They have also been the references for a number of absolute
measurements of clock transition frequencies in various optical frequency
standards in view of a future redefinition of the second. The phase coherent
optical frequency transfer via a stabilized telecom fiber link enables far
better resolution than any other means of frequency transfer based on satellite
links. The agreement for each pair of distant fountains compared is well within
the combined uncertainty of a few 10$^{-16}$ for all the comparisons, which
fully supports the stated PFSs' uncertainties. The comparison also includes a
rubidium fountain frequency standard participating in the steering of TAI and
enables a new absolute determination of the $^{87}$Rb ground state hyperfine
transition frequency with an uncertainty of $3.1\times 10^{-16}$.
  This paper is dedicated to the memory of Andr\'{e} Clairon, who passed away
on the 24$^{th}$ of December 2015, for his pioneering and long-lasting efforts
in atomic fountains. He also pioneered optical links from as early as 1997.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04911</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-03-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Son</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillgren</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espiritu</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Yanmeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Seongphill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baek</keyname><forenames>Hongwoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bockrath</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ruoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lau</keyname><forenames>Chun Ning</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Transport and Quantum Hall Effect in Ambipolar Black Phosphorus
  Double Quantum Wells</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Science Advances 3, e1603179 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum wells constitute one of the most important classes of devices in the
study of 2D systems. In a double layer QW, the additional &quot;which-layer&quot; degree
of freedom gives rise to celebrated phenomena such as Coulomb drag, Hall drag
and exciton condensation. Here we demonstrate facile formation of wide QWs in
few-layer black phosphorus devices that host double layers of charge carriers.
In contrast to tradition QWs, each 2D layer is ambipolar, and can be tuned into
n-doped, p-doped or intrinsic regimes. Fully spin-polarized quantum Hall states
are observed on each layer, with enhanced Lande g-factor that is attributed to
exchange interactions. Our work opens the door for using 2D semiconductors as
ambipolar single, double or wide QWs with unusual properties such as high
anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09067</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcilazo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valcarce</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vijande</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\,\,\,\,4}n$ system</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures. To be published in Chinese Physics C</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C 41, 074102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/7/074102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using local central Yukawa-type Malfliet-Tjon interactions reproducing the
low-energy parameters and phase shifs of the $nn$ system and the latest updates
of the $n\Lambda$ and $\Lambda\Lambda$ Nijmegen ESC08c potentials we study the
possible existence of a ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\,\,\,\,4}n$ bound state. Our
results indicate that the ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\,\,\,\,4}n$ is unbound, being
just above threshold. We discuss the role played by the $^1S_0$ $nn$ repulsive
term of the Yukawa-type Malfliet-Tjon interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01438</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galdi</keyname><forenames>Giovanni P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of Permanent Rotations and Long-Time Behavior of Inertial
  Motions of a Rigid Body with an Interior Liquid-Filled Cavity</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A rigid body, with an interior cavity entirely filled with a Navier-Stokes
liquid, moves in absence of external torques relative to the center of mass of
the coupled system body-liquid (inertial motions). The only steady-state
motions allowed are then those where the system, as a whole rigid body, rotates
uniformly around one of the central axes of inertia (permanent rotations).
Objective of this article is two-fold. On the one hand, we provide sufficient
conditions for the asymptotic, exponential stability of permanent rotations, as
well as for their instability. On the other hand, we study the asymptotic
behavior of the generic motion in the class of weak solutions and show that
there exists a time $t_0$ after that all such solutions must decay
exponentially fast to a permanent rotation. This result provides a {\em full}
and rigorous explanation of Zhukovsky's conjecture, and explains, likewise,
other interesting phenomena that are observed in both lab and numerical
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02580</id><created>2017-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Reiner</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Abhay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avraham</keyname><forenames>Nurit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Binghai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulga</keyname><forenames>Ion Cosma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Jung-Hyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karzig</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shtrikman</keyname><forenames>Hadas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beidenkopf</keyname><forenames>Haim</forenames></author></authors><title>Hot Electrons Regain Coherence in Semiconducting Nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The higher the energy of a particle is above equilibrium the faster it
relaxes due to the growing phase-space of available electronic states it can
interact with. In the relaxation process phase coherence is lost, thus limiting
high energy quantum control and manipulation. In one-dimensional systems high
relaxation rates are expected to destabilize electronic quasiparticles. We show
here that the decoherence induced by relaxation of hot electrons in
one-dimensional semiconducting nanowires evolves non-monotonically with energy
such that above a certain threshold hot-electrons regain stability with
increasing energy. We directly observe this phenomenon by visualizing for the
first time the interference patterns of the quasi-one-dimensional electrons
using scanning tunneling microscopy. We visualize both the phase coherence
length of the one-dimensional electrons, as well as their phase coherence time,
captured by crystallographic Fabry-Perot resonators. A remarkable agreement
with a theoretical model reveals that the non-monotonic behavior is driven by
the unique manner in which one dimensional hot-electrons interact with the cold
electrons occupying the Fermi-sea. This newly discovered relaxation profile
suggests a high-energy regime for operating quantum applications that
necessitate extended coherence or long thermalization times, and may stabilize
electronic quasiparticles in one dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05161</id><created>2017-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobota</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>S. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soifer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauthier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>M. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Y. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>S. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirchmann</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Z. -X.</forenames></author></authors><title>3D nature of ZrTe$_5$ band structure measured by
  high-momentum-resolution photoemission spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 195119 (2017) (Editors' Suggestion)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed a systematic high-momentum-resolution photoemission study
on ZrTe$_5$ using $6$ eV photon energy. We have measured the band structure
near the $\Gamma$ point, and quantified the gap between the conduction and
valence band as $18 \leq \Delta \leq 29$ meV. We have also observed
photon-energy-dependent behavior attributed to final-state effects and the 3D
nature of the material's band structure. Our interpretation indicates the gap
is intrinsic and reconciles discrepancies on the existence of a topological
surface state reported by different studies. The existence of a gap suggests
that ZrTe$_5$ is not a 3D strong topological insulator nor a 3D Dirac
semimetal. Therefore, our experiment is consistent with ZrTe$_5$ being a 3D
weak topological insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06394</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>B. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Page</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholey</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashley</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianco</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cullen</keyname><forenames>I. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darby</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eeckhaudt</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnsworthy</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gelletly</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Hornillos</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grahn</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenlees</keyname><forenames>P. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenkins</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joss</keyname><forenames>D. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julin</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juutinen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketelhut</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishada</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niikura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nyman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakarinen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podolyak</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahkila</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigby</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saren</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shizuma</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorri</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uusitalo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>William</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>W. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>L. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic factor and proton formation probability for the d3/2
  proton emitter 151mLu</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 770 (2017) 83</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quenching of the experimental spectroscopic factor for proton emission
from the short-lived $d_{3/2}$ isomeric state in $^{151m}$Lu was a
long-standing problem. In the present work, proton emission from this isomer
has been reinvestigated in an experiment at the Accelerator Laboratory of the
University of Jyv\&quot;{a}skyl\&quot;{a}. The proton-decay energy and half-life of this
isomer were measured to be 1295(5) keV and 15.4(8) $\mu$s, respectively, in
agreement with another recent study. These new experimental data can resolve
the discrepancy in the spectroscopic factor calculated using the spherical WKB
approximation. Using the R-matrix approach it is found that the proton
formation probability indicates no significant hindrance for the proton decay
of $^{151m}$Lu.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07893</id><created>2017-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>Andreas M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Force-induced elastic matrix-mediated interactions in the presence of a
  rigid wall</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, Soft Matter (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 13, 3373 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7SM00459A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an elastic composite material containing particulate inclusions
in a soft elastic matrix that is bounded by a rigid wall, e.g., the substrate.
If such a composite serves as a soft actuator, forces are imposed on or induced
between the embedded particles. We investigate how the presence of the rigid
wall affects the interactions between the inclusions in the elastic matrix. For
no-slip boundary conditions, we transfer Blake's derivation of a corresponding
Green's function from low-Reynolds-number hydrodynamics to the linearly elastic
case. Results for no-slip and free-slip surface conditions are compared to each
other and to the bulk behavior. Our results suggest that walls with free-slip
surface conditions are preferred when they serve as substrates for soft
actuators made from elastic composite materials. As we further demonstrate, the
presence of a rigid wall can qualitatively change the interactions between the
inclusions. In effect, it can switch attractive interactions into repulsive
ones (and vice versa). It should be straightforward to observe the effects in
future experiments and to combine our results, e.g., with the modeling of
biological cells and tissue on rigid surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08722</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>R. J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzm&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badnell</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Hoof</keyname><forenames>P. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatzikos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferland</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamically-consistent semi-classical $\ell$-changing rates</title><categories>physics.atom-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures. To be published in J Phys B. Author original
  version: journal accepted version, with minor changes, will be posted after
  embargo period</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. (2017) 50, 115201</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa6f58</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the results of the semi-classical (SC) and quantum-mechanical (QM)
formalisms for angular-momentum changing transitions in Rydberg atom collisions
given by Vrinceanu &amp; Flannery, J. Phys. B 34, L1 (2001), and Vrinceanu, Onofrio
&amp; Sadeghpour, ApJ 747, 56 (2012), with those of the SC formalism using a
modified Monte Carlo realization. We find that this revised SC formalism agrees
well with the QM results. This provides further evidence that the rates derived
from the QM treatment are appropriate to be used when modelling recombination
through Rydberg cascades, an important process in understanding the state of
material in the early universe. The rates for $\Delta\ell=\pm1$ derived from
the QM formalism diverge when integrated to sufficiently large impact
parameter, $b$. Further to the empirical limits to the $b$ integration
suggested by Pengelly &amp; Seaton, MNRAS 127, 165 (1964), we suggest that the
fundamental issue causing this divergence in the theory is that it does not
fully cater for the finite time taken for such distant collisions to complete.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00505</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Somajit</forenames></author></authors><title>Special Relativity (Lorentz Transformation) Follows from the Definition
  of Inertial Frames</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>Changes in v2: Addition to content and reference. Please feel free to
  email the author any critique, queries, comments or suggestions regarding
  this work</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Besides the defining space-time symmetries (homogeneity and isotropy) of
inertial frames, the derivation of Lorentz transformation requires postulating
the principle of relativity and the existence of a finite speed limit. In this
article, we point out that the existence of a finite speed limit can be readily
inferred from the nature of allowed inertial frames. We also show that the
principle of relativity can be obtained from the defining space-time symmetries
of every inertial frame. Therefore, if the conventional definition of inertial
frames is augmented properly, the special theory of relativity (Lorentz
transformation) would follow from the definition of inertial frames.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02007</id><created>2017-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Daniel</keyname><forenames>Scott F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linder</keyname><forenames>Eric V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Accelerated Parameter Estimation with DALE$\chi$</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider methods for improving the estimation of constraints on a
high-dimensional parameter space with a computationally expensive likelihood
function. In such cases Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) can take a long time to
converge and concentrates on finding the maxima rather than the often-desired
confidence contours for accurate error estimation. We employ DALE$\chi$ (Direct
Analysis of Limits via the Exterior of $\chi^2$) for determining confidence
contours by minimizing a cost function parametrized to incentivize points in
parameter space which are both on the confidence limit and far from previously
sampled points. We compare DALE$\chi$ to the nested sampling algorithm
implemented in MultiNest on a toy likelihood function that is highly
non-Gaussian and non-linear in the mapping between parameter values and
$\chi^2$. We find that in high-dimensional cases DALE$\chi$ finds the same
confidence limit as MultiNest using roughly an order of magnitude fewer
evaluations of the likelihood function. DALE$\chi$ is open-source and available
at https://github.com/danielsf/Dalex.git.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03010</id><created>2017-05-08</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sturrock</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinitz</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischbach</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of Ten Years of Radon-Chain Decay Measurements: Evidence of
  Solar Influences and Inferences Concerning Solar Internal Structure and the
  Role of Neutrinos</title><categories>astro-ph.SR hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gamma radiation associated with radon decay exhibits variations in both time
of year and time of day. The annual oscillation has its maximum value in June,
suggestive of a galactic influence. Measurements made at midnight show strong
evidence of an influence of solar rotation, but measurements made at noon do
not. We find several pairs of oscillations with frequencies separated by 1
cycle per year that is suggestive of an influence of rotation that is oblique
with respect to the normal to the ecliptic. We suggest that beta decays may be
stimulated by neutrinos and that the decay products tend to travel in the same
direction as the neutrinos. We estimate the relevant cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03458</id><created>2017-05-09</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hernando</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villuendas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sulc</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernando</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seoane</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plastino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximum Entropy Principle underlying the dynamics of automobile sales</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-fin.GN</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 color figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze an exhaustive data-set of new-cars monthly sales. The set refers
to 10 years of Spanish sales of more than 6500 different car model
configurations and a total of 10M sold cars, from January 2007 to January 2017.
We find that for those model configurations with a monthly market-share higher
than 0.1% the sales become scalable obeying Gibrat's law of proportional growth
under logistic dynamics. Remarkably, the distribution of total sales follows
the predictions of the Maximum Entropy Principle for systems subject to
proportional growth in dynamical equilibrium. We also encounter that the
associated dynamics are non-Markovian, i.e., the system has a decaying memory
or inertia of about 5 years. Thus, car sales are predictable within a certain
time-period. We show that the main characteristics of the dynamics can be
described via a construct based upon the Langevin equation. This construct
encompasses the fundamental principles that any predictive model on car sales
should obey.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03620</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Raktima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>Arun K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sandip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of Vanadyl Oxygen in Understanding Metallic Behavior of V2O5(001)
  Nanorods</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b08452</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Vanadium pentoxide (V2O5), the most stable member of vanadium oxide family,
exhibits interesting semiconductor to metal transition in the temperature range
of 530-560 K. The metallic behavior originates because of the reduction of V2O5
through oxygen vacancies. In the present report, V2O5 nanorods in the
orthorhombic phase with crystal orientation of (001) are grown using vapor
transport process. Among three nonequivalent oxygen atoms in a VO5 pyramidal
formula unit in V2O5 structure, the role of terminal vanadyl oxygen (OI) in the
formation of metallic phase above the transition temperature is established
from the temperature-dependent Raman spectroscopic studies. The origin of the
metallic behavior of V2O5 is also understood due to the breakdown of pdpi bond
between OI and nearest V atom instigated by the formation of vanadyl OI
vacancy, confirmed from the downward shift of the bottom most split-off
conduction bands in the material with increasing temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03692</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boehm</keyname><forenames>Celine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campo</keyname><forenames>Andres Olivares-Del</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palomares-Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascoli</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of a Neutrino-DM Coupling: The Scalar Case</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Poster presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 4
  pages, LaTeX, 2 png figures</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Olivares-Del Campo</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter (DM) and neutrinos are the two most compelling pieces of evidence
of new physics beyond the Standard Model of Particle Physics but these are
often treated as belonging to two different sectors. Yet DM-neutrino
interactions are known to have cosmological consequences. Here, we study the
scenario of a scalar DM candidate coupled to left-handed neutrinos via a Dirac
mediator. We determine the mass of a DM candidate that yields the right DM
relic abundance in a thermal scenario and it is consistent with large-scale
structure formation. In order to satisfy both constraints, a complex DM
candidate should have a mass larger than $8.14$ keV while the mass of a real DM
candidate should be above $18.1$ eV, independently of the value of the
DM-neutrino coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03913</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03913</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Buckley</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feld</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Hiding Thermal Dark Matter with Leptons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Any form of dark matter which was in thermal equilibrium with the Standard
Model in the early Universe must have some annihilation mechanism in order to
avoid overclosure. In general, such models are now constrained by the negative
experimental results from colliders, direct detection, and indirect detection,
all of which are capable of probing interactions at the approximate strength
suggested by a thermal cross section. It is timely to consider what scenarios
of thermal dark matter which are still viable. In this paper we consider a
class of dark matter models which is designed to avoid many of the current
constraints: Majorana dark matter coupling to the Standard Model through
leptophilic singlet scalars and pseudoscalars. We show that requiring realistic
electroweak symmetry breaking generically forces the mediators to couple with
quarks, allowing these models to be constrained by the current experimental
data. We find that -- barring fine-tuning -- this type of thermal dark matter
is excluded by a combination of direct and indirect detection for masses below
$\sim 100$ GeV. Heavier dark matter is still viable, but in principle visible
via its indirect detection signature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03935</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Domizio</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Future prospects for neutrinoless double-beta decay</title><categories>nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages,
  LaTeX</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-DiDomizio</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of neutrinoless double-beta decay plays a fundamental role in the
understanding of neutrino physics. Its observation would prove that neutrinos
are Majorana particles and that lepton number is not conserved. Experimental
searches demand detectors with a very large source mass and extremely low
background. We report on planned future experimental searches and discuss their
expected sensitivities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03979</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Xiaozheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Issei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Monte Carlo simulation of electrostatic interactions in inhomogeneous
  dielectric media: Correct sampling for the local lattice simulation algorithm</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a lattice Monte Carlo algorithm based on the one originally
proposed by Maggs and Rossetto for simulating electrostatic interactions in
inhomogeneous dielectric media. The original algorithm is known to produce
attractive interactions between particles of the same dielectric constant in
the medium of different dielectric constant. We demonstrate that such
interactions are spurious, caused by incorrectly biased statistical weight
arising from particle motion during the Monte Carlo moves. We propose a simple
parallel tempering algorithm that corrects this unphysical bias. The efficacy
of our algorithm is tested on a simple binary mixture and on an uncharged
polymer in a solvent, and applied to salt-doped polymer solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03985</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>de Wilt</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowell</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burton</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rathborne</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawamura</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharonian</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dense molecular gas at 12 mm towards Galactic TeV gamma-ray sources</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>24 pages, 26 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 468 (2): 2093-2113</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx369</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The High Energy Stereoscopic System (H.E.S.S.) has revealed many TeV (10 12
eV) gamma-ray sources along the Galactic Plane and around 30 percent of these
sources remain unidentified. The morphology and dynamics of dense gas
coincident and surrounding the gamma-ray emission can provide clues about the
nature of the TeV emission. The H2O Southern Galactic Plane Survey (HOPS)
undertaken with the Mopra radio telescope, includes several dense gas tracers,
such as NH3 (n,n) transitions and HC3N (3-2), star formation tracers including
H2O masers, and radio recombination lines which trace ionised gas. A search for
dense gas, traced by NH3 (1,1) emission seen in HOPS and additional
observations, towards Galactic TeV sources has been undertaken. Of the 49
Galactic TeV sources covered by 12 mm observations, NH3 (1,1) is detected
towards or adjacent to 38 of them. Dense gas counterparts have been detected
near several unidentified Galactic TeV sources which display morphology
pointing to a hadronic origin to the TeV gamma-rays. The dense gas detected
towards some TeV sources displays unusual emission characteristics, including
very broad linewidths and enhanced ortho-to-para NH3 abundance ratios towards
HESS J1745-303 and HESS J1801-233, which reflects previous shock activity
within the gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03994</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Davletshin</keyname><forenames>Yevgeniy R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumaradas</keyname><forenames>J. Carl</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical analysis of optoporation efficiency and bubble formation
  during femtosecond pulse interaction with gold nanoshell</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our group has recently developed a finite element model of a
nanoparticle-mediated optical breakdown phenomena. Previously, this model was
used to analyze the role of the nanoparticle morphology and the wavelength
dependence of a nanoparticle-mediated optical breakdown threshold during
near-infrared ps and fs pulse exposures. In this study, we provide a
theoretical insight into the optoporation efficiency of live cells and bubble
formation threshold during nanoparticle-mediated optical breakdown. It was done
by the calculation of maximum temperature and free electron density in the
vicinity of a single gold nanoshell in water during 70 femtosecond single pulse
exposure and comparison against published experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04000</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Arzola</keyname><forenames>Alejandro V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villasante-Barahona</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volke-Sep&#xfa;lveda</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xe1;kl</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zem&#xe1;nek</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Omnidirectional Transport in Fully Reconfigurable Two Dimensional
  Optical Ratchets</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages and 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 138002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.138002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fully reconfigurable two-dimensional (2D) rocking ratchet system created
with holographic optical micromanipulation is presented. We can generate
optical potentials with the geometry of any Bravais lattice in 2D and introduce
a spatial asymmetry with arbitrary orientation. Nontrivial directed transport
of Brownian particles along different directions is demonstrated numerically
and experimentally, including on-axis, perpendicular and oblique with respect
to an unbiased ac driving. The most important aspect to define the current
direction is shown to be the asymmetry and not the driving orientation, and yet
we show a system in which the asymmetry orientation of each potential well does
not coincide with the transport direction, suggesting an additional symmetry
breaking as a result of a coupling with the lattice configuration. Our
experimental device, due to its versatility, opens up a new range of
possibilities in the study of nonequilibrium dynamics at the microscopic level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04012</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Raktima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardar</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bera</keyname><forenames>Santanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magudapathy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sandip</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of 1-D finite size Heisenberg chain in increasing metal to
  insulator transition temperature in hole rich VO2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1039/C7NR00729A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  VO2 samples are grown with different oxygen concentrations leading to
different monoclinic, M1 and triclinic, T insulating phases which undergo a
first order metal to insulator transition (MIT) followed by a structural phase
transition (SPT) to rutile tetragonal phase. The metal insulator transition
temperature (Tc) was found to be increased with increasing native defects.
Vanadium vacancy (VV) is envisaged to create local strains in the lattice which
prevents twisting of the V-V dimers promoting metastable monoclinic, M2 and T
phases at intermediate temperatures. It is argued that MIT is driven by strong
electronic correlation. The low temperature insulating phase can be considered
as a collection of one-dimensional (1-D) half-filled band, which undergoes Mott
transition to 1-D infinitely long Heisenberg spin 1/2 chains leading to
structural distortion due to spin-phonon coupling. Presence of VV creates
localized holes (d0) in the nearest neighbor, thereby fragmenting the spin 1/2
chains at nanoscale, which in turn increase the Tc value more than that of an
infinitely long one. The Tc value scales inversely with the average size of
fragmented Heisenberg spin 1/2 chains following a critical exponent of 2/3,
which is exactly the same predicted theoretically for Heisenberg spin 1/2 chain
at nanoscale undergoing SPT (spin-Peierls transition). Thus, the observation of
MIT and SPT at the same time in VO2 can be explained from our phenomenological
model of reduced 1-D Heisenberg spin 1/2 chains. The reported increase
(decrease) in Tc value of VO2 by doping with metal having valency less (more)
than four, can also be understood easily with our unified model, for the first
time, considering finite size scaling of Heisenberg chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04013</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Preiser-Kapeller</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>A Collapse of the Eastern Mediterranean? New results and theories on the
  interplay between climate and societies in Byzantium and the Near East, ca.
  1000-1200 AD</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Peer-reviewed; with seven appendices, including three tables and 33
  figures</comments><journal-ref>Jahrbuch der \&quot;Osterreichischen Byzantinistik 65 (2015) 195-242</journal-ref><doi>10.1553/joeb65s195</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses a recently proposed scenario of a climate-induced
Collapse of the Eastern Mediterranean in the 11th century AD. It demonstrates
that such a scenario cannot be maintained when confronted with proxy data from
various regions. On the other hand, data on the interplay between environment
and economy in the Komnenian period (1081-1185) and evidence for a change of
climatic conditions in the period of the Angeloi (1185-1204) is presented,
arguing that climatic parameters should be taken into consideration when
comparing socio-economic dynamics in the Eastern Mediterranean with those in
Western Europe. The necessity of further research on the regional as well as
over-regional level for many aspects of the interaction between human society
and environment in the medieval Eastern Mediterranean is highlighted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04015</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaur</keyname><forenames>Kulwinder</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thapa</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Sunita</forenames></author></authors><title>Pursuit of thermoelectric properties in a novel Half Heusler compound:
  HfPtPb</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 Figures, 2 Tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the structural, electronic, mechanical and thermoelectric
properties of a new half Heusler compound, HfPtPb which is all metallic heavy
element and has been recently been proposed to be stable [Nature Chem 7 (2015)
308]. In the present work, we employ density functional theory and
semiclassical Boltzmann transport equations with constant relaxation time
approximation. The mechanical properties such as Shear modulus, Young modulus,
elastic constants, Poisson ratio, and shear anisotropy factor are investigated.
The elastic and phonon properties reveal that this compound is mechanically and
dynamically stable. Pugh and Frantsevich ratio demonstrates the ductile
behavior and Shear anisotropic factor reflects the anisotropic nature of
HfPtPb. The calculation of band structure predicts that this compound is
semiconductor in nature with band gap 0.86 eV. The thermoelectric transport
parameters such as Seebeck coefficient, electrical conductivity, and electronic
thermal conductivity and lattice thermal conductivity have been calculated as a
function of temperature. The highest value of Seebeck coefficient is obtained
for n-type doping at optimal carrier concentration. We predict the maximum
value of the figure of merit 0.25 at 1000 K. Our investigation suggests that
this material is n-type semiconductor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04023</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf3;&#x17a;d&#x17a;</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piechocki</keyname><forenames>W&#x142;odzimierz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plewa</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical structures specific to strong gravitational field: Quantum
  formalism</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of the general Bianchi IX spacetime, near the gravitational
singularity, underlies the Belinskii, Khalatnikov and Lifshitz scenario.
Asymptotically, near the singularity, the oscillations of the directional scale
factors (defining the spacetime metric) are freezed so the evolution of the
Bianchi IX model is devoid of chaotic features. However, it includes special
structures, that we call the wiggles, which change their properties in the
asymptotic regime. We propose the formalism, based on an affine quantization
scheme, to examine the fate of the wiggles at the quantum level. We present the
way of comparing the classical wiggles with their quantum counterparts. We
expect that our work may contribute towards understanding some quantum aspects
of the BKL scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04034</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Varshney</keyname><forenames>Atul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinberg</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Elastic wake instabilities in a creeping flow between two obstacles</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Fluids 2, 051301(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.2.051301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that a channel flow of a dilute polymer solution between two
widely spaced cylinders hindering the flow is an important paradigm of an
unbounded flow in the case in which the channel wall is located sufficiently
far from the cylinders. The quantitative characterization of instabilities in a
creeping viscoelastic channel flow between two widely spaced cylinders reveals
two elastically driven transitions, which are associated with the breaking of
time-reversal and mirror symmetries: Hopf and forward bifurcations described by
two order parameters $\mbox{v}_{rms}$ and $\bar{\omega}$, respectively. We
suggest that a decrease of the normalized distance between the obstacles leads
to a collapse of the two bifurcations into a codimension-2 point, a situation
general for many non-equilibrium systems. However, the striking and unexpected
result is the discovery of a mechanism of the vorticity growth via an increase
of a vortex length at the preserved streamline curvature in a viscoelastic
flow, which is in sharp contrast to the well-known suppression of the vorticity
in a Newtonian flow by polymer additives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04040</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ichinose</keyname><forenames>Wataru</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on the Feynman path integral for the Dirac equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is a continuation of the author's preceding one. In the preceding
paper the author has rigorously constructed the Feynman path integral for the
Dirac equation in the form of the sum-over-histories, satisfying the
superposition principle, over all paths of one electron in space-time that goes
in any direction at any speed, forward and backward in time with a finite
number of turns. In the present paper, first we will generalize the results in
the preceding paper and secondly prove in a direct way that our Feynman path
integral satisfies the unitarity principle and the causality one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04041</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shukron</keyname><forenames>Ofir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holcman</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Randomly cross-linked polymer models</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polymer models are used to describe chromatin, which can be folded at
different spatial scales by binding molecules. By folding, chromatin generates
loops of various sizes. We present here a randomly cross-linked (RCL) polymer
model, where monomer pairs are connected randomly. We obtain asymptotic
formulas for the steady-state variance, encounter probability, the radius of
gyration, instantaneous displacement and the mean first encounter time between
any two monomers. The analytical results are confirmed by Brownian simulations.
Finally, the present results can be used to extract the minimum number of
cross-links in a chromatin region from {conformation capture} data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04047</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Simitzi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranella</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stratakis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling the morphology and outgrowth of nerve and neuroglial cells:
  The effect of surface topography</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><journal-ref>Acta Biomaterialia, 51, 2017, 21-52</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actbio.2017.01.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike other tissue types, like epithelial tissue, which consist of cells
with a much more homogeneous structure and function, the nervous tissue spans
in a complex multilayer environment whose topographical features display a
large spectrum of morphologies and size scales. Traditional cell cultures,
which are based on two-dimensional cell-adhesive culture dishes or coverslips,
are lacking topographical cues and mainly simulate the biochemical
microenvironment of the cells. With the emergence of micro- and
nano-fabrication techniques new types of cell culture platforms are developed,
where the effect of various topographical cues on cellular morphology,
proliferation and differentiation, can be studied. Different approaches
(regarding the material, fabrication technique, topographical charactertistics,
etc.) have been implemented. The present review paper aims at reviewing the
existing body of literature on the use of artificial micro- and
nano-topographical features to control neuronal morphology, outgrowth and
neural network topology. The cell responses from phenomenology to investigation
of the underlying mechanisms- on the different topographies, including both
deterministic and random ones, are summarized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04052</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soignard</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khosravi</keyname><forenames>Afsaneh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manca</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marie</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Shery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbaszek</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tongay</keyname><forenames>Sefaattin</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of Highly Anisotropic Semiconducting GaTe Nanomaterials and
  Emerging Properties Enabled by Epitaxy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, supplement (submitted version)</comments><journal-ref>Advanced Materials 29, 1605551 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adma.201605551</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pseudo-one dimensional (pseudo-1D) materials are a new-class of materials
where atoms are arranged in chain like structures in two-dimensions (2D).
Examples include recently discovered black phosphorus, ReS2 and ReSe2 from
transition metal dichalcogenides, TiS3 and ZrS3 from transition metal
trichalcogenides and most recently GaTe. The presence of structural anisotropy
impacts their physical properties and leads to direction dependent light-matter
interactions, dichroic optical responses, high mobility channels, and
anisotropic thermal conduction. Despite the numerous reports on the vapor phase
growth of isotropic TMDCs and post transition metal chalcogenides such as MoS2
and GaSe, the synthesis of pseudo-1D materials is particularly difficult due to
the anisotropy in interfacial energy, which stabilizes dendritic growth rather
than single crystalline growth with well-defined orientation. The growth of
monoclinic GaTe has been demonstrated on flexible mica substrates with superior
photodetecting performance. In this work, we demonstrate that pseudo-1D
monoclinic GaTe layers can be synthesized on a variety of other substrates
including GaAs (111), Si (111) and c-cut sapphire by physical vapor transport
techniques. High resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM)
measurements, together with angle resolved micro-PL and micro-Raman techniques,
provide for the very first time atomic scale resolution experiments on
pseudo-1D structures in monoclinic GaTe and anisotropic properties.
Interestingly, GaTe nanomaterials grown on sapphire exhibit highly efficient
and narrow localized emission peaks below the band gap energy, which are found
to be related to select types of line and point defects as evidenced by PL and
Raman mapping scans. It makes the samples grown on sapphire more prominent than
those grown on GaAs and Si, which demonstrate more regular properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04061</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04061</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rica</keyname><forenames>Ra&#xfa;l A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spasenovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gieseler</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rondin</keyname><forenames>Lo&#xef;c</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novotny</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quidant</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author></authors><title>Optically levitated nanoparticle as a model system for stochastic
  bistable dynamics</title><categories>physics.optics physics.app-ph physics.class-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15141 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nano-mechanical resonators have gained an increasing importance in
nanotechnology owing to their contributions to both fundamental and applied
science. Yet, their small dimensions and mass raises some challenges as their
dynamics gets dominated by nonlinearities that degrade their performance, for
instance in sensing applications. Here, we report on the precise control of the
nonlinear and stochastic bistable dynamics of a levitated nanoparticle in high
vacuum. We demonstrate how it can lead to efficient signal amplification
schemes, including stochastic resonance. This work paves the way for the use of
levitated nanoparticles as a model system for stochastic bistable dynamics,
with applications to a wide variety of fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04075</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaari</keyname><forenames>Nermine</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rodney</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>ILM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Clouet</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Oxygen - Dislocation interaction in zirconium from first principles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Acta Materialia, Elsevier, 2017, 132, pp.416-424</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.05.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasticity in zirconium alloys is mainly controlled by the interaction of 1/3
1210 screw dislocations with oxygen atoms in interstitial octahedral sites of
the hexagonal close-packed lattice. This process is studied here using ab
initio calculations based on the density functional theory. The atomic
simulations show that a strong repulsion exists only when the O atoms lie in
the dislocation core and belong to the prismatic dislocation habit plane. This
is a consequence of the destruction of the octahedral sites by the stacking
fault arising from the dislocation dissociation. Because of the repulsion, the
dislocation partially cross-slips to an adjacent prismatic plane, in agreement
with experiments where the lattice friction on screw dislocations in Zr-O
alloys has been attributed to the presence of jogs on the dislocations due to
local cross-slip.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04079</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Labavic</keyname><forenames>Darka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer-Ortmanns</keyname><forenames>Hildegard</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal self-similar synchronization patterns and scaling in
  repulsively coupled oscillators</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study synchronization patterns in repulsively coupled Kuramoto oscillators
and focus on the impact of disorder in the natural frequencies. Among other
choices we select the grid size and topology in a way that we observe a
dynamically induced dimensional reduction with a continuum of attractors as
long as the natural frequencies are uniformly chosen. When we introduce
disorder in these frequencies, we find limit cycles with periods that are
orders of magnitude longer than the natural frequencies of individual
oscillators. Moreover we identify sequences of temporary patterns of
phase-locked motion, which are self-similar in time and whose periods scale
with a power of the inverse width about a uniform frequency distribution. This
behavior provides challenges for future research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04100</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>B&#xfc;rkle</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaidoukov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anglin</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent Steady States in Two-Dimensional Sonic Black Holes: Superfluid
  Vortices and Emission of Sound</title><categories>cond-mat.other gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simulation of a sonic black-hole/white-hole pair in a (2+1)-dimensional
Bose-Einstein condensate shows formation of superfluid vortices through
dynamical instabilities seeded by initial quantum noise. The instabilities
saturate in a quasi-steady state of superfluid turbulence within the supersonic
region, from which sound waves are emitted in qualitative resemblance to
Hawking radiance. The power spectrum of the radiation from the slowly decaying
two-dimensional sonic black hole is strongly non-thermal, however.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04102</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Simoni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viel</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Launay</keyname><forenames>Jean-Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of the spectral element method to the solution of the
  multichannel Schr\&quot;odinger equation</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the spectral element method to the determination of scattering and
bound states of the multichannel Schr\&quot;odinger equation. In our approach the
reaction coordinate is discretized on a grid of points whereas the internal
coordinates are described by either purely diabatic or locally diabatic
(diabatic-by-sector) bases. Bound levels and scattering matrix elements are
determined with spectral accuracy using relatively small numbers of points. The
scattering problem is cast as a linear system solved using state-of-the-art
sparse matrix non iterative packages. Boundary conditions can be imposed so to
compute a single column of the matrix solution. A comparison with
log-derivative propagators customarily used in molecular physics is performed.
The same discretization scheme can also be applied to bound levels that are
computed using direct scalable sparse-matrix solvers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04113</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoshimatsu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ara&#xfa;jo</keyname><forenames>N. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shinbrot</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Segregation of charged particles in shear induced diffusion</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study segregation of a binary mixture of similarly charged particles under
shear using particle-based simulations. We simulate particle dynamics using a
discrete-element model including electrostatic interactions and find that
particles segregate according to their net charge. Particles that are charged
twice as strong as other particles of the same electrical sign are seen more at
insulating boundaries with which we shear the system. Weakly charged particles,
on the other hand, stay more in the center of the sheared bed. We propose a
simple model based on electrostatic potential energy to understand this
segregation. The model shows that the segregated system we observe in our
simulations is indeed the most favorable configuration in terms of
electrostatic potential energy. Our simulations further show that for a given
packing fraction there is an optimal shear velocity where the segregation
maximally intensifies. We show that this maximum results from a competition
between diffusional and Coulomb fluxes. For a larger shear velocity, diffusion
suppresses segregation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04124</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf6;teman</keyname><forenames>Malin</forenames></author></authors><title>The complex world of superstrings: On semichiral sigma models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>PhD thesis: Digital Comprehensive Summaries of Uppsala Dissertations
  from the Faculty of Science and Technology 989. 139 pp. Uppsala</comments><msc-class>51P05, 81T60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-linear sigma models with extended supersymmetry have constrained target
space geometries, and can serve as effective tools for investigating and
constructing new geometries. Analyzing the geometrical and topological
properties of sigma models is necessary to understand the underlying structures
of string theory. The most general two-dimensional sigma model with manifest
N=(2,2) supersymmetry can be parametrized by chiral, twisted chiral and
semichiral superfields. In the research presented in this thesis, N=(4,4)
(twisted) supersymmetry is constructed for a semichiral sigma model. It is
found that the model can only have additional supersymmetry off-shell if the
target space has a dimension larger than four. For four-dimensional target
manifolds, supersymmetry can be introduced on-shell, leading to a hyperk\&quot;ahler
manifold, or pseudo-supersymmetry can be imposed off-shell, implying a target
space which is neutral hyperk\&quot;ahler.
  Different sigma models and corresponding geometries can be related to each
other by T-duality, obtained by gauging isometries of the Lagrangian. The
semichiral vector multiplet and the large vector multiplet are needed for
gauging isometries mixing semichiral superfields, and chiral and twisted chiral
superfields, respectively. We find transformations that close off-shell to a
N=(4,4) supersymmetry on the field strengths and gauge potentials of the
semichiral vector multiplet, and show that this is not possible for the large
vector multiplet.
  A sigma model parametrized by chiral and twisted chiral superfields can be
related to a semichiral sigma model by T-duality. The N=(4,4) supersymmetry
transformations of the former model are linear and close off-shell, whereas
those of the latter are non-linear and close only on-shell. We show that this
discrepancy can be understood from T-duality, and find the origin of the
non-linear terms in the transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04125</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sruthilaya</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanta</keyname><forenames>Rukmani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Sudhanwa</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Mass and Neutrinoless double beta decay in SO(10) GUT with
  Pati-Salam symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 15 figures, regular article</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate how a class of non-supersymmetric $SO(10)$ GUT with asymmetric
left-right theory $SU(2)_L \times U(1)_R \times U(1)_{B-L} \times SU(3)_C$ and
Pati-Salam theory $SU(2)_L \times SU(2)_R \times SU(4)_C$ as intermediate
symmetry breaking steps leads to successful gauge coupling unification
satisfying proton decay constraints. The motivation behind this work is two
fold: firstly to study the renormalization group evolution equations for gauge
couplings by keeping right-handed neutral gauge boson $Z_R$ around LHC energy
range leading interesting dilepton searches at collider while fixing charge
partner of the gauge boson $W_R$ at very high scale; secondly to explain
neutrino masses and associated lepton number violating process like
neutrinoless double beta decay in three possible cases depending on how
$SU(2)_L \times U(1)_R \times U(1)_{B-L} \times SU(3)_C$ breaks down to SM. We
include one extra fermion singlet per generation in order to implement gauged
extended seesaw where light neutrino mass is governed by natural type-II seesaw
mechanism whereas type-I seesaw contribution is exactly canceled out. Since
light neutrino mass formula is independent of Dirac neutrino mass matrix, the
value of Dirac neutrino mass is taken to be up-type quark mass matrix which is
a characteristics of Pati-Salam symmetry relating quarks with leptons. We
present analytic relation for effective Majorana mass parameter and
corresponding half-life arising from new physics contributions due to purely
left-handed currents through exchange of heavy right-handed neutrinos and
sterile neutrinos. We numerically estimate effective Majorana mass parameter
and half-life vs. lightest neutrino mass and derive lower bound on lightest
neutrino mass by saturating with experimental bounds like GERDA Phase-II,
KamLANDZen and EXO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04129</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Asai</keyname><forenames>Hidehiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabata</keyname><forenames>Shiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Control of Circularly Polarized THz Wave from Intrinsic Josephson
  Junctions by Local Heating</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110 (2017) 132601</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports a practical method of generating circularly polarized
terahertz (THz) waves from intrinsic Josephson junctions (IJJs) and controlling
their polarization states by external local heating. We theoretically find that
a mesa-structure IJJ whose geometry is almost square can emit circularly
polarized THz waves by local heating of the mesa. Moreover, we demonstrate that
the polarization states of the THz waves change dramatically with the local
heating position. Our results indicate that the use of local heating can
provide a high level of controllability of the THz emissions and significantly
extend the range of applications of IJJ-based THz emitters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04140</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Argaman</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Cosmic Bell Test: Measurement Settings from Milky Way Stars&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This Comment argues that two assumptions, which are presented as basic
assumptions of Bell's theorem in [J. Handsteiner et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 118,
060401 (2017)] and elsewhere, in fact follow from more basic premises.
Measurement independence follows from (i) the use of free variables and (ii)
the causal arrow of time. Determinism follows from (i) local causality and (ii)
perfect correlations (predicted by quantum mechanics). In particular, it is
pointed out that the measurement-independence violating toy model of [M.J.W.
Hall, Phys. Rev. Lett. 105, 250404 (2010)], is based on a retro-causal model.
While this may be controversial, it should be possible to achieve concensus on
the much simpler matter of what the basic assumptions of Bell's theorem are.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04145</id><created>2017-05-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasmani</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandya</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherically Symmetric Cosmological Model with Charged Anisotropic Fluid
  in Higher Dimensional Rosen's Bimetric Theory of Gravitation</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we have obtained cosmological models for the static spherically
symmetric spacetime with charged anisotropic fluid distribution in
(n+2)-dimensions in context of Rosen's Bimetric General Relativity (BGR). An
exact solution is obtained and a special case is considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04150</id><created>2017-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Coddens</keyname><forenames>Gerrit</forenames></author></authors><title>A solution for the paradox of the double-slit experiment</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>also available on HAL at CEA-01459890v3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that the double-slit experiment can be understood much better by
considering it as an experiment whereby one uses electrons to study the set-up
rather than an experiment whereby we use a set-up to study the behaviour of
electrons. We also show how the concept of undecidability can be used in an
intuitive way to make sense of the double-slit experiment and the quantum rules
for calculating coherent and incoherent probabilities. We meet here a situation
where the electrons always behave in a fully deterministic way (following
Einstein's conception of reality), while the detailed design of the set-up may
render the question about the way they move through the set-up experimentally
undecidable (which follows more Bohr's conception of reality). We show that the
expression $\psi_{1} + \psi_{2}$ for the wave function of the double-slit
experiment is numerically correct, but logically flawed. It has to be replaced
in the interference region by the logically correct expression $\psi'_{1} +
\psi'_{2}$, which has the same numerical value as $\psi_{1} + \psi_{2}$, such
that $\psi'_{1} + \psi'_{2} = \psi_{1} + \psi_{2}$, but with $\psi'_{1} =
{\psi_{1} +\psi_{2}\over{\sqrt{2}}} \,e^{\imath {\pi\over{4}}} \neq \psi_{1}$
and $\psi'_{2} = {\psi_{1} +\psi_{2}\over{\sqrt{2}}}\,e^{-\imath
{\pi\over{4}}}\neq \psi_{2}$. Here $\psi'_{1}$ and $\psi'_{2}$ are the correct
contributions from the slits to the total wave function $\psi'_{1} +
\psi'_{2}$. We have then $p = |\psi'_{1} + \psi'_{2}|^{2} = |\psi'_{1}|^{2} +
|\psi'_{2}|^{2} = p_{1}+p_{2} $ such that the paradox that quantum mechanics
(QM) would not follow the traditional rules of probability calculus disappears.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04156</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Anuar</keyname><forenames>N. Emir</forenames></author></authors><title>Canonical Quantization Approach of a Class of a Dissipative System:
  Applications to Quantum Tunnelling with Dissipative Coupling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a formalism for which a dissipative system is given by a
variational principle. The formalism applies to dynamical systems where its
trajectory is monotonic. Subsequently, we derive its Lagrangian and
Hamiltonian. From the Hamiltonian, we quantize canonically the classical
particle in a viscous media. We study the free quantum particle in a viscous
media and the dissipative quantum tunnelling. It is found that the dissipation
influences tunnelling probability by a factor that closely resembles the result
of Caldeira and Leggett.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04167</id><created>2017-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Majeed</keyname><forenames>Bushra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jamil</keyname><forenames>Mubasher</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and center of mass energy of colliding particles around black
  hole in f(R) gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 Pages, 2 Figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics D, Vol. 26, No. 5 (2017)
  1741017 (9 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817410176</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the dynamics of particles in the vicinity of a static
spherically symmetric black hole in f(R) gravity. Using the Euler-Lagrange
method the dynamical equations of a neutral particle are obtained. Assuming
that the particle is initially moving in the innermost stable circular orbit,
we have calculated its escape velocity, after a collision with some other
particle. The conditions for the escape of colliding particles are discussed.
The effective potential and the trajectories of the escaping particles are
studied graphically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04184</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronel</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial Scales of Living Cells, their Energetic and Informational
  Capacity and the Origin of the Arrow of Time</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical thermodynamic and kinetic, chemical and biological reasoning
restrict the spatial dimensions of living cells and confine them to between one
and one hundred micrometers. Cells should necessarily be macroscopic,
dissipative objects, resisting thermal fluctuations and providing sufficient
informational capacity. The upper limit of spatial dimensions of cells is
supplied by their ability to withstand gravity and inertia forces under
reasonable deformations. The upper limit of cell dimensions is also governed by
the hierarchy of characteristic time scales, inherent for mass and heat
transport. For micron-scaled cells, the traffic time (namely a typical time
necessary for the migration of one enzyme to another) is on the order of
magnitude of a millisecond, which coincides with the characteristic time scale
of a single round of the catalytic enzyme cycle. Among other important
consequences the macroscopic dimensions of living cells seen as dissipative
systems) give rise to the irreversibility of biological processes,
demonstrating the arrow of time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04192</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Cacciola</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muscoloni</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narula</keyname><forenames>Vaibhav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calamuneri</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nigro</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayer</keyname><forenames>Emeran A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labus</keyname><forenames>Jennifer S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anastasi</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quattrone</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quartarone</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milardi</keyname><forenames>Demetrio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cannistraci</keyname><forenames>Carlo Vittorio</forenames></author></authors><title>Coalescent embedding in the hyperbolic space unsupervisedly discloses
  the hidden geometry of the brain</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The human brain displays a complex network topology, whose structural
organization is widely studied using diffusion tensor imaging. The original
geometry from which emerges the network topology is known, as well as the
localization of the network nodes in respect to the brain morphology and
anatomy. One of the most challenging problems of current network science is to
infer the latent geometry from the mere topology of a complex network. The
human brain structural connectome represents the perfect benchmark to test
algorithms aimed to solve this problem. Coalescent embedding was recently
designed to map a complex network in the hyperbolic space, inferring the node
angular coordinates. Here we show that this methodology is able to
unsupervisedly reconstruct the latent geometry of the brain with an incredible
accuracy and that the intrinsic geometry of the brain networks strongly relates
to the lobes organization known in neuroanatomy. Furthermore, coalescent
embedding allowed the detection of geometrical pathological changes in the
connectomes of Parkinson's Disease patients. The present study represents the
first evidence of brain networks' angular coalescence in the hyperbolic space,
opening a completely new perspective, possibly towards the realization of
latent geometry network markers for evaluation of brain disorders and
pathologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04199</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yangmei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Hua Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Xiaozhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiangrong</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction of Stable Ground-State Lithium Polyhydrides under High
  Pressures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other physics.app-ph physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>34 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Inorg. Chem. 56, 3867 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.inorgchem.6b02709</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrogen-rich compounds are important for understanding the dissociation of
dense molecular hydrogen, as well as searching for room temperature
Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) superconductors. A recent high pressure
experiment reported the successful synthesis of novel insulating lithium
polyhydrides when above 130 GPa. However, the results are in sharp contrast to
previous theoretical prediction by PBE functional that around this pressure
range all lithium polyhydrides (LiHn (n = 2-8)) should be metallic. In order to
address this discrepancy, we perform unbiased structure search with first
principles calculation by including the van der Waals interaction that was
ignored in previous prediction to predict the high pressure stable structures
of LiHn (n = 2-11, 13) up to 200 GPa. We reproduce the previously predicted
structures, and further find novel compositions that adopt more stable
structures. The van der Waals functional (vdW-DF) significantly alters the
relative stability of lithium polyhydrides, and predicts that the stable
stoichiometries for the ground-state should be LiH2 and LiH9 at 130-170 GPa,
and LiH2, LiH8 and LiH10 at 180-200 GPa. Accurate electronic structure
calculation with GW approximation indicates that LiH, LiH2, LiH7, and LiH9 are
insulative up to at least 208 GPa, and all other lithium polyhydrides are
metallic. The calculated vibron frequencies of these insulating phases are also
in accordance with the experimental infrared (IR) data. This reconciliation
with the experimental observation suggests that LiH2, LiH7, and LiH9 are the
possible candidates for lithium polyhydrides synthesized in that experiment.
Our results reinstate the credibility of density functional theory in
description H-rich compounds, and demonstrate the importance of considering van
der Waals interaction in this class of materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04201</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Kensuke</forenames></author></authors><title>What Can We Learn from Noise? -- Mesoscopic Nonequilibrium Statistical
  Physics --</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures. Review article</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Japan Academy, Series B 92 (7), 204-221 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.2183/pjab.92.204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mesoscopic systems -- small electric circuits working in quantum regime --
offer us a unique experimental stage to explorer quantum transport in a tunable
and precise way. The purpose of this Review is to show how they can contribute
to statistical physics. We introduce the significance of fluctuation, or
equivalently noise, as noise measurement enables us to address the fundamental
aspects of a physical system. The significance of the fluctuation theorem (FT)
in statistical physics is noted. We explain what information can be deduced
from the current noise measurement in mesoscopic systems. As an important
application of the noise measurement to statistical physics, we describe our
experimental work on the current and current noise in an electron
interferometer, which is the first experimental test of FT in quantum regime.
Our attempt will shed new light in the research field of mesoscopic quantum
statistical physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04209</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bangga</keyname><forenames>Galih</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lutz</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xe4;mer</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames></author></authors><title>An Examination of Rotational Effects on Large Wind Turbine Blades</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>11 th EAWE PhD Seminar on Wind Energy in Europe</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CFD studies have been performed to demonstrate the effects of rotation on
large wind turbine blades. The 10 MW blade of the Advanced Aerodynamic Tools
for Large Rotors (AVATAR) project was selected in the present investigation. In
order to demonstrate the rotational augmentation, lift coefficients of the
blade sections were compared with the two-dimensional simulations at consistent
inflow conditions. The increase of the lift coefficient was observed at the
inboard section of the blade, showing the effect of rotation. A significant
delay of separation point as well as a massive reduction of the wake size occur
at the inboard blade section. The results of the present manuscript provide
more information of the rotational augmentation occurring in the near hub
region of wind turbine blades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04211</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04211</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bangga</keyname><forenames>Galih</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lutz</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xe4;mer</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Investigation of Unsteady Aerodynamic Effects on Thick
  Flatback Airfoils</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>German Wind Energy Conference 12</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unsteady characteristics of the flow over thick flatback airfoils have
been investigated by means of CFD calculations. Sandia airfoils which have 35%
maximum thickness with three different trailing edge thicknesses were selected.
The calculations provided good results compared with available experimental
data with regard to the lift curve and the impact of trailing edge thickness.
Unsteady CFD simulations revealed that the Strouhal number is found to be
independent of the lift coefficient before stall and increases with the
trailing edge. The present work shows the dependency of the Strouhal number and
the wake development on the trailing edge thickness. A recommendation of the
Strouhal number definition is given for flatback airfoils by considering the
trailing edge separation at low angle of attack. The detailed unsteady
characteristics of thick flatback airfoils are discussed more in the present
paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04213</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yang-Mei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Hua Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zi-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiang-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicted novel insulating electride compound between alkali metals
  lithium and sodium under high pressure</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B 26(5), 056102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/26/5/056102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The application of high pressure can fundamentally modify the crystalline and
electronic structures of elements as well as their chemical reactivity, which
could lead to the formation of novel materials. Here, we explore the reactivity
of lithium with sodium under high pressure, using a swarm structure searching
techniques combined with first-principles calculations, which identify a
thermodynamically stable LiNa compound adopting an orthorhombic oP8 phase at
pressure above 355 GPa. The formation of LiNa may be a consequence of strong
concentration of electrons transfer from the lithium and the sodium atoms into
the interstitial sites, which also leads to opening a relatively wide band gap
for LiNa-op8. This is substantially different from the picture that share or
exchange electrons in common compounds and alloys. In addition, lattice-dynamic
calculations indicate that LiNa-op8 remains dynamically stable when pressure
decompresses down to 70 GPa.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04215</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Alben</keyname><forenames>Silas</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved convection cooling in steady channel flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>30 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find steady channel flows that are locally optimal for transferring heat
from fixed-temperature walls, under the constraint of a fixed rate of viscous
dissipation (enstrophy = $Pe^2$), also the power needed to pump the fluid
through the channel. We generate the optima with net flux as a continuation
parameter, starting from parabolic (Poiseuille) flow, the unique optimum at
maximum net flux. Decreasing the flux, we eventually reach optimal flows that
concentrate the enstrophy in boundary layers of thickness $\sim Pe^{-2/5}$ at
the channel walls, and have a uniform flow with speed $\sim Pe^{4/5}$ outside
the boundary layers. We explain the scalings using physical arguments with a
unidirectional flow approximation, and mathematical arguments using a decoupled
approximation. We also show that with channels of aspect ratio (length/height)
$L$, the boundary layer thickness scales as $L^{3/5}$ and the outer flow speed
scales as $L^{-1/5}$ in the unidirectional approximation. At the Reynolds
numbers near the turbulent transition for 2D Poiseuille flow in air, we find a
60\% increase in heat transferred over that of Poiseuille flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04217</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gauld</keyname><forenames>Rhorry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slade</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author></authors><title>The small-x gluon from forward charm production: implications for a 100
  TeV proton collider</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the XXV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 3-7
  April 2017, University of Birmingham, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the constraints on the small-x gluon PDF that can be derived by
exploiting the forward D meson production data from the LHCb experiment at
$\sqrt{s}=5,7$ and 13 TeV. We then discuss the phenomenological implications of
the resulting improved small-x gluon for ultra-high energy astrophysics, in
particular neutrino telescopes, as well as for the proposed Future Circular
Collider (FCC) with $\sqrt{s}=100$ TeV. We illustrate how at the FCC even
electroweak scale cross-sections can become sensitive to the small-x region of
the quark and gluon PDFs, and then demonstrate how the addition of the LHCb
heavy meson production measurements leads to a reduction of PDF uncertainties
for various benchmark cross-sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04220</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wiedemann</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak-strong uniqueness in fluid dynamics</title><categories>math.AP physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a survey of recent results on weak-strong uniqueness for compressible
and incompressible Euler and Navier-Stokes equations, and also make some new
observations. The importance of the weak-strong uniqueness principle stems, on
the one hand, from the instances of non-uniqueness for the Euler equations
exhibited in the past years; and on the other hand from the question of
convergence of singular limits, for which weak-strong uniqueness represents an
elegant tool.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04231</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yixing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roke</keyname><forenames>Sylvie</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized expressions for hyper-Rayleigh scattering from isotropic
  liquids</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generalized expressions for second harmonic scattering from isotropically
distributed liquid molecules are derived for arbitrary scattering angles and
polarization states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04233</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>H&#xf6;randel</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rays</keyname><forenames>LOFAR key science project Cosmic</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the properites of cosmic rays with the LOFAR radio
  telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-energy cosmic rays, impinging on the atmosphere of the Earth initiate
cascades of secondary particles, the extensive air showers. The electrons and
positrons in the air shower emit electromagnetic radiation. This emission is
detected with the LOFAR radio telescope in the frequency range from 10 to 240
MHz. The data are used to determine the properties of the incoming cosmic rays.
The radio technique is now routinely used to measure the arrival direction, the
energy, and the particle type (atomic mass) of cosmic rays in the energy range
from $10^{17}$ to $10^{18}$ eV. This energy region is of particular
astrophysical interest, since in this regime a transition from a Galactic to an
extra-galactic origin of cosmic rays is expected. For illustration, the LOFAR
results are used to set constraints on models to describe the origin of
high-energy cosmic rays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04236</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorlach</keyname><forenames>Maxim A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnova</keyname><forenames>Daria A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korobkin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slobozhanyuk</keyname><forenames>Alexey P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhirihin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belov</keyname><forenames>Pavel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanikaev</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling scattering of light through topological transitions in
  all-dielectric metasurfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological phase transitions in condensed matter systems have shown
extremely rich physics, unveiling such exotic states of matter as topological
insulators, superconductors and superfluids. Photonic topological systems open
a whole new realm of research exhibiting a number of important distinctions
from their condensed matter counterparts. Photonic modes can couple to the
continuum of free space modes which makes it feasible to control and manipulate
scattering properties of the photonic structure via topology. At the same time,
the direct connection of scattering and topological properties of the photonic
states allows their probing by spectroscopic means via Fano resonances. Here we
demonstrate that the radiative coupling of modes supported by an all-dielectric
metasurface can be controlled and tuned under topological phase transitions due
to band inversion, correspondingly inducing a distinct switching of the quality
factors of the resonances associated with the bands. In addition, we develop a
technique to retrieve the topological properties of all-dielectric metasurfaces
from the measured far-field scattering characteristics. The collected
angle-resolved transmission and reflection spectra allow extracting the
momentum-dependent frequencies and lifetimes of the photonic modes. This
enables retrieval of the effective photonic Hamiltonian, including the effects
of a synthetic gauge field, and topological invariants~-- pseudo-spin Chern
numbers. Our results thus open a new avenue to design a new class of
metasurfaces with unique scattering characteristics controlled via topological
effects. This work also demonstrates how topological states of open systems can
be explored via far-field measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04237</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Marini</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leathersich</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mahaboob</keyname><forenames>Isra</forenames><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bulmer</keyname><forenames>John</forenames><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Newman</keyname><forenames>Neil</forenames><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>F.</keyname><affiliation>Shadi</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shahedipour-Sandvik</keyname></author></authors><title>MOCVD growth of N-polar GaN on on-axis sapphire substrate: impact of AlN
  nucleation layer on GaN surface hillock density</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Crystal Growth 442, 25-30 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2016.02.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the impact of growth conditions on surface hillock density of
N-polar GaN grown on nominally on-axis (0001) sapphire substrate by metal
organic chemical vapor deposition (MOCVD). Large reduction in hillock density
was achieved by implementation of an optimized high temperature AlN nucleation
layer and use of indium surfactant in GaN overgrowth. A reduction by more than
a factor of five in hillock density from 1000 to 170 hillocks/cm$^{-2}$ was
achieved as a result. Crystal quality and surface morphology of the resultant
GaN films were characterized by high resolution x-ray diffraction and atomic
force microscopy and found to be relatively unaffected by the buffer
conditions. It is also shown that the density of smaller surface features is
unaffected by AlN buffer conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04245</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Antonius</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louie</keyname><forenames>Steven G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of the Exciton-Phonon Coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of electron-phonon interactions on optical absorption spectra
requires a special treatment in materials with strong electron-hole
interactions. We conceptualize these effects as exciton-phonon coupling.
Through phonon absorption and emission, the optically accessible excitons are
scattered into dark finite-momentum exciton states. We derive a practical
expression for the exciton-phonon self-energy that relates to the temperature
dependence of the optical transitions and their broadening. This expression
differs qualitatively from previous approximated expressions found in
literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04274</id><created>2017-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Guterman</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonietti</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jiayin</forenames></author></authors><title>Plants to Polyelectrolytes: Theophylline Polymers and their Microsphere
  Synthesis</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>19 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Macromol. Rapid Commun. 2017, 38 (8), 1600748</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/marc.201600748</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To extend fossil oil supplies, sustainable feed stocks for the production of
useful reagents and polymers should be harnessed. In this regard, chemicals
derived from plants are excellent candidates. While the vast majority of plant
sources used for polymer science only contain CxHyOz, alkaloids such as
caffeine, nicotine, and theophylline possess nitrogen functionality that can
provide new functions for bio-derived polymers and their synthesis. In this
context, we exploited the chemistry of theophylline, a natural product found in
chocolate and tea, to create a cationic poly(theophylline) in a straightforward
fashion for the first time. We demonstrate how this new polymer can be
synthesized and used for the creation of narrowly disperse cationic
microspheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04275</id><created>2017-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Grygie</keyname><forenames>Konrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirchhecker</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Jiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonietti</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jiayin</forenames></author></authors><title>Main-chain Polyimidazolium Polymers by One-pot Synthesis and Application
  as Nitrogen-doped Carbon Precursors</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures</comments><doi>10.1002/macp.201600586</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports on the one-pot synthesis of main-chain
imidazolium-containing polymers, some of which show unusually high thermal
stability. The imidazolium polymers were obtained by modified
Debus-Radziszewski reactions for the chain build-up from simple organic
compounds, here pyruvaldehyde, formaldehyde, acetic acid, and a variety of
diamines. The reactions were performed in aqueous media at ambient conditions,
being synthetically elegant, convenient and highly efficient. Finally, a simple
anion-metathesis reaction was conducted to replace the acetate anion with
dicyanamide, and the thermal properties of the main-chain polyimidazoliums
before and after anion exchange were studied in detail, which demonstrated
chain cross-linking by the counterion and a coupled unusually high
carbonization yield of up to 66 wt% at 900 oC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04278</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Dymarsky</keyname><forenames>Anatoly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penedones</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trevisani</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vichi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Charting the space of 3D CFTs with a continuous global symmetry</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>67 pages, 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study correlation functions of a conserved spin-1 current $J_\mu$ in three
dimensional Conformal Field Theories (CFTs). We investigate the constraints
imposed by permutation symmetry and current conservation on the form of three
point functions $\langle J_\mu J_\nu \mathcal O_{\Delta,\ell}\rangle $ and the
four point function $\langle J_\mu J_\nu J_\rho J_\sigma \rangle $ and identify
the minimal set of independent crossing symmetry conditions. We obtain a
recurrence relation for conformal blocks for generic spin-1 operators in three
dimensions. In the process, we improve several technical points, facilitating
the use of recurrence relations. By applying the machinery of the numerical
conformal bootstrap we obtain universal bounds on the dimensions of certain
light operators as well as the central charge. Highlights of our results
include numerical evidence for the conformal collider bound and new constraints
on the parameters of the critical $O(2)$ model. The results obtained in this
work apply to any unitary, parity-preserving three dimensional CFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04279</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolahdouz</keyname><forenames>Ebrahim M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enquobahrie</keyname><forenames>Andinet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caranasos</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vavalle</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffith</keyname><forenames>Boyce E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Image-based immersed boundary model of the aortic root</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.CE cs.CV</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Each year, approximately 300,000 heart valve repair or replacement procedures
are performed worldwide, including approximately 70,000 aortic valve
replacement surgeries in the United States alone. This paper describes progress
in constructing anatomically and physiologically realistic immersed boundary
(IB) models of the dynamics of the aortic root and ascending aorta. This work
builds on earlier IB models of fluid-structure interaction (FSI) in the aortic
root, which previously achieved realistic hemodynamics over multiple cardiac
cycles, but which also were limited to simplified aortic geometries and
idealized descriptions of the biomechanics of the aortic valve cusps. By
contrast, the model described herein uses an anatomical geometry reconstructed
from patient-specific computed tomography angiography (CTA) data, and employs a
description of the elasticity of the aortic valve leaflets based on a
fiber-reinforced constitutive model fit to experimental tensile test data.
Numerical tests show that the model is able to resolve the leaflet biomechanics
in diastole and early systole at practical grid spacings. The model is also
used to examine differences in the mechanics and fluid dynamics yielded by
fresh valve leaflets and glutaraldehyde-fixed leaflets similar to those used in
bioprosthetic heart valves. Although there are large differences in the leaflet
deformations during diastole, the differences in the open configurations of the
valve models are relatively small, and nearly identical hemodynamics are
obtained in all cases considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04290</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ugolnikov</keyname><forenames>Oleg S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maslov</keyname><forenames>Igor A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stratospheric Aerosol Particles Size Distribution Based on Multi-Color
  Polarization Measurements of the Twilight Sky</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures, sumbitted to Journal of Aerosol Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarization measurements of the twilight background with Wide-Angle
Polarization Camera (WAPC) are used to detect the depolarization effect caused
by stratospheric aerosol near the altitude of 20 km. Based on a number of
observations in central Russia in spring and summer 2016, we found the
parameters of lognormal size distribution of aerosol particles. This confirmed
the previously published results of the colorimetric method as applied to the
same twilights. The mean particle radius (about 0.1 micrometers) and size
distribution are also in agreement with the recent data of in situ and
space-based remote sensing of stratospheric aerosol. Methods considered here
provide two independent techniques of the stratospheric aerosol study based on
the twilight sky analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04313</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Thomas S. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witt</keyname><forenames>Adolf N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author></authors><title>Extended Red Emission in IC59 and IC63</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analysed new wide-field, wide- and narrow-band optical images of IC 59 and
IC 63, two nebulae which are externally illuminated by the early B-star
{\gamma} Cas, with the objective of mapping the extended red emission (ERE), a
dust-related photoluminescence process that is still poorly understood, in
these two clouds. The spatial distribution of the ERE relative to the direction
of the incident radiation and relative to other emission processes, whose
carriers and excitation requirements are known, provides important constraints
on the excitation of the ERE. In both nebulae, we find the ERE intensity to
peak spatially well before the more extended distribution of mid-infrared
emission in the unidentified infrared bands, supporting earlier findings that
point toward far-ultraviolet (11 eV &lt; E$_\mathrm{{photon}}$ &lt; 13.6 eV) photons
as the source of ERE excitation. The band-integrated absolute intensities of
the ERE in IC 59 and IC 63 measured relative to the number density of photons
available for ERE excitation are lower by about two orders of magnitude
compared to ERE intensities observed in the high-latitude diffuse interstellar
medium (ISM). This suggests that the lifetime of the ERE carriers is
significantly reduced in the more intense radiation field prevailing in IC 59
and IC 63, pointing toward potential carriers that are only marginally stable
against photo-processing under interstellar conditions. A model involving
isolated molecules or molecular ions, capable of inverse internal conversion
and recurrent fluorescence, appears to provide the most likely explanation for
our observational results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0012189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0012189</id><created>2000-12-20</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davydychev</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalmykov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>New results for the epsilon-expansion of certain one-, two- and
  three-loop Feynman diagrams</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech hep-ph math.CA math.NA</categories><comments>49 pages, LaTeX, two figures (one in eps format), v3 is journal
  version; in v3 the typos in Egs.(2.17), (4.16), (B.12) corrected; in v4 the
  typos in Egs.(2.7),(4.10),(4.25),(B.11) corrected (see p.30 of present
  version)</comments><report-no>MZ-TH/00-52; DESY/01-065</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B605 (2001) 266-318</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0550-3213(01)00095-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For certain dimensionally-regulated one-, two- and three-loop diagrams,
problems of constructing the epsilon-expansion and the analytic continuation of
the results are studied. In some examples, an arbitrary term of the
epsilon-expansion can be calculated. For more complicated cases, only a few
higher terms in epsilon are obtained. Apart from the one-loop two- and
three-point diagrams, the examples include two-loop (mainly on-shell)
propagator-type diagrams and three-loop vacuum diagrams. As a by-product, some
new relations involving Clausen function, generalized log-sine integrals and
certain Euler--Zagier sums are established, and some useful results for the
hypergeometric functions of argument 1/4 are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/9608112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/9608112</id><created>1996-08-16</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grundberg</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindstrom</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rocek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Yang-Mills fields for Cosets</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, LateX. This updates the faulty TeX file which has prevented
  reading the article on the archive for more than 20 years</comments><report-no>ITP-SB-96-39, USITP-96-09</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B389 (1996) 299-304</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0370-2693(96)01278-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider theories with degenerate kinetic terms such as those that arise
at strong coupling in $N=2$ super Yang-Mills theory. We compute the components
of generalized $N=1,2$ supersymmetric sigma model actions in two dimensions.
The target space coordinates may be matter and/or Yang-Mills superfield
strengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
