<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:07:10Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-18" from="2017-05-18" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.4746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.4746</id><created>2013-04-17</created><updated>2013-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>J. W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complementary cosmological tests of RSII brane models</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for Classical and Quantum Gravity</comments><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/30/20/205003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we explore observational bounds on flat and non-flat
cosmological models in Type II Randall-Sundrum (RSII) branes. In a first
analysis, we consider current measurements of the expansion rate H(z) (with two
priors on the local Hubble parameter) and 288 Type Ia supernovae from the Sloan
Digital Sky Survey (within the framework of the mlcs2k2 light-curve fitting
method). We find that the joint analysis involving these data is an interesting
tool to impose limits on the brane tension density parameter (Omega_{lambda})
and that the spatial curvature has a negligible influence on Omega_{lambda}
estimates. In order to obtain stronger bounds for the contribution of the
$\Omega_{\lambda}$ we also add in our analysis the baryon oscillation peak
(BAO) and cosmic microwave background radiation (CMB) observations by using the
so-called CMB/BAO ratio. From this analysis we find that the Omega_{lambda}
contribution is less than 4.10^{-5} (1sigma).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.5004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.5004</id><created>2014-02-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle creation in a f(R) theory with cosmological constraints</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>To appear in the General Relativity and Gravitation. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1108.3346</comments><doi>10.1007/s10714-014-1699-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the creation of super-massive real scalar particles in
the framework of a $f(R)=R-\beta/R^n$ modified gravity theory, with parameters
constrained by observational data. The analysis is restrict to a homogeneous
and isotropic flat and radiation dominated universe. We compare the results to
the standard Einstein gravity with cosmological constant ($\Lambda CDM$ model),
and we show that the total number density of created particles in the $f(R)$
model is very close to the standard case. Another interesting result is that
the spectrum of created particles is $\beta$ independent at early times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.3654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.3654</id><created>2014-07-14</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iantchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-normal modes for de Sitter-Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om Black Holes</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP math.SP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasi-normal modes for black holes are the resonances for the scattering
of incoming waves by black holes. Here we consider scattering of massless
uncharged Dirac fields propagating in the outer region of de
Sitter-Reissner-Nordstr{\&quot;o}m black hole, which is spherically symmetric
charged exact solution of the Einstein-Maxwell equations. Using the spherical
symmetry of the equation and restricting to a fixed harmonic the problem is
reduced to a scattering problem for the 1D massless Dirac operator on the line.
The resonances for the problem are related to the resonances for a certain
semiclassical Schr{\&quot;o}dinger operator with exponentially decreasing positive
potential. We give exact relation between the sets of Dirac and Schr{\&quot;o}dinger
resonances. The asymptotic distribution of the resonances is close to the
lattice of pseudopoles associated to the non-degenerate maxima of the
potentials.
  Using the techniques of quantum Birkhoff normal form we give the complete
asymptotic formulas for the resonances. In particular, we calculate the first
three leading terms in the expansion. Moreover, similar results are obtained
for the de Sitter-Schwarzschild quasi-normal modes, thus improving the result
of S\'a Barreto and Zworski from 1997.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.7916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.7916</id><created>2014-10-29</created><updated>2015-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wakiya</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onimaru</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsutsui</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagasawa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baron</keyname><forenames>A. Q. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogita</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Udagawa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takabatake</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-Energy Optical Phonon Modes in the Caged Compound LaRu2Zn20</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B, 93, 064105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.064105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The caged compound LaRu2Zn20 exhibits a structural transition at TS =150 K,
whose driving mechanism remains elusive. We have investigated atomic dynamics
by the measurements of specific heat C and inelastic X-ray scattering (IXS).
The lattice part of the specific heat Clat divided by T3, Clat/T3, shows a
broad peak at around 15 K, which is reproduced by two Einstein modes with
characteristic temperatures of 35 K and 82 K, respectively. IXS measurements
along the [111] and [110] directions reveal optical phonon modes at 3 meV (35
K) and 7 meV (80 K), respectively, whose values agree with the values of
Einstein temperatures. The first principles calculation has assigned the phonon
modes at 3 meV as the optical modes of Zn atoms located at the middle of two La
atoms. The low-energy vibration of the Zn atom perpendicular to the there-fold
axis is thought to lead the structural instability of LaRu2Zn20.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01970</id><created>2015-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>Carl M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hook</keyname><forenames>Daniel W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavromatos</keyname><forenames>Nick E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Sarben</forenames></author></authors><title>PT-symmetric interpretation of unstable effective potentials</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>Preprint LCTS/2015-15</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 45LT01 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/45/45LT01</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conventional interpretation of the one-loop effective potentials of the
Higgs field in the Standard Model and the gravitino condensate in dynamically
broken supergravity is that these theories are unstable at large field values.
A PT-symmetric reinterpretation of these models at a quantum-mechanical level
eliminates these instabilities and suggests that these instabilities may also
be tamed at the quantum-field-theory level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05743</id><created>2015-07-21</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maurya</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamizhavel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonville</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetocaloric effect and magnetic phase diagram of EuRhAl4Si2</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, 20th International Conference on Magnetism (ICM
  2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  EuRhAl4Si2, crystallizes in tetragonal crystal structure and orders
antiferromagnetically at ~12 K. The isothermal magnetization along the two
principle directions is highly anisotropic despite Eu2+ being an S-state ion.
The variation of entropy change, which is a measure of MCE, with field and
temperature, calculated from the isothermal magnetization data taken at various
temperatures along the principal crystallographic directions present
interesting behavior in EuRhAl4Si2. In the magnetically ordered state the
entropy change is non-monotonic below spin flip fields; however, in the
paramagnetic region, it is negative irrespective of the strength of applied
magnetic field. For H || [001] the maximum entropy change at 7 T is -21 J/Kg K
around TN, which is large and comparable to the largest known values in this
temperature range. The variation of the MCE with field strongly depends upon
the direction of the applied magnetic field. Magnetic phase diagram of
EuRhAl4Si2 derived from M(H) data is also constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05104</id><created>2015-08-20</created><updated>2017-05-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ohm</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassler</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement-induced entanglement of two transmon qubits by a single
  photon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures; to be published in NJP</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 053018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6d46</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On-demand creation of entanglement between distant qubits is a necessary
ingredient for distributed quantum computation. We propose an entanglement
scheme that allows for single-shot deterministic entanglement creation by
detecting a single photon passing through a Mach-Zehnder interferometer with
one transmon qubit in each arm. The entanglement production essentially relies
on the fact that superconducting microwave structures allow to achieve strong
coupling between the qubit and the photon. By detecting the photon via a photon
counter, a parity measurement is implemented and the wave function of the two
qubits is projected onto a maximally entangled state. Most importantly, the
entanglement generation is heralded such that our protocol is not susceptible
to photon loss due to the indivisible nature of single photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00673</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2017-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Qiaoli</forenames></author></authors><title>Axions and Dark Matter</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, a contribution to the special issue of the Modern Physics
  Letters A &quot;Dark Matter Particle Candidates&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, 32, 1740003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231740003X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter constitutes about $23\%$ of the total energy density of the
universe but its properties are still little known besides that it should be
composed by cold and weakly interacting particles. Many beyond standard model
theories can provide proper candidates to serve as dark matter and the axion
introduced to solve the strong CP problem turns out to be an attractive one. In
this paper, we briefly review several important features of the axion and the
axion dark matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05255</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2015-12-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kehrein</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal nonanalytic behavior of the Hall conductance in a Chern
  insulator at the topologically driven nonequilibrium phase transition</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Hall conductance of a Chern insulator after a global quench of
the Hamiltonian. The Hall conductance in the long time limit is obtained by
applying the linear response theory to the diagonal ensemble. It is expressed
as the integral of the Berry curvature weighted by the occupation number over
the Brillouin zone. We identify a topologically driven nonequilibrium phase
transition, which is indicated by the nonanalyticity of the Hall conductance as
a function of the energy gap m_f in the post-quench Hamiltonian H_f. The
topological invariant for the quenched state is the winding number of the
Green's function W, which equals the Chern number for the ground state of H_f.
In the limit that m_f goes to zero, the derivative of the Hall conductance with
respect to m_f is proportional to ln(|m_f|), with the constant of
proportionality being the ratio of the change of W at m_f = 0 to the energy gap
in the initial state. This nonanalytic behavior is universal in two-band Chern
insulators such as the Dirac model, the Haldane model, or the Kitaev honeycomb
model in the fermionic basis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09144</id><created>2015-11-29</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Varma</keyname><forenames>Vipin Kerala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lerose</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietracaprina</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goold</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scardicchio</keyname><forenames>Antonello</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy diffusion in the ergodic phase of a many body localizable spin
  chain</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures, Published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 053101</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa668b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phenomenon of many-body localization in disordered quantum many-body
systems occurs when all transport is suppressed despite the fact that the
excitations of the system interact. In this work we report on the numerical
simulation of autonomous quantum dynamics for disordered Heisenberg chains when
the system is prepared with an initial inhomogeneity in the energy density
profile. Using exact diagonalisation and a dynamical code based on Krylov
subspaces we are able to simulate dynamics for up to L = 26 spins. We find,
surprisingly, the breakdown of energy diffusion even before the many-body
localization transition whilst the system is still in the ergodic phase.
Moreover, in the ergodic phase we also find a large region in parameter space
where the energy dynamics remains diffusive but where spin transport has been
previously evidenced to occur only subdiffusively: this is found to be true for
initial states composed of infinitely many hydrodynamic modes (square-wave
energy profile) or just the single longest mode (sinusoidal profile). This
suggestive finding points towards a peculiar ergodic phase where particles are
transported slower than energy, reminiscent of the situation in amorphous
solids and of the gapped phase of the anisotropic Heisenberg model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02454</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2015-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Almog</keyname><forenames>Assaf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Squartini</keyname><forenames>Tiziano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garlaschelli</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>The double role of GDP in shaping the structure of the International
  Trade Network</title><categories>q-fin.GN physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures. Contribution submitted for the International
  Workshop on Computational Economics and Econometrics - see also
  arXiv:1409.6649</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Comput. Econ. Econom., 7 (4), 381-398 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1504/IJCEE.2017.10003511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The International Trade Network (ITN) is the network formed by trade
relationships between world countries. The complex structure of the ITN impacts
important economic processes such as globalization, competitiveness, and the
propagation of instabilities. Modeling the structure of the ITN in terms of
simple macroeconomic quantities is therefore of paramount importance. While
traditional macroeconomics has mainly used the Gravity Model to characterize
the magnitude of trade volumes, modern network theory has predominantly focused
on modeling the topology of the ITN. Combining these two complementary
approaches is still an open problem. Here we review these approaches and
emphasize the double role played by GDP in empirically determining both the
existence and the volume of trade linkages. Moreover, we discuss a unified
model that exploits these patterns and uses only the GDP as the relevant
macroeconomic factor for reproducing both the topology and the link weights of
the ITN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05930</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puhlmann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heuer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complementarity in single photon interference - the role of mode
  functions and vacuum fields</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single photon first order interferences of spatially separated regions from
the cone structure of spontaneous parametric down conversion allow for
analyzing the role of the mode function in quantum optics. In earlier
experiments the role of the vacuum fields could be demonstrated in induced
coherence experiments as the source of complementarity \cite{Heu14}. Here the
spatial coherence properties of these vacuum fields are measured and as the
physical reason for complementarity in single photon quantum optics
demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00161</id><created>2016-04-30</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yamanaka</keyname><forenames>Nodoka</forenames></author></authors><title>Electric dipole moment of the deuteron in the standard model with $NN -
  \Lambda N - \Sigma N$ coupling</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-293</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. A963 (2017) 33-51</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2017.04.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the electric dipole moment (EDM) of the deuteron in the standard
model with $|\Delta S| =1$ interactions by taking into account the $NN -
\Lambda N - \Sigma N$ channel coupling, which is an important nuclear level
systematics. The two-body problem is solved with the Gaussian Expansion Method
using the realistic Argonne $v18$ nuclear force and the $YN$ potential which
can reproduce the binding energies of $^3_\Lambda$H, $^3_\Lambda$He, and
$^4_\Lambda$He. The $|\Delta S| =1$ interbaryon potential is modeled by the
one-meson exchange process. It is found that the deuteron EDM is modified by
less than 10\%, and the main contribution to this deviation is due to the
polarization of the hyperon-nucleon channels. The effect of the $YN$
interaction is small, and treating $ \Lambda N$ and $ \Sigma N$ channels as
free is a good approximation for the EDM of the deuteron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06469</id><created>2016-05-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pekker</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shneider</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial stage of cavitation in liquids and its observation by Rayleigh
  scattering</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Fluid Dynamics Research 49 (2017) 035503</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1873-7005/aa6430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theory is developed for the initial stage of cavitation in the framework of
Zel'dovich-Fisher theory of nucleation in the field of negative pressure, while
taking into account the surface tension dependence on the nanopore radius. A
saturation mechanism is proposed that limits the exponential dependence of the
nucleation rate on the energy required to create nanopores. An estimate of the
saturated density of nanopores at the nucleation stage is obtained. It is shown
that Rayleigh scattering can detect nanopores arising at the initial stage of
cavitation development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06936</id><created>2016-05-23</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miyazaki</keyname><forenames>Jisho</forenames></author></authors><title>Composite systems and state transformations in topos quantum theory</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Corrections on thoerems, some new theorems, and different
  presentations of results. Title changed. Submitted to Foundation of Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topos quantum theory provides representations of quantum states as direct
generalizations of the probability distribution, namely probability valuation.
In this article, we consider extensions of a known bijective correspondence
between quantum states and probability valuations to composite systems and to
state transformations. We show that multipartite probability valuations on
composite systems have a bijective correspondence to positive over pure tensor
states, according to a candidate definition of the composite systems in topos
quantum theory. Among the multipartite probability valuations, a special
attention is placed to Markov chains which are defined by generalizing
classical Markov chains from probability theory. We find an incompatibility
between the multipartite probability valuations and a monogamy property of
quantum states, which trivializes the Markov chains to product probability
valuations. Several observations on the transformations of probability
valuations are deduced from the results on multipartite probability valuations,
through duality relations between multipartite states and state
transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05912</id><created>2016-06-19</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martinez-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarnita</keyname><forenames>Corina E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seasonality can induce coexistence of multiple bet-hedging strategies in
  Dictyostelium discoideum via storage effect</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jtbi.2017.05.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  D. discoideum has been recently suggested as an example of bet-hedging. Upon
starvation a population of unicellular amoebae splits between aggregators,
which form a fruiting body made of a stalk and resistant spores, and
non-aggregators. Spores are favored by long starvation periods, but vegetative
cells can exploit resources in fast-recovering environments. This partition can
be understood as a bet-hedging strategy that evolves in response to stochastic
starvation times. A genotype is defined by a different balance between each
type of cells. In this framework, if the ecological conditions are defined in
terms of the mean starvation time (i.e. time between onset of starvation and
the arrival of a new food pulse), a single genotype dominates each environment,
which is inconsistent with the huge genetic diversity observed in nature. We
investigate whether seasonality, represented by a periodic alternation in the
mean starvation times, allows the coexistence of several strategies. We use a
non-spatial (well-mixed) setting where different strains compete for a pulse of
resources. We find that seasonality, which we model via two seasons, induces a
temporal storage effect that can promote the stable coexistence of multiple
genotypes. Two conditions need to be met. First, the distributions of
starvation times in each season cannot overlap in order to create two well
differentiated habitats within the year. Second, numerous growth-starvation
cycles have to occur during each season to allow well-adapted strains to grow
and survive the subsequent unfavorable period. Additional tradeoffs among
life-history traits can expand the range of coexistence and increase the number
of coexisting strategies, contributing towards explaining the genetic diversity
observed in D. discoideum
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06498</id><created>2016-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Helmich-Paris</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Repisky</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Visscher</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author></authors><title>Laplace-transformed atomic orbital-based M{\o}ller-Plesset perturbation
  theory for relativistic two-component Hamiltonians</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>accepted for publication in The Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 014107 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4955106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a formulation of Laplace-transformed atomic orbital-based
second-order M{\o}ller-Plesset perturbation theory (MP2) energies for
two-component Hamiltonians in the Kramers-restricted formalism. This low-order
scaling technique can be used to enable correlated relativistic calculations
for large molecular systems. We show that the working equations to compute the
relativistic MP2 energy differ by merely a change of algebra (quaternion
instead of real) from their non-relativistic counterparts. With a
proof-of-principle implementation we study the effect of the nuclear charge on
the magnitude of half-transformed integrals and show that for light elements
spin-free and spin-orbit MP2 energies are almost identical. Furthermore, we
investigate the effect of separation of charge distributions on the Coulomb and
exchange energy con- tributions, which show the same long-range decay with the
inter-electronic / atomic distance as for non-relativistic MP2. A linearly
scaling implementation is possible if the proper distance behavior is
introduced to the quaternion Schwarz-type estimates as for non-relativistic
MP2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07820</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Breysse</keyname><forenames>Patrick C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>Mubdi</forenames></author></authors><title>Feeding cosmic star formation: Exploring high-redshift molecular gas
  with CO intensity mapping</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, Published in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx451</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of molecular gas is crucial for understanding star formation,
feedback, and the broader ecosystem of a galaxy as a whole. However, we have
limited understanding of its physics and distribution in all but the nearest
galaxies. We present a new technique for studying the composition and
distribution of molecular gas in high-redshift galaxies inaccessible to
existing methods. Our proposed approach is an extension of carbon monoxide
intensity mapping methods, which have garnered significant experimental
interest in recent years. These intensity mapping surveys target the 115 GHz
$^{12}$CO (1-0) line, but also contain emission from the substantially fainter
110 GHz $^{13}$CO (1-0) transition. The method leverages the information
contained in the $^{13}$CO line by cross-correlating pairs of frequency
channels in an intensity mapping survey. Since $^{13}$CO is emitted from the
same medium as the $^{12}$CO, but saturates at a much higher column density,
this cross-correlation provides valuable information about both the gas density
distribution and isotopologue ratio, inaccessible from the $^{12}$CO alone.
Using a simple model of these molecular emission lines, we show that a future
intensity mapping survey can constrain the abundance ratio of these two species
and the fraction of emission from optically thick regions to order $\sim30\%$.
These measurements cannot be made by traditional CO observations, and
consequently the proposed method will provide unique insight into the physics
of star formation, feedback, and galactic ecology at high redshifts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07923</id><created>2016-06-25</created><updated>2016-07-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barros</keyname><forenames>K. N. N. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for cosmological signatures of the Einstein equivalence
  principle breaking</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>2 figures, 5pages, To appear in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 023524 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.023524</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modifications of gravity generated by a multiplicative coupling of a scalar
field to the electromagnetic Lagrangian lead to a breaking of Einstein
equivalence principle (EEPB) as well as to variations of fundamental constants.
In these theoretical frameworks, deviations of standard values of the fine
structure constant, $\Delta \alpha/\alpha=\phi$, and of the cosmic distance
duality relation, $D_L(1+z)^{-2}/D_A=\eta=1$, where $D_L$ and $D_A$ are the
luminosity and angular diameter distances, respectively, are unequivocally
linked. In this paper, we search for cosmological signatures of the EEPB by
using angular diameter distance from galaxy clusters, obtained via their
Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect (SZE) and X-ray observations, and distance modulus of
type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). The crucial point here is that we take into
account the dependence of the SZE/X-ray technique with $\phi$ and $\eta$. Our
new results show no indication of the EEPB.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02326</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mahato</keyname><forenames>Naveen K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klar</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>Sudarshan</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle methods for multi-group pedestrian flow</title><categories>physics.soc-ph math.NA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a multi-group microscopic model for pedestrian flow describing
the behaviour of large groups. It is based on an interacting particle system
coupled to an eikonal equation. Hydrodynamic multi-group models are derived
from the underlying particle system as well as scalar multi-group models. The
eikonal equation is used to compute optimal paths for the pedestrians. Particle
methods are used to solve the equations on all levels of the hierarchy.
Numerical test cases are investigated and the models and, in particular, the
resulting evacuation times are compared for a wide range of different
parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02481</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saracco</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straka</keyname><forenames>Mika J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Clemente</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabrielli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldarelli</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Squartini</keyname><forenames>Tiziano</forenames></author></authors><title>Inferring monopartite projections of bipartite networks: an
  entropy-based approach</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.data-an q-fin.GN</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 053022 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6b38</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bipartite networks are currently regarded as providing a major insight into
the organization of many real-world systems, unveiling the mechanisms driving
the interactions occurring between distinct groups of nodes. One of the most
important issues encountered when modeling bipartite networks is devising a way
to obtain a (monopartite) projection on the layer of interest, which preserves
as much as possible the information encoded into the original bipartite
structure. In the present paper we propose an algorithm to obtain
statistically-validated projections of bipartite networks, according to which
any two nodes sharing a statistically-significant number of neighbors are
linked. Since assessing the statistical significance of nodes similarity
requires a proper statistical benchmark, here we consider a set of four null
models, defined within the exponential random graph framework. Our algorithm
outputs a matrix of link-specific p-values, from which a validated projection
is straightforwardly obtainable, upon running a multiple hypothesis testing
procedure. Finally, we test our method on an economic network (i.e. the
countries-products World Trade Web representation) and a social network (i.e.
MovieLens, collecting the users' ratings of a list of movies). In both cases
non-trivial communities are detected: while projecting the World Trade Web on
the countries layer reveals modules of similarly-industrialized nations,
projecting it on the products layer allows communities characterized by an
increasing level of complexity to be detected; in the second case, projecting
MovieLens on the films layer allows clusters of movies whose affinity cannot be
fully accounted for by genre similarity to be individuated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04623</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grie&#xdf;hammer</keyname><forenames>Harald W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>H. -W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Kolck</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Physics Around the Unitarity Limit</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, published version, rewritten for clarity</comments><report-no>INT-PUB-16-019</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 202501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.202501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that many features of the structure of nuclei emerge from a strictly
perturbative expansion around the unitarity limit, where the two-nucleon S
waves have bound states at zero energy. In this limit, the gross features of
states in the nuclear chart are correlated to only one dimensionful parameter,
which is related to the breaking of scale invariance to a discrete scaling
symmetry and set by the triton binding energy. Observables are moved to their
physical values by small, perturbative corrections, much like in descriptions
of the fine structure of atomic spectra. We provide evidence in favor of the
conjecture that light, and possibly heavier, nuclei are bound weakly enough to
be insensitive to the details of the interactions but strongly enough to be
insensitive to the exact size of the two-nucleon system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08881</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delcamp</keyname><forenames>Clement</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dittrich</keyname><forenames>Bianca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riello</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author></authors><title>Fusion basis for lattice gauge theory and loop quantum gravity</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc</categories><comments>72 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2017)061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new basis for the gauge-invariant Hilbert space of lattice
gauge theory and loop quantum gravity in $(2+1)$ dimensions, the fusion basis.
In doing so, we shift the focus from the original lattice (or spin-network)
structure directly to that of the magnetic (curvature) and electric (torsion)
excitations themselves. These excitations are classified by the irreducible
representations of the Drinfel'd double of the gauge group, and can be readily
&quot;fused&quot; together by studying the tensor product of such representations. We
will also describe in detail the ribbon operators that create and measure these
excitations and make the quasi-local structure of the observable algebra
explicit. Since the fusion basis allows for both magnetic and electric
excitations from the onset, it turns out to be a precious tool for studying the
large scale structure and coarse-graining flow of lattice gauge theories and
loop quantum gravity. This is in neat contrast with the widely used
spin-network basis, in which it is much more complicated to account for
electric excitations, i.e. for Gau\ss~constraint violations, emerging at larger
scales. Moreover, since the fusion basis comes equipped with a hierarchical
structure, it readily provides the language to design states with sophisticated
multi-scale structures. Another way to employ this hierarchical structure is to
encode a notion of subsystems for lattice gauge theories and $(2+1)$ gravity
coupled to point particles. In a follow-up work, we will exploit this notion to
provide a new definition of entanglement entropy for these theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00783</id><created>2016-08-02</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fetisov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gulyaeva</keyname><forenames>R. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>YBa2Cu3O6+d-originated attraction force giving rise to Meissner effect
  at 300 K</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages + 8 figures; this is an edited version of the original
  submission. Fig. 7 is changed</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The exposure of YBCO to an air atmosphere at first at pH2O = 110 Pa and then
at pH2O = 1 kPa has been used for uncharacteristic and unusual properties of
YBCO to be observed. Among them there was an increased reactivity of YBCO with
respect to water. Besides, it was experimentally obtained extremely excessive
weight gain of hydrated YBCO samples that was not corresponding to the quantity
of the absorbed water. Finally, we obtained the significant negative value of
the room-temperature (RT) magnetic susceptibility in conventional magnetic
study of the hydrated YBCO that was confirmed by the direct observation of
decreasing weight of the same samples that were suspended above the source of
controlled magnetic field (DC mode) at RT. All the results were explained on
the basis of an approximate idea that there is a certain source of attractive
force inside YBCO, acting on surrounding particles and bodies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03395</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Masatoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological superconductors: a review</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>45 pages, 18 figures, 286 references; final accepted version to
  appear in Rep. Prog. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 80, 076501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6633/aa6ac7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This review elaborates pedagogically on the fundamental concept, basic
theory, expected properties, and materials realizations of topological
superconductors. The relation between topological superconductivity and
Majorana fermions are explained, and the difference between dispersive Majorana
fermions and a localized Majorana zero mode is emphasized. A variety of routes
to topological superconductivity are explained with an emphasis on the roles of
spin-orbit coupling. Present experimental situations and possible signatures of
topological superconductivity are summarized with an emphasis on intrinsic
topological superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07189</id><created>2016-08-25</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harshman</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Infinite Barriers and Symmetries for a Few Trapped Particles in One
  Dimension</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages in two-column format, 9+ figures; v2 heavily revised
  (especially introduction) and new references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053616 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053616</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article investigates the properties of a few interacting particles
trapped in a few wells and how these properties change under adiabatic tuning
of interaction strength and inter-well tunneling. While some system properties
are dependent on the specific shapes of the traps and the interactions, this
article applies symmetry analysis to identify generic features in the spectrum
of stationary states of few-particle, few-well systems. Extended attention is
given to a simple but flexible three-parameter model of two particles in two
wells in one dimension. A key insight is that two limiting cases, hard-core
repulsion and no inter-well tunneling, can both be treated as emergent
symmetries of the few-particle Hamiltonian. These symmetries are the
mathematical consequences of infinite barriers in configuration space. They are
necessary to explain the pattern of degeneracies in the energy spectrum, to
understand how degeneracies are broken for models away from limiting cases, and
to explain separability and integrability. These symmetry methods are
extendable to more complicated models and the results have practical
consequences for stable state control in few-particle, few-well systems with
ultracold atoms in optical traps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00448</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2017-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Menghui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Liying</forenames></author><author><keyname>ZHang</keyname><forenames>Huina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhesi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chensheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jinshan</forenames></author></authors><title>Do Mathematicians, Economists and Biomedical Scientists Trace Large
  Topics More Strongly Than Physicists?</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DL cs.SI</categories><comments>11 papges, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Informetrics 11(2) 598-607 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.joi.2017.04.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we extend our previous work on largeness tracing among
physicists to other fields, namely mathematics, economics and biomedical
science. Overall, the results confirm our previous discovery, indicating that
scientists in all these fields trace large topics. Surprisingly, however, it
seems that researchers in mathematics tend to be more likely to trace large
topics than those in the other fields. We also find that on average, papers in
top journals are less largeness-driven. We compare researchers from the USA,
Germany, Japan and China and find that Chinese researchers exhibit consistently
larger exponents, indicating that in all these fields, Chinese researchers
trace large topics more strongly than others. Further correlation analyses
between the degree of largeness tracing and the numbers of authors,
affiliations and references per paper reveal positive correlations -- papers
with more authors, affiliations or references are likely to be more
largeness-driven, with several interesting and noteworthy exceptions: in
economics, papers with more references are not necessary more largeness-driven,
and the same is true for papers with more authors in biomedical science. We
believe that these empirical discoveries may be valuable to science
policy-makers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02571</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jie-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Junyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hao-Lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yi-Fu</forenames></author></authors><title>Tracing Primordial Black Holes in Nonsingular Bouncing Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures, comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 769 (2017) 561</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.03.036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We in this paper investigate the formation and evolution of primordial black
holes (PBHs) in nonsingular bouncing cosmologies. We discuss the formation of
PBH in the contracting phase and calculate the PBH abundance as a function of
the sound speed and Hubble parameter. Afterwards, by taking into account the
subsequent PBH evolution during the bouncing phase, we derive the density of
PBHs and their Hawking radiation. Our analysis shows that nonsingular bounce
models can be constrained from the backreaction of PBHs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04759</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yamanaka</keyname><forenames>Nodoka</forenames></author></authors><title>Review of the electric dipole moment of light nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>35 pages, 9 figures. review, published version</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-294</report-no><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. E26 (2017) 1730002</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218301317300028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this review, we summarize the theoretical development on the electric
dipole moment of light nuclei. We first describe the nucleon level CP violation
and its parametrization. We then present the results of calculations of the EDM
of light nuclei in the ab initio approach and in the cluster model. The
analysis of the effect of several models beyond standard model is presented,
together with the prospects for its discovery. The advantage of the electric
dipole moment of light nuclei is focused in the point of view of the many-body
physics. The evaluations of the nuclear electric dipole moment generated by the
$\theta$-term and by the CP phase of the Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa matrix are
also reviewed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04806</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04806</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delcamp</keyname><forenames>Clement</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dittrich</keyname><forenames>Bianca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riello</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author></authors><title>On entanglement entropy in non-Abelian lattice gauge theory and 3D
  quantum gravity</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc</categories><comments>25 pages + Appendices</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement entropy is a valuable tool for characterizing the correlation
structure of quantum field theories. When applied to gauge theories, subtleties
arise which prevent the factorization of the Hilbert space underlying the
notion of entanglement entropy. Borrowing techniques from extended topological
field theories, we introduce a new definition of entanglement entropy for both
Abelian and non-Abelian gauge theories. Being based on the notion of
excitations, it provides a completely relational way of defining regions.
Therefore, it naturally applies to background independent theories, e.g.
gravity, by circumventing the difficulty of specifying the position of the
entangling surface. We relate our construction to earlier proposals and argue
that it brings these closer to each other. In particular, it yields the
non-Abelian analogue of the &quot;magnetic centre choice&quot;, as obtained through an
extended-Hilbert-space method, but applied to the recently introduced fusion
basis for 3D lattice gauge theories. We point out that the different
definitions of entanglement theory can be related to a choice of (squeezed)
vacuum state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07080</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liberman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleeorin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogachevskii</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haugen</keyname><forenames>N. E. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanism of unconfined dust explosions: turbulent clustering and
  radiation-induced ignition</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.SR physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, REVTEX4-1, revised</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2016-98</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 051101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.051101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is known that unconfined dust explosions typically starts off with a
relatively weak primary flame followed by a severe secondary explosion. We show
that clustering of dust particles in a temperature stratified turbulent flow
ahead of the primary flame may give rise to a significant increase in the
radiation penetration length. These particle clusters, even far ahead of the
flame, are sufficiently exposed and heated by the radiation from the flame to
become ignition kernels capable to ignite a large volume of fuel-air mixtures.
This efficiently increases the total flame surface area and the effective
combustion speed, defined as the rate of reactant consumption of a given
volume. We show that this mechanism explains the high rate of combustion and
overpressures required to account for the observed level of damage in
unconfined dust explosions, e.g., at the 2005 Buncefield vapor-cloud explosion.
The effect of the strong increase of radiation transparency due to turbulent
clustering of particles goes beyond the state-of-the-art of the application to
dust explosions and has many implications in atmospheric physics and
astrophysics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07773</id><created>2016-09-25</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolgov</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudenko</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relic abundance of MeV millicharged particles</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures; references added; final version published in JETP</comments><journal-ref>J. Exp. Theor. Phys. 124 (2017) no. 4, 564-569</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776117030116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relic abundance of light millicharged particles (MCPs) with the electric
charge $e' = 5\cdot 10^{-5} e$ and with the mass slightly below or above the
electron mass is calculated. The abundance depends on the mass ratio
$\eta=m_X/m_e$ and for $\eta&lt;1$ can be high enough to allow MCPs to be the
cosmological dark matter or to make a noticeable contribution to it. On the
other hand, for $\eta \gtrsim 1$ the cosmological energy density of MCPs can be
quite low, $\Omega_X h_0^2 \approx 0.02$ for scalar MCPs, and $\Omega_X h_0^2
\approx 0.001$ for spin 1/2 fermions. But even the lowest value of $\Omega_X
h_0^2$ is in tension with several existing limits on the MCP abundances and
parameters. However, these limits have been derived under some natural or
reasonable assumptions on the properties of MCPs. If these assumptions are
relaxed, a patch in the mass-charge plot of MCPs may appear, permitting them to
be dark matter particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02375</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02375</id><created>2016-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calder</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrow</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upton</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lumsden</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodward</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christianson</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit coupling controlled $J=3/2$ electronic ground state in
  5$d^{3}$ oxides</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>main text plus supplemental information</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 207202 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.207202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement of spin and orbital degrees of freedom drives the formation of
novel quantum and topological physical states. Discovering new spin-orbit
entangled ground states and emergent phases of matter requires both
experimentally probing the relevant energy scales and applying suitable
theoretical models. Here we report resonant inelastic x-ray scattering
measurements of the transition metal oxides Ca$_3$LiOsO$_6$ and Ba$_2$YOsO$_6$.
We invoke an intermediate coupling approach that incorporates both spin-orbit
coupling and electron-electron interactions on an even footing and reveal the
ground state of $5d^3$ based compounds, which has remained elusive in
previously applied models, is a novel spin-orbit entangled J=3/2 electronic
ground state. This work reveals the hidden diversity of spin-orbit controlled
ground states in 5d systems and introduces a new arena in the search for
spin-orbit controlled phases of matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02691</id><created>2016-11-08</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fried</keyname><forenames>Herbert M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsang</keyname><forenames>Peter H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabellini</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandou</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheu</keyname><forenames>Yeuan Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of Gluon Bundle based QCD Curves with ISR Elastic pp
  Scattering Data</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using previously described functional techniques for exact, non-perturbative,
gauge-invariant renormalized QCD processes, a simplified version of the
amplitudes - in which forms akin to Pomerons naturally appear - provides fits
to ISR Elastic pp scattering data. Extension of this work to LHC reactions is
presently underway.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09998</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Fuyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Qingsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xianhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiaofeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring magnetic field inside a microwave cavity via Rabi resonances
  in Cs atoms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a technique for measuring microwave (MW) field based on Rabi
resonances induced by the interaction of atoms with a phase-modulated MW field.
A theoretical model of field measurement is used to calculate Rabi frequency.
Single-peak feature of the measurement model makes the technique a valuable
tool for simple and fast field measurement. As an example, we use the technique
to determine the MW field strength inside a Cs vapor cell in the X-band
rectangular cavity for applied power in the range of -21 dBm to 20 dBm. The
results show that this proposed technique is capable for detecting the field
over a broad dynamical range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00009</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Hiren H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Package-X 2.0: A Mathematica package for the analytic calculation of
  one-loop integrals</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Package files are available at http://packagex.hepforge.org</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2017.04.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article summarizes new features and enhancements of the first major
update of Package-X. Package-X 2.0 can now generate analytic expressions for
arbitrarily high rank dimensionally regulated tensor integrals with up to four
distinct propagators, each with arbitrary integer weight, near an arbitrary
even number of spacetime dimensions, giving UV divergent, IR divergent, and
finite parts at (almost) any real-valued kinematic point. Additionally, it can
generate multivariable Taylor series expansions of these integrals around any
non-singular kinematic point to arbitrary order. All special functions and
abbreviations output by Package-X 2.0 supports Mathematica's arbitrary
precision evaluation capabilities to deal with issues of numerical stability.
Finally, tensor algebraic routines of Package-X have been polished and extended
to support open fermion chains both on and off shell. The documentation
(equivalent to over 100 printed pages) is accessed through Mathematica's
Wolfram Documentation Center and contains information on all Package-X symbols,
with over 300 basic usage examples, 3 project-scale tutorials, and instructions
on linking to FeynCalc and LoopTools.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00096</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fukaya</keyname><forenames>Hidenori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onogi</keyname><forenames>Tetsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamura</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author></authors><title>Six-dimensional regularization of chiral gauge theories on a lattice</title><categories>hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>14pages, 2figures, Proceedings of the 34th annual International
  Symposium on Lattice Field Theory. PoS(LATTICE2016)330, References added</comments><report-no>OU-HET-916</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a six-dimensional regularization of four dimensional chiral gauge
theories. We consider a massive Dirac fermion in six dimensions with two
different operators having domain-wall profiles in the fifth and the sixth
directions, respectively. A Weyl fermion appears as a localized mode at the
junction of the two domain-walls. In our formulation, the Stora-Zumino chain of
the anomaly descent equations, starting from the axial $U(1)$ anomaly in
six-dimensions to the gauge anomaly in four-dimensions, is naturally embedded.
Moreover, a similar inflow of the global anomalies is found. The anomaly free
condition is equivalent to requiring that the axial $U(1)$ anomaly and the
parity anomaly are canceled among the six-dimensional Dirac fermions. Putting
the gauge field at the four- dimensional junction and extending it to the bulk
using the Yang-Mills gradient flow, as recently proposed by Grabowska and
Kaplan, we define the four-dimensional path integral of the target chiral gauge
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01727</id><created>2016-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Isacsson</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cummings</keyname><forenames>Aron W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colombo</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colombo</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kinaret</keyname><forenames>Jari M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roche</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling Properties of Polycrystalline Graphene: A Review</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures. Accepted for publications in 2D Materials</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials, vol 4, 012002 (2017) (open access)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa5147</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an overview of the electrical, mechanical, and thermal properties
of polycrystalline graphene. Most global properties of this material, such as
the charge mobility, thermal conductivity, or Young's modulus, are sensitive to
its microstructure, for instance the grain size and the presence of line or
point defects. Both the local and global features of polycrystalline graphene
have been investigated by a variety of simulations and experimental
measurements. In this review, we summarize the properties of polycrystalline
graphene, and by establishing a perspective on how the microstructure impacts
its large-scale physical properties, we aim to provide guidance for further
optimization and improvement of applications based on this material, such as
flexible and wearable electronics, and high-frequency or spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07331</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Seveso</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris</keyname><forenames>Matteo G. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Can quantum probes satisfy the weak equivalence principle?</title><categories>gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics, Volume 380, May 2017, Pages 213-223</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.03.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the question whether quantum probes in a gravitational field can
be considered as test particles obeying the weak equivalence principle (WEP). A
formulation of the WEP is proposed which applies also in the quantum regime,
while maintaining the physical content of its classical counterpart. Such
formulation requires the introduction of a gravitational field not to modify
the Fisher information about the mass of a freely-falling probe, extractable
through measurements of its position. We discover that, while in a uniform
field quantum probes satisfy our formulation of the WEP exactly, gravity
gradients can encode nontrivial information about the particle's mass in its
wavefunction, leading to violations of the WEP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09365</id><created>2016-12-29</created><updated>2017-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos-da-Costa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for deviations from the General Relativity Theory with gas
  mass fraction of galaxy clusters and complementary probes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures. Accepted for publication in Physical Review D.
  The authors thank the anonymous referee for the valuable suggestions</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 084006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nowadays, thanks to the improved precision of cosmological data, it has been
possible to search for deviation from the general relativity theory with tests
on large cosmic scales. Particularly, there is a class of modified gravity
theories that breaks the Einstein equivalence principle (EEP) in the
electromagnetic sector, generating variations of the fine structure constant,
violations of the cosmic distance duality relation and the evolution law of the
cosmic microwave background (CMB) radiation. In recent papers, this class of
theories has been tested with angular diameter distances from galaxy clusters,
type Ia supernovae and CMB temperature.
  In this work we propose a new test by considering the most recent X-ray
surface brightness observations of galaxy clusters jointly with type Ia
supernovae and CMB temperature. {The crucial point here is that we take into
account the dependence of the X-ray gas mass fraction of galaxy clusters on
possible variations of the fine structure constant and violations of the cosmic
distance duality relation.} Our basic result is that this new approach is
competitive with the previous one and it also does not show significant
deviations from the general relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00936</id><created>2017-01-04</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>Ludovic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parisi</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-scale structure of randomly jammed particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figs</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 052125 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.052125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically analyse the density field of three-dimensional randomly jammed
packings of monodisperse soft frictionles spherical particles, paying special
attention to fluctuations occurring at large lengthscales. We study in detail
the two-point static structure factor at low wavevectors in Fourier space. We
also analyse the nature of the density field in real space by studying the
large-distance behavior of the two-point pair correlation function, of density
fluctuations in subsystems of increasing sizes, and of the direct correlation
function. We show that such real space analysis can be greatly improved by
introducing a coarse-grained density field to disentangle genuine large-scale
correlations from purely local effects. Our results confirm that both Fourier
and real space signatures of vanishing density fluctuations at large scale are
absent, indicating that randomly jammed packings are not hyperuniform. In
addition, we establish that the pair correlation function displays a
surprisingly complex structure at large distances, which is however not
compatible with the long-range negative correlation of hyperuniform systems but
fully compatible with an analytic form for the structure factor. This implies
that the direct correlation function is short-ranged, as we also demonstrate
directly. Our results reveal that density fluctuations in jammed packings do
not follow the behavior expected for random hyperuniform materials, but display
instead a more complex behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01839</id><created>2017-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>Sergey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frydendahl</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beermann</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenger</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coello</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mortensen</keyname><forenames>N. Asger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>White light generation and anisotropic damage in gold films near
  percolation threshold</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>42 pages in total of the main (27 pages) and supplementary (15 pages)
  material with 4 main and 10 supplementary figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 4, 1207 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strongly enhanced and confined electromagnetic fields generated in metal
nanostructures upon illumination are exploited in many emerging technologies by
either fabricating sophisticated nanostructures or synthesizing colloid
nanoparticles. Here we study effects driven by field enhancement in vanishingly
small gaps between gold islands in thin films near the electrically determined
percolation threshold. Optical explorations using two-photon luminescence (TPL)
and near-field microscopies reveals super-cubic TPL power dependencies with
white-light spectra, establishing unequivocally that the strongest TPL signals
are generated with close to the percolation threshold films, and occurrence of
extremely confined (~ 30 nm)and strongly enhanced (~ 100 times) fields at the
illumination wavelength. For linearly polarized and sufficiently powerful
light, we observe pronounced optical damage with TPL images being sensitive to
both wavelength and polarization of illuminating light. We relate these effects
to thermally induced morphological changes observed with scanning electron
microscopy images. Fascinating physics involved in light interaction with
near-percolation metal films along with their straightforward and scalable
one-step fabrication procedure promises a wide range of fascinating
developments and technological applications within diverse areas of modern
nanotechnology, from bio-molecule optical sensing to ultra-dense optical data
storage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03030</id><created>2017-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Buhl</keyname><forenames>Patrick M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freimuth</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;gel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokrousov</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological spin Hall effect in antiferromagnetic skyrmions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Status Solidi RRL 11, No. 4, 1700007 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssr.201700007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topological Hall effect (THE), as one of the primary manifestations of
non-trivial topology of chiral skyrmions, is traditionally used to detect the
emergence of skyrmion lattices with locally ferromagnetic order. In this work
we demonstrate that the appearance of non-trivial two-dimensional chiral
textures with locally {\it anti}-ferromagnetic order can be detected through
the spin version of the THE $-$ the topological spin Hall effect (TSHE).
Utilizing the semiclassical formalism, here used to combine chiral
antiferromagnetic textures with a density functional theory description of the
collinear, degenerate electronic structure, we follow the real-space real-time
evolution of electronic SU(2) wavepackets in an external electric field to
demonstrate the emergence of sizeable transverse pure spin current in synthetic
antiferromagnets of the Fe/Cu/Fe trilayer type. We further unravel the extreme
sensitivity of the TSHE to the details of the electronic structure, suggesting
that the magnitude and sign of the TSHE in transition-metal synthetic
antiferromagnets can be engineered by tuning such parameters as the thickness
or band filling. Besides being an important step in our understanding of the
topological properties of ever more complex skyrmionic systems, our results
bear great potential in stimulating the discovery of antiferromagnetic
skyrmions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07250</id><created>2017-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cola&#xe7;o</keyname><forenames>L. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gon&#xe7;alves</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcaniz</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Limits on evolution of the fine-structure constant in runaway dilaton
  models from Sunyaev-Zeldovich Observations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, PLB accepted</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, new bounds on possible variations of the fine structure
constant, $\alpha$, for a class of runaway dilaton models are performed. By
considering a possible evolution with redshift, $z$, such as
$\frac{\Delta\alpha}{\alpha}=-\gamma\ln(1+z)$, where in $\gamma$ are the
physical properties of the model, we constrain this parameter by using a
deformed cosmic distance duality relation jointly with gas mass fraction (GMF)
measurements of galaxy clusters and luminosity distances of type Ia supernovae.
The GMF's used in our analyses are from cluster mass data from 82 galaxy
clusters in the redshift range $0.12&lt;z&lt;1.36$, detected via the
Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect at 148 GHz by the Atacama Cosmology Telescope. The
type Ia supernovae are from the Union2.1 compilation. We also explore the
dependence of the results from four models used to describe the galaxy
clusters. As a result no evidence of variation was obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00213</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ryl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying nonclassicality by characteristic functions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053825 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053825</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we use the characteristic function, i.e., the Fourier
transform of the Glauber-Sudarshan phase-space distribution, to find the degree
of nonclassicality of a given state. This degree of nonclassicality quantifies
the nonclassicality in terms of quantum superpositions. We demonstrate two ways
to determine or to estimate the degree of nonclassicality by studying the
properties of the characteristic functions. The developed criteria are applied
to two examples of squeezed states undergoing a classical mixing or a
nonclassical superposition with vacuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02117</id><created>2017-02-07</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baldes</keyname><forenames>Iason</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational waves from the asymmetric-dark-matter generating phase
  transition</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 figures. V2: corrected typo, added references. V3: small
  corrections, added references</comments><report-no>DESY 17-021</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 1705 (2017) 028</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/05/028</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The baryon asymmetry, together with a dark matter asymmetry, may be produced
during a first order phase transition in a generative sector. We study the
possibility of a gravitational wave signal in a model realising such a
scenario. We identify areas of parameter space with strong phase transitions
which can be probed by future, space based, gravitational wave detectors. Other
signals of this scenario include collider signatures of a $Z'$, DM self
interactions, a contribution to $\Delta N_{\rm eff}$ and nuclear recoils at
direct detection experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03811</id><created>2017-02-13</created><updated>2017-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>Carl M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanpour</keyname><forenames>Nima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hook</keyname><forenames>Daniel W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klevansky</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xfc;nderhauf</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Zichao</forenames></author></authors><title>Behavior of eigenvalues in a region of broken-PT symmetry</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 052113 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PT-symmetric quantum mechanics began with a study of the Hamiltonian
$H=p^2+x^2(ix)^\varepsilon$. When $\varepsilon\geq0$, the eigenvalues of this
non-Hermitian Hamiltonian are discrete, real, and positive. This portion of
parameter space is known as the region of unbroken PT symmetry. In the region
of broken PT symmetry $\varepsilon&lt;0$ only a finite number of eigenvalues are
real and the remaining eigenvalues appear as complex-conjugate pairs. The
region of unbroken PT symmetry has been studied but the region of broken PT
symmetry has thus far been unexplored. This paper presents a detailed numerical
and analytical examination of the behavior of the eigenvalues for
$-4&lt;\varepsilon&lt;0$. In particular, it reports the discovery of an
infinite-order exceptional point at $\varepsilon=-1$, a transition from a
discrete spectrum to a partially continuous spectrum at $\varepsilon=-2$, a
transition at the Coulomb value $\varepsilon=-3$, and the behavior of the
eigenvalues as $\varepsilon$ approaches the conformal limit $\varepsilon=-4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05490</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crisford</keyname><forenames>Toby</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Jorge E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Violating weak cosmic censorship in AdS$_4$</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 181101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.181101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider time-dependent solutions of the Einstein-Maxwell equations using
anti-de Sitter (AdS) boundary conditions, and provide the first counterexample
to the weak cosmic censorship conjecture in four spacetime dimensions. Our
counterexample is entirely formulated in the Poincar\'e patch of AdS. We claim
that our results have important consequences for quantum gravity, most notably
to the weak gravity conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05771</id><created>2017-02-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Janet</keyname><forenames>Jon Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulik</keyname><forenames>Heather J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting Electronic Structure Properties of Transition Metal Complexes
  with Neural Networks</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>26 pages of text, 13 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Chemical Science, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7SC01247K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-throughput computational screening has emerged as a critical component
of materials discovery. Direct density functional theory (DFT) simulation of
inorganic materials and molecular transition metal complexes is often used to
describe subtle trends in inorganic bonding and spin-state ordering, but these
calculations are computationally costly and properties are sensitive to the
exchange-correlation functional employed. To begin to overcome these
challenges, we trained artificial neural networks (ANNs) to predict
quantum-mechanically-derived properties, including spin-state ordering,
sensitivity to Hartree-Fock exchange, and spin- state specific bond lengths in
transition metal complexes. Our ANN is trained on a small set of
inorganic-chemistry-appropriate empirical inputs that are both maximally
transferable and do not require precise three-dimensional structural
information for prediction. Using these descriptors, our ANN predicts
spin-state splittings of single-site transition metal complexes (i.e., Cr-Ni)
at arbitrary amounts of Hartree-Fock exchange to within 3 kcal/mol accuracy of
DFT calculations. Our exchange-sensitivity ANN enables improved predictions on
a diverse test set of experimentally-characterized transition metal complexes
by extrapolation from semi-local DFT to hybrid DFT. The ANN also outperforms
other machine learning models (i.e., support vector regression and kernel ridge
regression), demonstrating particularly improved performance in
transferability, as measured by prediction errors on the diverse test set. We
establish the value of new uncertainty quantification tools to estimate ANN
prediction uncertainty in computational chemistry, and we provide additional
heuristics for identification of when a compound of interest is likely to be
poorly predicted by the ANN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05991</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caracciolo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Achille</keyname><forenames>Matteo P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malatesta</keyname><forenames>Enrico M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sicuro</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size corrections in the random assignment problem</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 052129 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.052129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analytically derive, in the context of the replica formalism, the first
finite size corrections to the average optimal cost in the random assignment
problem for a quite generic distribution law for the costs. We show that, when
moving from a power-law distribution to a $\Gamma$ distribution, the leading
correction changes both in sign and in its scaling properties. We also examine
the behavior of the corrections when approaching a $\delta$-function
distribution. By using a numerical solution of the saddle-point equations, we
provide predictions that are confirmed by numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07562</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lozada-Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esfandiar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigorieva</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geim</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalable and efficient separation of hydrogen isotopes using
  graphene-based electrochemical pumping</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications (2017) 15215</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15215</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thousands of tons of isotopic mixtures are processed annually for heavy-water
production and tritium decontamination. The existing technologies remain
extremely energy intensive and require large capital investments. New
approaches are needed to reduce the industry's footprint. Recently, micron-size
crystals of graphene were shown to act as efficient sieves for hydrogen
isotopes pumped through graphene electrochemically. Here we report a
fully-scalable approach, using graphene obtained by chemical vapor deposition,
which allows a proton-deuteron separation factor of ca. 8, despite cracks and
imperfections. The energy consumption is projected to be orders of magnitude
smaller with respect to existing technologies. A membrane based on 30 m2 of
graphene, a readily accessible amount, could provide a heavy-water output
comparable to that of modern plants. Even higher efficiency is expected for
tritium separation. With no fundamental obstacles for scaling up, the
technology's simplicity, efficiency and green credentials call for
consideration by the nuclear and related industries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07724</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Christiansen</keyname><forenames>Nicolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichhorn</keyname><forenames>Astrid</forenames></author></authors><title>An asymptotically safe solution to the U(1) triviality problem</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages plus references; 5 figures; version identical with published
  one; slight change in notation; discussion of effect of charged matter added</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore whether quantum gravity effects within the asymptotic safety
paradigm can provide a predictive ultraviolet completion for Abelian gauge
theories. We evaluate the effect of quantum gravity fluctuations on the running
couplings in the gauge sector and discover an asymptotically safe fixed point
of the Renormalization Group. In particular, if the strength of gravitational
interactions remains below a critical strength, the minimal gauge coupling
becomes asymptotically free. Further, we point out that a completely
asymptotically free dynamics for the gauge field is impossible to achieve, as
asymptotically safe quantum gravity necessarily induces nonvanishing
higher-order interactions for the gauge field in the ultraviolet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01452</id><created>2017-03-04</created><updated>2017-05-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Ze-Di</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Di</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi-Wang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Jian-Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jin-Shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guang-Can</forenames></author></authors><title>Degenerate cavity supporting more than 31 Laguerre-Gaussian modes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, optics letters</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 42, Issue 10, pp. 2042-2045 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.002042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photons propagating in Laguerre-Gaussian modes have characteristic orbital
angular momentums, which are fundamental optical degrees of freedom. The
orbital angular momentum of light has potential application in high capacity
optical communication and even in quantum information processing. In this work,
we experimentally construct a ring cavity with 4 lenses and 4 mirrors that is
completely degenerate for Laguerre-Gaussian modes. By measuring the
transmission peaks and patterns of different modes, the ring cavity is shown to
supporting more than 31 Laguerre-Gaussian modes. The constructed degenerate
cavity opens a new way for using the unlimited resource of available angular
momentum states simultaneously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02753</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-04-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marbach</keyname><forenames>Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bocquet</keyname><forenames>Lyd&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Osmotic and diffusio-osmotic flow generation at high solute
  concentration. I. Mechanical approaches</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 194701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4982221</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we explore various forms of osmotic transport in the regime of
high solute concentration. We consider both the osmosis across membranes and
diffusio-osmosis at solid interfaces, driven by solute concentration gradients.
We follow a mechanical point of view of osmotic transport, which allows us to
gain much insight into the local mechanical balance underlying osmosis. We
demonstrate in particular how the general expression of the osmotic pressure
for mixtures, as obtained classically from the thermodynamic framework, emerges
from the mechanical balance controlling non-equilibrium transport under solute
gradients. Expressions for the rejection coefficient of osmosis and the
diffusio-osmotic mobilities are accordingly obtained. These results generalize
existing ones in the dilute solute regime to mixtures with arbitrary
concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02759</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-04-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marbach</keyname><forenames>Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bocquet</keyname><forenames>Lyd&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Osmotic and diffusio-osmotic flow generation at high solute
  concentration. II. Molecular dynamics simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 194702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981794</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we explore osmotic transport by means of molecular dynamics
(MD) simulations. We first consider osmosis through a membrane, and investigate
the reflection coefficient of an imperfectly semi-permeable membrane, in the
dilute and high concentration regimes. We then explore the diffusion-osmotic
flow of a solute-solvent fluid adjacent to a solid surface, driven by a
chemical potential gradient parallel to the surface. We propose a novel
non-equilibrium MD (NEMD) methodology to simulate diffusion-osmosis, by
imposing an external force on every particle, which properly mimics the
chemical potential gradient on the solute in spite of the periodic boundary
conditions. This NEMD method is validated theoretically on the basis of
linear-response theory by matching the mobility with their Green-Kubo
expressions. Finally, we apply the framework to more realistic systems, namely
a water-ethanol mixture in contact with a silica or a graphene surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04306</id><created>2017-03-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Morawetz</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum currents and pair correlation of electrons in a chain of
  localized dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>EPJB in press</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 90 (2017) 1-9</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-70642-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum transport of electrons in a wire of localized dots by hopping,
interaction and dissipation is calculated and a representation by an equivalent
RCL circuit is found. The exact solution for the electric-field induced
currents allows to discuss the role of virtual currents to decay initial
correlations and Bloch oscillations. The dynamical response function in random
phase approximation (RPA) is calculated analytically with the help of which the
static structure function and pair correlation function are determined. The
pair correlation function contains a form factor from the Brillouin zone and a
structure factor caused by the localized dots in the wire.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05554</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rigovacca</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farace</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Leonardo A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Pasquale</keyname><forenames>Antonella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovannetti</keyname><forenames>Vittorio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Versatile Gaussian probes for squeezing estimation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 + 7 pages, 6 + 3 figures; close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 052331 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052331</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an instance of black-box quantum metrology in the Gaussian
framework, where we aim to estimate the amount of squeezing applied on an input
probe, without previous knowledge on the phase of the applied squeezing. By
taking the quantum Fisher information (QFI) as the figure of merit, we evaluate
its average and variance with respect to this phase in order to identify probe
states that yield good precision for many different squeezing directions. We
first consider the case of single-mode Gaussian probes with the same energy,
and find that pure squeezed states maximize the average quantum Fisher
information (AvQFI) at the cost of a performance that oscillates strongly as
the squeezing direction is changed. Although the variance can be brought to
zero by correlating the probing system with a reference mode, the maximum AvQFI
cannot be increased in the same way. A different scenario opens if one takes
into account the effects of photon losses: coherent states represent the
optimal single-mode choice when losses exceed a certain threshold and,
moreover, correlated probes can now yield larger AvQFI values than all
single-mode states, on top of having zero variance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06761</id><created>2017-03-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames><affiliation>UPMC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Jihong</forenames><affiliation>UPMC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bonello</keyname><forenames>Bernard</forenames><affiliation>UPMC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Jianfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Dianlong</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave propagation in one-dimensional nonlinear acoustic metamaterials</title><categories>nlin.PS nlin.CD physics.class-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6d49</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The propagation of waves in the nonlinear acoustic metamaterials (NAMs) is
fundamentally different from that in the conventional linear ones. In this
article we consider two one-dimensional NAM systems featuring respectively a
diatomic and a tetratomic meta unit-cell. We investigate the attenuation of the
wave, the band structure and the bifurcations to demonstrate novel nonlinear
effects, which can significantly expand the bandwidth for elastic wave
suppression and cause nonlinear wave phenomena. Harmonic averaging approach,
continuation algorithm, Lyapunov exponents are combined to study the frequency
responses, the nonlinear modes, bifurcations of periodic solutions and chaos.
The nonlinear resonances are studied and the influence of damping on
hyper-chaotic attractors is evaluated. Moreover, a &quot;quantum&quot; behavior is found
between the low-energy and high-energy orbits. This work provides an important
theoretical base for the further understandings and applications of NAMs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07716</id><created>2017-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Zannotti</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diebel</keyname><forenames>Falko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boguslawski</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denz</keyname><forenames>Cornelia</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical catastrophes of the swallowtail and butterfly beams</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 053004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6ecd</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally realize higher-order catastrophic structures in light
fields to access the rich class of caustic swallowtail and butterfly beams.
These beams present solutions of paraxial diffraction catastrophe integrals
that are determined by potential functions, whose singular mapping manifests as
caustic hypersurfaces in control parameter space. We systematically analyze the
swallowtail and butterfly beams' caustics analytically and observe their field
distributions experimentally in real and Fourier space. Their spectra can be
described by polynomials or expressions with rational exponents capable to form
a cusp.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03613</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuqiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashi</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tohei</keyname><forenames>Tetsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Isao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikuhara</keyname><forenames>Yuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>Hiromichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric phase diagram of the SrTiO3-SrNbO3 solid solution system</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 121, 185102-1-7(2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermoelectric energy conversion - the exploitation of the Seebeck effect to
convert waste heat into electricity - has attracted an increasing amount of
research attention for energy harvesting technology. Niobium-doped strontium
titanate (SrTi1-xNbxO3) is one of the most promising thermoelectric material
candidates, particularly as it poses a much lesser environmental risk in
comparison to materials based on heavy metal elements. Two-dimensional electron
confinement, e.g. through the formation of superlattices or two-dimensional
electron gases, is recognized as an effective strategy to improve the
thermoelectric performance of SrTi1-xNbxO3. Although electron confinement is
closely related to the electronic structure, the fundamental electronic phase
behavior of the SrTi1-xNbxO3 solid solution system has yet to be
comprehensively investigated. Here, we present a thermoelectric phase diagram
for the SrTi1-xNbxO3 (0.05 =&lt; x =&lt; 1) solid solution system, which we derived
from the characterization of epitaxial films. We observed two thermoelectric
phase boundaries in the system, which originate from the step-like decrease in
carrier effective mass at x ~ 0.3, and from a local minimum in carrier
relaxation time at x ~ 0.5. The origins of these phase boundaries are
considered to be related to isovalent/heterovalent B-site substitution:
parabolic Ti 3d orbitals dominate electron conduction for compositions with x &lt;
0.3, whereas the Nb 4d orbital dominates when x &gt; 0.3. At x ~ 0.5, a tetragonal
distortion of the lattice, in which the B-site is composed of Ti4+ and Nb4+
ions, leads to the formation of tail-like impurity bands, which maximizes the
electron scattering. These results provide a foundation for further research
into improving the thermoelectric performance of SrTi1-xNbxO3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05763</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gobrecht</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>INAF - OA Teramo, Teramo, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cristallo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames><affiliation>INAF - OA Teramo, Teramo, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Piersanti</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames><affiliation>INAF - OA Teramo, Teramo, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bromley</keyname><forenames>Stefan T.</forenames><affiliation>IQTCUB, Barcelona, Spain</affiliation><affiliation>ICREA, Barcelona, Spain</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nucleation of small silicon carbide dust clusters in AGB stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 25 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ (2017), Vol. 840, page 117</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6db0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Silicon carbide (SiC) grains are a major dust component in carbon-rich AGB
stars. The formation pathways of these grains are, however, not fully
understood.\ We calculate ground states and energetically low-lying structures
of (SiC)$_n$, $n=1,16$ clusters by means of simulated annealing (SA) and Monte
Carlo simulations of seed structures and subsequent quantum-mechanical
calculations on the density functional level of theory. We derive the infrared
(IR) spectra of these clusters and compare the IR signatures to observational
and laboratory data.\ According to energetic considerations, we evaluate the
viability of SiC cluster growth at several densities and temperatures,
characterising various locations and evolutionary states in circumstellar
envelopes.\ We discover new, energetically low-lying structures for
Si$_{4}$C$_{4}$, Si$_{5}$C$_{5}$, Si$_{15}$C$_{15}$ and Si$_{16}$C$_{16}$, and
new ground states for Si$_{10}$C$_{10}$ and Si$_{15}$C$_{15}$. The clusters
with carbon-segregated substructures tend to be more stable by 4-9 eV than
their bulk-like isomers with alternating Si-C bonds. However, we find ground
states with cage (&quot;bucky&quot;-like) geometries for Si$_{12}$C$_{12}$ and
Si$_{16}$C$_{16}$ and low-lying, stable cage structures for n $\ge$ 12. The
latter findings indicate thus a regime of clusters sizes that differs from
small clusters as well as from large-scale crystals. Thus, and owing to their
stability and geometry, the latter clusters may mark a transition from a
quantum-confined cluster regime to crystalline, solid bulk-material.
  The calculated vibrational IR spectra of the ground-state SiC clusters shows
significant emission. They include the 10-13 $\mu$m wavelength range and the
11.3 $\mu$m feature inferred from laboratory measurements and observations,
respectively, though the overall intensities are rather low.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06653</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Shamir</keyname><forenames>M. Farasat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanwal</keyname><forenames>Fiza</forenames></author></authors><title>Noether Symmetry Analysis of Anisotropic Universe in Modified Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 Pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77(2017)286</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4869-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study anisotropic universe using Noether symmetries in
modified gravity. In particular, we choose locally rotationally symmetric
Bianchi type-$I$ universe for the analysis in $f(R,\mathcal{G})$ gravity, where
$R$ is the Ricci scalar and $\mathcal{G}$ is the Gauss-Bonnet invariant.
Firstly, a model $f(R,\mathcal{G})=f_0R^l+f_1\mathcal{G}^n$ is proposed and the
corresponding Noether symmetries are investigated. Further, we have also
recovered the Noether symmetries for $f(R)$ and $f(\mathcal{G})$ theories of
gravity. Secondly, some important cosmological solutions are reconstructed.
Exponential and power law solutions are reported for a well-known
$f(R,\mathcal{G})$ model, i.e., $f(R,\mathcal{G})=f_0R^n\mathcal{G}^{1-n}$.
Especially, the Kasner's solution is recovered and it is anticipated that the
familiar de-Sitter spacetime giving $\Lambda CDM$ cosmology may be
reconstructed for some suitable value of $n$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00738</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Pallavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ananth</keyname><forenames>Nandini</forenames></author></authors><title>An Almost Analytical Approach to Simulating 2D Electronic Spectra</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an almost analytical method to simulate 2D electronic spectra as
a double Fourier transform of the the non-linear response function (NRF)
corresponding to a particular optical pulse sequence. We employ a unitary
transformation to represent the total system Hamiltonian in a stationary basis
that allows us to separate contributions from decoherence and phonon-mediated
population relaxation to the NRF. Previously, one of us demonstrated the use of
an analytic, cumulant expansion approach to calculate the decoherence term.
Here, we extend this idea to obtain an accurate expression for the population
relaxation term, a significant improvement over standard quantum master
equation-based approximations. We numerically demonstrate the accuracy of our
method by computing the photon echo spectrum of a two-level system coupled to a
thermal bath, and we highlight the mechanistic insights obtained from our
simulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01612</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Perera</keyname><forenames>B. B. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stappers</keyname><forenames>B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyne</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassa</keyname><forenames>C. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cognard</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillemot</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theureau</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desvignes</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence for an intermediate-mass black hole in the globular cluster NGC
  6624</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures, Accepted by MNRAS on 23 February 2017. Erratum
  was accepted by MNRAS on 17 May 2017</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 468, 2114-2127 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PSR B1820$-$30A is located in the globular cluster NGC 6624 and is the
closest known pulsar to the centre of any globular cluster. We present more
than 25 years of high-precision timing observations of this millisecond pulsar
and obtain four rotational frequency time derivative measurements. Modelling
these higher-order derivatives as being due to orbital motion, we find
solutions which indicate that the pulsar is in either a low-eccentricity
($0.33\lesssim e\lesssim0.4$) smaller orbit with a low mass companion (such as
a main sequence star, white dwarf, neutron star, or stellar mass black hole) or
a high-eccentricity ($e\gtrsim0.9$) larger orbit with a massive companion. The
cluster mass properties and the observed properties of 4U 1820$-$30 and the
other pulsars in the cluster argue against the low-eccentricity possibility.
The high-eccentricity solution reveals that the pulsar is most likely orbiting
around an intermediate-mass black hole (IMBH) of mass $&gt; 7,500$~M$_\odot$
located at the cluster centre. A gravitational model for the globular cluster,
which includes such a central black hole (BH), predicts an acceleration that is
commensurate with that measured for the pulsar. It further predicts that the
model-dependent minimum mass of the IMBH is $\sim60,000$~M$_\odot$. Accounting
for the associated contribution to the observed period derivative indicates
that the $\gamma$-ray efficiency of the pulsar should be between 0.08 and 0.2.
Our results suggest that other globular clusters may also contain central black
holes and they may be revealed by the study of new pulsars found sufficiently
close to their centres.
  Note that we found an erratum in Section 5 and thus, the
$\sim$60,000~M$_\odot$ mass mentioned above has to be replaced by the correct
model-dependent mass limit of $\sim$20,000~M$_\odot$. See the erratum appended.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01810</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01810</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Luis B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Luiz P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Marcelo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Castro</keyname><forenames>Antonio S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic quantum dynamics of scalar bosons under a full vector
  Coulomb interaction</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 table. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1403.6035</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 310</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4881-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relativistic quantum dynamics of scalar bosons in the background of a
full vector coupling (minimal plus nonminimal vector couplings) is explored in
the context of the Duffin-Kemmer-Petiau formalism. The Coulomb phase shift is
determined for a general mixing of couplings and it is shown that the space
component of the nonminimal coupling is a {\it sine qua non} condition for the
exact closed-form scattering amplitude. It follows that the Rutherford cross
section vanishes in the absence of the time component of the minimal coupling.
Bound-state solutions obtained from the poles of the partial scattering
amplitude show that the time component of the minimal coupling plays an
essential role. The bound-state solutions depend on the nonminimal coupling and
the spectrum consists of particles or antiparticles depending on the sign of
the time component of the minimal coupling without chance for pair production
even in the presence of strong couplings. It is also shown that an accidental
degeneracy appears for a particular mixing of couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04878</id><created>2017-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Gouranga C</forenames></author></authors><title>Jet Quenching at RHIC and LHC and the Fragmentation Function in Vacuum</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages latex</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The value of the parton to hadron fragmentation function in QCD in vacuum
(for example from proton-proton collisions at high energy colliders) is
directly/indirectly used in the literature to study the jet quenching and the
hadron production from quark-gluon plasma at RHIC and LHC. In this paper we
show that this is not possible because, unlike the perturbative propagator in
non-equilibrium QCD, the parton to hadron fragmentation function is a
non-perturbative quantity in QCD and hence it is not possible to decompose the
fragmentation function in non-equilibrium QCD into the vacuum part and the
medium part.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05092</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Jiefang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Gengchiau</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Gaurav</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast and low-energy switching in voltage-controlled elliptical pMTJ</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>There are 28 pages and 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Switching magnetization in a perpendicular magnetic tunnel junction (pMTJ)
via voltage controlled magnetic anisotropy (VCMA) has shown the potential to
markedly reduce the switching energy. However, the requirement of an external
magnetic field poses a critical bottleneck for its practical applications. In
this work, we propose an elliptical-shaped pMTJ to eliminate the requirement of
providing an external field by an additional circuit. We demonstrate that a 10
nm thick in-plane magnetized bias layer (BL) separated by a metallic spacer of
3 nm from the free layer (FL) can be engineered within the MTJ stack to provide
the 50 mT bias magnetic field for switching. By conducting macrospin
simulation, we find that a fast switching in 0.38 ns with energy consumption as
low as 0.3 fJ at a voltage of 1.6 V can be achieved. Furthermore, we study the
phase diagram of switching probability, showing that a pulse duration margin of
0.15 ns is obtained and a low-voltage operation (~ 1 V) is favored. Finally,
the MTJ scalability is considered, and it is found that scaling-down may not be
appealing in terms of both the energy consumption and the switching time for
the precession based VCMA switching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05304</id><created>2017-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Musmarra</keyname><forenames>Juan Ignacio</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET &amp; UNMdP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Anabitarte</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET &amp; UNMdP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET &amp; UNMdP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Large scale solitonic back-reaction effects in pre-inflation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th physics.space-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1610.07979</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using Relativistic Quantum Geometry (RQG), we study the emergence of
back-reaction modes with solitonic properties, on astrophysical and
cosmological scales, in a model of pre-inflation where the universe emerge from
a topological phase transition. We found that, modes of the geometrical field
that describes back-reaction effects related to larger scales (cosmological
scales), are more coherent than those related to astrophysical scales, so that
they can be considered a coarse-grained soliton.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05418</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05418</id><created>2017-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vega</keyname><forenames>Hector J.</forenames><affiliation>+</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>Norma G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Warm Dark Matter Galaxies with Central Supermassive Black-Holes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>31 pages, 14 figures, new material</comments><msc-class>85A05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We generalize the Thomas-Fermi approach to galaxy structure to include
self-consistently and non-linearly central supermassive black holes. This
approach naturally incorporates the quantum pressure of the warm dark matter
(WDM) particles and shows its full powerful and clearness in the presence of
supermassive black holes (SPMHs). We find the main galaxy and central black
hole magnitudes: halo radius r_h , halo mass M_h, black hole mass M_BH,
velocity dispersion, phase space density, with their realistic astrophysical
values, masses and sizes over a wide galaxy range. The SMBH masses arise
naturally in this framework. Our extensive numerical calculations and detailed
analytic resolution show that with SMBH's, both WDM regimes: classical
(Boltzmann dilute) and quantum (compact) do necessarily co-exist in any galaxy:
from the smaller and compact galaxies to the largest ones. The transition from
the quantum to the classical region occurs precisely at the same point r_A
where the chemical potential vanishes. A novel halo structure with three
regions shows up: A small quantum compact core of radius r_A around the SMBH,
followed by a less compact region till the BH influence radius r_i, and then
for r&gt; r_i the known halo galaxy shows up with its astrophysical size. Three
representative families of galaxy plus central SMBH solutions are found and
analyzed:small, medium and large galaxies having SMBH masses of 10^5, 10^7 and
10^9 M_sun respectively. A minimum galaxy size and mass ~ 10^7 M_sun larger
than the one without SMBH is found. Small galaxies in the range 10^4 M_sun &lt;
M_h &lt; 10^7 M_sun cannot harbor central SMBHs. We find novel scaling M_BH - r_h
- M_h relations. The galaxy equation of state is derived: The pressure P(r)
takes huge values in the SMBH vecinity and then sharply decreases entering the
classical region following a local perfect gas behaviour.(Abridged)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05832</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Elnekiti</keyname><forenames>Abdulrhman</forenames></author></authors><title>New Directions In Cellular Automata</title><categories>cs.FL nlin.CG</categories><comments>Pre-print submission to Complex Systems journal</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We Propose A Novel Automaton Model which uses Arithmetic Operations as the
Evolving Rules, each cell has the states of the Natural Numbers k = (N), a
radius of r = 1/2 and operates on an arbitrary input size. The Automaton reads
an Arithmetic Expression as an input and outputs another Arithmetic Expression.
In Addition, we simulate a variety of One Dimensional Cellular Automata
Structures with different Dynamics including Elementary Cellular Automata.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05836</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Jefferson</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hee-Cheol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vafa</keyname><forenames>Cumrun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafrir</keyname><forenames>Gabi</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Classification of 5d SCFTs: Single Gauge Node</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>52 pages + appendix, 11 tables, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a number of apparently equivalent criteria necessary for the
consistency of a 5d SCFT in its Coulomb phase and use these criteria to
classify 5d SCFTs arising from a gauge theory with simple gauge group. These
criteria include the convergence of the 5-sphere partition function; the
positivity of particle masses and monopole string tensions; and the positive
definiteness of the metric in some region in the Coulomb branch. We find that
for large rank classical groups simple classes of SCFTs emerge where the bounds
on the matter content and the Chern-Simons level grow linearly with rank. For
classical groups of rank less than or equal to 8, our classification leads to
additional cases which do not fit in the large rank analysis. We also classify
the allowed matter content for all exceptional groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05846</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Traven</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Munari</keyname><forenames>Ulisse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dallaporta</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwitter</keyname><forenames>Toma&#x17e;</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate orbital solution for the new and metal poor eclipsing binary
  Tycho~5227-1023-1</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 839, Issue 1, article id. 52, 8
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The orbit and physical parameters of the previously unsolved double-lined
eclipsing binary Tyc 5227-1023-1, discovered during the search for RR Lyr
variables candidate members of the Aquarius stream, are derived using high
resolution \'echelle spectroscopy and $V$, $i^\prime$ photometry. Synthetic
spectral analysis of both components has been performed, yielding metallicity
[M/H] = $-0.63 \pm 0.11$ for both stars and the temperature of the secondary
which is in close agreement with the one from the orbital solution, while the
temperature of the primary is determined from photometry (T$_1 = 6350$ K). The
masses and radii ($M_1 = 0.96 \pm 0.02, M_2 = 0.84 \pm 0.01$ M$_{\odot}$, $R_1
= 1.39 \pm 0.01, R_2 = 0.98 \pm 0.01$ R$_{\odot}$) reveal that both stars have
already slightly evolved away from the Main Sequence band having an age of
about $7$ Gyr, and the results of synthetic spectral analysis support the claim
of co-rotation with the orbital motion. The radial velocity of the system is
$-60 \pm 2$ km sec$^{-1}$ while its distance, computed from orbital parameters
and the derived reddening $E_{B-V}$ = 0.053, is $496 \pm 35$ pc. Even though
Tyc 5227-1023-1 was initially treated as a possible member of the Aquarius
stream, the results presented here disagree with reported values for this
ancient structure, and suggest a likely membership of the thick disk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05861</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Tempelaar</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>Thomas L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knoester</keyname><forenames>Jasper</forenames></author></authors><title>Exciton-Exciton Annihilation Is Coherently Suppressed in H-Aggregates,
  but Not in J-Aggregates</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically demonstrate a strong dependence of the annihilation rate
between (singlet) excitons on the sign of dipole-dipole couplings between
molecules. For molecular H-aggregates, where this sign is positive, the phase
relation of the delocalized two-exciton wavefunctions causes a destructive
interference in the annihilation probability. For J-aggregates, where this sign
is negative, the interference is constructive instead, as a result of which no
such coherent suppression of the annihilation rate occurs. As a consequence,
room temperature annihilation rates of typical H- and J-aggregates differ by a
factor of ~3, while an order of magnitude difference is found for
low-temperature aggregates with a low degree of disorder. These findings, which
explain experimental observations, reveal a fundamental principle underlying
exciton-exciton annihilation, with major implications for technological devices
and experimental studies involving high excitation densities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05862</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Christoph A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathys</keyname><forenames>Gregoire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zadeh</keyname><forenames>Ida G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bootstrapping Chiral CFTs at Genus Two</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>27 pages + appendices, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Genus two partition functions of 2d chiral conformal field theories are given
by Siegel modular forms. We compute their conformal blocks and use them to
perform the conformal bootstrap. The advantage of this approach is that it
imposes crossing symmetry of an infinite family of four point functions and
also modular invariance at the same time. Since for a fixed central charge the
ring of Siegel modular forms is finite dimensional, we can perform this
analytically. In this way we derive bounds on three point functions and on the
spectrum of such theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05908</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Garimella</keyname><forenames>Kiran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Gianmarco De Francisci</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gionis</keyname><forenames>Aristides</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathioudakis</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effect of Collective Attention on Controversial Debates on Social
  Media</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>accepted at ACM WebScience 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the evolution of long-lived controversial debates as manifested on
Twitter from 2011 to 2016. Specifically, we explore how the structure of
interactions and content of discussion varies with the level of collective
attention, as evidenced by the number of users discussing a topic. Spikes in
the volume of users typically correspond to external events that increase the
public attention on the topic -- as, for instance, discussions about `gun
control' often erupt after a mass shooting.
  This work is the first to study the dynamic evolution of polarized online
debates at such scale. By employing a wide array of network and content
analysis measures, we find consistent evidence that increased collective
attention is associated with increased network polarization and network
concentration within each side of the debate; and overall more uniform lexicon
usage across all users.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05944</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Studenikin</keyname><forenames>Alexande</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic properties of neutrinos: three new phenomena in neutrino
  spin oscillations</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, the paper in the proceedings of the 19th International
  Seminar on High Energy Physics QUARKS-2016 with minor modifications</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf. 125 (2016) 04018</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In studies of neutrino electromagnetic properties we discuss three very
interesting aspects related to neutrino spin oscillations. First we consider
neutrino mixing and oscillations in the mass and flavour bases under the
influence of a constant magnetic field with nonzero transversal and
longitudinal components. Then we discuss the effect of neutrino spin
oscillations induced by electroweak interactions of neutrino with moving matter
in case there is matter transversal current or polarization. In the final part
of the paper we discuss recently developed approach to description of neutrino
spin and spin-flavour oscillations in a constant magnetic field that is based
on the use of the exact neutrino stationary states in the magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05969</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dumitrescu</keyname><forenames>Olivia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulase</keyname><forenames>Motohico</forenames></author></authors><title>An invitation to 2D TQFT and quantization of Hitchin spectral curves</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.AC math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>53 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>14H15, 14N35, 81T45 (Primary), 14F10, 14J26, 33C05, 33C10, 33C15,
  34M60, 53D37. 33C10, 33C15, 34M60, 53D37 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article consists of two parts. In Part 1, we present a formulation of
two-dimensional topological quantum field theories in terms of a functor from a
category of Ribbon graphs to the endofuntor category of a monoidal category.
The key point is that the category of ribbon graphs produces all Frobenius
objects. Necessary backgrounds from Frobenius algebras, topological quantum
field theories, and cohomological field theories are reviewed. A result on
Frobenius algebra twisted topological recursion is included at the end of Part
1.
  In Part 2, we explain a geometric theory of quantum curves. The focus is
placed on the process of quantization as a passage from families of Hitchin
spectral curves to families of opers. To make the presentation simpler, we
unfold the story using SL_2(\mathbb{C})-opers and rank 2 Higgs bundles defined
on a compact Riemann surface $C$ of genus greater than $1$. In this case,
quantum curves, opers, and projective structures in $C$ all become the same
notion. Background materials on projective coordinate systems, Higgs bundles,
opers, and non-Abelian Hodge correspondence are explained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05974</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bronsard</keyname><forenames>Sylvie A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelinovsky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry E.</forenames></author></authors><title>New integrable semi-discretizations of the coupled nonlinear Schrodinger
  equations</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have undertaken an algorithmic search for new integrable
semi-discretizations of physically relevant nonlinear partial differential
equations. The search is performed by using a compatibility condition for the
discrete Lax operators and symbolic computations. We have discovered a new
integrable system of coupled nonlinear Schrodinger equations which combines
elements of the Ablowitz-Ladik lattice and the triangular-lattice ribbon
studied by Vakhnenko. We show that the continuum limit of the new integrable
system is given by uncoupled complex modified Korteweg-de Vries equations and
uncoupled nonlinear Schrodinger equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05975</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyanguren</keyname><forenames>Arantza</forenames></author></authors><title>$|V_{ud}|$, $|V_{us}|$, $|V_{cd}|$, $|V_{cs}|$ and charm (semi)leptonic
  decays: WG1 summary from CKM 2016</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, WG1 summary for the 9th International Workshop
  on the CKM Unitarity Triangle (CKM 2016), 28 November - 2 December 2016, Tata
  Institute of Fundamental Research, India</comments><journal-ref>PoS (CKM2016) 014</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We summarize the current status of the determination of the CKM matrix
elements |V_ud| and |V_us|, which is at the precision frontier of CKM
phenomenology. We also review recent progress on the study of charm
(semi)leptonic decays, and the determination of |V_cd| and |V_cs|.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06003</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Tachibana</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshii</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanayama</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawai</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>MITSuME observation of V404 Cygni in the 2015 outburst: Two optical
  variable components with different variability</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables</comments><doi>10.1093/pasj/psx040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The black hole binary V404 Cygni (= GS 2023+338) had an outburst on June 15,
2015 after 26 years of quiescence. We report the multi-color optical
observation (g', Rc, and Ic) of this object at the beginning of its outburst
performed by the MITSuME 50cm telescope in Akeno, Yamanashi, and the
MURIKABUSHI 105 cm Telescope at Ishigakijima Astronomical Observatory. With
time domain analysis of the multi-color light curves, we successfully
decomposed optical variations into two components: a highly-variable, and a
little-variable component. The loci of the little-variable component in the
color-color diagram are consistent with that of the multi-temperature blackbody
radiation, while those of the highly-variable component trace out a power-law
spectrum with a spectral index {\alpha}~0.6-1.0. For the little-variable
component, we argue that an irradiated disk with the innermost temperature
higher than ~2.0$\times10^4$ K and the outermost temperature lower than
~6.5$\times10^3$ K is the most plausible source. The gradual rise trend of the
light curve during our observation is probably due to the growing of the
little-variable component. The observed spectral energy distribution (SED) from
the optical to ultraviolet can be expressed by a model consisting of a
power-law component and an irradiated disk component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06004</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Rout</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datar</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Suresh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirgule</keyname><forenames>E. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanal</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kujur</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A CsI(Tl) detector array for the measurement of light charged particles
  in heavy-ion reactions</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An array of eight CsI(Tl) detectors has been set up to measure the light
charged particles in nuclear reactions using heavy ions from the Pelletron
Linac Facility, Mumbai. The energy response of CsI(Tl) detector to
$\alpha$-particles from 5 to 40 MeV is measured using radioactive sources and
the $^{12}$C($^{12}$C, $\alpha$) reaction populating discrete states in
$^{20}$Ne. The energy non-linearity and the count rate effect on the pulse
shape discrimination property have also been measured and observed the
deterioration of pulse shape discrimination with higher count rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06006</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ran</keyname><forenames>Shi-Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermionic algebraic quantum spin liquid in an octa-kagome frustrated
  antiferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 95, 075140 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.075140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the ground state and finite-temperature properties of the
spin-1/2 Heisenberg antiferromagnet on an infinite octa-kagome lattice by
utilizing state-of-the-art tensor network-based numerical methods. It is shown
that the ground state has a vanishing local magnetization and possesses a
$1/2$-magnetization plateau with up-down-up-up spin configuration. A quantum
phase transition at the critical coupling ratio $J_{d}/J_{t}=0.6$ is found.
When $0&lt;J_{d}/J_{t}&lt;0.6$, the system is in a valence bond state, where an
obvious zero-magnetization plateau is observed, implying a gapful spin
excitation; when $J_{d}/J_{t}&gt;0.6$, the system exhibits a gapless excitation,
in which the dimer-dimer correlation is found decaying in a power law, while
the spin-spin and chiral-chiral correlation functions decay exponentially. At
the isotropic point ($J_{d}/J_{t}=1$), we unveil that at low temperature ($T$)
the specific heat depends linearly on $T$, and the susceptibility tends to a
constant for $T\rightarrow 0$, giving rise to a Wilson ratio around unity,
implying that the system under interest is a fermionic algebraic quantum spin
liquid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06030</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heuer</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milonni</keyname><forenames>Peter W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement, complementarity, and vacuum fields in spontaneous
  parametric down-conversion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using two crystals for spontaneous parametric down-conversion in a parallel
setup, we observe two-photon interference with high visibility. The high
visibility is consistent with complementarity and the absence of which-path
information. The observations are explained as effects of entanglement or
equivalently in terms of interfering probability amplitudes, and also by the
calculation of a second-order field correlation function in the Heisenberg
picture. The latter approach brings out explicitly the role of the vacuum
fields in the down-conversion at the crystals and in the photon coincidence
counting. For comparison we show that the Hong-Ou-Mandel dip can be explained
by the same approach in which the role of the vacuum signal and idler fields,
as opposed to entanglement involving vacuum states, is emphasized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06034</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Constantin</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabiano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x15a;miga</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Sala</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Jellium-with-gap model applied to semilocal kinetic functionals</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115153 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a highly-nonlocal generalization of the Lindhard function,
given by the jellium-with-gap model. We find a band-gap-dependent gradient
expansion of the kinetic energy, which performs noticeably well for large
atoms. Using the static linear response theory and the simplest semilocal model
for the local band gap, we derive a non-empirical generalized gradient
approximation (GGA) of the kinetic energy. This GGA kinetic energy functional
is remarkably accurate for the description of weakly interacting molecular
systems within the subsystem formulation of Density Functional Theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06039</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Ye</forenames></author></authors><title>Why does bulk boundary correspondence fail in some non-hermitian
  topological models</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bulk boundary correspondence is crucial to topological insulator as it
associates the boundary states (with zero energy, chiral or helical) to
topological numbers defined in bulk. The application of this correspondence
needs a prerequisite condition which is usually not mentioned explicitly: the
boundaries themselves cannot alter the bulk states, so as to the topological
numbers defined on them. In non-hermitian models with fractional winding
number, we prove that such precondition fails and the bulk boundary
correspondence is cut out. We show that, as eliminating the hopping between the
boundaries to simulate the evolution of a system from the periodic boundary
condition to the open boundary condition, exceptional points must be passed
through and the topological structure of the spectrum has been changed. This
makes the topological structures of a chain with open boundary totally
different from that without the boundary. We also argue that such exotic
behavior does not emerge when the open boundary is replaced by a domain-wall.
So the index theorem can be applied to the systems with domain-walls but cannot
be further used to those with open boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06050</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lykov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malyshev</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence to equilibrium for many particle systems</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><msc-class>82C22</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The goal of this paper is to give a short review of recent results of the
authors concerning classical Hamiltonian many particle systems. We hope that
these results support the new possible formulation of Boltzmann's ergodicity
hypothesis which sounds as follows. For almost all potentials, the minimal
contact with external world, through only one particle of $N$, is sufficient
for ergodicity. But only if this contact has no memory. Also new results for
quantum case are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06051</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Tuntsov</keyname><forenames>Artem V.</forenames><affiliation>Manly Astrophysics</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames><affiliation>CSIRO Paul Wild Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bannister</keyname><forenames>Keith W.</forenames><affiliation>CSIRO Astronomy and Space Science, Epping</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bignall</keyname><forenames>Hayley</forenames><affiliation>CSIRO Astronomy and Space Science, Kensington</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames><affiliation>CSIRO Astronomy and Space Science, Epping</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Cormac</forenames><affiliation>CSIRO Astronomy and Space Science, Kensington</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Mark A.</forenames><affiliation>Manly Astrophysics</affiliation></author></authors><title>Scintillation kinks, bumps and wiggles in the radio spectrum of the
  quasar PMN J1106-3647</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS, 12 pages, 5 figures and a very
  interesting appendix on caustic signatures in dynamic spectra which is
  further expanded at
  http://manlyastrophysics.org/MaterialForAstronomers/ResearchNotes/index.html</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1223</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report radio observations of the quasar PMN J1106-3647. Our data, taken
with the Australia Telescope Compact Array, show large variations in the
amplitude and shape of its spectrum, on a short time-scale. A great variety of
spectral features is evident, including: sharp kinks; broad spectral peaks; and
wiggles. No two spectra are alike. We interpret the variations as interstellar
scintillation of a radio source that is compact, but not point-like. Under this
interpretation, complex spectral structure can arise purely refractively, under
high magnification conditions, or from interference between waves that have
been scattered by small-scale density fluctuations (diffractive scintillation).
Both effects may be playing a role in J1106-3647, and we tentatively identify
kinks with the former, and wiggles with the latter. Diffractive scintillation
of AGN is uncommon, as the fringe visibility is low for all but the most
compact radio sources. Refractive interpretation of the kink implies that the
source has a sharp, concave boundary. Our data are consistent with a mildly
boosted synchrotron source, provided the scattering material is at a distance
~50 pc from us.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06064</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Padovani</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trigo</keyname><forenames>M. Diaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ettori</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatziminaoglou</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonker</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adami</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aird</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceccarelli</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Churazov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirasuolo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daddi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edge</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feruglio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainieri</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markoff</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merloni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicastro</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oskinova</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panessa</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pointecouteau</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robrade</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaye</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoehr</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Testi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tombesi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>ESO-Athena Synergy White Paper</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>70 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Advanced Telescope for High ENergy Astrophysics (Athena) is the X-ray
observatory mission selected by ESA within its Cosmic Vision 2015-2025
programme to address the Hot and Energetic Universe scientific theme. The
ESO-Athena Synergy Team (EAST) has been tasked to single out the potential
scientific synergies between Athena and optical/near-infrared (NIR) and sub/mm
ground based facilities, in particular those of ESO (i.e., the VLT and ELT,
ALMA and APEX), by producing a White Paper to identify and develop the: 1.
needs to access ESO ground-based facilities to achieve the formulated Athena
science objectives; 2. needs to access Athena to achieve the formulated science
objectives of ESO facilities contemporary to Athena; 3. science areas where the
synergetic use of Athena and ESO facilities in the late 2020s will result in
scientific added value. Community input to the process happened primarily via a
dedicated ESO - Athena Synergy Workshop that took place on Sept. 14 - 16, 2016
at ESO, Garching. This White Paper presents the results of the EAST's work,
sorted by synergy area, and deals with the following topics: 1. the Hot
Universe: Early groups and clusters and their evolution, Physics of the
Intracluster medium, Missing baryons in cosmic filaments; 2. the Energetic
Universe: Supermassive black hole (SMBH) history, SMBH accretion disks, Active
Galactic Nuclei feedback - Molecular outflows, Ultra-fast outflows, Accretion
Physics, Transient Science; 3. Observatory Science: Star Formation, Stars. It
then discusses the optical-NIR-sub-mm perspective by providing details on
VLT/MOONS, the E-ELT instruments, in particular the MOS, VISTA/4MOST, the ESO
and ALMA archives, future ALMA and ESO developments, and finally the (likely)
ESO - Athena astronomical scene in the 2020s. (abridged)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06065</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lagrow</keyname><forenames>Alec</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gai</keyname><forenames>Pratibha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyes</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Visualizing the Cu and Cu2O Interface Transition in Nanoparticles with
  Environmental Scanning Transmission Electron Microscopy</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of the American Chemical Society, 139, p 179, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the oxidation and reduction mechanisms of catalytically active
transition metal nanoparticles is important to improve their application in a
variety of chemical processes. In nanocatalysis the nanoparticles can undergo
oxidation or reduction in situ, and thus the redox species are not what are
observed before and after reactions. We have used the novel environmental
scanning transmission electron microscope (ESTEM) with 0.1 nm resolution in
systematic studies of complex dynamic oxidation and reduction mechanisms of
copper nanoparticles. The oxidation of copper has previously been reported to
be dependent on its crystallography and its interaction with the substrate. By
following the dynamic oxidation process in situ, in real time, with high-angle
annular dark-field imaging in the ESTEM, we use conditions ideal to track the
oxidation front as it progresses across a copper nanoparticle by following the
changes in the atomic number (z) contrast with time. The oxidation occurs via
the nucleation of the oxide phase (Cu2O) from one area of the nanoparticle
which then progresses unidirectionally across the particle, with the Cu-to-Cu2O
interface having a relationship of Cu{111} parallel to Cu2O{111}. The oxidation
kinetics are related to the temperature and oxygen pressure. When the process
is reversed in hydrogen, the reduction process is observed to be similar to the
oxidation, with the same crystallographic relationship between the two phases.
The dynamic observations provide unique insights into redox mechanisms which
are important to understanding and controlling the oxidation and reduction of
copper-based nanoparticles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06077</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Dillon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corsetti</keyname><forenames>Fabiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brar</keyname><forenames>Victor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Hsin-Zon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Qiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawakami</keyname><forenames>Roland K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zettl</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostofi</keyname><forenames>Arash A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lischner</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crommie</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatially resolving density-dependent screening around a single charged
  atom in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205419 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrons in two-dimensional graphene sheets behave as interacting chiral
Dirac fermions and have unique screening properties due to their symmetry and
reduced dimensionality. By using a combination of scanning tunneling
spectroscopy (STM/STS) measurements and theoretical modeling we have
characterized how graphene's massless charge carriers screen individual charged
calcium atoms. A back-gated graphene device configuration has allowed us to
directly visualize how the screening length for this system can be tuned with
carrier density. Our results provide insight into electron-impurity and
electron-electron interactions in a relativistic setting with important
consequences for other graphene-based electronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06078</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Samusev</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhin</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malureanu</keyname><forenames>Radu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takayama</keyname><forenames>Osamu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Permyakov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinev</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baranov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yermakov</keyname><forenames>Oleh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iorsh</keyname><forenames>Ivan V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>Andrey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrinenko</keyname><forenames>Andrei V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional optical plasmons with mixed polarization on anisotropic
  resonant metasurface</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical metasurfaces have great potential to form the platform for
manipulation of surface waves. A plethora of advanced surface-wave phenomena
utilizing negative refraction, self-collimation and channeling of 2D waves can
be realized through on-demand engineering of dispersion properties of a
periodic metasurface. In this letter, we report on the first-time direct
experimental polarization-resolved measurement of dispersion of 2D optical
plasmons supported by an anisotropic metasurface. We demonstrate that a
subdiffractive array of strongly coupled resonant anisotropic plasmonic
nanoparticles supports unusual optical surface waves with mixed TE- and TM-like
polarizations. With the assistance of numerical simulations we identify dipole
and quadrupole dispersion bands. The shape of isofrequency contours changes
drastically with frequency exhibiting nontrivial transformations of their
curvature and topology that is consistently confirmed by the experimental data.
By revealing polarization degree of freedom for surface waves, our results open
new routes for designing of planar on-chip devices for surface photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06094</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Quilez</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauging Lepton Flavour</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure; Contribution to the Proceedings of the 51st
  Rencontres de Moriond, Electroweak Session</comments><report-no>FTUAM-17-7</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The flavour lepton symmetry is gauged for both the Standard Model flavor
group and its extension with three degenerate right-handed neutrinos. As a
consequence of anomaly cancellation, exotic leptons are introduced which induce
a see-saw mechanism that generates the masses of the SM leptons. The model is
compared with Minimal Flavour Violation, the difference between the low-energy
effective operators resulting is identified, as well as the distinctive
experimental signals, particularly promising in the $\mu-\tau$ sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06095</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Benjamini</keyname><forenames>Itai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yadin</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author></authors><title>Upper bounds on the growth rate of Diffusion Limited Aggregation</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit Kesten's argument for the upper bound on the growth rate of DLA.
We are able to make the argument robust enough so that it applies to many
graphs, where only control of the heat kernel is required. We apply this to
many examples including transitive graphs of polynomial growth, graphs of
exponential growth, non-amenable graphs, super-critical percolation on Z^d,
high dimensional pre-Sierpinski carpets. We also observe that a careful
analysis shows that Kesten's original bound on Z^3 can be improved from t^{2/3}
to (t log t)^{1/2} .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06100</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yamei</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tritt</keyname><forenames>Terry M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poon</keyname><forenames>S. Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>High Thermoelectric Figure of Merit by Resonant Dopant in Half-Heusler
  Alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Submitted to AIP Advances</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Half-Heusler alloys have been one of the benchmark high temperature
thermoelectric materials owing to their thermal stability and promising figure
of merit ZT. Simonson et al. early showed that small amounts of vanadium doped
in Hf0.75Zr0.25NiSn enhanced the Seebeck coefficient and correlated the change
with the increased density of states near the Fermi level. We herein report a
systematic study on the role of vanadium (V), niobium (Nb), and tantalum (Ta)
as prospective resonant dopants in enhancing the ZT of n-type half-Heusler
alloys based on Hf0.6Zr0.4NiSn0.995Sb0.005. The V doping was found to increase
the Seebeck coefficient in the temperature range 300-1000 K, consistent with a
resonant doping scheme. In contrast, Nb and Ta act as normal n-type dopants, as
evident by the systematic decrease in electrical resistivity and Seebeck
coefficient. The combination of enhanced Seebeck coefficient due to the
presence of V resonant states and the reduced thermal conductivity has led to a
state-of-the-art ZT of 1.3 near 850 K in n-type
(Hf0.6Zr0.4)0.99V0.01NiSn0.995Sb0.005 alloys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06107</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Tai</keyname><forenames>Chaokang</forenames></author></authors><title>Left Radicalism and the Milky Way: Connecting the Scientific and
  Socialist Virtues of Anton Pannekoek</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>55 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Historical Studies in the Natural Sciences, vol. 47 no.2 (2017)
  pp. 200-254</journal-ref><doi>10.1525/hsns.2017.47.2.200</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anton Pannekoek (1873-1960) was both an influential Marxist and an innovative
astronomer. This paper will analyse the various innovative methods that he
developed to represent the visual aspect of the Milky Way and the statistical
distribution of stars in the galaxy through a framework of epistemic virtues.
Doing so will not emphasize the unique aspects of his astronomical research,
but also reveal its connections to his left radical brand of Marxism. A crucial
feature of Pannekoek's astronomical method was the active role ascribed to
astronomers. They were expected to use their intuitive ability to organize data
according to the appearance of the Milky Way, while at the same time they had
to avoid the influence of personal experience and theoretical presuppositions
about the shape of the system. With this method, he produced results that went
against the Kapteyn Universe and instead made him the first astronomer in the
Netherlands to find supporting evidence for Harlow Shapley's extended galaxy.
After exploring Pannekoek's Marxist philosophy, it is argued that both his
astronomical method and his interpretation of historical materialism can be
seen as strategies developed to make optical use of his particular conception
of the human mind.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06115</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ormaza</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abufager</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verlhac</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bachellier</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bocquet</keyname><forenames>M. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorente</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limot</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-flip scattering selection in a controlled molecular junction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple double-decker molecule with magnetic anisotropy, nickelocene, is
attached to the metallic tip of a low-temperature scanning tunneling
microscope. In the presence of a Cu(100) surface, the conductance around the
Fermi energy is governed by spin-flip scattering, the nature of which is
determined by the tunneling barrier thickness. The molecular tip exhibits
inelastic spin-flip scattering in the tunneling regime, while in the contact
regime a Kondo ground state is stabilized causing an order of magnitude change
in the zero-bias conductance. First principle calculations show that
nickelocene reversibly switches from a spin 1 to 1/2 between the two transport
regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06116</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Tadic</keyname><forenames>Bosiljka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andjelkovic</keyname><forenames>Miroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupte</keyname><forenames>Neelima</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical features of time series provide new perspectives on
  collective fluctuations in driven disordered systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mapping time series onto graphs and the use of graph theory methods opens up
the possibility to study the structure of the phase space manifolds underlying
the fluctuations of a dynamical variable. Here, we propose to go beyond the
standard graph measures and analyze the higher-order structures such as
triangles, tetrahedra and higher-order cliques and their complexes occurring in
the time-series networks, which are detectable by the algebraic topology
methods. We apply the methodology to the signal of Barkhausen noise
accompanying the domain-wall dynamics on the hysteresis loop of disordered
ferromagnets driven by the external field. Our analysis demonstrates how the
appearance of the complexes with cliques of a high order correlates to the
enhanced collective fluctuations in the central part of the hysteresis loop, in
contrast to the fractional Gaussian noise fluctuations at the beginning of the
loop, which correspond to the graph of a simpler topology. The multifractal
analysis of the corresponding segments of these time series confirms that we
deal with different types of the stochastic process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06117</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Velebit</keyname><forenames>Kristijan</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Zagreb, Croatia</affiliation><affiliation>1. Physikalisches Institut, Universit&#xe4;t Stuttgart, Stuttgart, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pop&#x10d;evi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Petar</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Zagreb, Croatia</affiliation><affiliation>Institute of Solid State Physics, Vienna University of Technology, Vienna, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Batisti&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Ivo</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, Faculty of Science, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eichler</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames><affiliation>1. Physikalisches Institut, Universit&#xe4;t Stuttgart, Stuttgart, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Helmuth</forenames><affiliation>Ecole Polytechnique F&#xe9;d&#xe9;rale de Lausanne, LPMC, Lausanne, Switzerland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Forr&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</forenames><affiliation>Ecole Polytechnique F&#xe9;d&#xe9;rale de Lausanne, LPMC, Lausanne, Switzerland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dressel</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames><affiliation>1. Physikalisches Institut, Universit&#xe4;t Stuttgart, Stuttgart, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bari&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Neven</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Zagreb, Croatia</affiliation><affiliation>1. Physikalisches Institut, Universit&#xe4;t Stuttgart, Stuttgart, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>Institute of Solid State Physics, Vienna University of Technology, Vienna, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tuti&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Zagreb, Croatia</affiliation></author></authors><title>Scattering dominated high-temperature phase of 1T-TiSe2: an optical
  conductivity study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>28 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The controversy regarding the precise nature of the high-temperature phase of
1T-TiSe2 lasts for decades. It has intensified in recent times when new
evidence for the excitonic origin of the low-temperature charge-density wave
state started to unveil. Here we address the problem of the high-temperature
phase through precise measurements and detailed analysis of the optical
response of 1T-TiSe2 single crystals. The separate responses of electron and
hole subsystems are identified and followed in temperature. We show that
neither semiconductor nor semimetal pictures can be applied in their generic
forms as the scattering for both types of carriers is in the vicinity of the
Ioffe-Regel limit with decay rates being comparable to or larger than the
offsets of band extrema. The nonmetallic temperature dependence of transport
properties comes from the anomalous temperature dependence of scattering rates.
Near the transition temperature the heavy electrons and the light holes
contribute equally to the conductivity. This surprising coincidence is regarded
as the consequence of dominant intervalley scattering that precedes the
transition. The low-frequency peak in the optical spectra is identified and
attributed to the critical softening of the L-point collective mode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06119</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Korcyl</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author></authors><title>Alleviating the window problem in large volume renormalization schemes</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a strategy for large volume non-perturbative renormalization which
alleviates the window problem by reducing cut-off effects. We perform a
proof-of-concept study using position space renormalization scheme and the CLS
$N_f=2+1$ ensembles generated at 5 different lattice spacings. We show that in
the advocated strategy results for the renormalization constants are to a large
extend independent of the specific lattice direction used to define the
renormalization condition. Hence, very short lattice distances become
accessible even on coarse lattices and the contact with perturbation theory can
be performed at much higher energy scales. Our results include
non-perturbatively estimated renormalization constants for quark bilinear
operators in the scalar, pseudoscalar and axial-vector channels using position
space renormalization scheme which we subsequently translate to the
$\overline{\mathrm{MS}}$ scheme perturbatively at $1.5$ GeV. Our proposal is
applicable to other non-perturbative large volume renormalization schemes such
as RI-MOM and its variants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06126</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yikun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Shenhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoo</keyname><forenames>Iam Choon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jianying</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast Optical Signal Processing with Bragg Structures</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>To be published in a special issue of journal Applied Sciences, on
  the topic of Guided-Wave Optics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phase, amplitude, speed, and polarization, in addition to many other
properties of light, can be modulated by photonic Bragg structures. In
conjunction with nonlinearity and quantum effects, a variety of ensuing micro-
or nano-photonic applications can be realized. This paper reviews various
optical phenomena in several exemplary 1D Bragg gratings. Important examples
are resonantly absorbing photonic structures, chirped Bragg grating, and
cholesteric liquid crystals; their unique operation capabilities and key issues
are considered in detail. These Bragg structures are expected to be used in
wide-spread applications involving light field modulations, especially in the
rapidly advancing field of ultrafast optical signal processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06140</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuzmicheva</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmichev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadakov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muratov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usoltsev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martovitsky</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shipilov</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chareev</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitrofanova</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pudalov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Evidence of Two Superconducting Gaps in FeSe$_{0.5}$Te$_{0.5}$:
  SnS-Andreev Spectroscopy and Lower Critical Field</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>JETP Letters 104, 852 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364016240048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present direct measurements of the superconducting order parameter in
nearly optimal FeSe$_{0.5}$Te$_{0.5}$ single crystals with critical temperature
$T_C \approx 14$ K. Using intrinsic multiple Andreev reflection effect (IMARE)
spectroscopy and measurements of lower critical field, we directly determined
two superconducting gaps, $\Delta_L \approx 3.3 - 3.4$ meV and $\Delta_S
\approx 1$ meV, and their temperature dependences. We show that a two-band
model fits well the experimental data. The estimated electron-boson coupling
constants indicate a strong intraband and a moderate interband interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06147</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cavoretto</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Rossi</keyname><forenames>Alessandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freda</keyname><forenames>Roberta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Hanli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venturino</keyname><forenames>Ezio</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Methods for Pulmonary Image Registration</title><categories>q-bio.QM math.NA physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to complexity and invisibility of human organs, diagnosticians need to
analyze medical images to determine where the lesion region is, and which kind
of disease is, in order to make precise diagnoses. For satisfying clinical
purposes through analyzing medical images, registration plays an essential
role. For instance, in Image-Guided Interventions (IGI) and computer-aided
surgeries, patient anatomy is registered to preoperative images to guide
surgeons complete procedures. Medical image registration is also very useful in
surgical planning, monitoring disease progression and for atlas construction.
Due to the significance, the theories, methods, and implementation method of
image registration constitute fundamental knowledge in educational training for
medical specialists. In this chapter, we focus on image registration of a
specific human organ, i.e. the lung, which is prone to be lesioned. For
pulmonary image registration, the improvement of the accuracy and how to obtain
it in order to achieve clinical purposes represents an important problem which
should seriously be addressed. In this chapter, we provide a survey which
focuses on the role of image registration in educational training together with
the state-of-the-art of pulmonary image registration. In the first part, we
describe clinical applications of image registration introducing artificial
organs in Simulation-based Education. In the second part, we summarize the
common methods used in pulmonary image registration and analyze popular papers
to obtain a survey of pulmonary image registration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06152</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmelz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakosarenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chwala</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nau</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anders</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linzen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>H. -G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thin-film based ultralow noise SQUID magnetometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Applied Superconductivity ( Volume: 26,
  Issue: 5, Aug. 2016, page 1600804)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TASC.2016.2530699</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the development of an ultralow noise thin-film based SQUID
magnetometer. A niobium thin-film pickup coil is connected to the input coil of
a SQUID current sensor. The low capacitance of the used sub-micrometer
cross-type Josephson junctions enable superior noise performance of the device.
Application scenarios e.g. in geophysics and ultra-low field magnetic resonance
imaging are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06157</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Algin</keyname><forenames>Abdullah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arikan</keyname><forenames>Ali Serdar</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective approach for taking into account interactions of
  quasiparticles from the low-temperature behavior of a deformed fermion-gas
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment (2017)
  043105</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa6687</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A deformed fermion gas model aimed at taking into account thermal and
electronic properties of quasiparticle systems is devised. The model is
constructed by the fermionic Fibonacci oscillators whose spectrum is given by a
generalized Fibonacci sequence. We first introduce some new properties
concerning the Fibonacci calculus. We then investigate the low-temperature
thermostatistical properties of the model, and derive many of the deformed
thermostatistical functions such as the chemical potential and the entropy in
terms of the model deformation parameters p and q. We specifically focus on the
p,q-deformed Sommerfeld parameter for the heat capacity of the model, and its
behavior is compared with those of both the free-electron Fermi theory and the
experimental data for some materials. The results obtained in this study reveal
that the present deformed fermion model leads to an effective approach
accounting for interaction and compositeness of quasiparticles, which have
remarkable implications in many technological applications such as in
nanomaterials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06162</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Koyunlu</keyname><forenames>Gokhan</forenames></author></authors><title>Traveling Wave Solutions to Conformable Time Fractional RLW-class
  equations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><msc-class>5C07, 35R11, 35Q53</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The traveling wave solutions to some nonlinear conformable time fractional
partial differential equations in RLW-class are set up by using sech and csch
ansatzs. The conformable time fractional forms of the equal-width (EW),
regularized long wave (RLW) and symmetric regularized long wave (sRLW)
equations are considered in the study. By the assist of the simple traveling
wave transformation, the equations are converted to some ordinary differential
equations. Then, assuming these equations have solutions of forms of powers of
sech and csch functions lead to determine the powers of the solutions if exist.
The determination of the relation among the other parameters in the solutions
follows the previous process. Finally, the solutions are expressed in some
explicit forms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06166</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmelz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakosarenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nau</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anders</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linzen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>H. -G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nearly quantum limited nanoSQUIDs based on cross-type Nb/AlOx/Nb
  junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Supercond. Sci. Technol. 30 (2017) 014001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-2048/30/1/014001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the development of nearly quantum limited SQUIDs with miniature
pickup loop dimensions. The implemented high quality and low capacitance
cross-type Nb/AlOx/Nb Josephson junctions offer large $I_CR_N$-products and
therefore enable an exceptional low noise level of the SQUIDs. Devices with
loop dimensions of 1 {\mu}m exhibit white flux noise levels as low as $45
n{\Phi}_0/Hz^{1/2}$ corresponding to an energy resolution {\epsilon} of about 1
h at 4.2 K, with h being Plancks constant. Moreover, the large usable voltage
swings of the devices of about 300 {\mu}V allow highly sensitive and easy
single-stage operation while exploring nearly the intrinsic noise of the
SQUIDs, beneficial e.g. for sensor arrays in SQUID microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06176</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wilbring</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>H. -W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei&#xdf;ner</keyname><forenames>Ulf-G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-body universality in the B meson sector</title><categories>hep-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The charged exotic mesons Z_b(10610) and Z'_b(10650) observed by the Belle
collaboration in 2011 are very close to the B*Bbar and B*B*bar thresholds,
respectively. This suggests their interpretation as shallow hadronic molecules
of B and B* mesons. Using the masses of the Z_b(10610) and Z'_b(10650) as
input, we predict the phase shifts for the scattering of B and B* mesons off
the exotic mesons Z_b(10610) and Z'_b(10650) to leading order in a
non-relativistic effective field theory with contact interactions. Moreover, we
rule out the possibility for universal bound states of three B and B* mesons
arising from the Efimov effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06182</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Cierniak</keyname><forenames>Mateusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xe4;hn</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the In-Medium Momentum Dependence of the Dynamical Quark Mass</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, conference proceedings of CPOD 2016, accepted for
  publication in Acta Physica Polonica B</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the two standard equations of states based on the
Nambu-Jona-Lasinio (NJL) model and the thermodynamic bag (tdBag) model for
dense, cold quark matter from a perspective based on the Dyson-Schwinger (DS)
formalism. A different, but technically not more complicated approximation
reproduces the model of Munczek and Nemirovsky (MN) which accounts in a
simplified way for chiral symmetry breaking and confinement as a dynamic
process rooted in the momentum dependence of QCD model gap solutions. We review
the mass gap solutions for the MN model in the chiral limit and sketch the
behavior of mass gap solutions for finite bare quark masses at finite chemical
potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06185</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>Zahir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahayanathan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mankuzhiyil</keyname><forenames>Nijil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>Pankaj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Ranjeev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iqbal</keyname><forenames>Naseer</forenames></author></authors><title>Clues on High Energy Emission Mechanism from Blazar 3C 454.3 during 2015
  August Flare</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>28 pages, 9 figures, 5 tables Accepted 2017 May 12. Received 2017 May
  12; in original form 2016 November 07</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1194</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a detailed spectral study of a recent flaring activity from the
Flat Spectrum Radio Quasar (FSRQ), 3C\,454.3, observed simultaneously in
optical, UV, X-ray and $\gamma$-ray energies during 16 to 28 August, 2015. The
source reached its peak $\gamma$-ray flux of $(1.9\pm0.2)\times\,10^{-05} \;
{\rm ph\,cm^{-2}\,s^{-1}}$ on 22 August. The time averaged broadband spectral
energy distribution (SED) is obtained for three time periods, namely &quot;flaring
state&quot;; covering the peak $\gamma$-ray flux, &quot;post flaring state&quot;; immediately
following the peak flare and &quot;quiescent state&quot;; separated from the flaring
event and following the post flaring state. The SED corresponding to the
flaring state is investigated using different emission models involving
synchrotron, synchrotron self Compton (SSC) and external Compton (EC)
mechanisms. Our study suggests that the X-ray and $\gamma$-ray emission from
3C\,454.3 cannot be attributed to a single emission mechanism and instead, one
needs to consider both SSC and EC mechanisms. Moreover, the target photon
energy responsible for the EC process corresponds to an equivalent temperature
of 564 K, suggesting that the flare location lies beyond the broad line
emitting region of the FSRQ. SED fitting of the other two flux states further
supports these inferences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06188</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Crippa</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nobili</keyname><forenames>Camilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seis</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spirito</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Eulerian and Lagrangian solutions to the continuity and Euler equations
  with $L^1$ vorticity</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the first part of this paper we establish a uniqueness result for
continuity equations with velocity field whose derivative can be represented by
a singular integral operator of an $L^1$ function, extending the Lagrangian
theory in \cite{BouchutCrippa13}. The proof is based on a combination of a
stability estimate via optimal transport techniques developed in \cite{Seis16a}
and some tools from harmonic analysis introduced in \cite{BouchutCrippa13}. In
the second part of the paper, we address a question that arose in
\cite{FilhoMazzucatoNussenzveig06}, namely whether 2D Euler solutions obtained
via vanishing viscosity are renormalized (in the sense of DiPerna and Lions)
when the initial data has low integrability. We show that this is the case even
when the initial vorticity is only in~$L^1$, extending the proof for the $L^p$
case in \cite{CrippaSpirito15}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06202</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Weitzel</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bockelman</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Duncan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couvares</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xfc;rthwein</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>Edgar Fajardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Data Access for LIGO on the OSG</title><categories>cs.DC astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, submitted to PEARC17</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During 2015 and 2016, the Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory
(LIGO) conducted a three-month observing campaign. These observations delivered
the first direct detection of gravitational waves from binary black hole
mergers. To search for these signals, the LIGO Scientific Collaboration uses
the PyCBC search pipeline. To deliver science results in a timely manner, LIGO
collaborated with the Open Science Grid (OSG) to distribute the required
computation across a series of dedicated, opportunistic, and allocated
resources. To deliver the petabytes necessary for such a large-scale
computation, our team deployed a distributed data access infrastructure based
on the XRootD server suite and the CernVM File System (CVMFS). This data access
strategy grew from simply accessing remote storage to a POSIX-based interface
underpinned by distributed, secure caches across the OSG.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06209</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chesley</keyname><forenames>Steven R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veres</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Projected Near-Earth Object Discovery Performance of the Large Synoptic
  Survey Telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><report-no>JPL Publication 16-11 (April 2017)</report-no><doi>10.5281/zenodo.580425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This report describes the methodology and results of an assessment study of
the performance of the Large Synoptic Survey Telescope (LSST) in its planned
efforts to detect and catalog near-Earth objects (NEOs). The baseline LSST
survey approach is designed to make only two visits to a given field in a given
night, leading to two possible NEO detections per night. These nightly pairs
must be linked across nights to derive orbits of moving objects. However, the
presence of false detections in the data stream leads to the possibility of
high rates of false tracklets, and the ensuing risk that the resulting orbit
catalog may be contaminated by false orbits. To understand the challenges
stemming from a two-visit-per-night cadence, we conducted high-fidelity linkage
tests on a full-density simulated LSST detection stream. We also sought to
quantify the overall performance of LSST as an NEO discovery system under the
hypothesis that detections from the baseline cadence can be successfully
linked. Our simulations revealed that in 10 years LSST would catalog ~60% of
NEOs with absolute magnitude H&lt;22, which is a proxy for 140m and larger
objects. This results neglects linking losses and the contribution of any other
NEO surveys. Including our worst-case linking efficiency we reach a overall
performance assessment of 55% completeness of NEOs with H&lt;22. We estimate that
survey mis-modeling could account for systematic errors of up to 5%. We find
that restricting the evaluation metric to so-called Potentially Hazardous
Asteroids (PHAs) increases the completeness by 3-4%, and that including the
benefits of past and expected future NEO survey activity increases completeness
at the end of the baseline LSST survey by 15-20%. Assembling these results
leads to a projection that by the end of the baseline LSST survey the NEO
catalog will be 80+/-5% complete for PHAs with H &lt; 22.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06221</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Cely</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyong</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-interacting dark matter as a solution to the problems in
  small-scale structures</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented at Moriond Electroweak (23 Mar. 2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter self-interactions are a well-motivated solution to the
core-vs.-cusp and the too-big-to-fail problems. They are commonly induced by
means of a light mediator, that is also responsible for the dark matter
freeze-out in the early universe. Motivated by the fact that such scenario is
excluded in its simplest realizations, we will discuss the possibility that the
relic density of a self-interacting dark matter candidate can proceed from the
freeze-out of only annihilations into SM particles. We will argue that scalar
and Majorana dark matter in the mass range of 10 to 500 MeV, coupled to a
slightly heavier massive gauge boson, are the only candidates in agreement with
multiple current experimental constraints. We will also discuss prospects of
establishing or excluding these two scenarios in future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06228</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Morawetz</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Reversed Currents in Charged Liquid Bridges</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Water 2017, 9(5), 353</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/w9050353</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The velocity profile in a water bridge is reanalyzed. Assuming hypothetically
that the bulk charge has a radial distribution, a surface potential is formed
that is analogous to the Zeta potential. The Navier Stokes equation is solved,
neglecting the convective term; then, analytically and for special field and
potential ranges, a sign change of the total mass flow is reported caused by
the radial charge distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06230</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasankiadeh</keyname><forenames>Qader Dorosti</forenames><affiliation>for the Pierre Auger Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Advanced Reconstruction Strategies for the Auger Engineering Radio Array</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>6th International Conference on Acoustic and Radio EeV Neutrino
  Detection Activities, 2014</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Auger Engineering Radio Array (AERA) aims to detect extensive air showers
caused by the interactions of ultra-high energy cosmic rays with the Earth's
atmosphere, providing complementary information to the Auger surface,
fluorescence and muon detectors. AERA, currently consisting of 124 radio
stations, comprises an area of about 6 km$^{2}$. The main objective for
exploiting a radio detector is to measure the fundamental air-shower
parameters, such as the direction, energy and composition. We have developed
reconstruction strategies and algorithms to precisely measure the air-shower
parameters with high efficiency. In addition, we will present the results
obtained by applying the reconstruction strategies on the experimental data
taken by AERA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06233</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Ming-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Yuwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Shinian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yiqin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yuwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Shouyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the Magnetizing Relationship of the Kickers for CSNS</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to proceedings of IPAC2017, Copenhagen, Denmark, May 14-19,
  2017</comments><report-no>MOPIK036</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extraction system of CSNS mainly consists of two kinds of magnets: eight
kickers and one lambertson magnet. In this paper, firstly, the magnetic test
results of the eight kickers were introduced and then the filed uniformity and
magnetizing relationship of the kickers were given. Secondly, during the beam
commissioning in the future, in order to obtain more accurate magnetizing
relationship, a new method to measure the magnetizing coefficients of the
kickers by the real extraction beam was given and the data analysis would also
be processed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06234</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Liangxiao</forenames></author></authors><title>A charging method for electric vehicle using multi battery series mode</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A charging method for electric vehicle using multi battery series mode which
consisted of the following steps was introduced: the battery series is firstly
charged at a constant power with a charging current of I1. When the terminal
voltage over the battery series has reached the 1st threshold voltage, the
charging current will reduce to I2 and the power remains constant. When the
terminal voltage over the battery series has reached the 2nd threshold voltage,
the charging current will reduce to I3 and the power remains constant (the 2nd
threshold voltage is larger than 1st threshold voltage). When the terminal
voltage over the battery series has reached the 3rd threshold voltage, which is
the rated voltage of the battery series, the charging process is completed (3rd
threshold voltage is larger than 2nd threshold voltage). Contents in this paper
provide a charging method for electric vehicles using multi battery series mode
with high charging efficiency and security level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06237</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Crespi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bentivegna</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitsios</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusca</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poderini</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvacho</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabello</keyname><forenames>Ad&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciarrino</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osellame</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-photon quantum contextuality on a chip</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In classical physics, properties of the objects exist independently on the
context, i.e. whether and how measurements are performed. Quantum physics
showed this assumption to be wrong and that Nature is indeed &quot;contextual&quot;.
Contextuality has been observed in the simplest physical systems such as single
particles, and plays fundamental roles in quantum computation advantage. Here,
we demonstrate for the first time quantum contextuality in an integrated
photonic chip. The chip implements different combinations of measurements on a
single photon delocalized on four distinct spatial modes. We show violations of
a CHSH-like non-contextuality inequality by 14 standard deviations. This paves
the way to compact and portable devices for contextuality-based quantum-powered
protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06248</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Grinberg</keyname><forenames>Itay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gendelman</keyname><forenames>Oleg V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization in Coupled Finite Vibro-Impact Chains: Discrete Breathers
  and Multibreathers</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>06B99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the dynamics of strongly localized periodic solutions (discrete
breathers) in two-dimensional array of coupled finite one-dimensional chains of
oscillators. Localization patterns with both single and multiple localization
sites (multibreathers) are considered. The model is scalar, i.e. each particle
can move only parallel to the axis of the chain it belongs to. The model
involves symmetric parabolic on-site potential with rigid constraints (the
displacement domain of each particle is finite) and a linear nearest-neighbor
coupling in the chain, and also between the neighbors in adjacent chains. When
the particle approaches the constraint, it undergoes an elastic Newtonian
impact. The rigid impact constraints are the only source of nonlinearity in the
system. The model allows easy computation of highly accurate approximate
solutions for the breathers and multibreathers with an arbitrary set of
localization sites in conservative setting. The vibro-impact nonlinearity
permits explicit derivation of a monodromy matrix for the breather and
multi-breather solutions. Consequently, the stability of the derived breather
and multibreather solutions can be studied in the framework of simple methods
of linear algebra, without additional approximations. It is shown that due to
the coupling of the chains, the breather solutions can undergo the symmetry
breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06254</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Bobrov</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokkedee</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gribov</keyname><forenames>N. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanson</keyname><forenames>I. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>A. G. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of nonequilibrium phonons on the amplitude of magnetoquantum
  oscillations in the point-contact resistance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica B, 204, 83 (1995)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/0921-4526(94)00246-R</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For metallic point contacts with Be and Al the magnetoquantum oscillations in
the contact resistance have been investigated as a function of the applied
voltage over the contact. For one set of point contacts the oscillation
amplitude is found to vary nonmonotonously with the applied voltage with
similarities to the point-contact spectrum of the electron-phonon interaction.
The other part of the investigated point contacts shows a decrease of the
oscillation amplitude with increasing bias voltage. For the understanding of
the voltage dependence of the amplitude of the point-contact magnetoresistance
oscillations the influence of nonequilibrium phonons generated by the
ballistically injected electrons will be discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06267</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolesov</keyname><forenames>Grigory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocia</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heller</keyname><forenames>Eric J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Graphene Terahertz Absorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unique terahertz properties of graphene has been identified for novel
optoelectronic applications. In a graphene sample with bias voltage added,
there is an enhanced absorption in the far infrared region and a diminished
absorption in the infrared region. The strength of enhancement(diminishment)
increases with the gate voltage, and the enhancement compensates the
diminishment. We find that it is the coherence length of electrons in graphene
that allows pure electronic transitions between states differing by small
momentums and makes intraband transition possible, is responsible for the far
infrared enhancement. Phonon assisted processes are not necessary and would not
in any case contribute to a sum rule. This naturally leads to results obeying
the general sum-rule in optical absorptions. Our prediction of the strength of
enhancement(diminishment) in terms of the bias agrees with experiments. This is
the first direct calculation we are aware of, since the prior phonon assisted
model for indirect transition should not obey a sum rule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06276</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ayuso</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence in Molecular Photoionization</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>PhD thesis, Universidad Autonoma de Madrid, Dec 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of attosecond technology has enabled the real-time
observation of coherent electron motion in atoms, molecules and condensed
phases. Experimentally, it is now possible to generate laser pulses of
durations of only a few tens of attoseconds. These durations are of the order
of the revolution period of the first Bohr orbit (150 asec), opening the way to
visualize and even control electron dynamics at its natural time scale. This
PhD thesis constitutes a theoretical study of fundamental phenomena occurring
in gas-phase molecules upon interaction with light. We have investigated
ultrafast charge migration in biological molecules initiated by attosecond XUV
pulses. In addition, we have studied the high-energy interferences that arise
in the vibrationally-resolved photoelectron spectra of small polyatomic
molecules. In order to explore these complex phenomena, we have employed
numerical methods that describe molecular photoionization by evaluating
continuum scattering wave functions, allowing us to compute different
observables such as time-dependent electron densities or photoionization cross
sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
