<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:09:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-26" from="2017-05-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.4250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.4250</id><created>2012-12-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames><affiliation>TAPIR, Caltech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>O'Connor</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames><affiliation>CITA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gossan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>TAPIR, Caltech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Abdikamalov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>TAPIR, Caltech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gamma</keyname><forenames>U. C. T.</forenames><affiliation>TAPIR, Caltech</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Drasco</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Grinnell</affiliation><affiliation>TAPIR, Caltech</affiliation></author></authors><title>Core-Collapse Supernovae, Neutrinos, and Gravitational Waves</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of the Neutrino
  2012 conference, Kyoto, Japan. arXiv admin note: the fifth author on the
  list, U. Gamma, is fictitious</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2013.04.036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Core-collapse supernovae are among the most energetic cosmic cataclysms. They
are prodigious emitters of neutrinos and quite likely strong galactic sources
of gravitational waves. Observation of both neutrinos and gravitational waves
from the next galactic or near extragalactic core-collapse supernova will yield
a wealth of information on the explosion mechanism, but also on the structure
and angular momentum of the progenitor star, and on aspects of fundamental
physics such as the equation of state of nuclear matter at high densities and
low entropies. In this contribution to the proceedings of the Neutrino 2012
conference, we summarize recent progress made in the theoretical understanding
and modeling of core-collapse supernovae. In this, our emphasis is on
multi-dimensional processes involved in the explosion mechanism such as
neutrino-driven convection and the standing accretion shock instability. As an
example of how supernova neutrinos can be used to probe fundamental physics, we
discuss how the rise time of the electron antineutrino flux observed in
detectors can be used to probe the neutrino mass hierarchy. Finally, we lay out
aspects of the neutrino and gravitational-wave signature of core-collapse
supernovae and discuss the power of combined analysis of neutrino and
gravitational wave data from the next galactic core-collapse supernova.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.7576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.7576</id><created>2013-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>V&#xe4;is&#xe4;l&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harju</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mantere</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miettinen</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sault</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walmsley</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whiteoak</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-resolution ammonia mapping of the very young protostellar core
  Chamaeleon-MMS1</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures. Submitted to Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 564, A99 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201322069</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cha-MMS1 was mapped in the NH_3(1,1) line and the 1.2 cm continuum using the
Australia Telescope Compact Array, ATCA. The angular resolution of the ATCA
observations is 7'' (~ 1000 AU), and the velocity resolution is 50 m s^{-1}.
The core was also mapped with the 64-m Parkes telesope in the NH_3(1,1) and
(2,2) lines. Observations from Herschel Space Observatory and Spitzer Space
telescope were used to help interpretation. A compact high column density core
with a steep velocity gradient is detected in ammonia, with a fractional
ammonia abundance compatible with determinations towards other dense cores. The
direction of the velocity gradient agrees with previous single-dish
observations, and the overall velocity distribution can be interpreted as
rotation. The rotation axis goes through the position of a compact far-infrared
source detected by Spitzer and Herschel. The specific angular momentum of the
core is typical for protostellar envelopes. A string of 1.2 cm continuum
sources is tentatively detected near the rotation axis. The ammonia spectra
suggest the presence of warm embedded gas in its vicinity. An hourglass-shaped
structure is seen in ammonia at the cloud's average LSR velocity, also aligned
with the rotation axis. Although this structure resembles a pair of outflow
lobes the ammonia spectra show no indications of shocked gas. The observed
ammonia structure mainly delineates the inner envelope around the central
source. The velocity gradient is likely to originate in the angular momentum of
the contracting core, although influence of the outflow from the neighbouring
young star IRS4 is possibly visible on one side of the core. The tentative
continuum detection and the indications of a warm background component near the
rotation axis suggest that the core contains a deeply embedded outflow which
may have been missed in previous single-dish CO surveys owing to beam dilution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.1504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.1504</id><created>2014-06-05</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kol</keyname><forenames>Barak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shir</keyname><forenames>Ruth</forenames></author></authors><title>1-loop Color structures and sunny diagrams</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, v2: typo corrected in Table 1</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2015)085</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently the space of tree level color structures for gluon scattering was
determined in arXiv:1403.6837 together with its transformation properties under
permutations. Here we generalize the discussion to loops, demonstrating a
reduction of an arbitrary color diagram to its vacuum skeleton plus rays. For
1-loop there are no residual relations and we determine the space of color
structures both diagrammatically and algebraically in terms of certain sunny
diagrams. We present the generating function for the characteristic polynomials
and a list of irreducible representations for $3 \le n \le 9$ external legs.
Finally we present a new proof for the 1-loop shuffle relations based on the
cyclic shuffle and split operations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2138</id><created>2014-06-09</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salazar</keyname><forenames>Maria Amelia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sepe</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Contact Isotropic Realisations of Jacobi Manifolds via Spencer Operators</title><categories>math.SG math.DG nlin.SI</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 033, 44 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.033</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the importance of symplectic isotropic realisations in the study
of Poisson manifolds, this paper investigates the local and global theory of
contact isotropic realisations of Jacobi manifolds, which are those of minimal
dimension. These arise naturally when considering multiplicity-free actions in
contact geometry, as shown in this paper. The main results concern a
classification of these realisations up to a suitable notion of isomorphism, as
well as establishing a relation between the existence of symplectic and contact
isotropic realisations for Poisson manifolds. The main tool is the classical
Spencer operator which is related to Jacobi structures via their associated Lie
algebroid, which allows to generalise previous results as well as providing
more conceptual proofs for existing ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.2909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.2909</id><created>2014-07-10</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smolin</keyname><forenames>Lee</forenames></author></authors><title>Linking shape dynamics and loop quantum gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, no figures, mistake fixed, other small changes</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 90, 044070 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.90.044070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Shape dynamics is a reformulation of general relativity, locally equivalent
to Einstein's theory, in which the refoliation invariance of the older theory
is traded for local scale invariance. Shape dynamics is here derived in a
formulation related to the Ashtekar variables by beginning with a modification
of the Plebanski action. The constraints of shape dynamics and their algebra
are reproduced in terms of these new variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1706</id><created>2014-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Spallucci</keyname><forenames>Euro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smailagic</keyname><forenames>Anais</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-classical approach to quantum black holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>27 pages, 9 figures. This is the draft of an invited contribution to
  the book &quot;Advances in black hole researches&quot;, Nova Science Publisher, (2015)</comments><journal-ref>&quot;Advances in black holes research'' p.1-26, Ed.: A. Barton, Nova
  Science Publisher, Inc. (2015), ISBN: 978-1-63463-168-6</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Chapter we would like to review a &quot;~phenomenological~&quot; approach
taking into account the most fundamental feature of string theory or, more in
general, of quantum gravity, whatever its origin, which is the existence of a
minimal length in the space-time fabric. This length is generally identified
with the Planck length, or the string length, but it could be also much longer
down to the TeV region. A simple and effective way to keep track of the effects
the minimal length in black hole geometries is to solve the Einstein equations
with an energy momentum tensor describing non point-like matter. The immediate
consequence is the absence of any curvature singularity. Where textbook
solutions of the Einstein equations loose any physical meaning because of
infinite tidal forces, we find a de Sitter vacuum core of high, but finite,
energy density and pressure. An additional improvement regards the final stage
of the black hole evaporation leading to a vanishing Hawking temperature even
in the neutral, non-rotating, case. In spite of th simplicity of this model we
are able to describe the final stage of the black hole evaporation, resulting
in a cold remnant with a degenerate, extremal, horizon of radius of the order
of the minimal length. In this chapter we shall describe only neutral,
spherically symmetric, regular black holes although charged, rotating and
higher dimensional black holes can be found in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.3270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.3270</id><created>2014-11-12</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duhart</keyname><forenames>Horacio Gonz&#xe1;lez</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;rters</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmer</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>The Semi-Infinite Asymmetric Exclusion Process: Large Deviations via
  Matrix Products</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures</comments><msc-class>Primary 60F10, Secondary 37K05, 60K35, 82C22</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the totally asymmetric exclusion process on the positive integers
with a single particle source at the origin. Liggett (1975) has shown that the
long term behaviour of this process has a phase transition: If the particle
production rate at the source is below a critical value, the stationary measure
is a product measure, otherwise the stationary measure is spatially correlated.
Following the approach of Derrida et al. (1993) it was shown by Gro{\ss}kinsky
(2004) that these correlations can be described by means of a matrix product
representation. In this paper we derive a large deviation principle with
explicit rate function for the particle density in a macroscopic box based on
this representation. The novel and rigorous technique we develop for this
problem combines spectral theoretical and combinatorial ideas and has the
potential to be applicable to other models described by matrix products.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02311</id><created>2015-04-09</created><updated>2016-04-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Subramanian</keyname><forenames>Kandaswamy</forenames></author></authors><title>The origin, evolution and signatures of primordial magnetic fields</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>57 pages, 12 figures, Invited review for Reports on Progress in
  Physics, in Press</comments><journal-ref>Reports on Progress in Physics, Volume 79, Issue 7, article id.
  076901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/79/7/076901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The universe is magnetized on all scales probed so far. On the largest
scales, galaxies and galaxy clusters host magnetic fields at the micro Gauss
level coherent on scales up to ten kpc. Recent observational evidence suggests
that even the intergalactic medium in voids could host a weak $\sim 10^{-16}$
Gauss magnetic field, coherent on Mpc scales. An intriguing possibility is that
these observed magnetic fields are a relic from the early universe, albeit one
which has been subsequently amplified and maintained by a dynamo in collapsed
objects. We review here the origin, evolution and signatures of primordial
magnetic fields. After a brief summary of magnetohydrodynamics in the expanding
universe, we turn to magnetic field generation during inflation and other phase
transitions. We trace the linear and nonlinear evolution of the generated
primordial fields through the radiation era, including viscous effects.
Sensitive observational signatures of primordial magnetic fields on the cosmic
microwave background, including current constraints from Planck, are discussed.
After recombination, primordial magnetic fields could strongly influence
structure formation, especially on dwarf galaxy scales. The resulting
signatures on reionization, the redshifted 21 cm line, weak lensing and the
Lyman-$\alpha$ forest are outlined. Constraints from radio and $\gamma$-ray
astronomy are summarized. Astrophysical batteries and the role of dynamos in
reshaping the primordial field are briefly considered. The review ends with
some final thoughts on primordial magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06719</id><created>2015-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Alves</keyname><forenames>Erivelton O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Wesley B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avelar</keyname><forenames>Ardiley T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation instability in high-order coupled nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger
  equations with saturable nonlinearities</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 33, 1134-1142 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.33.001134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of a saturable nonlinearity on the modulation instability in
oppositely directed coupler in the presence of high-order effects is
investigated. By using the standard linear stability analysis, we obtain the
instability gain that exhibits a significant change in the bands of instability
due to the effects of a saturable nonlinearity. We also show that even in the
presence of saturation there is no change in instability gain when we compare
the results obtained for both channels not influenced by self-steepening effect
or for both channels influenced by self-steepening effect but opposite in sign.
Regarding the Raman effect, there is reflection symmetry (asymmetry) to the
gain at zero perturbation frequency when the values of the Raman coefficients
in each directional coupler are equal and with same (opposite) sign. For the
anomalous group velocity dispersion regime we observe that the growth of the
saturation parameter is followed by an increase in the null gain region near
{\Omega} = 0, enlarging the separation of the instability bands close to this
point. Finally, we show that an efficient control of the modulation instability
can be realized by adjusting self-steepening effect and intrapulse Raman
scattering, even in the presence of a saturable nonlinearity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02573</id><created>2015-08-11</created><updated>2016-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Daoyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>Ian R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabitz</keyname><forenames>Herschel</forenames></author></authors><title>Fault Tolerant Filtering and Fault Detection for Quantum Systems Driven
  By Fields in Single Photon States</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1504.06780</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 57, 062201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4952760</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to solve a fault tolerant filtering and fault
detection problem for a class of open quantum systems driven by a
continuous-mode bosonic input field in single photon states when the systems
are subject to stochastic faults. Optimal estimates of both the system
observables and the fault process are simultaneously calculated and
characterized by a set of coupled recursive quantum stochastic differential
equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00158</id><created>2015-09-01</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berczik</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spurzem</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Boosted Tidal Disruption by Massive Black Hole Binaries During Galaxy
  Mergers FROM The View of N-Body Simulation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/2/195</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supermassive black hole binaries (SMBHBs) are productions of the hierarchical
galaxy formation model. There are many close connections between central SMBH
and its host galaxy because the former plays very important roles on the
formation and evolution of a galaxy. For this reason, the evolution of SMBHBs
in merging galaxies is an essential problem. Since there are many discussions
about SMBHB evolution in gas rich environment, we focus on the quiescent
galaxy, using tidal disruption as a diagnostic tool. Our study is based on a
series of numerical large particle number direct N-body simulations for dry
major mergers. According to the simulation results, the evolution can be
divided into three phases. In phase I, the tidal disruption rate for two well
separated SMBHs in merging system has similar level to single SMBH in isolate
galaxy. After two SMBHs getting close enough to form a bound binary in phase
II, the disruption rate can be enhanced for ~ 2 order of magnitudes within a
short time. This &quot;boosted&quot; disruption stage finishes after the SMBHB evolving
to compact binary system in phase III, corresponding to a drop back of
disruption rate to a level of a few times higher than that in Phase I. How to
correctly extrapolate our N-body simulation results to reality, and
implications of our results to observations, are discussed too.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02199</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amariti</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Integral identities for 3d dualities with SP(2N) gauge groups</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 2 figures, typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we study the reduction of 4d Seiberg duality to 3d for SP(2N)
SQCD with an adjoint field. We follow a general prescription that consists in
compactifying the dual 4d theories on the circle. This generates an effective
3d duality. The pure 3d duality is obtained by combining the zero radius limit
with a real mass flow. Here we perform this limit by a double scaling
procedure: we turn on real masses proportional to the radius before shrinking
the circle. We apply this mechanism to the reduction of the 4d superconformal
index to the three sphere partition function. While the reduction of the 4d
index on the circle is straightforward, the 3d limit necessitates the double
scaling. We describe this limit on the index, finding the integral identity for
the partition functions of the 3d dual theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06609</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flanigan</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarrick</keyname><forenames>Heather</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Glenn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Bradley R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abitbol</keyname><forenames>Maximilian H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Araujo</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradford</keyname><forenames>Kristi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cantor</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Che</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Day</keyname><forenames>Peter K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doyle</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kjellstrand</keyname><forenames>Carl Bjorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>LeDuc</keyname><forenames>Henry G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limon</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luu</keyname><forenames>Vy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Amber</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mroczkowski</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Carole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmuidzinas</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon noise from chaotic and coherent millimeter-wave sources measured
  with horn-coupled, aluminum lumped-element kinetic inductance detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Matches published version (which is open access) and includes
  supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 108, 083504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4942804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report photon-noise limited performance of horn-coupled, aluminum
lumped-element kinetic inductance detectors at millimeter wavelengths. The
detectors are illuminated by a millimeter-wave source that uses an active
multiplier chain to produce radiation between 140 and 160 GHz. We feed the
multiplier with either amplified broadband noise or a continuous-wave tone from
a microwave signal generator. We demonstrate that the detector response over a
40 dB range of source power is well-described by a simple model that considers
the number of quasiparticles. The detector noise-equivalent power (NEP) is
dominated by photon noise when the absorbed power is greater than approximately
1 pW, which corresponds to $\mathrm{NEP} \approx 2 \times 10^{-17} \,
\mathrm{W} \, \mathrm{Hz}^{-1/2}$, referenced to absorbed power. At higher
source power levels we observe the relationships between noise and power
expected from the photon statistics of the source signal: $\mathrm{NEP} \propto
P$ for broadband (chaotic) illumination and $\mathrm{NEP} \propto P^{1/2}$ for
continuous-wave (coherent) illumination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06676</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kr&#x161;&#x161;&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Renormalization in Teleparallel Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, v3: Extended discussion on reference tetrads. Matches the
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.1, 44</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4621-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of IR divergences of the action in the covariant
formulation of teleparallel gravity in asymptotically Minkowski spacetimes. We
show that divergences are caused by inertial effects and can be removed by
adding an appropriate surface term, leading to the renormalized action. This
process can be viewed as a teleparallel analogue of holographic
renormalization. Moreover, we explore the variational problem in teleparallel
gravity and explain how the variation with respect to the spin connection
should be performed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07194</id><created>2015-10-24</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Cheuk-Yin</forenames></author></authors><title>Event-by-Event Study of Space-Time Dynamics in Flux-Tube Fragmentation</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal pf Physics G 44, 075102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa6fdb</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the semi-classical description of the flux-tube fragmentation process for
hadron production and hadronization in high-energy $e^+e^-$ annihilations and
$pp$ collisions, the rapidity-space-time ordering and the local conservation
laws of charge, flavor, and momentum provide a set of powerful tools that may
allow the reconstruction of the space-time dynamics of quarks and mesons in
exclusive measurements of produced hadrons, on an event-by-event basis. We
propose procedures to reconstruct the space-time dynamics from event-by-event
exclusive hadron data to exhibit explicitly the ordered chain of hadrons
produced in a flux tube fragmentation. As a supplementary tool, we infer the
average space-time coordinates of the $q$-$\bar q$ pair production vertices
from the $\pi^-$ rapidity distribution data obtained by the NA61/SHINE
Collaboration in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}$ = 6.3 to 17.3 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06450</id><created>2015-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Colombi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guenneau</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roux</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation seismology: composite soil lenses for steering surface
  elastic Rayleigh waves</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.geo-ph physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1038/srep25320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metamaterials are artificially structured media that can focus (lensing) or
reroute (cloaking) waves, and typically this is developed for electromagnetic
waves at millimetric down to nanometric scales or for acoustics or thin elastic
plates at centimeter scales. Extending the concepts of Kadic et al. 2013 we
show that the underlying ideas are generic across wave systems and scales by
generalizing these concepts to seismic waves at frequencies, and lengthscales
of the order of hundreds of meters, relevant to civil engineering. By applying
ideas from transformation optics we can manipulate and steer Rayleigh surface
wave solutions of the vector Navier equations of elastodynamics; this is
unexpected as this vector system is, unlike Maxwell's electromagnetic
equations, not form invariant under transformations. As a paradigm of the
conformal geophysics that we are creating, we design a square arrangement of
Luneburg lenses to reroute and then refocus Rayleigh waves around a building
with the dual aim of protection and minimizing the effect on the wavefront
(cloaking) after exiting the lenses. To show that this is practically
realisable we deliberately choose to use material parameters readily available
and this metalens consists of a composite soil structured with buried pillars
made of softer material. The regular lattice of inclusions is homogenized to
give an effective material with a radially varying velocity profile that can be
directly interpreted as a lens refractive index. We develop the theory and then
use full 3D time domain numerical simulations to conclusively demonstrate the
validity of the transformation seismology ideas: we demonstrate, at frequencies
of seismological relevance 3-10 Hz, and for low speed sedimentary soil ($v_s$:
300-500 m/s), that the vibration of a structure is reduced by up to 6 dB at its
resonance frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07775</id><created>2015-12-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Higuchi</keyname><forenames>Katsuhiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higuchi</keyname><forenames>Masahiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Basic variables to be reproduced in the first-principles theory for
  superconductors: Fluctuation of the particle number</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>no figure</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 064704/1-11 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.064704</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the diagonal elements of the second-order reduced density matrix
(RDM2) can be chosen as basic variables for describing the superconducting
state, instead of the off-diagonal elements of the RDM2 that are usually
adopted as basic variables in the density functional scheme. The diagonal
elements of the RDM2 are called pair-density (PD), which is explicitly related
to the fluctuation of the particle number of the system. In this paper, we
argue that the fluctuation of the particle number can become an indication of
the superconducting state, and that the density functional scheme in which the
PD is chosen as a basic variable would be a promising first-principles theory
for superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03576</id><created>2016-02-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chenlu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Guodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Aiji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jianwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nie</keyname><forenames>Simin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Hongming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lingxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Genfu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Xiaowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Shaolong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fengfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shenjin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Qinjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zuyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chuangtian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic Evidence of Temperature-Induced Lifshitz Transition and
  Topological Nature in ZrTe5</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>22 Pages, 4 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15512 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topological materials have attracted much attention recently. While
three-dimensional topological insulators are becoming abundant, two-dimensional
topological insulators remain rare, particularly in natural materials. ZrTe5
has host a long-standing puzzle on its anomalous transport properties; its
underlying origin remains elusive. Lately, ZrTe5 has ignited renewed interest
because it is predicted that single-layer ZrTe5 is a two-dimensional
topological insulator and there is possibly a topological phase transition in
bulk ZrTe5. However, the topological nature of ZrTe5 is under debate as some
experiments point to its being a three-dimensional or quasi-two-dimensional
Dirac semimetal. Here we report high-resolution laser-based angle-resolved
photoemission measurements on ZrTe5. The electronic property of ZrTe5 is
dominated by two branches of nearly-linear-dispersion bands at the Brillouin
zone center. These two bands are separated by an energy gap that decreases with
decreasing temperature but persists down to the lowest temperature we measured
(~2 K). The overall electronic structure exhibits a dramatic temperature
dependence; it evolves from a p-type semimetal with a hole-like Fermi pocket at
high temperature, to a semiconductor around ~135 K where its resistivity
exhibits a peak, to an n-type semimetal with an electron-like Fermi pocket at
low temperature. These results indicate a clear electronic evidence of the
temperature-induced Lifshitz transition in ZrTe5. They provide a natural
understanding on the underlying origin of the resistivity anomaly at ~135 K and
its associated reversal of the charge carrier type. Our observations also
provide key information on deciphering the topological nature of ZrTe5 and
possible temperature-induced topological phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05194</id><created>2016-02-16</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Potter</keyname><forenames>Andrew C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morimoto</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishwanath</keyname><forenames>Ashvin</forenames></author></authors><title>Classification of Interacting Topological Floquet Phases in One
  Dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, v3: title changed to reflect published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 041001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.041001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Periodic driving of a quantum system can enable new topological phases with
no analog in static systems. In this paper we systematically classify
one-dimensional topological and symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phases in
interacting fermionic and bosonic quantum systems subject to periodic driving,
which we dub Floquet SPTs (FSPTs). For physical realizations of interacting
FSPTs, many-body localization by disorder is a crucial ingredient, required to
obtain a stable phase that does not catastrophically heat to infinite
temperature. We demonstrate that bosonic and fermionic FSPTs phases are
classified by the same criteria as equilibrium phases, but with an enlarged
symmetry group $\tilde G$, that now includes discrete time translation symmetry
associated with the Floquet evolution. In particular, 1D bosonic FSPTs are
classified by projective representations of the enlarged symmetry group
$H^2({\tilde G},U(1))$. We construct explicit lattice models for a variety of
systems, and then formalize the classification to demonstrate the completeness
of this construction. We also derive general constraints on localization and
symmetry based on the representation theory of the symmetry group, and show
that symmetry-preserving localized phases are possible only for Abelian
symmetry groups. In particular, this rules out the possibility of many-body
localized SPTs with continuous spin symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07338</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vivek</keyname><forenames>Skanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelleher</keyname><forenames>Colm P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaikin</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weeks</keyname><forenames>Eric R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long Wavelength Fluctuations and the Glass Transition in 2D and 3D</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. 114, 1850-1855 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1607226113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phase transitions significantly differ between two-dimensional and
three-dimensional systems, but the influence of dimensionality on the glass
transition is unresolved. We use microscopy to study colloidal systems as they
approach their glass transitions at high concentrations, and find differences
between 2D and 3D. We find that in 2D particles can undergo large displacements
without changing their position relative to their neighbors, in contrast with
3D. This is related to Mermin-Wagner long-wavelength fluctuations that
influence phase transitions in 2D. However, when measuring particle motion only
relative to their neighbors, 2D and 3D have similar behavior as the glass
transition is approached, showing that the long wavelength fluctuations do not
cause a fundamental distinction between 2D and 3D glass transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05911</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Spallucci</keyname><forenames>Euro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smailagic</keyname><forenames>Anais</forenames></author></authors><title>A particle-like description of Planckian black holes</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 Figures. Draft of the invited contribution to the book:
  &quot;Quantum Gravity: Theory and Research&quot; Nova Science Publishers, Inc</comments><journal-ref>&quot;Quantum Gravity: Theory and Research&quot;, Ed.: B. Mitchell, Nova
  Science Pub. Inc. (2017), ISBN: 978-1-53610-798-2</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we abandon the idea that even a &quot;quantum&quot; black hole, of Planck
size, can still be described as a classical, more or less complicated,
geometry. Rather, we consider a genuine quantum mechanical approach where a
Planckian black hole is, by all means, just another &quot;particle&quot;, even if with a
distinguishing property: its linear size increases with the energy. The horizon
dynamics is equivalently described in terms of a particle moving in
gravitational potential derived from the horizon equation itself in a
self-consistent manner. The particle turning-points match the radius of the
inner and outer horizons of a charged black hole. This classical model pave the
way towards the wave equation for a truly quantum black hole. We compute the
exact form of the wave function and determine the energy spectrum. Finally, we
describe the classical limit in which the quantum picture correctly approaches
the classical geometric formulation. We find that the quantum-to-classical
transition occurs far above the Planck scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06918</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06918</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2017-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lagraa</keyname><forenames>Meriem Hadjer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagraa</keyname><forenames>Mohammed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Touhami</keyname><forenames>Nabila</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Hamiltonian formalism of the tetrad-gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages, Updated version to match with the published version in
  Class. Quant. Grav</comments><journal-ref>2017, Class. Quant. Grav. 34 115010</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed analysis of the Hamiltonian constraints of the
d-dimensional tetrad-connection gravity where the non-dynamical part of the
spatial connection is fixed to zero by an adequate guage transformation. This
new action depending on the co-tetrad and the dynamical part of the spatial
connection leads to Lorentz, scalar and vectorial first-class polynomial
constraints obeying a closed algebra in terms of Poisson brackets. This algebra
closes on the structure constants instead of structure functions resulting from
the Hamiltonian formalisms based on the A.D.M. decomposition. The same algebra
of the reduced first-class constraints defined on the reduced phase-space,
where the second-class constraints are solved, is obtained in terms of Dirac
brackets. These first-class constraintslead to the same physical degrees of
freedom of the general relativity. PACS numbers: 04.20.Cv, 04.20.Fy, 11.10.Ef,
11.30.Cp
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00640</id><created>2016-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Jentschura</keyname><forenames>Ulrich D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ehrlich</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Lepton-pair Cerenkov radiation emitted by tachyonic neutrinos:
  Lorentz-covariant approach and IceCube data</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages; accepted for publication in the Advances of High-Energy
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>Adv. High Energy Phys. 2016 (2016) 4764981</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/4764981</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current experiments do not exclude the possibility that one or more neutrinos
are very slightly superluminal or that they have a very small tachyonic mass.
Important bounds on the size of a hypothetical tachyonic neutrino mass term are
set by lepton pair Cerenkov radiation (LPCR), i.e., by the decay channel nu -&gt;
e^+ e^- nu which proceeds via a virtual Z0 boson. Here, we use a
Lorentz-invariant dispersion relation which leads to very tight constraints on
the tachyonic mass of neutrinos; we also calculate decay and energy loss rates.
A possible cutoff seen in the IceCube neutrino spectrum for E_nu &gt; 2 PeV, due
to the potential onset of LPCR, is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00704</id><created>2016-07-03</created><updated>2016-07-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>MINERvA Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Aliaga</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kordosky</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altinok</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellantoni</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bercellie</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betancourt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bravar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budd</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carneiro</keyname><forenames>M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Endress</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felix</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fields</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fine</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gago</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gran</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higuera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hurtado</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiveni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleykamp</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maher</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caicedo</keyname><forenames>D. A. Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGivern</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGowan</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messerly</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mislivec</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morfin</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousseau</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naples</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norrick</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nuruzzaman</keyname></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdue</keyname><forenames>G. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ransome</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rimal</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruterbories</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schellman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salinas</keyname><forenames>C. J. Solano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falero</keyname><forenames>S. Sanchez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tice</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valencia</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolcott</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wospakrik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Flux Predictions for the NuMI Beam</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>v2 includes supplemental material consisting of the flux prediction
  and uncertainties in ascii and root format, a program to read the ascii
  datafiles, and a short guide with additional details. v3 fixes a couple of
  typographical errors on the units for some quantities in the beam focusing
  section</comments><report-no>Fermilab PUB-16-091-ND</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 092005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.092005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Knowledge of the neutrino flux produced by the Neutrinos at the Main Injector
(NuMI) beamline is essential to the neutrino oscillation and neutrino
interaction measurements of the MINERvA, MINOS+, NOvA and MicroBooNE
experiments at Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory. We have produced a flux
prediction which uses all available and relevant hadron production data,
incorporating measurements of particle production off of thin targets as well
as measurements of particle yields from a spare NuMI target exposed to a 120
GeV proton beam. The result is the most precise flux prediction achieved for a
neutrino beam in the one to tens of GeV energy region. We have also compared
the prediction to in situ measurements of the neutrino flux and find good
agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04158</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cuesta</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delius</keyname><forenames>Gustav W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Sheldon Spectrum and the Plankton Paradox: Two Sides of the Same Coin. A
  trait-based plankton size-spectrum model</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 1 figure, needs Springer class file svjour3.cls</comments><msc-class>92D40, 92D25, 92C37</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Biol. (2017) 1--30</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00285-017-1132-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Sheldon spectrum describes a remarkable regularity in aquatic ecosystems:
the biomass density as a function of logarithmic body mass is approximately
constant over many orders of magnitude. While size-spectrum models have
explained this phenomenon for assemblages of multicellular organisms, this
paper introduces a species-resolved size-spectrum model to explain the
phenomenon in unicellular plankton. A Sheldon spectrum spanning the cell-size
range of unicellular plankton necessarily consists of a large number of
coexisting species covering a wide range of characteristic sizes. The
coexistence of many phytoplankton species feeding on a small number of
resources is known as the Paradox of the Plankton. Our model resolves the
paradox by showing that coexistence is facilitated by the allometric scaling of
four physiological rates. Two of the allometries have empirical support, the
remaining two emerge from predator-prey interactions exactly when the
abundances follow a Sheldon spectrum. Our plankton model is a scale-invariant
trait-based size-spectrum model: it describes the abundance of phyto- and
zooplankton cells as a function of both size and species trait (the maximal
size before cell division). It incorporates growth due to resource consumption
and predation on smaller cells, death due to predation, and a flexible cell
division process. We give analytic solutions at steady state for both the
within-species size distributions and the relative abundances across species.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05897</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Peng Kian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurtsiefer</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of very narrow spectral lines with temporal intensity
  interferometry</title><categories>astro-ph.IM quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc 469, 1617-1621 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx968</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Context: Some stellar objects exhibit very narrow spectral lines in the
visible range additional to their blackbody radiation. Natural lasing has been
suggested as a mechanism to explain narrow lines in Wolf-Rayet stars. However,
the spectral resolution of conventional astronomical spectrographs is still
about two orders of magnitude too low to test this hypothesis. Aims: We want to
resolve the linewidth of narrow spectral emissions in starlight. Methods: A
combination of spectral filtering with single-photon-level temporal correlation
measurements breaks the resolution limit of wavelength-dispersing spectrographs
by moving the linewidth measurement into the time domain. Results: We
demonstrate in a laboratory experiment that temporal intensity interferometry
can determine a 20 MHz wide linewidth of Doppler-broadened laser light, and
identify a coherent laser light contribution in a blackbody radiation
background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01174</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Soares</keyname><forenames>Ivano Dami&#xe3;o</forenames></author></authors><title>A boosted Kerr black hole solution and the structure of a general
  astrophysical black hole</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 1figure</comments><msc-class>83-XX, 83C15, 83C57</msc-class><journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravitation (2017) 49:77</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2239-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A solution of Einstein's vacuum field equations that describes a boosted Kerr
black hole relative to an asymptotic Lorentz frame at the future null infinity
is derived. The solution has three parameters (mass, rotation and boost) and
corresponds to the most general configuration that an astrophysical black hole
must have; it reduces to the Kerr solution when the boost parameter is zero. In
this solution the ergosphere is north-south asymmetric, with dominant lobes in
the direction opposite to the boost. However the event horizon, the Cauchy
horizon and the ring singularity, which are the core of the black hole
structure, do not alter, being independent of the boost parameter. Possible
consequences for astrophysical processes connected with Penrose processes in
the asymmetric ergosphere are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02263</id><created>2016-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Riofrio</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flammia</keyname><forenames>S. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nigg</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blatt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental quantum compressed sensing for a seven-qubit system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages + 6 page appendix, 36 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Comm. 8, 15305 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15305</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Well-controlled quantum devices with their increasing system size face a new
roadblock hindering further development of quantum technologies: The effort of
quantum tomography---the characterization of processes and states within a
quantum device---scales unfavorably to the point that state-of-the-art systems
can no longer be treated. Quantum compressed sensing mitigates this problem by
reconstructing the state from an incomplete set of observables. In this work,
we present an experimental implementation of compressed tomography of a seven
qubit system---the largest-scale realization to date---and we introduce new
numerical methods in order to scale the reconstruction to this dimension.
Originally, compressed sensing has been advocated for density matrices with few
non-zero eigenvalues. Here, we argue that the low-rank estimates provided by
compressed sensing can be appropriate even in the general case. The reason is
that statistical noise often allows only for the leading eigenvectors to be
reliably reconstructed: We find that the remaining eigenvectors behave in a way
consistent with a random matrix model that carries no information about the
true state. We report a reconstruction of quantum states from a topological
color code of seven qubits, prepared in a trapped ion architecture, based on
tomographically incomplete data involving 127 Pauli basis measurement settings
only, repeated 100 times each.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02943</id><created>2016-08-09</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harper</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flammia</keyname><forenames>Steven T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating the fidelity of T gates using standard interleaved randomized
  benchmarking</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, 2(1) p.015008 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa5f8d</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Randomized benchmarking (RB) is an important protocol for robustly
characterizing the error rates of quantum gates. The technique is typically
applied to the Clifford gates since they form a group that satisfies a
convenient technical condition of forming a unitary 2-design, in addition to
having a tight connection to fault-tolerant quantum computing and an efficient
classical simulation. In order to achieve universal quantum computing one must
add at least one additional gate such as the T gate (also known as the $\pi$/8
gate). Here we propose and analyze a simple variation of the standard
interleaved RB protocol that can accurately estimate the average fidelity of
the T gate while retaining the many advantages of a unitary 2-design and the
fidelity guarantees that such a design delivers, as well as the efficient
classical simulation property of the Clifford group. Our work complements prior
methods that have succeeded in estimating T gate fidelities, but only by
relaxing the 2-design constraint and using a more complicated data analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08517</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Haifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorobeychik</keyname><forenames>Yevgeniy</forenames></author></authors><title>Empirically Grounded Agent-Based Models of Innovation Diffusion: A
  Critical Review</title><categories>cs.SI cs.AI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Innovation diffusion has been studied extensively in a variety of
disciplines, including sociology, economics, marketing, ecology, and computer
science. Traditional literature on innovation diffusion has been dominated by
models of aggregate behavior and trends. However, the agent-based modeling
(ABM) paradigm is gaining popularity as it captures agent heterogeneity and
enables fine-grained modeling of interactions mediated by social and geographic
networks. While most ABM work on innovation diffusion is theoretical,
empirically grounded models are increasingly important, particularly in guiding
policy decisions. We present a critical review of empirically grounded
agent-based models of innovation diffusion, developing a categorization of this
research based on types of agent models as well as applications. By connecting
the modeling methodologies in the fields of information and innovation
diffusion, we suggest that the maximum likelihood estimation framework widely
used in the former is a promising paradigm for calibration of agent-based
models for innovation diffusion. Although many advances have been made to
standardize ABM methodology, we identify four major issues in model calibration
and validation, and suggest potential solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00953</id><created>2016-09-04</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Junpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guang-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Kangjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yupeng</forenames></author></authors><title>On the solutions of the $Z_n$-Belavin model with arbitrary number of
  sites</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>24pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics B 920 (2017) 419-441</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.04.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The periodic $Z_n$-Belavin model on a lattice with an arbitrary number of
sites $N$ is studied via the off-diagonal Bethe Ansatz method (ODBA). The
eigenvalues of the corresponding transfer matrix are given in terms of an
unified inhomogeneous $T-Q$ relation. In the special case of $N=nl$ with $l$
being also a positive integer, the resulting $T-Q$ relation recovers the
homogeneous one previously obtained via algebraic Bethe Ansatz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04673</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laubscher</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kesselring</keyname><forenames>Markus S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wootton</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Poking holes and cutting corners to achieve Clifford gates with the
  surface code</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 15 figures, comments welcome; v2 - improvements and
  clarifications given in the manuscript. No significant changes in the main
  conclusions; v3 - same as v2 with corrected fig. 2 and ; v4 - minor changes
  following peer review. One new figure; v5 - version to be published, final
  author copy, minor typos and mistakes corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021029 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The surface code is currently the leading proposal to achieve fault-tolerant
quantum computation. Among its strengths are the plethora of known ways in
which fault-tolerant Clifford operations can be performed, namely, by deforming
the topology of the surface, by the fusion and splitting of codes and even by
braiding engineered Majorana modes using twist defects. Here we present a
unified framework to describe these methods, which can be used to better
compare different schemes, and to facilitate the design of hybrid schemes. Our
unification includes the identification of twist defects with the corners of
the planar code. This identification enables us to perform single-qubit
Clifford gates by exchanging the corners of the planar code via code
deformation. We analyse ways in which different schemes can be combined, and
propose a new logical encoding. We also show how all of the Clifford gates can
be implemented with the planar code without loss of distance using code
deformations, thus offering an attractive alternative to ancilla-mediated
schemes to complete the Clifford group with lattice surgery.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04754</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petrat</keyname><forenames>S&#xf6;ren</forenames></author></authors><title>Hartree Corrections in a Mean-field Limit for Fermions with Coulomb
  Interaction</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, LaTex</comments><msc-class>35Q40, 35Q55, 81Q05, 82C10</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, 50(24) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6e0b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the many-body dynamics of fermions with Coulomb interaction in a
mean-field scaling limit where the kinetic and potential energy are of the same
order for large particle numbers. In the considered limit the spatial variation
of the mean-field is small. We prove two results about this scaling limit.
First, due to the small variation, i.e., small forces, we show that the
many-body dynamics can be approximated by the free dynamics with an appropriate
phase factor with the conjectured optimal error term. Second, we show that the
Hartree dynamics gives a better approximation with a smaller error term. In
this sense, assuming that the error term in the first result is optimal, we
derive the Hartree equations from the many-body dynamics with Coulomb
interaction in a mean-field scaling limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06738</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Steve M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieder</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Filling-enforced Magnetic Dirac Semimetals in Two Dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 186401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.186401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Filling-enforced Dirac semimetals, or those required at specific fillings by
the combination of crystalline and time-reversal symmetries, have been proposed
and discovered in numerous materials. However, Dirac points in these materials
are not generally robust against breaking or modifying time-reversal symmetry.
We present a new class of two-dimensional Dirac semimetal protected by the
combination of crystal symmetries and a special, antiferromagnetic
time-reversal symmetry. Systems in this class of magnetic layer groups, while
having broken time-reversal symmetry, still respect the operation of
time-reversal followed by a half-lattice translation. In contrast to 2D
time-reversal-symmetric Dirac semimetal phases, this magnetic Dirac phase is
capable of hosting just a single isolated Dirac point at the Fermi level, and
that Dirac point can be stabilized solely by symmorphic crystal symmetries. We
find that this Dirac point represents a new quantum critical point, and lives
at the boundary between Chern insulating, antiferromagnetic topological
crystalline insulating, and trivial insulating phases. We present density
functional theoretic calculations which demonstrate the presence of this 2D
magnetic Dirac semimetallic phase in FeSe monolayers and discuss the
implications for engineering quantum phase transitions in these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06871</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Dom&#xed;nguez-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forr&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeney</keyname><forenames>Sylvia</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay between optical, viscous and elastic forces on an optically
  trapped Brownian particle immersed in a viscoelastic fluid</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Applied Physics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 143702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a detailed study of the interplay between the different
interactions which appear in the Brownian motion of a micronsized sphere
immersed in a viscoelastic fluid measured with optical trapping interferometry.
To explore a wide range of viscous, elastic and optical forces, we analyze two
different viscoelastic solutions at various concentrations, which provide a
dynamic polymeric structure surrounding the Brownian sphere. Our experiments
show that, depending of the fluid, optical forces, even if small, slightly
modify the complex modulus at low frequencies. Based on our findings, we
propose an alternative methodology to calibrate this kind of experimental
set-up when non-Newtonian fluids are used. Understanding the influence of the
optical potential is essential for a correct interpretation of the mechanical
properties obtained by optically-trapped probe-based studies of biomaterials
and living matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08631</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Saurya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Bilocal theory and gravity I</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the aim of investigating the relation between gravity and non-locality
at the classical level, we study a bilocal scalar field model. Bilocality
introduces new (internal) degrees of freedom that seem to reproduce gravity. We
show that the equations of motion of the massless branch of the free bilocal
model match those of linearized gravity. We also discuss higher orders of
perturbation theory, where there is self-interaction in both gravity and the
bilocal field sectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08984</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santorelli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montes</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of the ions in Liquid Argon Detectors and electron signal
  quenching</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Submitted to Astroparticle Physics</comments><journal-ref>Astropart.Phys. 92 (2017) 11-20</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2017.04.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A study of the dynamics of the positive charges in liquid argon has been
carried out in the context of the future massive time projection chambers
proposed for dark matter and neutrino physics. Given their small mobility
coefficient in liquid argon, the ions spend a considerably longer time in the
active volume with respect to the electrons. The positive charge density can be
additionally increased by the injection, in the liquid volume, of the ions
produced by the electron multiplying devices located in gas argon. The impact
of the ion current on the uniformity of the field has been evaluated as well as
the probability of the charge signal quenching due to the electron-ion
recombination along the drift. The study results show some potential concerns
for massive detectors with drift of many meters operated on surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05657</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mozrzymas</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Studzi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Nilanjana</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of irreducibly covariant quantum channels for finite groups</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>43 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 58, 052204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain an explicit characterization of linear maps, in particular, quantum
channels, which are covariant with respect to an irreducible representation
($U$) of a finite group ($G$), whenever $U \otimes U^c$ is simply reducible
(with $U^c$ being the contragradient representation). Using the theory of group
representations, we obtain the spectral decomposition of any such linear map.
The eigenvalues and orthogonal projections arising in this decomposition are
expressed entirely in terms of representation characteristics of the group $G$.
This in turn yields necessary and sufficient conditions on the eigenvalues of
any such linear map for it to be a quantum channel. We also obtain a wide class
of quantum channels which are irreducibly covariant by construction. For
two-dimensional irrreducible representations of the symmetric group $S(3)$, and
the quaternion group $Q$, we also characterize quantum channels which are both
irreducibly covariant and entanglement breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06135</id><created>2016-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Finnian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>Jessica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Visser</keyname><forenames>Matt</forenames></author></authors><title>&quot;Twisted&quot; black holes are unphysical</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 18 (2017) 1771001</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317710018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  So-called &quot;twisted&quot; black holes have recently been proposed by Zhang
(1609.09721 [gr-qc]), and further considered by Chen and Jing (1610.00886
[gr-qc]), and more recently by Ong (1610.05757 [gr-qc]). While these spacetimes
are certainly Ricci-flat, and so mathematically satisfy the vacuum Einstein
equations, they are also merely minor variants on Taub--NUT spacetimes.
Consequently they exhibit several unphysical features that make them quite
unreasonable as realistic astrophysical objects. Specifically, these &quot;twisted&quot;
black holes are not (globally) asymptotically flat. Furthermore, they contain
closed timelike curves that are not hidden behind any event horizon --- the
most obvious of these closed timelike curves are small azimuthal circles around
the rotation axis, but the effect is more general. The entire region outside
the horizon is infested with closed timelike curves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03849</id><created>2016-11-11</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dyhdalo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogner</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furnstahl</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Applying the Density Matrix Expansion with Coordinate-Space Chiral
  Interactions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>52 pages, 6 figures. Two equations corrected. Mathematica notebooks
  used in derivations are bundled in the submission. Corresponds to published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 054314 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.054314</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the density matrix expansion (DME) at Hartree-Fock level with
long-range chiral effective field theory interactions defined in coordinate
space up to next-to-next-to-leading order. We consider chiral potentials both
with and without explicit Delta isobars. The challenging algebra associated
with applying the DME to three-nucleon forces is tamed using a new organization
scheme, which will also facilitate generalizations. We include local regulators
on the interactions to mitigate the effects of singular potentials on the DME
couplings and simplify the optimization of generalized Skyrme-like functionals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04968</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Higginson</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antiochos</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeVore</keyname><forenames>C. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyper</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zurbuchen</keyname><forenames>T. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of Coronal-Hole Boundaries</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal. 837 (2017) 113</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/837/2/113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Remote and in-situ observations strongly imply that the slow solar wind
consists of plasma from the hot, closed-field corona that is released onto open
magnetic field lines. The Separatrix Web (S-Web) theory for the slow wind
proposes that photospheric motions, at the scale of supergranules, are
responsible for generating dynamics at coronal-hole boundaries, which result in
the closed plasma release. We use three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic (3D
MHD) simulations to determine the effect of photospheric flows on the open and
closed magnetic flux of a model corona with a dipole magnetic field and an
isothermal solar wind. A rotational surface motion is used to approximate
photospheric supergranular driving and is applied at the boundary between the
coronal hole and helmet streamer. The resulting dynamics consist primarily of
prolific and efficient interchange reconnection between open and closed flux.
Magnetic flux near the coronal-hole boundary experiences multiple interchange
events, with some flux interchanging over fifty times in one day. Additionally,
we find that the interchange reconnection occurs all along the coronal-hole
boundary, even producing a lasting change in magnetic-field connectivity in
regions that were not driven by the applied motions. Our results show that
these dynamics should be ubiquitous in the Sun and heliosphere. We discuss the
implications of our simulations for understanding the observed properties of
the slow solar wind, with particular focus on the global-scale consequences of
interchange reconnection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05137</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ezaki</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Takamitsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohzeki</keyname><forenames>Masayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy landscape analysis of neuroimaging data</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.stat-mech physics.data-an</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A 375, 20160287 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsta.2016.0287</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Computational neuroscience models have been used for understanding neural
dynamics in the brain and how they may be altered when physiological or other
conditions change. We review and develop a data-driven approach to neuroimaging
data called the energy landscape analysis. The methods are rooted in
statistical physics theory, in particular the Ising model, also known as the
(pairwise) maximum entropy model and Boltzmann machine. The methods have been
applied to fitting electrophysiological data in neuroscience for a decade, but
their use in neuroimaging data is still in its infancy. We first review the
methods and discuss some algorithms and technical aspects. Then, we apply the
methods to functional magnetic resonance imaging data recorded from healthy
individuals to inspect the relationship between the accuracy of fitting, the
size of the brain system to be analyzed, and the data length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06801</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hue</keyname><forenames>L. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arbuzov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ngan</keyname><forenames>N. T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>H. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing neutrino and Higgs sectors in $SU(2)_1 \times SU(2)_2 \times
  U(1)_Y$ model with lepton-flavor non-universality</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>40 pages, 1 figure; Journal vesion</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 346</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4866-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The neutrino and Higgs sectors in the $\mbox{SU(2)}_1 \times \mbox{SU(2)}_2
\times \mbox{U(1)}_Y $ model with lepton-flavor non-universality are discussed.
We show that active neutrinos can get Majorana masses from radiative
corrections, after adding only new singly charged Higgs bosons. The mechanism
for generation of neutrino masses is the same as in the Zee models. This also
gives a hint to solving the dark matter problem based on similar ways discussed
recently in many radiative neutrino mass models with dark matter. Except the
active neutrinos, the appearance of singly charged Higgs bosons and dark matter
does not affect significantly the physical spectrum of all particles in the
original model. We indicate this point by investigating the Higgs sector in
both cases before and after singly charged scalars are added into it. Many
interesting properties of physical Higgs bosons, which were not shown
previously, are explored. In particular, the mass matrices of charged and
CP-odd Higgs fields are proportional to the coefficient of triple Higgs
coupling $\mu$. The mass eigenstates and eigenvalues in the CP-even Higgs
sector are also presented. All couplings of the SM-like Higgs boson to normal
fermions and gauge bosons are different from the SM predictions by a factor
$c_h$, which must satisfy the recent global fit of experimental data, namely
$0.995&lt;|c_h|&lt;1$. We have analyzed a more general diagonalization of gauge boson
mass matrices, then we show that the ratio of the tangents of the $W-W'$ and
$Z-Z'$ mixing angles is exactly the cosine of the Weinberg angle, implying that
number of parameters is reduced by 1. Signals of new physics from decays of new
heavy fermions and Higgs bosons at LHC and constraints of their masses are also
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00320</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramadhan</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wesolowski</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wakabayashi</keyname><forenames>Tomonari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiromaru</keyname><forenames>Haruo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujino</keyname><forenames>Tatsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kodama</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duley</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanderson</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of hydrogen- and methyl-capped long-chain polyynes by intense
  ultrashort laser pulse irradiation of toluene</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures, 31 references</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 118, 680-685 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2017.03.096</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrogen- and methyl-capped polyynes were synthesized by irradiating pure
liquid toluene with 35 femtosecond, 300 {\mu}J laser pulses having a central
wavelength of 800 nm, generated by a regeneratively amplified Ti:sapphire
tabletop laser at a repetition rate of 1 kHz. Raman spectroscopy was used to
confirm the presence of polyynes in the irradiated samples while
high-performance liquid chromatography was used to separate hydrogen-capped
polyynes up to C18H2 and methyl-capped polyynes up to HC14CH3. These represent
the first such methyl-capped polyynes and the longest hydrogen capped chains
synthesized to date by the ultrafast laser based method. Furthermore our
results show that choice of the starting solvent molecule directly influences
the end caps of the polyynes which can be produced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00413</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Satyanarayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyaya</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yongcheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring the CP property of Higgs coupling to tau leptons in the VBF
  channel at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><report-no>PITT-PACC 1617</report-no><journal-ref>J. High Energ. Phys. (2017) 2017: 128</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)128</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the prospects of measuring the CP property of the Higgs ($h$)
coupling to tau leptons using the vector boson fusion (VBF) production mode at
the high-luminosity LHC. Utilizing the previously proposed angle between the
planes spanned by the momentum vectors of the $(\pi^+\pi^0)$ and $(\pi^-
\pi^0)$ pairs originating in $\tau^\pm$ decays as the CP-odd observable, we
perform a detailed Monte Carlo analysis, taking into account the relevant
standard model backgrounds, as well as detector resolution effects. We find
that excluding a pure CP-odd coupling hypothesis requires $\mathcal{O}(400
{~\rm fb}^{-1})$ luminosity at the 14 TeV LHC, and values of the CP-mixing
angle larger than about $25^\circ$ can be excluded at $95\%$ confidence level
using $3 {~\rm ab}^{-1}$ data. It is observed that the uncertainty in the
angular resolution of the neutral pion momenta does not constitute a
significant hurdle. Achieving a signal to background ratio ($S/B$) close to
one, while keeping a high enough signal yield required to study the angular
distributions selects out VBF as a promising mode to probe the CP nature of the
$h\tau\tau$ coupling, with gluon fusion suffering from a low $S/B$, and the
$W^\pm h/Zh$ mode (with leptonically decaying $W^\pm /Z$) having a much smaller
signal rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00303</id><created>2017-01-01</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tejeda</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gafton</keyname><forenames>Emanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosswog</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tidal disruptions by rotating black holes: relativistic hydrodynamics
  with Newtonian codes</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages, 13 figures, accepted for publication in Monthly Notices of
  the Royal Astronomical Society 2017</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1089</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an approximate approach for studying the relativistic regime of
stellar tidal disruptions by rotating massive black holes. It combines an exact
relativistic description of the hydrodynamical evolution of a test fluid in a
fixed curved spacetime with a Newtonian treatment of the fluid's self-gravity.
Explicit expressions for the equations of motion are derived for Kerr spacetime
using two different coordinate systems. We implement the new methodology within
an existing Newtonian Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics code and show that
including the additional physics involves very little extra computational cost.
We carefully explore the validity of the novel approach by first testing its
ability to recover geodesic motion, and then by comparing the outcome of tidal
disruption simulations against previous relativistic studies. We further
compare simulations in Boyer--Lindquist and Kerr--Schild coordinates and
conclude that our approach allows accurate simulation even of tidal disruption
events where the star penetrates deeply inside the tidal radius of a rotating
black hole. Finally, we use the new method to study the effect of the black
hole spin on the morphology and fallback rate of the debris streams resulting
from tidal disruptions, finding that while the spin has little effect on the
fallback rate, it does imprint heavily on the stream morphology, and can even
be a determining factor in the survival or disruption of the star itself. Our
methodology is discussed in detail as a reference for future astrophysical
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00489</id><created>2017-01-02</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Nobuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschi</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauscher</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Alexander St. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cescutti</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainties in s-process nucleosynthesis in massive stars determined
  by Monte Carlo variations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures, 9 tables; published version in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (2): 1752-1767</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx696</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $s$-process in massive stars produces the weak component of the
$s$-process (nuclei up to $A \sim 90$), in amounts that match solar abundances.
For heavier isotopes, such as barium, production through neutron capture is
significantly enhanced in very metal-poor stars with fast rotation. However,
detailed theoretical predictions for the resulting final $s$-process abundances
have important uncertainties caused both by the underlying uncertainties in the
nuclear physics (principally neutron capture reaction and $\beta$-decay rates)
as well as by the stellar evolution modeling. In this work, we investigated the
impact of nuclear-physics uncertainties relevant to the $s$-process in massive
stars. Using a Monte-Carlo based approach, we performed extensive nuclear
reaction network calculations that include newly evaluated upper and lower
limits for the individual temperature dependent reaction rates. We found that
most of the uncertainty in the final abundances is caused by uncertainties in
the neutron capture rates, while $\beta$-decay rate uncertainties affect only a
few nuclei near $s$-process branchings. The $s$-process in rotating metal-poor
stars shows quantitatively different uncertainties and key reactions, although
the qualitative characteristics are similar. We confirmed that our results do
not significantly change at different metallicities for fast rotating massive
stars in the very low metallicity regime. We highlight which of the identified
key reactions are realistic candidates for improved measurement by future
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00859</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Dellis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isakov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalfagiannis</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tetzner</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthopoulos</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koutsogeorgis</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rapid laser-induced photochemical conversion of sol-gel precursors to
  In2O3 layers and their application in thin-film transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1039/c7tc00169j</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the development of indium oxide (In2O3) transistors via a single
step laser-induced photochemical conversion process of a sol-gel metal oxide
precursor. Through careful optimization of the laser annealing conditions we
demonstrated successful conversion of the precursor to In2O3 and its subsequent
implementation in n-channel transistors with electron mobility up to 13 cm2/Vs.
Importantly, the process does not require thermal annealing making it
compatible with temperature sensitive materials such as plastic. On the other
hand, the spatial conversion/densification of the sol-gel layer eliminates
additional process steps associated with semiconductor patterning and hence
significantly reduces fabrication complexity and cost. Our work demonstrates
unambiguously that laser-induced photochemical conversion of sol-gel metal
oxide precursors can be rapid and compatible with large-area electronics
manufacturing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01748</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Onose</keyname><forenames>Alexandru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabbech</keyname><forenames>Arwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiaux</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>An accelerated splitting algorithm for radio-interferometric imaging:
  when natural and uniform weighting meet</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 469 (1): 938-949</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx755</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next generation radio-interferometers, like the Square Kilometre Array, will
acquire tremendous amounts of data with the goal of improving the size and
sensitivity of the reconstructed images by orders of magnitude. The efficient
processing of large-scale data sets is of great importance. We propose an
acceleration strategy for a recently proposed primal-dual distributed
algorithm. A preconditioning approach can incorporate into the algorithmic
structure both the sampling density of the measured visibilities and the noise
statistics. Using the sampling density information greatly accelerates the
convergence speed, especially for highly non-uniform sampling patterns, while
relying on the correct noise statistics optimises the sensitivity of the
reconstruction. In connection to CLEAN, our approach can be seen as including
in the same algorithmic structure both natural and uniform weighting, thereby
simultaneously optimising both the resolution and the sensitivity. The method
relies on a new non-Euclidean proximity operator for the data fidelity term,
that generalises the projection onto the $\ell_2$ ball where the noise lives
for naturally weighted data, to the projection onto a generalised ellipsoid
incorporating sampling density information through uniform weighting.
Importantly, this non-Euclidean modification is only an acceleration strategy
to solve the convex imaging problem with data fidelity dictated only by noise
statistics. We showcase through simulations with realistic sampling patterns
the acceleration obtained using the preconditioning. We also investigate the
algorithm performance for the reconstruction of the 3C129 radio galaxy from
real visibilities and compare with multi-scale CLEAN, showing better
sensitivity and resolution. Our MATLAB code is available online on GitHub.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03195</id><created>2017-01-11</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Hao-Chung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Min-Hsiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Moderate Deviation Analysis for Classical-Quantum Channels and Quantum
  Hypothesis Testing</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>See also concurrent work (arXiv:1701.03114) by Christopher Chubb,
  Vincent Tan, and Marco Tomamichel. Typos are corrected in v2</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the tradeoffs between the error probabilities of
classical-quantum channels and the blocklength $n$ when the transmission rates
approach the channel capacity at a rate slower than $1/\sqrt{n}$, a research
topic known as moderate deviation analysis. We show that the optimal error
probability vanishes under this rate convergence. Our main technical
contributions are a tight quantum sphere-packing bound, obtained via Chaganty
and Sethuraman's concentration inequality in strong large deviation theory, and
asymptotic expansions of error-exponent functions. Moderate deviation analysis
for quantum hypothesis testing is also established. The converse directly
follows from our channel coding result, while the achievability relies on a
martingale inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03298</id><created>2017-01-12</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Meng-Chwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasko</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author></authors><title>Four-Dimensional N=2 Supersymmetric Theory with Boundary as a
  Two-Dimensional Complex Toda Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, minor changes, published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP05(2017)121</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a series of dimensional reductions of the 6d, $\mathcal{N}=(2,0)$
SCFT on $S^2\times\Sigma\times I\times S^1$ down to 2d on $\Sigma$. The
reductions are performed in three steps: (i) a reduction on $S^1$ (accompanied
by a topological twist along $\Sigma$) leading to a supersymmetric Yang-Mills
theory on $S^2\times\Sigma\times I$, (ii) a further reduction on $S^2$
resulting in a complex Chern--Simons theory defined on $\Sigma\times I$, with
the real part of the complex Chern-Simons level being zero, and the imaginary
part being proportional to the ratio of the radii of $S^2$ and $S^1$, and (iii)
a final reduction to the boundary modes of complex Chern--Simons theory with
the Nahm pole boundary condition at both ends of the interval $I$, which gives
rise to a complex Toda CFT on the Riemann surface $\Sigma$. As the reduction of
the 6d theory on $\Sigma$ would give rise to an $\mathcal{N}=2$ supersymmetric
theory on $S^2\times I\times S^1$, our results imply a 4d-2d duality between
four-dimensional $\mathcal{N}=2$ supersymmetric theory with boundary and
two-dimensional complex Toda theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04044</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X</forenames></author></authors><title>An Improved Adaptive Minimum Action Method for the Calculation of
  Transition Path in Non-gradient Systems</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 12 figures</comments><msc-class>82C26, 60H30, 34F05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The minimum action method (MAM) is to calculate the most probable transition
path in randomly perturbed stochastic dynamics, based on the idea of action
minimization in the path space. The accuracy of the numerical path between
different metastable states usually suffers from the &quot;clustering problem&quot; near
fixed points. The adaptive minimum action method (aMAM) solves this problem by
relocating image points equally along arc-length with the help of moving mesh
strategy. However, when the time interval is large, the images on the path may
still be locally trapped around the transition state in a tangle, due to the
singularity of the relationship between arc-length and time at the transition
state. Additionally, in most non-gradient dynamics, the tangent direction of
the path is not continuous at the transition state so that a geometric corner
forms, which brings extra challenges for the aMAM. In this note, we improve the
aMAM by proposing a better monitor function that does not contain the numerical
approximation of derivatives, and taking use of a generalized scheme of the
Euler-Lagrange equation to solve the minimization problem, so that both the
path-tangling problem and the non-smoothness in parametrizing the curve do not
exist. To further improve the accuracy, we apply the Weighted Essentially
non-oscillatory (WENO) method for the interpolation to achieve better
performance. Numerical examples are presented to demonstrate the advantages of
our new method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04115</id><created>2017-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wells</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwolek</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodman</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>W. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Loading a linear Paul trap to saturation from a magneto-optical trap</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053416 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present experimental measurements of the steady-state ion number in a
linear Paul trap (LPT) as a function of the ion-loading rate. These
measurements, taken with (a) constant Paul trap stability parameter $q$, (b)
constant radio-frequency (rf) amplitude, or (c) constant rf frequency, show
nonlinear behavior. At the loading rates achieved in this experiment, a plot of
the steady-state ion number as a function of loading rate has two regions: a
monotonic rise (region I) followed by a plateau (region II). Also described are
simulations and analytical theory which match the experimental results. Region
I is caused by rf heating and is fundamentally due to the time dependence of
the rf Paul-trap forces. We show that the time-independent pseudopotential,
frequently used in the analytical investigation of trapping experiments, cannot
explain region I, but explains the plateau in region II and can be used to
predict the steady-state ion number in that region. An important feature of our
experimental LPT is the existence of a radial cut-off $\hat R_{\rm cut}$ that
limits the ion capacity of our LPT and features prominently in the analytical
and numerical analysis of our LPT-loading results. We explain the dynamical
origin of $\hat R_{\rm cut}$ and relate it to the chaos border of the fractal
of non-escaping trajectories in our LPT. We also present an improved model of
LPT ion-loading as a function of time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01729</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bastianello</keyname><forenames>Alvise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collura</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sotiriadis</keyname><forenames>Spyros</forenames></author></authors><title>Quenches from gaussian bosons to Tonks-Girardeau gas: stationary states
  and effects of a confining potential</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 174303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.174303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the general problem of quenching an interacting Bose gas from the
noninteracting regime to the strong repulsive case described by the
Tonks-Girardeau limit, with the initial state being a gaussian ensemble for the
bosons. A generic multi-point correlation function in the steady state can be
fully described in terms of a Fredholm-like determinant suitable both for a
numerical study and for an analytical study in certain limiting cases. Finally,
we extend the study to the presence of a smooth confining potential showing
that, in the thermodynamic limit, the time evolution of the two-point function
can be mapped to a classical problem in a properly defined phase-space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02351</id><created>2017-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dedkov</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klesse</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sp&#xe4;th</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papp</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voloshina</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoupling of graphene from Ni(111) via oxygen intercalation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>submitted on 08.02.2017</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 121, 10 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2017.05.068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The combination of the surface science techniques (STM, XPS, ARPES) and
density-functional theory calculations was used to study the decoupling of
graphene from Ni(111) by oxygen intercalation. The formation of the
antiferromagnetic (AFM) NiO layer at the interface between graphene and
ferromagnetic (FM) Ni is found, where graphene protects the underlying AFM/FM
sandwich system. It is found that graphene is fully decoupled in this system
and strongly $p$-doped via charge transfer with a position of the Dirac point
of $(0.69\pm0.02)$ eV above the Fermi level. Our theoretical analysis confirms
all experimental findings, addressing also the interface properties between
graphene and AFM NiO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04713</id><created>2017-02-15</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klauder</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced Quantization: The Right way to Quantize Everything</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, contribution to conference proceedings, version approved by
  referee</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Canonical quantization relies on Cartesian, canonical, phase-space
coordinates to promote to Hermitian operators, which also become the principal
ingredients in the quantum Hamiltonian. While generally appropriate, this
procedure can also fail, e.g., for covariant, quartic, scalar fields in
five-and-more spacetime dimensions (and possibly four spacetime dimensions as
well), which become trivial; such failures are normally blamed on the `problem'
rather than on the 'quantization procedure'. In Enhanced Quantization the
association of $c$-numbers to $q$-numbers is chosen very differently such that:
(i) there is no need to seek classical, Cartesian, phase-space coordinates;
(ii) every classical, contact transformation is applicable and no change of the
quantum operators arises; (iii) a new understanding of the importance of
'Cartesian coordinates' is established; and (iv) although discussed elsewhere
in detail, the procedures of enhanced quantization offer fully acceptable
solutions yielding non-trivial results for quartic scalar fields in
four-and-more spacetime dimensions. In early sections, this paper offers a
wide-audience approach to the basic principles of Enhanced Quantization using
simple examples; later, several significant examples are cited for a deeper
understanding. An historical note concludes the paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06753</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kiraly</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauptmann</keyname><forenames>Nadine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>Mikhail I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khajetoorians</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Single Vacancies in Black Phosphorus at the Atomic Level</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Nano Letters (2017)</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b00766</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Utilizing a combination of low-temperature scanning tunneling
microscopy/spectroscopy (STM/STS) and electronic structure calculations, we
characterize the structural and electronic properties of single atomic
vacancies within several monolayers of the surface of black phosphorus. We
illustrate, with experimental analysis and tight-binding calculations, that we
can depth profile these vacancies and assign them to specific sublattices
within the unit cell. Measurements reveal that the single vacancies exhibit
strongly anisotropic and highly delocalized charge density, laterally extended
up to 20 atomic unit cells. The vacancies are then studied with STS, which
reveals in-gap resonance states near the valence band edge and a strong
p-doping of the bulk black phosphorus crystal. Finally, quasiparticle
interference generated near these vacancies enables the direct visualization of
the anisotropic band structure of black phosphorus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07090</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Guo-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Guang-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phase transition from nodal to nodeless d-wave
  superconductivity in electron-doped cuprate superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 117, (2017) 67007</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/67007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike the hole-doped cuprates, both nodal and nodeless superconductivity
(SC) are observed in the electron-doped cuprates. To understand these two types
of SC states, we propose a unified theory by considering the two-dimensional
t-J model in proximity to an antiferromagnetic (AF) long-range ordering state.
Within the slave-boson mean-field approximation, the d-wave pairing symmetry is
still the most energetically favorable even in the presence of the external AF
field. In the nodal phase, it is found that the nodes carry vorticity and are
protected by the adjoint symmetry of time-reversal and one unit lattice
translation. Robust edge modes are obtained, suggesting the nodal d-wave SC
being a topological weak-pairing phase. As decreasing the doping concentration
or increasing the AF field, the nodes with opposite vorticity annihilate and
the nodeless strong-pairing phase emerges. The topological phase transition is
characterized by a critical point with anisotropic Bogoliubov quasiparticles,
and a universal understanding is thus established for all electron-doped
cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00213</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Chiung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Piljin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental Vortices, Wall-Crossing, and Particle-Vortex Duality</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>75 pages, 24 figures; v2: a reference added, published version</comments><report-no>KIAS-P17001</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1705 (2017) 099</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore 1d vortex dynamics of 3d supersymmetric Yang-Mills theories, as
inferred from factorization of exact partition functions. Under Seiberg-like
dualities, the 3d partition function must remain invariant, yet it is not a
priori clear what should happen to the vortex dynamics. We observe that the 1d
quivers for the vortices remain the same, and the net effect of the 3d duality
map manifests as 1d Wall-Crossing phenomenon; Although the vortex number can
shift along such duality maps, the ranks of the 1d quiver theory are
unaffected, leading to a notion of fundamental vortices as basic building
blocks for topological sectors. For Aharony-type duality, in particular, where
one must supply extra chiral fields to couple with monopole operators on the
dual side, 1d wall-crossings of an infinite number of vortex quiver theories
are neatly and collectively encoded by 3d determinant of such extra chiral
fields. As such, 1d wall-crossing of the vortex theory encodes the
particle-vortex duality embedded in the 3d Seiberg-like duality. For $\mathcal
N = 4$, the D-brane picture is used to motivate this 3d/1d connection, while,
for $\mathcal N = 2$, this 3d/1d connection is used to fine-tune otherwise
ambiguous vortex dynamics. We also prove some identities of 3d supersymmetric
partition functions for the Aharony duality using this vortex wall-crossing
interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04344</id><created>2017-03-13</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amitai</keyname><forenames>Ehud</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;rch</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunnenkamp</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruder</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization of an optomechanical system to an external drive</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053858 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053858</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optomechanical systems driven by an effective blue detuned laser can exhibit
self-sustained oscillations of the mechanical oscillator. These
self-oscillations are a prerequisite for the observation of synchronization.
Here, we study the synchronization of the mechanical oscillations to an
external reference drive. We study two cases of reference drives: (1) An
additional laser applied to the optical cavity; (2) A mechanical drive applied
directly to the mechanical oscillator. Starting from a master equation
description, we derive a microscopic Adler equation for both cases, valid in
the classical regime in which the quantum shot noise of the mechanical
self-oscillator does not play a role. Furthermore, we numerically show that, in
both cases, synchronization arises also in the quantum regime. The
optomechanical system is therefore a good candidate for the study of quantum
synchronization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07811</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Calcagni</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>David Rodr&#xed;guez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronco</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Black holes in multi-fractional and Lorentz-violating models</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures. v2: minor typos corrected, references added</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 335 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4879-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study static and radially symmetric black holes in the multi-fractional
theories of gravity with $q$-derivatives and with weighted derivatives,
frameworks where the spacetime dimension varies with the probed scale and
geometry is characterized by at least one fundamental length $\ell_*$. In the
$q$-derivatives scenario, one finds a tiny shift of the event horizon.
Schwarzschild black holes can present an additional ring singularity, not
present in general relativity, whose radius is proportional to $\ell_*$. In the
multi-fractional theory with weighted derivatives, there is no such
deformation, but non-trivial geometric features generate a
cosmological-constant term, leading to a de Sitter--Schwarzschild black hole.
For both scenarios, we compute the Hawking temperature and comment on the
resulting black hole thermodynamics. In the case with $q$-derivatives, black
holes can be hotter than usual and possess an additional ring singularity,
while in the case with weighted derivatives they have a de Sitter hair of
purely geometric origin, which may lead to a solution of the cosmological
constant problem similar to that in unimodular gravity. Finally, we compare our
findings with other Lorentz-violating models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02704</id><created>2017-04-10</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nati</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devlin</keyname><forenames>Mark J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerbino</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Bradley R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keating</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teply</keyname><forenames>Grant</forenames></author></authors><title>POLOCALC: a Novel Method to Measure the Absolute Polarization
  Orientation of the Cosmic Microwave Background</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, Accepted by Journal of Astronomical
  Instrumentation</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Astronomical Instrumentation, Vol. 6, No. 2 (2017)
  1740008 (13 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S2251171717400086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a novel method to measure the absolute orientation of the
polarization plane of the CMB with arcsecond accuracy, enabling unprecedented
measurements for cosmology and fundamental physics. Existing and planned CMB
polarization instruments looking for primordial B-mode signals need an
independent, experimental method for systematics control on the absolute
polarization orientation. The lack of such a method limits the accuracy of the
detection of inflationary gravitational waves, the constraining power on the
neutrino sector through measurements of gravitational lensing of the CMB, the
possibility of detecting Cosmic Birefringence, and the ability to measure
primordial magnetic fields. Sky signals used for calibration and direct
measurements of the detector orientation cannot provide an accuracy better than
1 deg. Self-calibration methods provide better accuracy, but may be affected by
foreground signals and rely heavily on model assumptions. The POLarization
Orientation CALibrator for Cosmology, POLOCALC, will dramatically improve
instrumental accuracy by means of an artificial calibration source flying on
balloons and aerial drones. A balloon-borne calibrator will provide far-field
source for larger telescopes, while a drone will be used for tests and smaller
polarimeters. POLOCALC will also allow a unique method to measure the
telescopes' polarized beam. It will use microwave emitters between 40 and 150
GHz coupled to precise polarizing filters. The orientation of the source
polarization plane will be registered to sky coordinates by star cameras and
gyroscopes with arcsecond accuracy. This project can become a rung in the
calibration ladder for the field: any existing or future CMB polarization
experiment observing our polarization calibrator will enable measurements of
the polarization angle for each detector with respect to absolute sky
coordinates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03328</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03328</id><created>2017-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Wesley B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salasnich</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero-dimensional limit of the two-dimensional Lugiato-Lefever equation</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 15 figures, Eur. Phys. Journal D, in press (Topical Issue
  &quot;Theory and Applications of the Lugiato-Lefever Equation&quot;)</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. D (2017) 71: 112</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2017-80060-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study effects of tight harmonic-oscillator confinement on the
electromagnetic field in a laser cavity by solving the two-dimensional
Lugiato-Lefever (2D LL) equation, taking into account self- focusing or
defocusing nonlinearity, losses, pump, and the trapping potential. Tightly
confined (quasi-zero-dimensional) optical modes (pixels), produced by this
model, are analyzed by means of the variational approximation, which provides a
qualitative picture of the ensuing phenomena. This is followed by systematic
simulations of the time-dependent 2D LL equation, which reveal the shape,
stability, and dynamical behavior of the resulting localized patterns. In this
way, we produce stability diagrams for the expected pixels. Then, we consider
the LL model with the vortical pump, showing that it can produce stable pixels
with embedded vorticity (vortex solitons) in remarkably broad sta- bility
areas. Alongside confined vortices with the simple single-ring structure, in
the latter case the LL model gives rise to stable multi-ring states, with a
spiral phase field. In addition to the numeri- cal results, a qualitatively
correct description of the vortex solitons is provided by the Thomas-Fermi
approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06987</id><created>2017-04-23</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>Jianwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieke</keyname><forenames>George H.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Intrinsic Far-infrared Continua of Type-1 Quasars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Minor corrections to match the published version, 14 pages, 9
  figures, 5 tables. The quasar intrinsic IR templates can be found at
  http://u.arizona.edu/~jianwei/data/AGN_temp.ascii or in the published paper</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 841, 76 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The range of currently proposed active galactic nucleus (AGN) far-infrared
templates results in uncertainties in retrieving host galaxy information from
infrared observations and also undermines constraints on the outer part of the
AGN torus. We discuss how to test and reconcile these templates. Physically,
the fraction of the intrinsic AGN IR-processed luminosity compared with that
from the central engine should be consistent with the dust-covering factor. In
addition, besides reproducing the composite spectral energy distributions
(SEDs) of quasars, a correct AGN IR template combined with an accurate library
of star-forming galaxy templates should be able to reproduce the IR properties
of the host galaxies, such as the luminosity-dependent SED shapes and aromatic
feature strengths. We develop tests based on these expected behaviors and find
that the shape of the AGN intrinsic far-IR emission drops off rapidly starting
at $\sim20~\mu$m and can be matched by an Elvis et al. (1994)-like template
with minor modification. Despite the variations in the near- to mid-IR bands,
AGNs in quasars and Seyfert galaxies have remarkably similar intrinsic far-IR
SEDs at $\lambda \sim 20$-$100~\mu$ m, suggesting similar emission character of
the outermost region of the circumnuclear torus. The variations of the
intrinsic AGN IR SEDs among the type-1 quasar population can be explained by
the changing relative strengths of four major dust components with similar
characteristic temperatures, and there is evidence for compact AGN-heated dusty
structures at sub-kpc scales in the far-IR.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07758</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lepadatu</keyname><forenames>Serban</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified Treatment of Spin Torques using a Coupled Magnetisation Dynamics
  and Three-Dimensional Spin Current Solver</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A three-dimensional spin current solver based on a generalised spin
drift-diffusion description, including the spin Hall effect, is integrated with
a magnetisation dynamics solver. The resulting model is shown to simultaneously
reproduce the spin-orbit torques generated using the spin Hall effect, spin
pumping torques generated by magnetisation dynamics in multilayers, as well as
the spin transfer torques acting on magnetisation regions with spatial
gradients, whilst field-like and spin-like torques are reproduced in a spin
valve geometry. Two approaches to modelling interfaces are analysed, one based
on the spin mixing conductance and the other based on continuity of spin
currents where the spin dephasing length governs the absorption of transverse
spin components. In both cases analytical formulas are derived for the
spin-orbit torques in a heavy metal / ferromagnet bilayer geometry, showing in
general both field-like and damping-like torques are generated. The limitations
of the analytical approach are discussed, showing that even in a simple bilayer
geometry, due to the non-uniformity of the spin currents, a full
three-dimensional treatment is required. Finally the model is applied to the
quantitative analysis of the spin Hall angle in Pt by reproducing published
experimental data on the ferromagnetic resonance linewidth in the bilayer
geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01761</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Jianhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localized dark solitons and vortices in defocusing media with spatially
  inhomogeneous nonlinearity</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages,9 figures,Physical Review E, in press</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 052214 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.052214</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies have demonstrated that defocusing cubic nonlinearity with
local strength growing from the center to the periphery faster than $r^{D}$, in
space of dimension $D$ with radial coordinate $r$, supports a vast variety of
robust bright solitons. In the framework of the same model, but with a weaker
spatial-growth rate, $\sim r^{\alpha }$ with $\alpha \leq D$, we here test the
possibility to create stable\textit{\ localized continuous waves} (LCWs) in
one- and two-dimensional (1D and 2D) geometries, \textit{% localized dark
solitons} (LDSs) in 1D, and \textit{localized dark vortices} (LDVs) in 2D,
which are all realized as loosely confined states with a divergent norm.
Asymptotic tails of the solutions, which determine the divergence of the norm,
are constructed in a universal analytical form by means of the Thomas-Fermi
approximation (TFA). Global approximations for the LCWs, LDSs, and LDVs are
constructed on the basis of interpolations between analytical approximations
available far from (TFA) and close to the center. In particular, the
interpolations for the 1D LDS, as well as for the 2D LDVs, are based on a
\textquotedblleft deformed-tanh&quot; expression, which is suggested by the usual 1D
dark-soliton solution. In addition to the 1D fundamental LDSs with the single
notch, and 2D vortices with $S=1$, higher-order LDSs with multiple notches are
found too, as well as double LDVs, with $S=2$. Stability regions for the modes
under the consideration are identified by means of systematic simulations, the
LCWs being completely stable in 1D and 2D, as they are ground states in the
corresponding settings. Basic evolution scenarios are identified for those
vortices which are unstable. The settings considered in this work may be
implemented in nonlinear optics and in Bose-Einstein condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05257</id><created>2017-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Trail</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Needs</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape and Energy Consistent Pseudopotentials for Correlated Electron
  systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures. Includes supplemental information</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 204107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984046</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method is developed for generating pseudopotentials for use in
correlated-electron calculations. The paradigms of shape and energy consistency
are combined and defined in terms of correlated-electron wave-functions. The
resulting energy consistent correlated electron pseudopotentials (eCEPPs) are
constructed for H, Li--F, Sc--Fe, and Cu. Their accuracy is quantified by
comparing the relaxed molecular geometries and dissociation energies they
provide with all electron results, with all quantities evaluated using coupled
cluster singles doubles and triples calculations. Errors inherent in the
pseudopotentials are also compared with those arising from a number of
approximations commonly used with pseudopotentials. The eCEPPs provide a
significant improvement in optimised geometries and dissociation energies for
small molecules, with errors for the latter being an order-of-magnitude smaller
than for Hartree-Fock-based pseudopotentials available in the literature.
Gaussian basis sets are optimised for use with these pseudopotentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06866</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hirosawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maebashi</keyname><forenames>Hideaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogata</keyname><forenames>Masao</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Spin Relaxation Time due to the Orbital Currents in Dirac
  Electron Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn., 86, 063705 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.063705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nuclear spin relaxation time $T_1$ is calculated taking account of the
contributions from orbital currents of Dirac electrons. We consider a simple
model of non-interacting Dirac electron gas in the three-dimensional bulk
system. The obtained result shows $T^3$ dependence of $1/T_1$ at temperatures
$T$ above the energy gap. This temperature dependence agrees qualitatively with
the recent $\beta$-NMR experiment on the bulk of the topological insulator
$\mathrm{Bi}_{0.9}\mathrm{Sb}_{0.1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07902</id><created>2017-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Hees</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghez</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naoz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becklin</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boehle</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chappell</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dehghanfar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosmo</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;del</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witzel</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing General Relativity with stellar orbits around the supermassive
  black hole in our Galactic center</title><categories>astro-ph.GA gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, version accepted for publication in Phys. Rev.
  Letters. Original title &quot;Seeking a fifth force with...&quot; changed upon request
  of the PRL editors</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Letters 118, 211101, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.211101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Letter, we demonstrate that short-period stars orbiting around the
supermassive black hole in our Galactic Center can successfully be used to
probe the gravitational theory in a strong regime. We use 19 years of
observations of the two best measured short-period stars orbiting our Galactic
Center to constrain a hypothetical fifth force that arises in various scenarios
motivated by the development of a unification theory or in some models of dark
matter and dark energy. No deviation from General Relativity is reported and
the fifth force strength is restricted to an upper 95% confidence limit of
$\left|\alpha\right| &lt; 0.016$ at a length scale of $\lambda=$ 150 astronomical
units. We also derive a 95% confidence upper limit on a linear drift of the
argument of periastron of the short-period star S0-2 of $\left|\dot
\omega_\textrm{S0-2} \right|&lt; 1.6 \times 10^{-3}$ rad/yr, which can be used to
constrain various gravitational and astrophysical theories. This analysis
provides the first fully self-consistent test of the gravitational theory using
orbital dynamic in a strong gravitational regime, that of a supermassive black
hole. A sensitivity analysis for future measurements is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08725</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Eriksson</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engelhardt</keyname><forenames>I. A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andre</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bostrom</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edberg</keyname><forenames>N. J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odelstad</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vigren</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahlund</keyname><forenames>J. -E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebreton</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miloch</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paulsson</keyname><forenames>J. J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wedlund</keyname><forenames>C. Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karlsson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarvinen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broiles</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandt</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carr</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galand</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norberg</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cold and warm electrons at comet 67P</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Astronomy and Astrophysics (2016) 30159</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201630159</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong electron cooling on the neutral gas in cometary comae has been
predicted for a long time, but actual measurements of low electron temperature
are scarce. We present in situ measurements of plasma density, electron
temperature and spacecraft potential by the Rosetta Langmuir probe instrument,
LAP. Data acquired within a few hundred km from the nucleus are dominated by a
warm component with electron temperature typically 5--10 eV at all heliocentric
distances covered (1.25 to 3.83 AU). A cold component, with temperature no
higher than about 0.1 eV, appears in the data as short (few to few tens of
seconds) pulses of high probe current, indicating local enhancement of plasma
density as well as a decrease in electron temperature. These pulses first
appeared around 3 AU and were seen for longer periods close to perihelion. The
general pattern of pulse appearance follows that of neutral gas and plasma
density. We have not identified any periods with only cold electrons present.
The electron flux to Rosetta was always dominated by higher energies, driving
the spacecraft potential to order -10 V. The warm (5--10 eV) electron
population is interpreted as electrons retaining the energy they obtained when
released in the ionisation process. The sometimes observed cold populations
with electron temperatures below 0.1 eV verify collisional cooling in the coma.
The cold electrons were only observed together with the warm population. The
general appearance of the cold population appears to be consistent with a
Haser-like model, implicitly supporting also the coupling of ions to the
neutral gas. The expanding cold plasma is unstable, forming filaments that we
observe as pulses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08726</id><created>2017-05-24</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Kunyi</forenames></author></authors><title>The fluid running in the subnanochannel with functional surface</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures,Corrected typos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have researched the motion of gas in the subnanochannel with functional
surface which wettability has a gradient for the fluid by using molecular
dynamics simulation. The results show that the gas is driven to flow under a
single heat source and without any other work or energy applied to the system.
The driving source is owed to the potential gradient of the functional face
which keeps the fluid running in the subnanochannel. The width of the channel
and the pressure of the reservoir has a significant influence on the flow
velocity, which, respectively, has an optimal value for the maximum velocity.
The flow velocity grows with the increasing temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08732</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08732</id><created>2017-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Fatollahi</keyname><forenames>Amir H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Mechanics of Magnetic Monopoles</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figs</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The site-reduction of U(1) lattice gauge theory along the spatial directions
is used to model the monopole dynamics. The reduced theory is that of the
angle-valued coordinates on the discrete worldline. Below the critical coupling
$g_{c}=1.125$ and temperature $T_c=0.335$ the model exhibits a first order
phase transition. It is argued that the phase structure matches with the
proposed role for magnetic monopoles in the confinement mechanism based on the
dual Meissner effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08749</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08749</id><created>2017-05-19</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naqvi</keyname><forenames>K. Razi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Superior but Equally Convenient Alternative to the Steady-State
  Approximation and Secular Equilibrium</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The steady-state approximation (hereafter abbreviated as SSA) consists in
setting $dy/dt=0$, where $y$ denotes the concentration of a short-lived
intermediate subject to first-order decay with a rate constant $k$. The sole
reason for enforcing SSA is to convert the rate equation for $y$ into an
algebraic equation. The conditions under which SSA becomes trustworthy are now
well understood, but a firm grasp of the physical content of the approximation
requires more maturity than few teachers, let alone their students, may be
expected to possess. Furthermore, there is no simple way to gauge the accuracy
of the results derived by imposing SSA. The purpose of this note is to
demonstrate that a better, but equally simple, approximation results if,
instead of setting $dy/dt$ to zero, one substitutes $y(t+\tau)$ for $y+\tau
dy/dt$, where $\tau=1/k$; SSA is a cruder approximation because it neglects the
second term. For systems modelled as damped harmonic oscillators, the &quot;reverse
Taylor approximation&quot; can be extended by retaining one more term in the Taylor
expansion. The utility of the approximation (or its extension) is demonstrated
by examining the following systems: radioactive equilibria, Brownian motion,
dynamic response of linear first- and second-order systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08778</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Yanmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiong</forenames></author></authors><title>Periodic solutions of semilinear Duffing equations with impulsive
  effects</title><categories>math.CA nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we are concerned with the existence of periodic solutions for
semilinear Duffing equations with impulsive effects. Firstly for the autonomous
one, basing on Poincar\'{e}-Birkhoff twist theorem, we prove the existence of
infinitely many periodic solutions. Secondly, as for the nonautonomous case,
the impulse brings us great challenges for the study, and there are only
finitely many periodic solutions, which is quite different from the
corresponding equation without impulses. Here, taking the autonomous one as an
auxiliary equation, we find the relation between these two equations and then
obtain the result also by Poincar\'{e}-Birkhoff twist theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08888</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08888</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faghihi</keyname><forenames>Niloufar</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of $1/f$ noise motivated by a model for musical melodies</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a model to generate power spectrum noise with intensity
proportional to 1/f as a function of frequency f. The model arises from a
broken-symmetry variable which corresponds to absolute pitch, where
fluctuations occur in an attempt to restore that symmetry, influenced by
interactions in the creation of musical melodies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08891</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bouma</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames><affiliation>Princeton University</affiliation><affiliation>MIT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Winn</keyname><forenames>Joshua N.</forenames><affiliation>Princeton University</affiliation><affiliation>MIT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kosiarek</keyname><forenames>Jacobi</forenames><affiliation>MIT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>McCullough</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames><affiliation>JHU</affiliation></author></authors><title>Planet Detection Simulations for Several Possible TESS Extended Missions</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>The views, opinions, assumptions, examples, and results expressed in
  this article are solely those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect
  the official policy or position of the TESS Science Team, any of the authors'
  employers or affiliated institutions, NASA, or any agency of the U.S.
  government. This article has not been endorsed or reviewed by NASA or the
  TESS Science Team</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) will perform a two-year
survey of nearly the entire sky, with the main goal of detecting exoplanets
smaller than Neptune around bright and nearby stars. There do not appear to be
any fundamental obstacles to continuing science operations for at least several
years after the two-year Primary Mission. To provide a head start to those who
will plan and propose for such a mission, we present simulations of exoplanet
detections in a third year of TESS operations. Our goal is to provide a helpful
reference for the exoplanet-related aspects of any Extended Mission, while
recognizing this will be only one part of a larger community discussion of the
scientific goals. We use Monte Carlo simulations to try and anticipate the
quantities and types of planets that would be detected in each of 6 plausible
scenarios for a one-year Extended Mission following the two-year Primary
Mission. We find that: (1) there is no sharp fall-off in the planet discovery
rate in the third year; (2) the quantity of newly detected sub-Neptune radius
planets does not depend strongly on the schedule of pointings; (3) an important
function of an Extended Mission would be improving our ability to predict the
times of future transits and occultations of TESS-detected planets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08897</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Stephen P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>George G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kargaltsev</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinger</keyname><forenames>Noel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renaud</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mereghetti</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Pulsar-wind nebulae and magnetar outflows: observations at radio, X-ray,
  and gamma-ray wavelengths</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>61 pages, 44 figures (reduced in quality for size reasons). Published
  in Space Science Reviews, &quot;Jets and Winds in Pulsar Wind Nebulae, Gamma-ray
  Bursts and Blazars: Physics of Extreme Energy Release&quot;</comments><doi>10.1007/s11214-017-0356-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review observations of several classes of neutron-star-powered outflows:
pulsar-wind nebulae (PWNe) inside shell supernova remnants (SNRs), PWNe
interacting directly with interstellar medium (ISM), and magnetar-powered
outflows. We describe radio, X-ray, and gamma-ray observations of PWNe,
focusing first on integrated spectral-energy distributions (SEDs) and global
spectral properties. High-resolution X-ray imaging of PWNe shows a bewildering
array of morphologies, with jets, trails, and other structures. Several of the
23 so far identified magnetars show evidence for continuous or sporadic
emission of material, sometimes associated with giant flares, and a few
possible &quot;magnetar-wind nebulae&quot; have been recently identified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08924</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Jiawen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lefler</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Licht</keyname><forenames>Gad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vicini</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Licht</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author></authors><title>Carbon Nanotube Wools Directly from CO2 By Molten Electrolysis Value
  Driven Pathways to Carbon Dioxide Greenhouse Gas Mitigation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>26 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A climate mitigation comprehensive solution is presented through the first
high yield, low energy synthesis of macroscopic length carbon nanotubes (CNT)
wool from CO2 by molten carbonate electrolysis, suitable for weaving into
carbon composites and textiles. Growing CO2 concentrations, the concurrent
climate change and species extinction can be addressed if CO2 becomes a sought
resource rather than a greenhouse pollutant. Inexpensive carbon composites
formed from carbon wool as a lighter metal, textiles and cement replacement
comprise a major market sink to compactly store transformed anthropogenic CO2.
100x-longer CNTs grow on Monel versus steel. Monel, electrolyte equilibration,
and a mixed metal nucleation facilitate the synthesis. CO2, the sole reactant
in this transformation, is directly extractable from dilute (atmospheric) or
concentrated sources, and is cost constrained only by the (low) cost of
electricity. Today's $100K per ton CNT valuation incentivizes CO2 removal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08936</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Valdez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jim&#xe9;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angelats-Silva</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transverse Magnetoresistance of Zn$_{0.9}$Co$_{0.1}$O:Al Thin Films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transverse magnetoresistance of thin films of the Diluted Magnetic
Semiconductor Zn$_{1-x}$Co$_{x}$O:Al on glass was studied for temperatures in
the range of 5 to 100 K. Measurements were made on thin films grown by rf
magnetron sputtering, with a thickness of approximately 200 nm. ZnO was alloyed
with Co to a concentration $x$ of 0.1 and co-doped with a 5.5% wt concentration
of Al. The electrical resistivity was measured along the sample surface by the
four-point probe method with a magnetic field of up to 4 T applied
perpendicular to the surface of the film. The experimental results of the
magnetoresistance have been interpreted by means of a semiclassical model that
combines a relaxation-time approximation to describe scattering processes in
ZnO and a phenomenological approach to the spin-disorder scattering due to the
indirect exchange interaction of the magnetic impurities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08939</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>Stanis&#x142;aw H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petric</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchriegler</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bjeoumikhov</keyname><forenames>Aniouar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bjeoumikhov</keyname><forenames>Zemfira</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Borany</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Munnik</keyname><forenames>Frans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radtke</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renno</keyname><forenames>Axel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinholz</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scharf</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tilgner</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wedell</keyname><forenames>Reiner</forenames></author></authors><title>Road to micron resolution with a color X-ray camera -- polycapillary
  optics characterization</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>early version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a color X-ray camera, spatial resolution is achieved by means of a
polycapillary optic conducting X-ray photons from small regions on a sample to
distinct energy dispersive pixels on a CCD matrix. At present, the resolution
limit of color X-ray camera systems can go down to several microns and is
mainly restricted to pixel dimensions. The recent development of an efficient
subpixel resolution algorithm allows a release from pixel size, limiting the
resolution only to the quality of the optics. In this work polycapillary
properties that influence the spatial resolution are systematized and assessed
both theoretically and experimentally. It is demonstrated that with the current
technological level reaching one micron resolution is challenging, but
possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08944</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Siavashpouri</keyname><forenames>Mahsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wachauf</keyname><forenames>Christian H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakhary</keyname><forenames>Mark J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Praetorius</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietz</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dogic</keyname><forenames>Zvonimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular engineering of chiral colloidal liquid crystals using DNA
  origami</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Nature Materials (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4909</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Establishing precise control over the shape and the interactions of the
microscopic building blocks is essential for design of macroscopic soft
materials with novel structural, optical and mechanical properties. Here, we
demonstrate robust assembly of DNA origami filaments into cholesteric liquid
crystals, 1D supramolecular twisted ribbons and 2D colloidal membranes. The
exquisite control afforded by the DNA origami technology establishes a
quantitative relationship between the microscopic filament structure and the
macroscopic cholesteric pitch. Furthermore, it also enables robust assembly of
1D twisted ribbons, which behave as effective supramolecular polymers whose
structure and elastic properties can be precisely tuned by controlling the
geometry of the elemental building blocks. Our results demonstrate the
potential synergy between DNA origami technology and colloidal science, in
which the former allows for rapid and robust synthesis of complex particles,
and the latter can be used to assemble such particles into bulk materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08956</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Naibert</keyname><forenames>Tyler</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polshyn</keyname><forenames>Hryhoriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durkin</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolin</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrido-Menacho</keyname><forenames>Rita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chua</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondragon-Shem</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Taylor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Nadya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budakian</keyname><forenames>Raffi</forenames></author></authors><title>$\Phi_0$-Magnetic Force Microscopy for Imaging and Control of Vortex
  Dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Harnessing the properties of vortices in superconductors is crucial for
fundamental science as well as technological applications; thus, it has been an
ongoing goal to develop experimental techniques that can locally probe and
control vortices. Here, we present a scanning probe technique that enables
studies of vortex dynamics in superconducting systems by leveraging the
resonant behavior of a raster-scanned, magnetic-tipped cantilever. Key features
of this experimental platform are the high degree of tunability and the local
nature of the probe. Applying this technique to lattices of superconductor
island arrays on a metal, we obtain a variety of striking spatial patterns that
encode information about the energy landscape for vortices in the system. We
interpret these patterns in terms of local vortex dynamics, and extract the
relative strengths of the characteristic energy scales in the system, such as
the vortex-magnetic field and vortex-vortex interaction strengths, as well as
the vortex chemical potential. We also demonstrate that the relative strengths
of the interactions can be tuned. This experimental setup has the potential for
future applications in more complex systems, as well as in the manipulation of
vortex-bound Majorana fermions for quantum computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08959</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Aguill&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Cesar A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Much</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenbaum</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergara</keyname><forenames>J. David</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity from Quantum Spacetime by Twisted Deformation of the Quantum
  Poincar\'e Group</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>43 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a quantum geometric space in the context of what could be
considered an emerging effective theory from Quantum Gravity. Specifically we
consider a two-parameter class of twisted Poincar\'e algebras, from which
Lie-algebraic noncommutativities of the translations are derived as well as
associative star-products, deformed Riemannian geometries, Lie-algebraic
twisted Minkowski spaces and quantum effects that arise as noncommutativities.
Starting from a universal differential algebra of forms based on the above
mentioned Lie-algebraic noncommutativities of the translations, we construct
the noncommutative differential forms and Inner and Outer derivations, which
are the noncommutative equivalents of the vector fields in the case of
commutative differential geometry. Having established the essentials of this
formalism we construct a bimodule, required to be central under the action of
the Inner derivations in order to have well defined contractions and from where
the algebraic dependence of its coefficients is derived. This again then
defines the noncommutative equivalent of the geometrical line-element in
commutative differential geometry. We stress, however, that even though the
components of the twisted metric are by construction symmetric in their algebra
valuation, this is not so for their inverse and thus to construct it we made
use of Gel'fand's theory of quasi-determinants, which is conceptually
straightforward but computationally becoming quite complicate beyond an algebra
of 3 generators. The consequences of the noncommutativity of the Lie-algebra
twisted geometry are further discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08969</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Christiansen</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datchev</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resolvent estimates on asymptotically cylindrical manifolds and on the
  half line</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>This paper is a companion to the paper `Wave asymptotics for
  manifolds with infinite cylindrical ends' by the same authors, but each paper
  can be read independently of the other</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Manifolds with infinite cylindrical ends have continuous spectrum of
increasing multiplicity as energy grows, and in general embedded resonances and
eigenvalues can accumulate at infinity. However, we prove that if geodesic
trapping is sufficiently mild, then such an accumulation is ruled out, and
moreover the cutoff resolvent is uniformly bounded at high energies. We obtain
as a corollary the existence of resonance free regions near the continuous
spectrum.
  We also obtain improved estimates when the resolvent is cut off away from
part of the trapping, and along the way we prove some resolvent estimates for
repulsive potentials on the half line which may be of independent interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08972</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Christiansen</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datchev</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave asymptotics for manifolds with infinite cylindrical ends</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>This paper is a companion to the paper `Resolvent estimates on
  asymptotically cylindrical manifolds and on the half line' by the same
  authors, but each paper can be read independently of the other</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe wave decay rates associated to embedded resonances and spectral
thresholds for manifolds with infinite cylindrical ends. We show that if the
cut-off resolvent is polynomially bounded at high energies, as is the case in
certain favorable geometries, then there is an associated asymptotic expansion,
up to a $O(t^{-k_0})$ remainder, of solutions of the wave equation on compact
sets as $t \to \infty$. In the most general such case we have $k_0=1$, and
under an additional assumption on the ends of the manifold we have $k_0 =
\infty$. If we localize the solutions to the wave equation in frequency as well
as in space, our results hold for quite general manifolds with infinite
cylindrical ends.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08978</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Pitkin</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isi</keyname><forenames>Maximiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veitch</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woan</keyname><forenames>Graham</forenames></author></authors><title>A nested sampling code for targeted searches for continuous
  gravitational waves from pulsars</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>46 pages, 34 figures. Document detailing and characterising analysis
  software for a gravitational wave search. The document source, example
  scripts and jupyter notebooks used can be found at
  https://github.com/mattpitkin/CW_nested_sampling_doc</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This document describes a code to perform parameter estimation and model
selection in targeted searches for continuous gravitational waves from known
pulsars using data from ground-based gravitational wave detectors. We describe
the general workings of the code and characterise it on simulated data
containing both noise and simulated signals. We also show how it performs
compared to a previous MCMC and grid-based approach to signal parameter
estimation. Details how to run the code in a variety of cases are provided in
Appendix A.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09000</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Canuto</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taira</keyname><forenames>Kunihiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional compressible viscous flow around a circular cylinder</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>24 pages, 14 figures, 6 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics (2015), vol. 785, pp. 349-371</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.635</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct numerical simulation is performed to study compressible, viscous flow
around a circular cylinder. The present study considers two-dimensional,
shock-free continuum flow by varying the Reynolds number between 20 and 100 and
the freestream Mach number between 0 and 0.5. The results indicate that
compressibility effects elongate the near wake for cases above and below the
critical Reynolds number for two-dimensional flow under shedding. The wake
elongation becomes more pronounced as the Reynolds number approaches this
critical value. Moreover, we determine the growth rate and frequency of linear
instability for cases above the critical Reynolds number. From the analysis, it
is observed that the frequency of the B\'enard-von K\'arm\'an vortex street in
the time-periodic, fully-saturated flow increases from the dominant unstable
frequency found from the linear stability analysis as the Reynolds number
increases from its critical value, even for the low range of Reynolds numbers
considered. We also notice that the compressibility effects reduce the growth
rate and dominant frequency in the linear growth stage. Semi-empirical
functional relationships for the growth rate and the dominant frequency in
linearized flow around the cylinder in terms of the Reynolds number and
freestream Mach number are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09007</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Scammell</keyname><forenames>H. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sushkov</keyname><forenames>O. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction of ultra-narrow Higgs resonance in magnon Bose-condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Higgs resonance modes in condensed matter systems are generally broad;
meaning large decay widths or short relaxation times. This common feature has
obscured and limited their observation to a select few systems. Contrary to
this, the present work predicts that Higgs resonances in magnetic field
induced, three-dimensional magnon Bose-condensates have vanishingly small decay
widths. Specifically for parameters relating to TlCuCl$_3$, we find an energy
($\Delta_H$) to width ($\Gamma_H$) ratio $\Delta_H/\Gamma_H\sim500$, making
this the narrowest predicted Higgs mode in a condensed matter system, some two
orders of magnitude `narrower' than the sharpest condensed matter Higgs
observed so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09009</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Silu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jisun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelton</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plummer</keyname><forenames>E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Rongying</forenames></author></authors><title>Nontrivial Berry phase in magnetic BaMnSb2 semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United
  States of America (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1706657114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The subject of topological materials has attracted immense attention in
condensed-matter physics, because they host new quantum states of matter
containing Dirac, Majorana, or Weyl fermions. Although Majorana fermions can
only exist on the surface of topological superconductors, Dirac and Weyl
fermions can be realized in both 2D and 3D materials. The latter are semimetals
with Dirac/Weyl cones either not tilted (type I) or tilted (type II). Although
both Dirac and Weyl fermions have massless nature with the nontrivial Berry
phase, the formation of Weyl fermions in 3D semimetals require either
time-reversal or inversion symmetry breaking to lift degeneracy at Dirac
points. Here, we demonstrate experimentally that canted antiferromagnetic
BaMnSb2 is a 3D Weyl semimetal with a 2D electronic structure. The Shubnikov-de
Hass oscillations of the magnetoresistance give nearly zero effective mass with
high mobility and the nontrivial Berry phase. The ordered magnetic arrangement
(ferromagnetic ordering in the ab plane and antiferromagnetic ordering along
the c axis below 286 K) breaks the time-reversal symmetry, thus offering us an
ideal platform to study magnetic Weyl fermions in a centrosymmetric material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09014</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Abreu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Figueiredo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowada</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquezino</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posner</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portugal</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The tessellation problem of quantum walks</title><categories>cs.DM cs.CC math.CO quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figs</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum walks have received a great deal of attention recently because they
can be used to develop new quantum algorithms and to simulate interesting
quantum systems. In this work, we focus on a model called staggered quantum
walk, which employs advanced ideas of graph theory and has the advantage of
including the most important instances of other discrete-time models. The
evolution operator of the staggered model is obtained from a tessellation
cover, which is defined in terms of a set of partitions of the graph into
cliques. It is important to establish the minimum number of tessellations
required in a tessellation cover, and what classes of graphs admit a small
number of tessellations. We describe two main results: (1) infinite classes of
graphs where we relate the chromatic number of the clique graph to the minimum
number of tessellations required in a tessellation cover, and (2) the problem
of deciding whether a graph is $k$-tessellable for $k\ge 3$ is NP-complete.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09019</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Woo</keyname><forenames>Seonghoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Kyung Mee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Hee-Sung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Min-Seung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Im</keyname><forenames>Mi-Young</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ki-Suk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Kun Soo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Jung-Il</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Jun Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>Byoung-Chul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koo</keyname><forenames>Hyun Cheol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Joonyeon</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit torque-driven skyrmion dynamics revealed by time-resolved
  X-ray microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15573 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15573</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic skyrmions are topologically-protected spin textures with attractive
properties suitable for high-density and low-power spintronic device
applications. Much effort has been dedicated to understanding the dynamical
behaviours of the magnetic skyrmions. However, experimental observation of the
ultrafast dynamics of this chiral magnetic texture in real space, which is the
hallmark of its quasiparticle nature, has so far remained elusive. Here, we
report nanosecond-dynamics of a 100 nm-size magnetic skyrmion during a current
pulse application, using a time-resolved pump-probe soft X-ray imaging
technique. We demonstrate that distinct dynamic excitation states of magnetic
skyrmions, triggered by current-induced spin-orbit torques, can be reliably
tuned by changing the magnitude of spin-orbit torques. Our findings show that
the dynamics of magnetic skyrmions can be controlled by the spin-orbit torque
on the nanosecond time scale, which points to exciting opportunities for
ultrafast and novel skyrmionic applications in the future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09036</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Hennigh</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author></authors><title>Lat-Net: Compressing Lattice Boltzmann Flow Simulations using Deep
  Neural Networks</title><categories>stat.ML physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) is a hugely important subject with
applications in almost every engineering field, however, fluid simulations are
extremely computationally and memory demanding. Towards this end, we present
Lat-Net, a method for compressing both the computation time and memory usage of
Lattice Boltzmann flow simulations using deep neural networks. Lat-Net employs
convolutional autoencoders and residual connections in a fully differentiable
scheme to compress the state size of a simulation and learn the dynamics on
this compressed form. The result is a computationally and memory efficient
neural network that can be iterated and queried to reproduce a fluid
simulation. We show that once Lat-Net is trained, it can generalize to large
grid sizes and complex geometries while maintaining accuracy. We also show that
Lat-Net is a general method for compressing other Lattice Boltzmann based
simulations such as Electromagnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09060</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Hatzinikitas</keyname><forenames>Agapitos N.</forenames></author></authors><title>One-loop Partition Functions in Hyperbolic Space
  $\mathbb{H}^n(\mathbb{R})$</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We first study the problem of the one-loop partition function for a free
massive quantum field theory living on a fixed background hyperbolic space on
the field of real numbers, $\mathbb{H}^n(\mathbb{R}), \,\, n\geq 2$. Earlier
attempts were limited to $n=3$ dimensions due to the computational complexity.
We have developed a new method to determine the fundamental solution of the
heat equation and techniques to specify its asymptotics in the small time
limit. These enable us to determine the regular part and the ultra violet
divergences of the one-loop effective action in the scalar case. The
contribution of the Abelian gauge excitations to the one-loop partition
function were treated separately using Fourier analysis and bi-tensor
techniques on $\mathbb{H}^n(\mathbb{R})$. Finally, by employing the DeWitt's
method, we confirmed the correctness and extended our results to any dimension
regarding the first three heat kernel coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09067</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Whelan</keyname><forenames>David G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baker</keyname><forenames>R. David</forenames></author></authors><title>HD 46487 is Now a Classical Be Star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures; accepted for publication in JAAVSO, Vol. 45</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first observations of hydrogen line emission detected around
the B-type star HD 46487, a well-studied star in the CoRoT field of view. The
emission is only evident in the H$\alpha$ line, for which the observed
violet-red peak separation ($\Delta v_{p}$) is typical of a B$e$ star with a
circumstellar disk. The absence of dust emission from the infrared spectral
energy distribution excludes the possibility of a very young star. The star's
magnitude (V=5.079) and regular use in the literature for a variety of studies
suggests that the line emission had a high probability of being found
previously, had it been evident; since such was not the case, we believe that
the B$e$ phenomenon for HD 46487 has only very recently &quot;turned on.&quot; We
therefore recommend that this star be spectroscopically and photometrically
monitored to track continued changes to its circumstellar morphology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09075</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Swetamber</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahata</keyname><forenames>Sasibhusan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupte</keyname><forenames>Neelima</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization, phase slips and coherent structures in area-preserving
  maps</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures, Perspectives in Nonlinear Dynamics 2016 (24th -
  29th July 2016), Berlin, Germany. The paper is a part of the proceedings to
  appear in Pramana - Journal of Physics (Indian Academy of Sciences);
  distributed in print outside India and online worldwide by Springer</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of synchronization of coupled Hamiltonian systems exhibits
interesting features due to the non-uniform or mixed nature (regular and
chaotic) of the phase space. We study these features by investigating the
synchronization of unidirectionally coupled area-preserving maps coupled by the
Pecora-Carroll method. We find that coupled standard maps show complete
synchronization for values of the nonlinearity parameter at which regular
structures are still present in phase space. The distribution of
synchronization times has a power law tail indicating long synchronization
times for at least some of the synchronizing trajectories. With the
introduction of coherent structures using parameter perturbation in the system,
this distribution crosses over to exponential behavior, indicating shorter
synchronization times, and the number of initial conditions which synchronize
increases significantly, indicating an enhancement in the basin of
synchronization. On the other hand, coupled blinking vortex maps display both
phase synchronization and phase slips, depending on the location of the initial
conditions. We discuss the implication of our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09089</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Top quark properties measurements at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>On behalf of the ATLAS and CMS Collaborations. Proceedings for
  Rencontres de Moriond EW Interactions and Unified Theories 2017. 8 pages, 8
  figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Highlights of measurements of the properties of the top quark at the LHC are
presented. The measurements probe a range of the properties of the top quark,
including the structure of the $Wtb$ vertex, the top-Z coupling and the
top-quark mass. The results are compared to Standard Model predictions and in
some cases limits on physics beyond the Standard Model are also extracted in
the context of effective field theory models. The measurements use data
collected by the ATLAS and CMS experiments during pp collisions at a
centre-of-mass energy of 8 or 13 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09111</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Verzi</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsunesada</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of Energy Spectrum of Ultra-High Energy Cosmic Rays</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>31 pages, 19 figures, accepted for publication in Prog. Theor. Exp.
  Phys</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra-High Energy Cosmic Rays (UHECRs) are charged particles of energies
above $10^{18}$ eV that originate outside of the Galaxy. Because the flux of
the UHECRs at Earth is very small, the only practical way of observing UHECRs
is by measuring the extensive air showers (EAS) produced by UHECRs in the
atmosphere. This is done by using air fluorescence detectors and giant arrays
of particle detectors on the ground. The Pierre Auger Observatory (Auger) and
Telescope Array (TA) are two large cosmic ray experiments which use such
techniques and cover 3000 km$^2$ and 700 km$^2$ areas on the ground,
respectively. In this paper, we present the UHECR spectrum reported by the TA,
using an exposure of 6300 km$^2$ sr yr accumulated over 7 years of data taking,
and the corresponding result of Auger, using 10 years of data with a total
exposure exceeding 50000 km$^2$ sr yr. We review the astrophysical
interpretation of the two measurements, and discuss their systematic
uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09121</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Venkatesh</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venkatesan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lakshmanan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Design and implementation of dynamic logic gates and R-S flip-flop using
  quasiperiodically driven Murali-Lakshmanan-Chua circuit</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume
  27, 033105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4977977</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the propagation of a square wave signal in a quasi-periodically
driven Murali-Lakshmanan-Chua (QPDMLC) circuit system. It is observed that
signal propagation is possible only above a certain threshold strength of the
square wave or digital signal and all the values above the threshold amplitude
are termed as 'region of signal propagation'. Then, we extend this region of
signal propagation to perform various logical operations like AND/NAND/OR/NOR
and hence it is also designated as the 'region of logical operation'. Based on
this region, we propose implementing the dynamic logic gates, namely
AND/NAND/OR/NOR, which can be decided by the asymmetrical input square waves
without altering the system parameters. Further, we show that a single QPDMLC
system will produce simultaneously two outputs which are complementary to each
other. As a result, a single QPDMLC system yields either AND as well as NAND or
OR as well as NOR gates simultaneously. Then we combine the corresponding two
QPDMLC systems in a cross-coupled way and report that its dynamics mimics that
of fundamental R-S flip-flop circuit. All these phenomena have been explained
with analytical solutions of the circuit equations characterizing the system
and finally the results are compared with the corresponding numerical and
experimental analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09125</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liverts</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnea</keyname><forenames>Nir</forenames></author></authors><title>Helium-like atoms. The Green's function approach to the Fock expansion
  calculations</title><categories>physics.atom-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The renewed Green's function approach to calculating the angular Fock
coefficients, $\psi_{k,p}(\alpha,\theta)$ is presented. The final formulas are
simplified and specified to be applicable for analytical as well as numerical
calculations. The Green's function formulas with the hyperspherical angles
$\theta=0,\pi$ (arbitrary $\alpha$) or $\alpha=0,\pi$ (arbitrary $\theta$) are
indicated as corresponding to the angular Fock coefficients possessing physical
meaning. The most interesting case of $\theta=0$ corresponding to a collinear
arrangement of the particles is studied in detail. It is emphasized that this
case represents the generalization of the specific cases of the
electron-nucleus ($\alpha=0$) and electron-electron ($\alpha=\pi/2$)
coalescences. It is shown that the Green's function method for $\theta=0$
enables us to calculate any component/subcomponent of the angular Fock
coefficient in the form of a single series representation with arbitrary angle
$\theta$. Those cases, where the Green's function approach can not be applied,
are thoroughly studied, and the corresponding solutions are found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09130</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Satija</keyname><forenames>Indubala I</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology Induced Oscillations in Majorana Fermions in a Quasiperiodic
  Superconducting Chain</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spatial profile of the Majorana fermion wave function in a one-dimensional
$p$-wave superconductors ($\cal{PWS}$) with quasi periodic disorder is shown to
exhibit spatial oscillations. These oscillations damp out in the interior of
the chain and are characterized by a period that has topological origin and is
equal to the Chern number determining the Hall conductivity near half-filling
of a two-dimensional electron gas in a crystal. This mapping unfolds in view of
a correspondence between the critical point for the topological transition in
$\cal{PWS}$ and the {\it strong coupling fixed point} of the Harper's equation.
Oscillatory character of these modes persist in a generalized model related to
an extended Harper system where the electrons also tunnel to the diagonals of a
square lattice. However, beyond a bicritical point, the Majorana oscillations
occur with a random period, characterized by an invariant fractal set.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09140</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rius</keyname><forenames>Nuria</forenames></author></authors><title>Atmospheric neutrinos and new physics</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages,
  LaTeX, 5 figures</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Rius</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss recent searches for new physics using high-energy atmospheric
neutrino data from IceCube, namely sterile neutrinos with masses in the range
$\Delta m^2 = 0.01$ eV$^2$ - 10 eV$^2$, and non-standard interactions (NSI) in
the $\nu_\mu - \nu_\tau$ sector. We also present a brief review of the current
status of NSI theory and phenomenology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09148</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Liberman</keyname><forenames>Gilad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solomon</keyname><forenames>Eddy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lustig</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frydman</keyname><forenames>Lucio</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple-coil k-space interpolation enhances resolution in single-shot
  spatiotemporal MRI</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 figs in main text; 2 in Supplementary Information; 0 tables</comments><journal-ref>Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/mrm.26731</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: Spatio-temporal encoding (SPEN) experiments can deliver single-scan
MR images without folding complications and with robustness to chemical shift
and susceptibility artifacts. It is here shown that further resolution
improvements can arise by relying on multiple receivers, to interpolate the
sampled data along the low-bandwidth dimension. The ensuing multiple-sensor
interpolation is akin to recently introduced SPEN interleaving procedures,
albeit without requiring multiple shots.
  Methods: By casting SPEN's spatial rasterization in k-space, it becomes
evident that local k-data interpolations enabled by multiple receivers are akin
to real-space interleaving of SPEN images. The practical implementation of such
resolution-enhancing procedure becomes similar to those normally used in SMASH
or SENSE, yet relaxing these methods' fold-over constraints.
  Results: Experiments validating the theoretical expectations were carried out
on phantoms and human volunteers on a 3T scanner. The experiments showed the
expected resolution enhancement, at no cost in the sequence's complexity. With
the addition of multibanding and stimulated echo procedures, 48-slices
full-brain coverage could be recorded free from distortions at sub-mm
resolution, in 3 sec.
  Conclusion: Super-resolved SPEN with SENSE (SUSPENSE) achieves the goals of
multi-shot SPEN interleaving within one single scan, delivering single-shot
sub-mm in-plane resolutions in scanners equipped with suitable multiple
sensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09149</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghose</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuous Quantum-Classical Transitions and Measurement: A Relook</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  The measurement problem in quantum mechanics originates in the inability of
the Schr\&quot;odinger equation to predict definite outcomes of measurements. This
is due to the lack of objectivity of the eigenstates of the measuring
apparatus. Such objectivity can be achieved if a unified realist conceptual
framework can be formulated in terms of wave functions and operators acting on
them for both the quantum and classical domains. Such a framework was proposed
and an equation for the wave function (13, 14) smoothly interpolates between
the quantum and classical limits. The arguments leading to the equation are
clarified in this paper, and the theory is developed further. The measurement
problem in quantum mechanics is then briefly reviewed and re-examined from the
point of view of this theory, and it is shown how the classical limit of the
wave function of the measuring apparatus leads to a natural solution of the
problem of definite measurement outcomes without the need for either collapse
or pragmatic thermodynamic arguments. This is consistent with Bohr's emphasis
on the primacy of classical concepts and classical measuring devices. Possible
tests of the theory using low-dimensional systems such as quantum dots are
indicated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09151</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Myrzakul</keyname><forenames>Tolkynay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudekli</keyname><forenames>Ertan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakul</keyname><forenames>Shynaray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakulov</keyname><forenames>Ratbay</forenames></author></authors><title>Noether symmetry of FRW cosmology with f - essence</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we investigate the dynamics of the universe on the background
of f-essence when a non-minimal coupling with gravity. Field equations are
obtained and using the Noether theorem, explicit forms of the coupling function
and the Lagrange function of the f-essence were obtained. Accordingly, for this
model, the cosmological parameters that describe the accelerated expansion of
the universe are determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09154</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Ershkov</keyname><forenames>Sergey V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Forbidden zones for circular regular orbits of the Moons in Solar
  system, R3BP</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 Tab.; Key words: restricted three-body problem, orbits of
  the Moon, relative motion; Cite this article as: ERSHKOV, S.V. J Astrophys
  Astron (2017) 38:5. doi:10.1007/s12036-017-9425-1</comments><msc-class>70F15, 70F07 (Celestial mechanics)</msc-class><journal-ref>J Astrophys Astron (2017) 38:5</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12036-017-9425-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previously, we have considered the equations of motion of the three-body
problem in a Lagrange form (which means a consideration of relative motions of
3-bodies in regard to each other). Analyzing such a system of equations, we
considered the case of small-body motion of negligible mass around the 2-nd of
two giant-bodies (which are rotating around their common centre of masses on
Kepler trajectories), the mass of which is assumed to be less than the mass of
central body. In the current development, we have derived a key parameter that
determines the character of quasi-circular motion of the small 3-rd body
relative to the 2-nd body (Planet). Namely, by making several approximations in
the equations of motion of the three-body problem, such the system could be
reduced to the key governing Riccati-type ordinary differential equations.
Under assumptions of R3BP (restricted three-body problem), we additionally note
that Riccati-type ODEs above should have the invariant form if the key
governing (dimensionless) parameter remains in the range 0.001-0.01. Such an
amazing fact let us evaluate the forbidden zones for Moons orbits in the inner
Solar system or the zones of the meanings of distances (between Moon-Planet)
for which the motion of small body could be predicted to be unstable according
to basic features of the solutions of Riccati-type.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09155</id><created>2017-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>Hyunseok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaczmarowski</keyname><forenames>Amy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>Izabela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Dane</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimization of self-interstitial clusters in 3C-SiC with Genetic
  Algorithm</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci nucl-th</categories><comments>30 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Nucl. Mater. 492 (2017) 62-73</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jnucmat.2017.05.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under irradiation, SiC develops damage commonly referred to as black spot
defects, which are speculated to be self-interstitial atom clusters. To
understand the evolution of these defect clusters and their impacts (e.g.,
through radiation induced swelling) on the performance of SiC in nuclear
applications, it is important to identify the cluster composition, structure,
and shape. In this work the genetic algorithm code StructOpt was utilized to
identify groundstate cluster structures in 3C-SiC. The genetic algorithm was
used to explore clusters of up to ~30 interstitials of C-only, Si-only, and
Si-C mixtures embedded in the SiC lattice. We performed the structure search
using Hamiltonians from both density functional theory and empirical
potentials. The thermodynamic stability of clusters was investigated in terms
of their composition (with a focus on Si-only, C-only, and stoichiometric) and
shape (spherical vs. planar), as a function of the cluster size (n). Our
results suggest that large Si-only clusters are likely unstable, and clusters
are predominantly C-only for n &lt;= 10 and stoichiometric for n &gt; 10. The results
imply that there is an evolution of the shape of the most stable clusters,
where small clusters are stable in more spherical geometries while larger
clusters are stable in more planar configurations. We also provide an estimated
energy vs. size relationship, E(n), for use in future analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09161</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>I. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakke</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>On an atom with a magnetic quadrupole moment in a rotating frame</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1705.08193</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus 132, 24 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11290-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum description of an atom with a magnetic quadrupole moment in the
presence of a uniform effective magnetic field is analysed. The atom is also
subject to rotation and a scalar potential proportional to the inverse of the
radial distance. It is shown that the spectrum of energy is modified, in
contrast to the Landau-type levels, and there is a restriction on the possible
values of the cyclotron frequency which stems from the influence of the
rotation and scalar potential proportional to the inverse of the radial
distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09175</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fedoseev</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ioppolo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamberts</keyname><forenames>Thanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhen</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuppen</keyname><forenames>Herma M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnartz</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient Surface Formation Route of Interstellar Hydroxylamine through
  NO Hydrogenation II: the multilayer regime in interstellar relevant ices</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics, Volume 137, Issue 5, page 054714
  (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4738893</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydroxylamine (NH2OH) is one of the potential precursors of complex
pre-biotic species in space. Here we present a detailed experimental study of
hydroxylamine formation through nitric oxide (NO) surface hydrogenation for
astronomically relevant conditions. The aim of this work is to investigate
hydroxylamine formation efficiencies in polar (water-rich) and non-polar
(carbon monoxide-rich) interstellar ice analogues. A complex reaction network
involving both final (N2O, NH2OH) and intermediate (HNO, NH2O, etc.) products
is discussed. The main conclusion is that hydroxylamine formation takes place
via a fast and barrierless mechanism and it is found to be even more abundantly
formed in a water-rich environment at lower temperatures. In parallel, we
experimentally verify the non-formation of hydroxylamine upon UV photolysis of
NO ice at cryogenic temperatures as well as the non-detection of NC- and
NCO-bond bearing species after UV processing of NO in carbon monoxide-rich
ices. Our results are implemented into an astrochemical reaction model, which
shows that NH2OH is abundant in the solid phase under dark molecular cloud
conditions. Once NH2OH desorbs from the ice grains, it becomes available to
form more complex species (e.g., glycine and beta-alanine) in gas phase
reaction schemes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09184</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fedoseev</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ioppolo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Dongfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamberts</keyname><forenames>Thanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnartz</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author></authors><title>Low Temperature Surface Formation of NH3 and HNCO: hydrogenation of
  nitrogen atoms in CO-rich interstellar ice analogues</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 446,
  Issue 1, p.439-448 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stu2028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solid state astrochemical reaction pathways have the potential to link the
formation of small nitrogen-bearing species, like NH3 and HNCO, and prebiotic
molecules, specifically amino acids. To date, the chemical origin of such small
nitrogen containing species is still not well understood, despite the fact that
ammonia is an abundant constituent of interstellar ices toward young stellar
objects and quiescent molecular clouds. This is mainly because of the lack of
dedicated laboratory studies. The aim of the present work is to experimentally
investigate the formation routes of NH3 and HNCO through non-energetic surface
reactions in interstellar ice analogues under fully controlled laboratory
conditions and at astrochemically relevant temperatures. This study focuses on
the formation of NH3 and HNCO in CO-rich (non-polar) interstellar ices that
simulate the CO freeze-out stage in dark interstellar cloud regions, well
before thermal and energetic processing start to become relevant. We
demonstrate and discuss the surface formation of solid HNCO through the
interaction of CO molecules with NH radicals - one of the intermediates in the
formation of solid NH3 upon sequential hydrogenation of N atoms. The importance
of HNCO for astrobiology is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09187</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Barbaroux</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornean</keyname><forenames>Horia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockmeyer</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral gaps in graphene antidot lattices</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><msc-class>81Q10 (primary), 46N50, 81Q37, 34L10, 47A10 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the gap creation problem in an antidot graphene lattice, i.e. a
sheet of graphene with periodically distributed obstacles. We prove several
spectral results concerning the size of the gap and its dependence on different
natural parameters related to the antidot lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09197</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Engelbrecht</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strauss</keyname><forenames>Du Toit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roux</keyname><forenames>Kobus le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>Adri</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards a greater understanding of the reduction of drift coefficients
  in the presence of turbulence</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Drift effects play a significant role in the transport of charged particles
in the heliosphere. A turbulent magnetic field is also known to reduce the
effects of particle drifts. The exact nature of this reduction, however, is not
clear. This study aims to provide some insight into this reduction, and
proposes a relatively simple, tractable means of modelling it that provides
results in reasonable agreement with numerical simulations of the drift
coefficient in a turbulent magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09208</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Smolin</keyname><forenames>Lee</forenames></author></authors><title>What are we missing in our search for quantum gravity?</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Latex, 21 pages. For Foundations of Mathematics and Physics : an
  IJGMMP special issue</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some reflections are presented on the state of the search for a quantum
theory of gravity. I discuss diverse regimes of possible quantum gravitational
phenomenon, some well explored, some novel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09209</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fedoseev</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ioppolo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnartz</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author></authors><title>Deuterium enrichment of ammonia produced by surface N+H/D addition
  reactions at low temperature</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 446,
  Issue 1, p.449-458 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stu1852</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The surface formation of NH3 and its deuterated isotopologues - NH2D, NHD2,
and ND3 - is investigated at low temperatures through the simultaneous addition
of hydrogen and deuterium atoms to nitrogen atoms in CO-rich interstellar ice
analogues. The formation of all four ammonia isotopologues is only observed up
to 15 K, and drops below the detection limit for higher temperatures.
Differences between hydrogenation and deuteration yields result in a clear
deviation from a statistical distribution in favour of deuterium enriched
species. The data analysis suggests that this is due to a higher sticking
probability of D atoms to the cold surface, a property that may generally apply
to molecules that are formed in low temperature surface reactions. The results
found here are used to interpret ammonia deuterium fractionation as observed in
pre-protostellar cores.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09214</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ballett</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hostert</keyname><forenames>Matheus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascoli</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Sterile Neutrinos at $\nu$STORM: Decoherence and CP violation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Poster presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 4
  pages, LaTeX, 7 figures</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Hostert</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light sterile neutrino oscillations can be partially or completely washed out
at short-baseline experiments due to the breaking of neutrino production
coherence. In this work we address this issue in sterile searches at
$\nu$STORM, an experimental proposal for a beam of neutrinos from the decay of
stored muons. We work with 3+1 and 3+2 models, the latter introducing CP
violation at short-baselines. We find that decoherence effects are only
relevant for sterile masses above $\Delta m^2 \gtrsim 10$ eV$^2$, and that,
even in that regime, we are able to place strong appearance bounds in such
clean environments. In addition, the novel signatures of CP violation in the
parameter space of interest can be identified with a significance of up to
$\gtrsim 3 \sigma$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09215</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Frodason</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansen</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bj&#xf8;rheim</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svensson</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alkauskas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Zn vacancy as a polaronic hole trap in ZnO</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 094105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.094105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work explores the Zn vacancy in ZnO using hybrid density functional
theory calculations. The Zn vacancy is predicted to be an exceedingly deep
polaronic acceptor that can bind a localized hole on each of the four
nearest-neighbor O ions. The hole localization is accompanied by a distinct
outward relaxation of the O ions, which leads to lower symmetry and reduced
formation energy. Notably, we find that initial symmetry-breaking is required
to capture this effect, which might explain the absence of polaronic hole
localization in some previous hybrid density functional studies. We present a
simple model to rationalize our findings with regard to the approximately
equidistant thermodynamic charge-state transition levels. Furthermore, by
employing a one-dimensional configuration coordinate model with parameters
obtained from the hybrid density functional theory calculations, luminescence
lineshapes were calculated. The results show that the isolated Zn vacancy is
unlikely to be the origin of the commonly observed luminescence in the visible
part of the emission spectrum from \textit{n}-type material, but rather the
luminescence in the infrared region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09223</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Pancorbo</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dom&#xed;nguez-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Brownian dynamics simulations to explore experimental microsphere
  diffusion with optical tweezers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Proceeding for the International Conference on Computational Science
  (ICCS 2017). To be published on Procedia Computer Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop two-dimensional Brownian dynamics simulations to examine the
motion of disks under thermal fluctuations and Hookean forces. Our simulations
are designed to be experimental-like, since the experimental conditions define
the available time-scales which characterize the solution of Langevin
equations. To define the fluid model and methodology, we explain the basics of
the theory of Brownian motion applicable to quasi-twodimensional diffusion of
optically-trapped microspheres. Using the data produced by the simulations, we
propose an alternative methodology to calculate diffusion coefficients. We
obtain that, using typical input parameters in video-microscopy experiments,
the averaged values of the diffusion coefficient differ from the theoretical
one less than a 1\%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09226</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Radovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novakovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carruba</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mar&#x10d;eta</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>An automatic approach to exclude interlopers from asteroid families</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1273</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Asteroid families are valuable source of information to many asteroid-related
re- searches, assuming a reliable list of their members could be obtained.
However, as the number of known asteroids increases fast it becomes more and
more difficult to obtain robust list of members of an asteroid family. Here we
are proposing a new approach to deal with the problem, based on the well known
Hierarchical Clustering Method (HCM). An additional step in the whole procedure
is introduced in order to reduce a so-called chaining effect. The main idea is
to prevent chaining through an al- ready identified interloper. We show that in
this way a number of potential interlopers among family members is
significantly reduced. Moreover, we developed an automatic on-line based portal
to apply this procedure, i.e to generate a list of family members as well as a
list of potential interlopers. The Asteroid Families Portal (AFP) is freely
available to all interested researchers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09235</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fedoseev</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuppen</keyname><forenames>Herma M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ioppolo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamberts</keyname><forenames>Thanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnartz</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental evidence for Glycolaldehyde and Ethylene Glycol formation
  by surface hydrogenation of CO molecules under dense molecular cloud
  conditions</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 448,
  Issue 2, p.1288-1297 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stu2603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This study focuses on the formation of two molecules of astrobiological
importance - glycolaldehyde (HC(O)CH2OH) and ethylene glycol (H2C(OH)CH2OH) -
by surface hydrogenation of CO molecules. Our experiments aim at simulating the
CO freeze-out stage in interstellar dark cloud regions, well before thermal and
energetic processing become dominant. It is shown that along with the formation
of H2CO and CH3OH - two well established products of CO hydrogenation - also
molecules with more than one carbon atom form. The key step in this process is
believed to be the recombination of two HCO radicals followed by the formation
of a C-C bond. The experimentally established reaction pathways are implemented
into a continuous-time random-walk Monte Carlo model, previously used to model
the formation of CH3OH on astrochemical time-scales, to study their impact on
the solid-state abundances in dense interstellar clouds of glycolaldehyde and
ethylene glycol.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09238</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dyks</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The origin of radio pulsar polarisation</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>21 pages, 20 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarisation of radio pulsar profiles involves a number of poorly understood,
intriguing phenomena, such as the existence of comparable amounts of orthogonal
polarisation modes (OPMs), strong distortions of polarisation angle (PA) curves
into shapes inconsistent with the rotating vector model (RVM), and the strong
circular polarisation V which can be maximum (instead of zero) at the OPM
jumps. It is shown that the existence of comparable OPMs and of the large V
results from a coherent addition of phase-delayed waves in natural propagation
modes, which are produced by an incident linearly polarised signal. The
coherent mode summation implies opposite polarisation properties to those known
from the incoherent case, in particular, the OPM jumps occur at peaks of V ,
whereas V changes sign at a maximum of the linear polarisation fraction L/I.
These features are indispensable to interpret various observed polarisation
effects. It is shown that statistical properties of the emission mechanism and
of propagation effects can be efficiently parametrised in a simple model of
coherent mode addition, which is successfully applied to complex polarisation
phenomena, such as the stepwise PA curve of PSR B1913+16 and the strong
distortions of the PA curve within core components of pulsars B1933+16 and
B1237+25. The inclusion of coherent mode addition opens the possibility for a
number of new polarisation effects, such as inversion of relative modal
strength, twin minima in L/I coincident with peaks in V , 45 deg PA jumps in
weakly polarised emission, and loop-shaped core PA distortions. The empirical
treatment of the coherency of mode addition makes it possible to advance the
understanding of pulsar polarisation beyond the RVM model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09273</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Pau&#x10d;o</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kla&#x10d;ka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The imprint of the MOND external field effect on the Oort cloud comets
  aphelia distribution</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables; submitted to A&amp;A, comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Milgromian dynamics (MD or MOND) is a promising physical description
excelling especially in galaxies. When formulated as a modified gravity theory,
it leads to the so called external field effect (EFE). In the case of the solar
system this means that bodies orbiting the Sun are influenced, beyond its tidal
effect, by the external gravitational field of the Galaxy with magnitude
$\sim2\times10^{-10}$ m s$^{-2}$ and time-varying direction. Aphelia of
intermediate outer Oort cloud (OC) comets ($30&lt;X&lt;60,~X\equiv
10^{6}/a[\text{au}]$, where $a$ is semimajor axis) are distributed
non-uniformly on the celestial sphere, showing an apparent concentration around
a great circle centered at Galactic longitudes $L=-45$ and 135 deg. Such
non-uniformity is beyond that attributable to the classical injectors of
comets, stellar encounters and the Galactic tides, as well as the expected
observational biases. We investigated a hypothesis that the great circle
concentration of aphelia is a consequence of the long-term action of EFE in the
framework of MD. We considered exclusively quasi-linear MOND (QUMOND) theory.
We built our model of the OC in MD on an analytical approximation of the QUMOND
potential for a point mass in the dominant external field of constant
magnitude. The model is well applicable at heliocentric distances
$r\gtrsim10~000$ au. Constraints on the strength of EFE found by the analysis
of the Cassini radio-tracking data were taken into account. We demonstrated
characteristic imprint of the EFE on the distribution of aphelia of candidate
outer OC comets that migrated down to $r=10~000$ au. By both analytical and
numerical calculations, we showed that the combined effect of EFE and the
Galactic tides could qualitatively account for the characteristic features seen
in the observed distribution of aphelia of the outer OC comets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
