<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:06:28Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-15" from="2017-05-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0904.1573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0904.1573</id><created>2009-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Parrondo</keyname><forenames>Juan M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broeck</keyname><forenames>Christian van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawai</keyname><forenames>Ryoichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy production and the arrow of time</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 11, 073008 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/11/7/073008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an exact relationship between the entropy production and the
distinguishability of a process from its time-reverse, quantified by the
relative entropy between forward and backward states. The relationship is shown
to remain valid for a wide family of initial conditions, such as canonical,
constrained canonical, multi-canonical and grand canonical distributions, as
well as both for classical and quantum systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.0419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.0419</id><created>2012-04-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Braeck</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gron</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>A river model of space</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2013) 128: 24</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2013-13024-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the theory of general relativity gravitational phenomena are usually
attributed to the curvature of four-dimensional spacetime. In this context we
are often confronted with the question of how the concept of ordinary physical
three-dimensional space fits into this picture. In this work we present a
simple and intuitive model of space for both the Schwarzschild spacetime and
the de Sitter spacetime in which physical space is defined as a specified set
of freely moving reference particles. Using a combination of orthonormal basis
fields and the usual formalism in a coordinate basis we calculate the physical
velocity field of these reference particles. Thus we obtain a vivid description
of space in which space behaves like a river flowing radially toward the
singularity in the Schwarzschild spacetime and radially toward infinity in the
de Sitter spacetime. We also consider the effect of the river of space upon
light rays and material particles and show that the river model of space
provides an intuitive explanation for the behavior of light and particles at
and beyond the event horizons associated with these spacetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.6533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.6533</id><created>2012-06-27</created><updated>2013-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Curtis</keyname><forenames>Jason L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolfgang</keyname><forenames>Angie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Jason T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brewer</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ruprecht 147: The oldest nearby open cluster as a new benchmark for
  stellar astrophysics</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>31 pages, 21 figures, 6 tables. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>The Astronomical Journal (2013), Volume 145, Issue 5</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-6256/145/5/134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ruprecht 147 is a hitherto unappreciated open cluster that holds great
promise as a standard in fundamental stellar astrophysics. We have conducted a
radial velocity survey of astrometric candidates with Lick, Palomar, and MMT
observatories and have identified over 100 members, including 5 blue
stragglers, 11 red giants, and 5 double-lined spectroscopic binaries (SB2s). We
estimate the cluster metallicity from spectroscopic analysis, using
Spectroscopy Made Easy (SME), and find it to be [M/H] = +0.07 \pm 0.03. We have
obtained deep CFHT/MegaCam g'r'i' photometry and fit Padova isochrones to the
(g' - i') and 2MASS (J - K) CMDs using the \tau^2 maximum-likelihood procedure
of Naylor (2009), and an alternative method using 2D cross-correlations
developed in this work. We find best fits for isochrones at age t = 2.5 \pm
0.25 Gyr, m - M = 7.35 \pm 0.1, and A_V = 0.25 \pm 0.05, with additional
uncertainty from the unresolved binary population and possibility of
differential extinction across this large cluster. The inferred age is heavily
dependent by our choice of stellar evolution model: fitting Dartmouth and
PARSEC models yield age parameters of 3 Gyr and 3.25 Gyr respectively. At
approximately 300 pc and 3 Gyr, Ruprecht 147 is by far the oldest nearby star
cluster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.7306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.7306</id><created>2013-04-26</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yatsuyanagi</keyname><forenames>Yuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatori</keyname><forenames>Tadatsugu</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanism of self-organization in point vortex system</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Typographic errors in Eq. (27) and (28) are corrected</comments><journal-ref>Fluid Dyn. Res. 47 (2015) 065506</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0169-5983/47/6/065506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mechanism of the self-organization in an unbounded two-dimensional (2D)
point vortex system is discussed. A kinetic equation for the system with
positive and negative vortices is derived using the Klimontovich formalism.
Similar to the Fokker-Planck collision term, the obtained collision term
consists of a diffusion term and a drift term. It is revealed that the
mechanism for the self-organization in the 2D point vortex system at negative
absolute temperature is mainly provided by the drift term. Positive and
negative vortices are driven toward opposite directions respectively by the
drift term. As a result, well-known, two isolated clumps with positive and
negative vortices, respectively, are formed as an equilibrium distribution.
Regardless of the number of species of the vortices, either single- or
double-sign, it is found that the collision term has following physically good
properties: (i) When the system reaches a quasi-stationary state near the
thermal equilibrium state with negative absolute temperature, the sign of $d
\omega / d \psi$ is expected to be positive, where $\omega$ is the vorticity
and $\psi$ is the stream function. In this case, the diffusion term decreases
the mean field energy, while the drift term increases it. As a whole, the total
mean field energy is conserved. (ii) Similarly, the diffusion term increases
the Boltzmann entropy, while the drift term decreases it. As a whole, the total
entropy production rate is positive or zero ($H$ theorem), which ensures that
the system relaxes to the global thermal equilibrium state characterized by the
zero entropy production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.1222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.1222</id><created>2013-08-06</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Alwis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatefi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quevedo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability, Tunneling and Flux Changing de Sitter Transitions in the
  Large Volume String Scenario</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>An error (equation 5.5) is corrected and references added. The main
  conclusion is unchanged</comments><report-no>DAMTP-2013-42</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP11(2013)179</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2013)179</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the non-perturbative stability of the Large Volume Scenario (LVS) of
IIB string compactifications, by analysing transitions mediated by the
Brown-Teitelboim (BT) brane nucleations and by Coleman De Luccia tunneling
(CDL). We find that, as long as the effective field theory description holds,
the LVS AdS minima are stable despite being non-supersymmetric. This opens the
possibility of having a CFT dual. Metastable de Sitter vacua behave differently
depending on the uplifting mechanism. We find explicit expressions for the
different decay rates in terms of exponentials of the volume. Among the
transitions of dS to dS those with increasing volume and decreasing vacuum
energy are preferred, though dS decays to AdS (big-crunch sinks) have higher
probability. However, the probability of transitions via the CDL mechanism to
decompactification are exponentially much larger compared to these. The BT
decays correspond to flux/D3 brane transitions mediated by the nucleation of
D5/NS5 branes. We compare our results with previous analysis for KKLT, type
IIA, and 6D Einstein-Maxwell studies. In particular we find no indication for a
bubble of nothing decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2560</id><created>2014-09-08</created><updated>2017-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>Anibal D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgsino-like Dark Matter From Sneutrino Late Decays</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures. Final version PLB</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 770C (2017) pp. 161-165</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.054</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider Higgsino-like dark matter (DM) in the Minimal Supersymmetric
Standard Model (MSSM) with additional right-handed neutrino chiral superfields,
and propose a new non-thermal way of generating the right amount of relic DM
via sneutrino late decays. Due to the large DM annihilation cross-section,
decays must occur at lower temperatures than the freeze-out temperature $T_d\ll
T_{F,\tilde{\chi}^0_1}\sim \mu/25$, implying a mostly right-handed lightest
sneutrino with very small Yukawa interactions. In that context, the right
amount of Higgsino-like DM relic density can be accounted for if sneutrinos are
produced via thermal freeze-in in the early Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0917</id><created>2014-11-04</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Giga</keyname><forenames>Yoshikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ibrahim</keyname><forenames>Slim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Shengyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoneda</keyname><forenames>Tsuyoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Global well posedness for a two-fluid model</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a two fluid system which models the motion of a charged fluid with
Rayleigh friction, and in the presence of an electro-magnetic field satisfying
Maxwell's equations. We study the well-posdness of the system in both space
dimensions two and three. Regardless of the size of the initial data, we first
prove the global well-posedness of the Cauchy problem when the space dimension
is two. However, in space dimension three, we construct global weak-solutions
\`a la Leray, and we prove the local well-posedness of Kato-type solutions.
These solutions turn out to be global when the initial data are sufficiently
small. Our results extend Giga-Yoshida (1984) ones to the space dimension two,
and improve them in terms of requiring less regularity on the velocity fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07147</id><created>2015-02-25</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forrester</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>Muttalib--Borodin ensembles in random matrix theory --- realisations and
  correlation functions</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>46 pages, 7 figures. Introduction rewritten, proof of Proposition 1.3
  clarified, typos corrected, and references updated</comments><msc-class>60B20, 15B52, 82D35, 30E10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Muttalib--Borodin ensembles are characterised by the pair interaction term in
the eigenvalue probability density function being of the form $\prod_{1 \le j &lt;
k \le N}(\lambda_k - \lambda_j) (\lambda_k^\theta - \lambda_j^\theta)$. We
study the Laguerre and Jacobi versions of this model --- so named by the form
of the one-body interaction terms --- and show that for $\theta \in \mathbb
Z^+$ they can be realised as the eigenvalue PDF of certain random matrices with
Gaussian entries. For general $\theta &gt; 0$, realisations in terms of the
eigenvalue PDF of ensembles involving triangular matrices are given. In the
Laguerre case this is a recent result due to Cheliotis, although our derivation
is different. We make use of a generalisation of a double contour integral
formula for the correlation functions contained in a paper by Adler, van
Moerbeke and Wang to analyse the global density (which we also analyse by
studying characteristic polynomials), and the hard edge scaled correlation
functions. For the global density functional equations for the corresponding
resolvents are obtained; solving this gives the moments in terms of
Fuss--Catalan numbers (Laguerre case --- a known result) and particular
binomial coefficients (Jacobi case). For $\theta \in \mathbb Z^+$ the Laguerre
and Jacobi cases are closely related to the squared singular values for
products of $\theta$ standard Gaussian random matrices, and truncations of
unitary matrices, respectively. At the hard edge the double contour integral
formulas provide a double contour integral form of the scaled correlation
kernel obtained by Borodin in terms of Wright's Bessel function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03323</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2015-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Siddhartha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balu</keyname><forenames>Radhakrishnan</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of correlations in Local Random Quantum Circuits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures. Updated abstract</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf Process 2016, Volume 15 Issue 11</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1412-y</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a dynamical bound on the propagation of correlations in local
random quantum circuits - lattice spin systems where piecewise quantum
operations - in space and time - occur with classical probabilities.
Correlations are quantified by the Frobenius norm of the commutator of two
positive operators acting on space-like separated local Hilbert spaces. For
times $t=O(L)$ correlations spread to distances $\mathcal{D}=t$ growing, at
best, diffusively for any distance within that radius with extensively
suppressed distance dependent corrections whereas for $t=o(L^2)$ all parts of
the system get almost equally correlated with exponentially suppressed distance
dependent corrections and approach the maximum amount of correlations that may
be established asymptotically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03557</id><created>2015-07-17</created><updated>2016-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Uecker</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lustig</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating Absolute-Phase Maps Using ESPIRiT and Virtual Conjugate Coils</title><categories>cs.CV cs.CE physics.med-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 77 (2017) 1201-1207</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/mrm.26191</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: To develop an ESPIRiT-based method to estimate coil sensitivities
with image phase as a building block for efficient and robust image
reconstruction with phase constraints. Theory and Methods: ESPIRiT is a new
framework for calibration of the coil sensitivities and reconstruction in
parallel Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI). Applying ESPIRiT to a combined set
of physical and virtual conjugate coils (VCC-ESPIRiT) implicitly exploits
conjugate symmetry in k-space similar to VCC-GRAPPA. Based on this method, a
new post-processing step is proposed for the explicit computation of coil
sensitivities that include the absolute phase of the image. The accuracy of the
computed maps is directly validated using a test based on projection onto fully
sampled coil images and also indirectly in phase-constrained parallel-imaging
reconstructions. Results: The proposed method can estimate accurate
sensitivities which include low-resolution image phase. In case of
high-frequency phase variations VCC-ESPIRiT yields an additional set of maps
that indicates the existence of a high-frequency phase component. Taking this
additional set of maps into account can improve the robustness of
phase-constrained parallel imaging. Conclusion: The extended VCC-ESPIRiT is a
useful tool for phase-constrained imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06330</id><created>2015-09-21</created><updated>2015-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wykes</keyname><forenames>Megan S. Davies</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palacci</keyname><forenames>Jeremie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>Takuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ristroph</keyname><forenames>Leif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>Michael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelley</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic self-assembly of microscale rotors and swimmers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1039/C5SM03127C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biological systems often involve the self-assembly of basic components into
complex and function- ing structures. Artificial systems that mimic such
processes can provide a well-controlled setting to explore the principles
involved and also synthesize useful micromachines. Our experiments show that
immotile, but active, components self-assemble into two types of structure that
exhibit the fundamental forms of motility: translation and rotation.
Specifically, micron-scale metallic rods are designed to induce extensile
surface flows in the presence of a chemical fuel; these rods interact with each
other and pair up to form either a swimmer or a rotor. Such pairs can
transition reversibly be- tween these two configurations, leading to kinetics
reminiscent of bacterial run-and-tumble motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03404</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Starke</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schober</keyname><forenames>G. A. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic Theory of the Refractive Index</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>consistent with published version in Optik - International Journal
  for Light and Electron Optics (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Optik 140, 62 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijleo.2017.03.088</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the refractive index from the viewpoint of modern first-principles
materials physics. We first argue that the standard formula, $n^2 =
\varepsilon_{\mathrm r} \mu_{\mathrm r}$, is generally in conflict with
fundamental principles on the microscopic level. Instead, it turns out that an
allegedly approximate relation, $n^2 = \varepsilon_{\mathrm r}$, which is
already being used for most practical purposes, can be justified theoretically
at optical wavelengths. More generally, starting from the fundamental,
Lorentz-covariant electromagnetic wave equation in materials as used in plasma
physics, we rederive a well-known, three-dimensional form of the wave equation
in materials and thereby clarify the connection between the covariant
fundamental response tensor and the various cartesian tensors used to describe
optical properties. Finally, we prove a general theorem by which the
fundamental, covariant wave equation can be reformulated concisely in terms of
the microscopic dielectric tensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03004</id><created>2015-11-10</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smotlacha</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pincak</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Boundary conditions and Green function approach of the spin-orbit
  interaction in the graphitic nanocone</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Geom. Methods Mod. Phys., 1750116 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021988781750116X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The boundary effects affecting the Hamiltonian for the nanocone with
curvatureinduced spin orbit coupling were considered and the corresponding
electronic structure was calculated. These boundary effects include the spin
orbit coupling, the electron mass acquisition and the Coulomb interaction.
Different numbers of the pentagonal defects in the tip were considered. The
Green function approach into the second order was used for getting more precise
results in the case of the spin orbit coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04381</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-06-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Cong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Ming-Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>$\gamma\gamma\rightarrow M^{+}M^{-}(M=\pi, K)$ processes with twist-3
  corrections in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C, 77 (2017) 219</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4764-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the $\gamma\gamma\rightarrow M^{+}M^{-}(M=\pi, K)$ processes with
the contributions from the two-particle twist-2 and twist-3 distribution
amplitudes of pion and kaon mesons on BHL prescription in the standard
hard-scattering approach. The results show that the contributions from twist-3
parts are actually not power suppressed comparing with the leading-twist
contributions and the cross sections agree well with the experimental data in
the two-photon center-of-mass energy $W&gt;2.8$ GeV. We also predict the cross
section ratio $\sigma_{0}(\pi^{+}\pi^{-})/\sigma_{0}(K^{+}K^{-})$, which is
compatible with the experimental data from TPC and Belle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04424</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2017-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Royer</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimsmo</keyname><forenames>Arne L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Didier</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blais</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast and High-Fidelity Entangling Gate through Parametrically Modulated
  Longitudinal Coupling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, Supplemental Material</comments><journal-ref>Quantum 1, 11 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-05-11-11</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate an approach to universal quantum computation based on the
modulation of longitudinal qubit-oscillator coupling. We show how to realize a
controlled-phase gate by simultaneously modulating the longitudinal coupling of
two qubits to a common oscillator mode. In contrast to the more familiar
transversal qubit-oscillator coupling, the magnitude of the effective
qubit-qubit interaction does not rely on a small perturbative parameter. As a
result, this effective interaction strength can be made large, leading to short
gate times and high gate fidelities. We moreover show how the gate infidelity
can be exponentially suppressed with squeezing and how the entangling gate can
be generalized to qubits coupled to separate oscillators. Our proposal can be
realized in multiple physical platforms for quantum computing, including
superconducting and spin qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07764</id><created>2016-03-24</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Duho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>Rolf A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Windhorst</keyname><forenames>Rogier A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of the Intrinsic Mid-Infrared L-band to Visible--Near-Infrared
  Flux Ratios in Spectral Synthesis Models of Composite Stellar Populations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>33 pages (15 appendix+figsets), 16 (+14) figures, 5 (+2) tables;
  AASTeX6, pdflatex; Published on ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6ba1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the intrinsic flux ratios of various visible--near-infrared
filters with respect to 3.5micron for simple and composite stellar populations,
and their dependence on age, metallicity and star formation history. UV/optical
light from stars is reddened and attenuated by dust, where different sightlines
across a galaxy suffer varying amounts of extinction. Tamura et al. (2009)
developed an approximate method to correct for dust extinction on a
pixel-by-pixel basis, dubbed the &quot;beta_V&quot; method, by comparing the observed
flux ratio to an empirical estimate of the intrinsic ratio of visible and
~3.5micron data. Through extensive modeling, we aim to validate the &quot;beta_V&quot;
method for various filters spanning the visible through near-infrared
wavelength range, for a wide variety of simple and composite stellar
populations. Combining Starburst99 and BC03 models, we built spectral energy
distributions (SEDs) of simple (SSP) and composite (CSP) stellar populations
for various realistic star formation histories (SFHs), while taking metallicity
evolution into account. We convolve various 0.44--1.65micron filter throughput
curves with each model SED to obtain intrinsic flux ratios beta_{lam,0}. When
unconstrained in redshift, the total allowed range of beta_{V,0} is 0.6--4.7,
or almost a factor of eight. At known redshifts, and in particular at low
redshifts (z&lt;0.01), beta_{V,0} is predicted to span a narrow range of 0.6--1.9,
especially for early-type galaxies (0.6--0.7), and is consistent with observed
beta_V values. The beta_lam method can therefore serve as a first-order dust
correction method for large galaxy surveys that combine JWST (rest-frame
3.5micron) and HST (rest-frame visible--near-IR) data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07180</id><created>2016-05-23</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pozas-Kerstjens</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Martinez</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement harvesting from the electromagnetic vacuum with
  hydrogenlike atoms</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages (12 pages manuscript + 16 pages of appendices), 6 figures.
  RevTeX 4.1. V4: A few minor typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064074 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study how two fully-featured hydrogenlike atoms harvest entanglement from
the electromagnetic field vacuum, even when the atoms are spacelike separated.
We compare the electromagnetic case ---qualitatively and quantitatively--- with
previous results that used scalar fields and featureless, idealized atomic
models. Our study reveals the new traits that emerge when we relax these
idealizations, such as anisotropies in entanglement harvesting and the effect
of exchange of angular momentum. We show that, under certain circumstances,
relaxing previous idealizations makes vacuum entanglement harvesting more
efficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03721</id><created>2016-06-12</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kamikado</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanazawa</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchino</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author></authors><title>Mobile impurity in a Fermi sea from the functional renormalization group
  analytically continued to real time</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-220</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013612 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013612</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by experiments with cold atoms, we investigate a mobile impurity
immersed in a Fermi sea in three dimensions at zero temperature by means of the
functional renormalization group. We first perform the derivative expansion of
the effective action to calculate the ground state energy and Tan's contact
across the polaron-molecule transition for several mass imbalances. Next we
study quasiparticle properties of the impurity by using a real-time method
recently developed in nuclear physics, which allows one to go beyond the
derivative expansion. We obtain the spectral function of the polaron, the
effective mass and quasiparticle weight of attractive and repulsive polarons,
and clarify how they are affected by mass imbalances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07801</id><created>2016-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strand</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author></authors><title>A Fluctuating Lattice Boltzmann Method for the Diffusion Equation</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures, submitted to PRE</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 033302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.033302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a fluctuating lattice Boltzmann method for the diffusion equation.
The derivation removes several shortcomings of previous derivations for
fluctuating lattice Boltzmann methods for hydrodynamic systems. The comparative
simplicity of this diffusive system highlights the basic features of this first
exact derivation of a fluctuating lattice Boltzmann method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05672</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aczel</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luke</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden Order Signatures in the Antiferromagnetic Phase of
  U(Ru$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$)$_2$Si$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 104440 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.104440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comprehensive set of elastic and inelastic neutron scattering
measurements on a range of Fe-doped samples of U(Ru$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$)$_2$Si$_2$
with 0.01~$\le~x~\le$~0.15. All of the samples measured exhibit long-range
antiferromagnetic order, with the size of the magnetic moment quickly
increasing to 0.51~$\mu_B$ at 2.5\% doping and continuing to increase
monotonically with doping, reaching 0.69~$\mu_B$ at 15\% doping. Time-of-flight
and inelastic triple-axis measurements show the existence of excitations at
(1~0~0) and (1.4~0~0) in all samples, which are also observed in the parent
compound. While the excitations in the 1\% doping are quantitatively identical
to the parent material, the gap and width of the excitations change rapidly at
2.5\% Fe doping and above. The 1\% doped sample shows evidence for a separation
in temperature between the hidden order and antiferromagnetic transitions,
suggesting that the antiferromagnetic state emerges at very low Fe dopings. The
combined neutron scattering data suggests not only discontinuous changes in the
magnetic moment and excitations between the hidden order and antiferromagnetic
phases, but that these changes continue to evolve up to at least $x$~=~0.15.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03691</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsuzaki</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohki</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamawaki</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Side of the Standard Model: Dormant New Physics Awaken</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 eps figures, further several discussions added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find that the nonperturbative physics of the standard-model Higgs
Lagrangian provides a dark matter candidate, &quot;dormant skyrmion in the standard
model&quot;, the same type of the skyrmion, a soliton, as in the hadron physics. It
is stabilized by another nonperturbative object in the standard model, the
dynamical gauge boson of the hidden local symmetry, which is also an analogue
of the rho meson.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00258</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ankowski</keyname><forenames>Artur M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>Camillo</forenames></author></authors><title>Systematic uncertainties in long-baseline neutrino-oscillation
  experiments</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 (2017) 054001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa61b2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Future neutrino-oscillation experiments are expected to bring definite
answers to the questions of neutrino-mass hierarchy and violation of
charge-parity symmetry in the lepton sector. To realize this ambitious program
it is necessary to ensure a significant reduction of uncertainties,
particularly those related to neutrino-energy reconstruction. In this paper, we
discuss different sources of systematic uncertainties, paying special attention
to those arising from nuclear effects and detector response. By analyzing
nuclear effects we show the importance of developing accurate theoretical
models, capable to provide quantitative description of neutrino cross sections,
together with the relevance of their implementation in Monte Carlo generators
and extensive testing against lepton-scattering data. We also point out the
fundamental role of efforts aiming to determine detector responses in test-beam
exposures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01448</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Ze-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jianhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Shun-Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization Group Approach to Stability of Two-dimensional
  Interacting Type-II Dirac Fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Final pulished version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 195412 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The type-II Weyl/Dirac fermions are a generalization of conventional or
type-I Weyl/Dirac fermions, whose conic spectrum is tilted such that the Fermi
surface becomes lines in two dimensions, and surface in three dimensions rather
than discrete points of the conventional Weyl/Dirac fermions. The
mass-independent renormalization group calculations show that the tilting
parameter decreases monotonically with respect to the length scale, which leads
to a transition from two dimensional type-II Weyl/Dirac fermions to the type-I
ones. Because of the non-trivial Fermi surface, a photon gains a finite mass
partially via the chiral anomaly, leading to the strong screening effect of the
Weyl/Dirac fermions. Consequently, anisotropic type-II Dirac semimetals become
stable against the Coulomb interaction. This work provides deep insight into
the interplay between the geometry of Fermi surface and the Coulomb
interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03163</id><created>2016-09-11</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Second-order perturbation theory for 3He and pd scattering in pionless
  EFT</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>24 pages, 7 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 (2017) 064007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa60d6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work implements pionless effective field theory with the two-nucleon
system expanded around the unitarity limit at second order perturbation theory.
The expansion is found to converge well. All Coulomb effects are treated in
perturbation theory, including two-photon contributions at
next-to-next-to-leading order. After fixing a three-nucleon force to the 3He
binding energy at this order, proton-deuteron scattering in the doublet S-wave
channel is calculated for moderate center-of-mass momenta.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05075</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hood</keyname><forenames>A. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cargill</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Moortel</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new approach for modelling chromospheric evaporation in response to
  enhanced coronal heating: I The method</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 597, A81 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new computational approach that addresses the difficulty of
obtaining the correct interaction between the solar corona and the transition
region in response to rapid heating events. In the coupled corona, transition
region and chromosphere system, an enhanced downward conductive flux results in
an upflow (chromospheric evaporation). However, obtaining the correct upflow
generally requires high spatial resolution in order to resolve the transition
region. With an unresolved transition region, artificially low coronal
densities are obtained because the downward heat flux jumps across the
unresolved region to the chromosphere, underestimating the upflows. Here, we
treat the lower transition region as a discontinuity that responds to changing
coronal conditions through the imposition of a jump condition that is derived
from an integrated form of energy conservation. To illustrate and benchmark
this approach against a fully resolved one-dimensional model, we present
field-aligned simulations of coronal loops in response to a range of impulsive
(spatially uniform) heating events. We show that our approach leads to a
significant improvement in the coronal density evolution than just when using
coarse spatial resolutions insufficient to resolve the lower transition region.
Our approach compensates for the jumping of the heat flux by imposing a
velocity correction that ensures that the energy from the heat flux goes into
driving the transition region dynamics, rather than being lost through
radiation. Hence, it is possible to obtain improved coronal densities. The
advantages of using this approach in both one-dimensional hydrodynamic and
three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamic simulations are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05540</id><created>2016-09-18</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cerrito</keyname><forenames>Lucio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millar</keyname><forenames>Declan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Span&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovering and profiling Z' bosons using asymmetry observables in top
  quark pair production with the lepton-plus-jets final state at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 33 figures, 4 tables, 93 citations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensitivity of top quark pair production at the Large Hadron Collider to
the presence and nature of an underlying Z' boson is studied, accounting for
six-fermion decay with full tree-level Standard Model ttbar interference and
all intermediate particles allowed off-shell. Focus is placed on the
lepton-plus-jets final state, emulating experimental conditions, including
kinematic requirements and top quark pair reconstruction in the presence of
missing transverse energy and combinatorial ambiguity in jet-top assignment.
Considering a resonance with mass of 4 TeV, and assuming 300 inverse fb of
proton-proton collisions with a centre of mass energy of 13 TeV data, a
combination of forward-backward and top polarisation asymmetries are shown to
distinguish Z' embedded by different classes of Grand-Unified-Theory-inspired
models. In combination with the differential cross section, they may be used to
increase the significance of the signal when tested against the Standard Model,
as shown using a likelihood-based statistical test.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07403</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Warren P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kneller</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohlmann</keyname><forenames>Sebastian T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roepke</keyname><forenames>Friedrich K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholberg</keyname><forenames>Kate</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seitenzahl</keyname><forenames>Ivo R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrinos from type Ia supernovae: The gravitationally confined
  detonation scenario</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR hep-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 29 figures, 3 tables. Edited to match accepted PRD version,
  results unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 043006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.043006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite their use as cosmological distance indicators and their importance in
the chemical evolution of galaxies, the unequivocal identification of the
progenitor systems and explosion mechanism of normal type Ia supernova (SN Ia)
remains elusive. The leading hypothesis is that such a supernova is a
thermonuclear explosion of a carbon-oxygen white dwarf, but the exact explosion
mechanism is still a matter of debate. Observation of a galactic SN Ia would be
of immense value in answering the many open questions related to these events.
One potentially useful source of information about the explosion mechanism and
progenitor is the neutrino signal.
  In this paper we compute the expected neutrino signal from a gravitationally
confined detonation (GCD) explosion scenario for a SN~Ia and show how the flux
at Earth contains features in time and energy unique to this scenario. We then
calculate the expected event rates in the Super-K, Hyper-K, JUNO, DUNE, and
IceCube detectors and find both Hyper-K and IceCube would see a few events for
a GCD supernova at 1 kpc or closer, while Super-K, JUNO, and DUNE would see a
events if the supernova were closer than ${\sim}0.3$ kpc. The distance and
detector criteria needed to resolve the time and spectral features arising from
the explosion mechanism, neutrino production, and neutrino oscillation
processes are also discussed.
  The neutrino signal from the GCD is then compared with the signal from a
deflagration-to-detonation transition (DDT) explosion model computed
previously. We find the overall event rate is the most discriminating feature
between the two scenarios followed by the event rate time structure. Using the
event rate in the Hyper-K detector alone, the DDT can be distinguished from the
GCD at 2$\sigma$ if the distance to the supernova is less than $2.3\;{\rm kpc}$
for a normal mass ordering and $3.6\;{\rm kpc}$ for an inverted ordering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07838</id><created>2016-09-25</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Chu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poletti</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Solutions for dissipative quadratic open systems: part II - fermions</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1609.07249</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A, 95, 052107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second part of a work in which we show how to solve a large class
of Lindblad master equations for non-interacting particles on $L$ sites. Here
we concentrate on fermionic particles. In parallel to part I for bosons, but
with important differences, we show how to reduce the problem to diagonalizing
an $L \times L$ non-Hermitian matrix which, for boundary dissipative driving of
a uniform chain, is a tridiagonal bordered Toeplitz matrix. In this way, both
for fermionic and spin systems alike, we can obtain analytical expressions for
the normal master modes and their relaxation rates (rapidities) and we show how
to construct the non-equilibrium steady state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09301</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tavakoli</keyname><forenames>Armin</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum communication games manifest preparation contextuality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This pre-print has been replaced. Please see instead arXiv:1704.08223</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Communication games are collaborative information processing tasks involving
a number of players with limited communication. Such games are useful tools for
studying physical theories. A physical theory exhibits preparation
contextuality whenever observed behaviour cannot be explained by a preparation
noncontextual model. Here we show that there is a fundamental connection
between the performance in communication games and the degree of preparation
(non)contextuality. For this purpose, we present a general framework that
allows us to construct communication games such that the game performance
corresponds to a measure of preparation (non)contextuality. We illustrate the
power of this framework by, 1) deriving many examples of tests of preparation
contextuality, 2) showing that quantum violations of Bell inequalities can be
derived from quantum violations of preparation noncontextuality, 3)
qualitatively and quantitatively explaining related previous results on
preparation contextuality in quantum communication games, and 4) solving the
open problem of revealing the preparation contextuality of the maximally mixed
quantum state in any dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01657</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2016-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zihe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fryslie</keyname><forenames>Stewart T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>Bradley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carney</keyname><forenames>P. Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choquette</keyname><forenames>Kent D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parity-Time Symmetry in Coherently Coupled Vertical Cavity Laser Arrays</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optica, 4 (2017) 323-329</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report parity-time (PT) symmetry breaking in electrically injected,
coherently coupled, vertical cavity surface emitting laser arrays. We predict
beam steering, mode evolution and mode hopping as a consequence of the
non-Hermiticity of the array analyzed by temporal coupled mode theory with both
asymmetric gain distribution and local frequency detuning. We present
experimental confirmation of the predicted mode evolution, mode hopping and PT
symmetry breaking with quantitative agreement with the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03071</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuoco</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xe4;mer</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korsmeier</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel dark matter constraints from antiprotons in the light of AMS-02</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages + 3 of supplemental material, 7 figures, 1 tables. Matches
  version published on physical review letters</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 191102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.191102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate dark matter (DM) limits from cosmic-ray antiproton observations
using the recent precise AMS-02 measurements. We properly take into account
cosmic-ray propagation uncertainties fitting at the same time DM and
propagation parameters, and marginalizing over the latter. We find a
significant (~4.5 sigma) indication of a DM signal for DM masses near 80 GeV,
with a hadronic annihilation cross-section close to the thermal value, sigma v
~3e-26 cm3s-1. Intriguingly, this signal is compatible with the DM
interpretation of the Galactic center gamma-ray excess. Confirmation of the
signal will require a more accurate study of the systematic uncertainties,
i.e., the antiproton production cross-section, and modelling of the solar
modulation effect. Interpreting the AMS-02 data in terms of upper limits on
hadronic DM annihilation, we obtain strong constraints excluding a thermal
annihilation cross-section for DM masses below about 50 GeV and in the range
between approximately 150 and 500 GeV, even for conservative propagation
scenarios. Except for the range around 80 GeV, our limits are a factor 4
stronger than the limits from gamma-ray observations of dwarf galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03860</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>He</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray counterpart of gravitational waves due to binary neutron star
  mergers: light curves, luminosity functions, and event rate densities</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figure, accepted in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 835, 7 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/835/1/7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zhang (2013) proposed a type of GRB-less X-ray transient associated with
double neutron star (NS-NS) mergers under the conjecture of a rapidly-spinning
magnetar merger product with the line of sight off the short GRB jet. We
investigate possible light curves of these transients by considering different
observer's viewing angles. We perform Monte Carlo simulations to calculate the
peak luminosity function (LF) and event rate density of these X-ray transients.
By considering that a fraction of massive neutron stars may be supra-massive
and later collapse into black holes after spinning down, we investigate how the
predicted LF depends on the equation of state (EoS) of the central object and
the geometry of the system. In general, the LF can be fit by two log-normal
distributions peaking around $10^{46.4}$ and $10^{49.6}$ $\rm erg\,s^{-1}$,
corresponding to the trapped and free zones, respectively. For the majority of
the EoS models, the current non-detection is consistent with having a free zone
solid angle at most a few times of the solid angle of the short GRB jet. The
event rate density of these X-ray transients is around a few tens of $\rm
Gpc^{-3}yr^{-1}$ for luminosity above $10^{45}$ $\rm erg\,s^{-1}$. We predict
that future X-ray telescopes (such as Einstein Probe) with sensitivity $\sim
10^{-11}$ $\rm erg\,s^{-1}\,cm^{-2}$ would detect as many as several tens of
such transients per year per steradian. Within 200 Mpc, the aLIGO average range
for NS-NS mergers, the estimated event rate of these transients is about 1
transient per year all sky.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01189</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Steffens</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riofrio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCutcheon</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMillan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tame</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rarity</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimentally exploring compressed sensing quantum tomography</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Sci. Technol. 2, 025005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa6ae2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the light of the progress in quantum technologies, the task of verifying
the correct functioning of processes and obtaining accurate tomographic
information about quantum states becomes increasingly important. Compressed
sensing, a machinery derived from the theory of signal processing, has emerged
as a feasible tool to perform robust and significantly more resource-economical
quantum state tomography for intermediate-sized quantum systems. In this work,
we provide a comprehensive analysis of compressed sensing tomography in the
regime in which tomographically complete data is available with reliable
statistics from experimental observations of a multi-mode photonic
architecture. Due to the fact that the data is known with high statistical
significance, we are in a position to systematically explore the quality of
reconstruction depending on the number of employed measurement settings,
randomly selected from the complete set of data, and on different model
assumptions. We present and test a complete prescription to perform efficient
compressed sensing and are able to reliably use notions of model selection and
cross-validation to account for experimental imperfections and finite counting
statistics. Thus, we establish compressed sensing as an effective tool for
quantum state tomography, specifically suited for photonic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04165</id><created>2016-11-13</created><updated>2017-03-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okumura</keyname><forenames>Teppei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takada</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>More</keyname><forenames>Surhud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masaki</keyname><forenames>Shogo</forenames></author></authors><title>Reconstruction of halo power spectrum from redshift-space galaxy
  distribution: cylinder-grouping method and halo exclusion effect</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 15 figures, 2 tables, resubmitted to MNRAS after addressing
  the first referee report</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 469 (1): 459-475</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx850</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The peculiar velocity field measured by redshift-space distortions (RSD) in
galaxy surveys provides a unique probe of the growth of large-scale structure.
However, systematic effects arise when including satellite galaxies in the
clustering analysis. Since satellite galaxies tend to reside in massive halos
with a greater halo bias, the inclusion boosts the clustering power. In
addition, virial motions of the satellite galaxies cause a significant
suppression of the clustering power due to nonlinear RSD effects. We develop a
novel method to recover the redshift-space power spectrum of halos from the
observed galaxy distribution by minimizing the contamination of satellite
galaxies. The cylinder grouping method (CGM) we study effectively excludes
satellite galaxies from a galaxy sample. However, we find that this technique
produces apparent anisotropies in the reconstructed halo distribution over all
the scales which mimic RSD. On small scales, the apparent anisotropic
clustering is caused by exclusion of halos within the anisotropic cylinder used
by the CGM. On large scales, the misidentification of different halos in the
large-scale structures, aligned along the line-of-sight, into the same CGM
group, causes the apparent anisotropic clustering via their cross-correlation
with the CGM halos. We construct an empirical model for the CGM halo power
spectrum, which includes correction terms derived using the CGM window function
at small scales as well as the linear matter power spectrum multiplied by a
simple anisotropic function at large scales. We apply this model to a mock
galaxy catalog at z=0.5, designed to resemble SDSS-III BOSS CMASS galaxies, and
find that our model can predict both the monopole and quadrupole power spectra
of the host halos up to k&lt;0.5 h/Mpc to within 5%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08823</id><created>2016-11-27</created><updated>2017-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Puljiz</keyname><forenames>Mate</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>Andreas M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Forces and torques on rigid inclusions in an elastic environment:
  resulting matrix-mediated interactions, displacements, and rotations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>24 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 053002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.053002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Embedding rigid inclusions into elastic matrix materials is a procedure of
high practical relevance, for instance for the fabrication of elastic composite
materials. We theoretically analyze the following situation. Rigid spherical
inclusions are enclosed by a homogeneous elastic medium under stick boundary
conditions. Forces and torques are directly imposed from outside onto the
inclusions, or are externally induced between them. The inclusions respond to
these forces and torques by translations and rotations against the surrounding
elastic matrix. This leads to elastic matrix deformations, and in turn results
in mutual long-ranged matrix-mediated interactions between the inclusions.
Adapting a well-known approach from low-Reynolds-number hydrodynamics, we
explicitly calculate the displacements and rotations of the inclusions from the
externally imposed or induced forces and torques. Analytical expressions are
presented as a function of the inclusion configuration in terms of
displaceability and rotateability matrices. The role of the elastic environment
is implicitly included in these relations. That is, the resulting expressions
allow a calculation of the induced displacements and rotations directly from
the inclusion configuration, without having to explicitly determine the
deformations of the elastic environment. In contrast to the hydrodynamic case,
compressibility of the surrounding medium is readily taken into account. We
present the complete derivation based on the underlying equations of linear
elasticity theory. In the future, the method will, for example, be helpful to
characterize the behavior of externally tunable elastic composite materials, to
accelerate numerical approaches, as well as to improve the quantitative
interpretation of microrheological results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09373</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ginzburg</keyname><forenames>Sivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sari</keyname><forenames>Re'em</forenames></author></authors><title>Hot-Jupiter Core Mass from Roche-lobe Overflow</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Matched to published version</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 469, 278-285 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx832</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The orbits of many observed hot Jupiters are decaying rapidly due to tidal
interaction, eventually reaching the Roche limit. We analytically study the
ensuing coupled mass loss and orbital evolution during the Roche-lobe overflow
and find two possible scenarios. Planets with light cores $M_c\lesssim
6M_\oplus$ (assuming a nominal tidal dissipation factor $Q\sim 10^6$ for the
host star) are transformed into Neptune-mass gas planets, orbiting at a
separation (relative to the stellar radius) $a/R_\star\approx 3.5$. Planets
with heavier cores $M_c\gtrsim 6M_\oplus$ plunge rapidly until they are
destroyed at the stellar surface. Remnant gas-Neptunes, which are stable to
photo-evaporation, are absent from the observations, despite their unique
transit radius ($5-10R_\oplus$). This result suggests that $M_c\gtrsim
6M_\oplus$, providing a useful constraint on the poorly-known core mass that
may distinguish between different formation theories of gas giants.
Alternatively, if one assumes a prior of $M_c\approx 6 M_\oplus$ from the
core-accretion theory, our results suggest that $Q$ does not lie in the range
$10^6\lesssim Q\lesssim 10^7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02188</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pavlou</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavrommatis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moustakidis</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic Study of ${}^1{S_0}$ Superfluidity in Dilute Neutron Matter</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12297-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Singlet $S$-wave superfluidity of dilute neutron matter is studied within the
correlated BCS method, which takes into account both pairing and short-range
correlations. First, the equation of state (EOS) of normal neutron matter is
calculated within the Correlated Basis Function (CBF) method in lowest cluster
order using the ${}^1{S_0}$ and ${}^3P$ components of the Argonne $V_{18}$
potential, assuming trial Jastrow-type correlation functions. The ${}^1{S_0}$
superfluid gap is then calculated with the corresponding component of the
Argonne $V_{18}$ potential and the optimally determined correlation functions.
The dependence of our results on the chosen forms for the correlation functions
is studied, and the role of the $P$-wave channel is investigated. Where
comparison is meaningful, the values obtained for the ${}^1{S_0}$ gap within
this simplified scheme are consistent with the results of similar and more
elaborate microscopic methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05055</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barankai</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>On the positivity preservation of the free Euclidean Dirac equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, a small numerical error has been corrected, some new
  references have been added</comments><msc-class>35Q41</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the free Euclidean Dirac equation can preserve the positivity of
its initial data only in two spacetime dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06895</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nanda</keyname><forenames>Gaurav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguilera-Servin</keyname><forenames>Juan Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakyta</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korm&#xe1;nyos</keyname><forenames>Andor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleiner</keyname><forenames>Reinhold</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koelle</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandersypen</keyname><forenames>Lieven M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Srijit</forenames></author></authors><title>Current-phase relation of ballistic graphene Josephson junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Supplementary information added; some references modified</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b00097</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The current-phase relation (CPR) of a Josephson junction (JJ) determines how
the supercurrent evolves with the superconducting phase difference across the
junction. Knowledge of the CPR is essential in order to understand the response
of a JJ to various external parameters. Despite the rising interest in
ultra-clean encapsulated graphene JJs, the CPR of such junctions remains
unknown. Here, we use a fully gate-tunable graphene superconducting quantum
intereference device (SQUID) to determine the CPR of ballistic graphene JJs.
Each of the two JJs in the SQUID is made with graphene encapsulated in
hexagonal boron nitride. By independently controlling the critical current of
the JJs, we can operate the SQUID either in a symmetric or asymmetric
configuration. The highly asymmetric SQUID allows us to phase-bias one of the
JJs and thereby directly obtain its CPR. The CPR is found to be skewed,
deviating significantly from a sinusoidal form. The skewness can be tuned with
the gate voltage and oscillates in anti-phase with Fabry-P\'{e}rot resistance
oscillations of the ballistic graphene cavity. We compare our experiments with
tight-binding calculations which include realistic graphene-superconductor
interfaces and find a good qualitative agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01472</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-02-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krijtenburg-Lewerissa</keyname><forenames>Kim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pol</keyname><forenames>Henk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brinkman</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Joolingen</keyname><forenames>Wouter</forenames></author></authors><title>Insights into teaching quantum mechanics in secondary and lower
  undergraduate education</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. ST Phys. Educ. Res. 13, 010109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.13.010109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This study presents a review of the current state of research on teaching
quantum mechanics in secondary and lower undergraduate education. A conceptual
approach to quantum mechanics is being implemented in more and more
introductory physics courses around the world. Because of the differences
between the conceptual nature of quantum mechanics and classical physics,
research on misconceptions, testing, and teaching strategies for introductory
quantum mechanics is needed. For this review, 74 articles were selected and
analyzed for the misconceptions, research tools, teaching strategies and
multimedia applications investigated. Outcomes were categorized according to
their contribution to the various subtopics of quantum mechanics. Analysis
shows that students have difficulty relating quantum physics to physical
reality. It also shows that the teaching of complex quantum behavior, such as
time dependence, superposition and the measurement problem, has barely been
investigated for the secondary and lower undergraduate level. At the secondary
school level, this review shows a need to investigate student difficulties
concerning wave functions and potential wells. Investigation of research tools
shows the necessity for the development of assessment tools for secondary and
lower undergraduate education, which cover all major topics and are suitable
for statistical analysis. Furthermore, this review shows the existence of very
diverse ideas concerning teaching strategies for quantum mechanics and a lack
of research into which strategies promote understanding. This review underlines
the need for more empirical research into student difficulties, teaching
strategies, activities and research tools intended for a conceptual approach
for quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01645</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Sharing Means Renting?: An Entire-marketplace Analysis of Airbnb</title><categories>cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>WebSci '17</comments><doi>10.1145/3091478.3091504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Airbnb, an online marketplace for accommodations, has experienced a
staggering growth accompanied by intense debates and scattered regulations
around the world. Current discourses, however, are largely focused on opinions
rather than empirical evidences. Here, we aim to bridge this gap by presenting
the first large-scale measurement study on Airbnb, using a crawled data set
containing 2.3 million listings, 1.3 million hosts, and 19.3 million reviews.
We measure several key characteristics at the heart of the ongoing debate and
the sharing economy. Among others, we find that Airbnb has reached a global yet
heterogeneous coverage. The majority of its listings across many countries are
entire homes, suggesting that Airbnb is actually more like a rental marketplace
rather than a spare-room sharing platform. Analysis on star-ratings reveals
that there is a bias toward positive ratings, amplified by a bias toward using
positive words in reviews. The extent of such bias is greater than Yelp
reviews, which were already shown to exhibit a positive bias. We investigate a
key issue---commercial hosts who own multiple listings on Airbnb---repeatedly
discussed in the current debate. We find that their existence is prevalent,
they are early-movers towards joining Airbnb, and their listings are
disproportionately entire homes and located in the US. Our work advances the
current understanding of how Airbnb is being used and may serve as an
independent and empirical reference to inform the debate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01776</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01776</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Korosec</keyname><forenames>Chapin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forde</keyname><forenames>Nancy R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Engineering Nanoscale Biological Molecular Motors</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.BM q-bio.SC</categories><comments>To be published in &quot;Physics in Canada&quot;, vol. 73, issue 2 (2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the operation of biological molecular motors, nanoscale
machines that transduce electrochemical energy into mechanical work, is
enhanced by bottom-up strategies to synthesize novel motors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02022</id><created>2017-01-08</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Mechanical stability of the CMS strip tracker measured with a laser
  alignment system</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/TRK-15-002</comments><report-no>CMS-TRK-15-002, CERN-EP-2016-320</report-no><journal-ref>JINST 12 (2017) P04023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/12/04/P04023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CMS tracker consists of 206 square meters of silicon strip sensors
assembled on carbon fibre composite structures and is designed for operation in
the temperature range from -25 to +25 degrees C. The mechanical stability of
tracker components during physics operation was monitored with a few micron
resolution using a dedicated laser alignment system as well as particle tracks
from cosmic rays and hadron-hadron collisions. During the LHC operational
period of 2011-2013 at stable temperatures, the components of the tracker were
observed to experience relative movements of less than 30 microns. In addition,
temperature variations were found to cause displacements of tracker structures
of about 2 microns/degree C, which largely revert to their initial positions
when the temperature is restored to its original value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02928</id><created>2017-01-11</created><updated>2017-04-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Shibdas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berry</keyname><forenames>Dominic W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>Ian R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huntington</keyname><forenames>Elanor H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust Guaranteed-Cost Adaptive Quantum Phase Estimation</title><categories>quant-ph cs.SY math.OC</categories><comments>Minor corrections; 18 pages, 9 figures, 5 appendices</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 052322 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052322</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum parameter estimation plays a key role in many fields like quantum
computation, communication and metrology. Optimal estimation allows one to
achieve the most precise parameter estimates, but requires accurate knowledge
of the model. Any inevitable uncertainty in the model parameters may heavily
degrade the quality of the estimate. It is therefore desired to make the
estimation process robust to such uncertainties. Robust estimation was
previously studied for a varying phase, where the goal was to estimate the
phase at some time in the past, using the measurement results from both before
and after that time within a fixed time interval up to current time. Here, we
consider a robust guaranteed-cost filter yielding robust estimates of a varying
phase in real time, where the current phase is estimated using only past
measurements. Our filter minimizes the largest (worst-case) variance in the
allowable range of the uncertain model parameter(s) and this determines its
guaranteed cost. It outperforms in the worst case the optimal Kalman filter
designed for the model with no uncertainty, that corresponds to the center of
the possible range of the uncertain parameter(s). Moreover, unlike the Kalman
filter, our filter in the worst case always performs better than the best
achievable variance for heterodyne measurements, that we consider as the
tolerable threshold for our system. Furthermore, we consider effective quantum
efficiency and effective noise power, and show that our filter provides the
best results by these measures in the worst case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05416</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of uniaxial single-ion anisotropy on the magnetic and thermal
  properties of Heisenberg antiferromagnets within unified molecular field
  theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>41 pages, 41 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 094421 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.094421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of uniaxial single-ion anisotropy -DSz^2 on the magnetic and
thermal properties of Heisenberg antiferromagnets (AFMs) is investigated. The
uniaxial anisotropy is treated exactly and the Heisenberg interactions are
treated within unified molecular field theory (MFT) [Phys. Rev. B 91, 064427
(1915)], where thermodynamic variables are expressed in terms of directly
measurable parameters. The properties of collinear AFMs with ordering along the
z axis (D &gt; 0) in applied fields Hz = 0 are calculated versus D and temperature
T. The high-field average magnetization per spin muz(Hz,D,T) is found, and the
critical field Hc(D,T) is derived at which the second-order AFM to PM phase
transition occurs. The magnetic properties of the spin-flop (SF) phase are
calculated, including the zero-field properties TN(D) and mu(D,T). The
high-field muz(Hz,D,T) is determined, together with the associated spin-flop
field HSF(D,T) at which a second-order SF to PM phase transition occurs. The
free energies of the AFM, SF and PM phases are derived from which Hz-T phase
diagrams are constructed. For a certain combination of parameters we find a
topologically distinct phase diagram where a spin-flop bubble occurs at finite
Hz and T. Also calculated are properties arising from a perpendicular magnetic
field. In addition to the above results for D &gt; 0, some properties with D &lt; 0
are determined. In order to compare the properties of the above spin systems
with those of noninteracting systems with DSz^2 uniaxial anisotropy with either
sign of D, an Appendix is included in which results for the thermal and
magnetic properties of such noninteracting spin systems are provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05434</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kroon</keyname><forenames>Juan A. Valiente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Jarrod L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dain's invariant on non-time symmetric initial data sets</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend Dain's construction of a geometric invariant characterising static
initial data sets for the vacuum Einstein field equations to situations with a
non-vanishing extrinsic curvature. This invariant gives a measure of how much
the initial data sets deviates from stationarity. In particular, it vanishes if
and only if the initial data set is stationary. Thus, the invariant provides a
quantification of the amount of gravitational radiation contained in the
initial data set.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06542</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bastianello</keyname><forenames>Alvise</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Luca</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mussardo</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Non Relativistic Limit of Integrable QFT with fermionic excitations</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys A 50 234002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6f69</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to investigate the non-relativistic limit of
integrable quantum field theories with fermionic fields, such as the O(N)
Gross-Neveu model, the supersymmetric Sinh-Gordon and non-linear sigma models.
The non-relativistic limit of these theories is implemented by a double scaling
limit which consists of sending the speed of light c to infinity and rescaling
at the same time the relevant coupling constant of the model in such a way to
have finite energy excitations. For the general purpose of mapping the space of
continuous non-relativistic integrable models, this paper completes and
integrates the analysis done in Ref.[1] on the non-relativistic limit of purely
bosonic theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07220</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lhotel</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ressouche</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damay</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirebeau</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ollivier</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mutka</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de R&#xe9;otier</keyname><forenames>P. Dalmas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yaouanc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marin</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decorse</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petit</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Field induced phase diagram of the XY pyrochlore antiferromagnet
  Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134426 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the field-temperature phase diagram of the XY pyrochlore
antiferromagnet Er$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$, by means of magnetization and neutron
diffraction experiments. Depending on the field strength and direction relative
to the high symmetry cubic directions $[001], [1\bar{1}0]$ and $[111]$, the
refined field induced magnetic structures are derived from the zero field
$\psi_2$ and $\psi_3$ states of the $\Gamma_5$ irreducible representation which
describes the ground state of XY pyrochlore antiferromagnets. At low field,
domain selection effects are systematically at play. In addition, for $[001]$,
a phase transition is reported towards a $\psi_3$ structure at a characteristic
field $H_c^{001}=$ 43 mT. For $[1\bar{1}0]$ and $[111]$, the spins are
continuously tilted by the field from the $\psi_2$ state, and no phase
transition is found while domain selection gives rise to sharp anomalies in the
field dependence of the Bragg peaks intensity. For $[1\bar{1}0]$, these results
are confirmed by high resolution inelastic neutron scattering experiments,
which in addition allow us to determine the field dependence of the spin gap.
This study agrees qualitatively with the scenario proposed theoretically by
Maryasin {\it et al.} [Phys. Rev. B {\bf 93}, 100406(R) (2016)], yet the
strength of the field induced anisotropies is significantly different from
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07409</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for single production of vector-like quarks decaying to a Z boson
  and a top or a bottom quark in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 13 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/B2G-16-001</comments><report-no>CMS-B2G-16-001, CERN-EP-2016-326</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 05 (2017) 029</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search for single production of vector-like quarks, T and B, decaying into
a Z boson and a top or a bottom quark, respectively, is presented. The search
is performed using data collected by the CMS experiment at the LHC in
proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 13 TeV, corresponding to an integrated
luminosity of 2.3 inverse femtobarns. An exotic T quark production mode through
the decay of a heavy Z' resonance is also considered. The search is performed
in events with a Z boson decaying leptonically, accompanied by a bottom or a
top quark decaying hadronically. No excess of events is observed over the
standard model background expectation. Products of production cross section and
branching fraction for T and B quarks from 1.26 and 0.13 pb are excluded at 95%
confidence level for the range of resonance mass considered, which is between
0.7 and 1.7 TeV. Limits on the product of the Z' boson production cross section
and branching fraction, with the Z' boson decaying to the Tt final state, are
set between 0.31 and 0.13 pb, for Z' boson masses in the range from 1.5 to 2.5
TeV. This is the first search at 13 TeV for single production of vector-like
quarks in events with a Z boson decaying leptonically accompanied by boosted
jets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08245</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-04-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Jian-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xing-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Bo-Lun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodsky</keyname><forenames>Stanley J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel All-Orders Single-Scale Approach to QCD Renormalization
  Scale-Setting</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures. Discussions improved and references updated. To
  be published in Phys.Rev.D</comments><report-no>SLAC-PUB-16917</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 094006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.094006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Principle of Maximal Conformality (PMC) provides a rigorous method for
eliminating renormalization scheme-and-scale ambiguities for perturbative QCD
predictions. The PMC uses the renormalization group equation to fix the
$\beta$-pattern of each order in an arbitrary pQCD approximant, and it then
determines the optimal renormalization scale by absorbing all $\{\beta_{i}\}$
terms into the running coupling at each order. The resulting coefficients of
the pQCD series match the scheme-independent conformal series with $\beta=0$.
As in QED, different renormalization scales appear at each order; we call this
the multi-scale approach. In this paper, we present a novel single-scale
approach for the PMC, in which a single effective scale is constructed to
eliminate all non-conformal $\beta$-terms up to a given order simultaneously.
The PMC single-scale approach inherits the main features of the multi-scale
approach; for example, its predictions are scheme-independent, and the pQCD
convergence is greatly improved due to the elimination of divergent renormalon
terms. As an application of the single-scale approach, we investigate the
$e^+e^-$ annihilation cross-section ratio $R_{e^+e^-}$ and the Higgs
decay-width $\Gamma(H \to b \bar{b})$, including four-loop QCD contributions.
The resulting predictions are nearly identical to the multi-scale predictions
for both the total and differential contributions. Thus in many cases, the PMC
single-scale approach PMC-s, which requires a simpler analysis, could be
adopted as a reliable substitution for the PMC multi-scale approach for setting
the renormalization scale for high-energy processes, particularly when one does
not need detailed information at each order. The elimination of the
renormalization scale uncertainty increases the precision of tests of the
Standard Model at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08410</id><created>2017-01-29</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wykes</keyname><forenames>Megan S. Davies</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tong</keyname><forenames>Jiajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>Takuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yanpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ristroph</keyname><forenames>Leif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>Michael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelley</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Guiding microscale swimmers using teardrop-shaped posts</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1039/C7SM00203C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The swimming direction of biological or artificial microscale swimmers tends
to be randomised over long time-scales by thermal fluctuations. Bacteria use
various strategies to bias swimming behaviour and achieve directed motion
against a flow, maintain alignment with gravity or travel up a chemical
gradient. Herein, we explore a purely geometric means of biasing the motion of
artificial nanorod swimmers. These artificial swimmers are bimetallic rods,
powered by a chemical fuel, which swim on a substrate printed with
teardrop-shaped posts. The artificial swimmers are hydrodynamically attracted
to the posts, swimming alongside the post perimeter for long times before
leaving. The rods experience a higher rate of departure from the higher
curvature end of the teardrop shape, thereby introducing a bias into their
motion. This bias increases with swimming speed and can be translated into a
macroscopic directional motion over long times by using arrays of
teardrop-shaped posts aligned along a single direction. This method provides a
protocol for concentrating swimmers, sorting swimmers according to different
speeds, and could enable artificial swimmers to transport cargo to desired
locations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.09113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.09113</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takemura</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navadeh-Toupchi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberli</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portella-Oberli</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deveaud</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin anisotropic interactions of lower-polaritons in the vicinity of
  polaritonic Feshbach resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine experimentally the spinor interaction constants of
lower-polaritons $\alpha_1$ and $\alpha_2$ using resonant pump-probe
spectroscopy with a spectrally narrow pump pulse. Our experimental findings are
analyzed with the Bogoliubov-like theory and mean-field two channel model based
on the lower-polariton and biexciton basis. We find an enhancement of the
attractive interaction and dissipative nonlinearity of lower-polaritons with
anti-parallel spins in the vicinity of the biexciton resonance when the energy
of two lower-polaritons approaches energetically that of the biexciton. These
observations are consistent with the existence of a scattering resonance
between lower-polaritons and biexcitons (polaritonic Feshbach resonance).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00443</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staveley-Smith</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailes</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jameson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Straten</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schediwy</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>HIPSR: A Digital Signal Processor for the Parkes 21-cm Multibeam
  Receiver</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><journal-ref>J. Astron. Instrum. 05, 1641007 (2016) [11 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S2251171716410075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  HIPSR (HI-Pulsar) is a digital signal processing system for the Parkes 21-cm
Multibeam Receiver that provides larger instantaneous bandwidth, increased
dynamic range, and more signal processing power than the previous systems in
use at Parkes. The additional computational capacity enables finer spectral
resolution in wideband HI observations and real-time detection of Fast Radio
Bursts during pulsar surveys. HIPSR uses a heterogeneous architecture,
consisting of FPGA-based signal processing boards connected via high-speed
Ethernet to high performance compute nodes. Low-level signal processing is
conducted on the FPGA-based boards, and more complex signal processing routines
are conducted on the GPU-based compute nodes. The development of HIPSR was
driven by two main science goals: to provide large bandwidth, high-resolution
spectra suitable for 21-cm stacking and intensity mapping experiments; and to
upgrade the Berkeley-Parkes-Swinburne Recorder (BPSR), the signal processing
system used for the High Time Resolution Universe (HTRU) Survey and the Survey
for Pulsars and Extragalactic Radio Bursts (SUPERB).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01064</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rohwer</keyname><forenames>Christian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambassi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Viscosity of a sheared correlated (near-critical) model fluid in
  confinement</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures. Title modified and minor typos fixed from
  previous version</comments><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa6e75</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Second-order phase transitions are characterized by a divergence of the
spatial correlation length of the order parameter fluctuations. For confined
systems, this is known to lead to remarkable equilibrium physical phenomena,
including finite-size effects and critical Casimir forces. We explore here some
non-equilibrium aspects of these effects in the stationary state resulting from
the action of external forces: by analyzing a model of a correlated fluid under
shear, spatially confined by two parallel plates, we study the resulting
viscosity within the setting of (Gaussian) Landau-Ginzburg theory.
Specifically, we introduce a model in which the hydrodynamic velocity field
(obeying the Stokes equation) is coupled to an order parameter with dissipative
dynamics. The well-known Green-Kubo relation for bulk systems is generalized
for confined systems. This is shown to result in a non-local Stokes equation
for the fluid flow, due to the correlated fluctuations. The resulting effective
shear viscosity shows universal as well as non-universal contributions, which
we study in detail. In particular, the deviation from the bulk behavior is
universal, depending on the ratio of the correlation length and the film
thickness $L$. In addition, at the critical point the viscosity is proportional
to $\ell/L$, where $\ell$ is a dynamic length scale. These findings are
expected to be experimentally observable, especially for systems where the bulk
viscosity is affected by critical fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04107</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Noguchi</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fournier</keyname><forenames>Jean-Baptiste</forenames></author></authors><title>Membrane structure formation induced by two types of banana-shaped
  proteins</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The assembly of banana-shaped rodlike proteins on membranes, and the
associated membrane shape transformations, are investigated by analytical
theory and coarse-grained simulations. The membrane-mediated interactions
between two banana-shaped inclusions are derived theoretically using a
point-like formalism based on fixed anisotropic curvatures, both for zero
surface tension and for finite surface tension. On a larger scale, the
interactions between assemblies of such rodlike inclusions are determined
analytically. Meshless membrane simulations are performed in the presence of a
large number of inclusions of two types, corresponding to curved rods of
opposite curvatures, both for flat membranes and vesicles. Rods of the same
type aggregate into linear assemblies perpendicular to the rod axis, leading to
membrane tubulation. However, rods of the other type, those of opposite
curvature, are attracted to the lateral sides of these assemblies, and
stabilize a straight bump structure that prevents tubulation. When the two
types of rods have almost opposite curvatures, the bumps attract one another,
forming a stripe structure. Positive surface tension is found to stabilize the
stripe formation. The simulation results agree well with the theoretical
predictions provided the point-like curvatures of the model are scaled-down to
account for the effective flexibility of the simulated rods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04365</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Melott</keyname><forenames>A. L</forenames><affiliation>Kansas</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kachelriess</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semikoz</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Overholt</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A supernova at 50 pc: Effects on the Earth's atmosphere and biota</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR physics.geo-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>5 figures. Revised version to be published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 840 105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6c57</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent 60Fe results have suggested that the estimated distances of supernovae
in the last few million years should be reduced from 100 pc to 50 pc. Two
events or series of events are suggested, one about 2.7 million years to 1.7
million years ago, and another may at 6.5 to 8.7 million years ago. We ask what
effects such supernovae are expected to have on the terrestrial atmosphere and
biota. Assuming that the Local Bubble was formed before the event being
considered, and that the supernova and the Earth were both inside a weak,
disordered magnetic field at that time, TeV-PeV cosmic rays at Earth will
increase by a factor of a few hundred. Tropospheric ionization will increase
proportionately, and the overall muon radiation load on terrestrial organisms
will increase by a factor of 150. All return to pre-burst levels within 10kyr.
In the case of an ordered magnetic field, effects depend strongly on the field
orientation. The upper bound in this case is with a largely coherent field
aligned along the line of sight to the supernova, in which case TeV-PeV cosmic
ray flux increases are 10^4; in the case of a transverse field they are below
current levels. We suggest a substantial increase in the extended effects of
supernovae on Earth and in the lethal distance estimate; more work is
needed.This paper is an explicit followup to Thomas et al. (2016). We also here
provide more detail on the computational procedures used in both works.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05020</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LLorca</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiscale modelling of the morphology and spatial distribution of
  {\theta}' precipitates in Al-Cu alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Acta Materialia, 132, 611-626, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.04.042</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  A multiscale approach based on the phase-field model is developed to simulate
homogeneous and heterogeneous formation of {\theta}' precipitates during high
temperature ageing in Al-Cu alloys. The model parameters that determine the
different energy contributions (chemical free energy, interfacial energy,
lattice parameters, elastic constants) were obtained from either computational
thermodynamics databases or from first-principles density functional theory and
molecular statics simulations. From the information, the evolution and
equilibrium morphology of the {\theta}' precipitates is simulated in 3D using
the phase-field model. The model was able to reproduce the evolution of the
different orientation variants of plate-like shaped {\theta}' precipitates with
orientation relationship (001){\theta}'//(001){\alpha} and
[100]{\theta}'//[100]{\alpha} during homogeneous nucleation as well as the
heterogeneous nucleation on dislocations, leading to the formation of
precipitate arrays. Heterogeneous nucleation on pre-existing dislocation(s) was
triggered by the interaction energy between the dislocation stress field and
the stress-free transformation strain associated to the nucleation of the
{\theta}' precipitates. Moreover, the mechanisms controlling the evolution of
the morphology and the equilibrium aspect ratio of the precipitates were
ascertained. All the predictions of the multiscale model were in good agreement
with experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08788</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wulff</keyname><forenames>Linus</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrability of the superstring in AdS(3) x S(2) x S(2) x T(3)</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure; v3: Minor clarifications, matches published
  version</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa70b5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type II supergravity admits an AdS(3) x S(2) x S(2) x T(3) solution with
fluxes depending on several free parameters. We determine the constraints on
these parameters imposed by the requirement of (classical) integrability of the
superstring sigma model. To do this we analyze the low-energy effective action
for the spinning GKP string. The absence of particle production in the
tree-level S-matrix of bosonic excitations is shown to imply the vanishing of
two of the four parameters in the NSNS three-form flux. This reduces the
supergravity background to either the one-parameter AdS(3) x S(2) x S(2) x T(3)
background preserving eight supersymmetries, or a non-supersymmetric branch,
which differs only by flipping a sign in the RR flux. We show that both these
branches can be obtained from AdS(3) x S(3) x S(3) x S(1) by T-dualities on the
(Hopf) circle fibers of the three-spheres and therefore the integrability of
the string in these backgrounds follows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01433</id><created>2017-03-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Fattoyev</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horowitz</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuetrumpf</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Nuclear Pasta and Nuclear Symmetry Energy</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.SR nucl-ex physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 18 figures, 8 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 055804 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.055804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex and exotic nuclear geometries are expected to appear naturally in
dense nuclear matter found in the crust of neutron stars and supernovae
environment collectively referred to as nuclear pasta. The pasta geometries
depend on the average baryon density, proton fraction and temperature and are
critically important in the determination of many transport properties of
matter in supernovae and the crust of neutron stars. Using a set of
self-consistent microscopic nuclear energy density functionals we present the
first results of large scale quantum simulations of pasta phases at baryon
densities $0.03 \leq \rho \leq 0.10$ fm$^{-3}$, proton fractions $0.05 \leq Y_p
\leq 0.40$, and zero temperature. The full quantum simulations, in particular,
allow us to thoroughly investigate the role and impact of the nuclear symmetry
energy on pasta configurations. We use the Sky3D code that solves the Skyrme
Hartree-Fock equations on a three-dimensional Cartesian grid. For the nuclear
interaction we use the state of the art UNEDF1 parametrization, which was
introduced to study largely deformed nuclei, hence is suitable for studies of
the nuclear pasta. Density dependence of the nuclear symmetry energy is
simulated by tuning two purely isovector observables that are insensitive to
the current available experimental data. We find that a minimum total number of
nucleons $A=2000$ is necessary to prevent the results from containing spurious
shell effects and to minimize finite size effects. We find that a variety of
nuclear pasta geometries are present in the neutron star crust and the result
strongly depends on the nuclear symmetry energy. The impact of the nuclear
symmetry energy is less pronounced as the proton fractions increase. Quantum
nuclear pasta calculations at $T=0$ MeV are shown to get easily trapped in
meta-stable states, and possible remedies to avoid meta-stable solutions are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02505</id><created>2017-03-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Cadoni</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames></author><author><keyname>jain</keyname><forenames>Parul</forenames></author></authors><title>How is the Presence of Horizons and Localized Matter Encoded in the
  Entanglement Entropy?</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A, Vol. 32 (2017) 1750083</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X1750083X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the new theoretical paradigm that views spacetime geometry as
emerging from the entanglement of a pre-geometric theory, we investigate the
issue of the signature of the presence of horizons and localized matter on the
entanglement entropy (EE) S_E for the case of three-dimensional AdS (AdS_3)
gravity. We use the holographically dual two-dimensional CFT on the torus and
the related modular symmetry in order to treat bulk black holes and conical
singularities (sourced by pointlike masses not shielded by horizons) on the
same footing. In the regime where boundary tori can be approximated by
cylinders we are able to give universal expressions for the EE of black holes
and conical singularities. We argue that the presence of horizons/localized
matter in the bulk is encoded in the EE in terms of (i) enhancement/reduction
of the entanglement of the AdS_3 vacuum, (ii) scaling as area/volume of the
leading term of the perturbative expansion of S_E, (iii) exponential/periodic
behaviour of S_E, (iv) presence of unaccessible regions in the
noncompact/compact dimension of the boundary cylinder. In particular, we show
that the reduction effect of matter on the entanglement of the vacuum found by
Verlinde for the de Sitter vacuum extends to the AdS_3 vacuum
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04312</id><created>2017-04-13</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrier</keyname><forenames>Meydi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arakawa</keyname><forenames>Tomonori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hata</keyname><forenames>Tokuro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delagrange</keyname><forenames>Rapha&#xeb;lle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deblock</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teratani</keyname><forenames>Yoshimichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakano</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oguri</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Kensuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Fluctuations along Symmetry Crossover in Kondo-correlated
  Quantum Dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 196803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.196803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Universal properties of entangled many-body states are controlled by their
symmetry and quantum fluctuations. By magnetic-field tuning of the spin-orbital
degeneracy in a Kondo-correlated quantum dot, we have modified quantum
fluctuations to directly measure their influence on the many-body properties
along the crossover from $SU(4)$ to $SU(2)$ symmetry of the ground state.
High-sensitive current noise measurements combined with the non-equilibrium
Fermi liquid theory clarify that the Kondo resonance and electron correlations
are enhanced as the fluctuations, measured by the Wilson ratio, increase along
the symmetry crossover. Our achievement demonstrates that non-linear noise
constitutes a measure of quantum fluctuations that can be used to tackle
quantum phase transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05154</id><created>2017-04-17</created><updated>2017-05-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zai-Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elbadawi</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Toan Trong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kianinia</keyname><forenames>Mehran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Timothy B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edgar</keyname><forenames>James H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toth</keyname><forenames>Milos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharonovich</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic Engineering of Single Photon Sources in 2D Boron Nitride Zai-Quan</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>manuscript will be updated later</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Artificial atomic systems in solids such as single photon emitters are
becoming increasingly important building blocks in quantum information
processing and scalable quantum nanophotonic networks. Here, we report on a
controllable way to engineer emitters in two-dimensional (2D) hexagonal boron
nitride (hBN) crystals using plasma processing. The method is robust, and
yields a 7-fold increase in the density of emitters in hBN, which is promising
for their deployment in practical devices. While as-fabricated emitters suffer
from blinking and bleaching, a subsequent annealing step yields photo-stable
emitters. The presented process is the first step towards controllable
placement of quantum emitters in hBN for integrated on-chip quantum
nanophotonics based on 2D materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06013</id><created>2017-04-20</created><updated>2017-05-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Toru</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferrimagnetism in the Spin-1/2 Heisenberg Antiferromagnet on a Distorted
  Triangular Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5pages, 5figures, to be published in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 063702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.063702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ground state of the spin-$1/2$ Heisenberg antiferromagnet on a distorted
triangular lattice is studied using a numerical-diagonalization method. The
network of interactions is the $\sqrt{3}\times\sqrt{3}$ type; the interactions
are continuously controlled between the undistorted triangular lattice and the
dice lattice. We find new states between the nonmagnetic 120-degree-structured
state of the undistorted triangular case and the up-up-down state of the dice
case. The intermediate states show spontaneous magnetizations that are smaller
than one third of the saturated magntization corresponding to the up-up-down
state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08436</id><created>2017-04-27</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoneda</keyname><forenames>Tsuyoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathematical analysis of pulsatile flow, vortex breakdown and
  instantaneous blow-up for the axisymmetric Euler equations</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1610.09099</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics along the particle trajectories for the 3D axisymmetric Euler
equations are considered. It is shown that if the inflow is rapidly increasing
(pushy) in time, the corresponding laminar profile of the incompressible Euler
flow is not (in some sense) stable provided that the swirling component is not
zero. It is also shown that if the vorticity on the axis is not zero (with some
extra assumptions), then there is no steady flow. We can rephrase these
instability to an instantaneous blow-up. In the proof, Frenet-Serret formulas
and orthonormal moving frame are essentially used.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00897</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chuprikov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunneling time and superposition principle</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figs. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1005.1323; first two sections rewritten</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that scattering a quantum particle on a one-dimensional potential
barrier as well as scattering the electromagnetic wave on a
quasi-one-dimensional layered structure (both represent scattering problems
with one 'source' and two 'sinks') violate the superposition principle; the
role of nonlinear elements is played here by the potential barrier and the
layered structure, splitting the incident (probability and electromagnetic)
wave into two parts (transmitted and reflected). This explains why all attempts
to solve the tunneling time problem within the framework of the standard
(linear) models of these processes, both in quantum mechanics and in classical
electrodynamics, have been unsuccessful. We revise the traditional formulation
of the superposition principle, present a new (nonlinear) wave model, by the
example of the quantum-mechanical scattering process, and show that concepts of
the tunneling time developed on its basis are free from the Hartman paradox.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03075</id><created>2017-05-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiltsev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Fermilab Proton Accelerator Complex Status and Improvement Plans</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>11 pp</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Pub-17-129-APC</report-no><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 16 (2017) 1730012</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317300129</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Fermilab carries out an extensive program of accelerator-based high energy
particle physics research at the Intensity Frontier that relies on the
operation of 8 GeV and 120 GeV proton beamlines for a number of fixed target
experiments. Routine operation with a world-record 700kW of average 120 GeV
beam power on the neutrino target was achieved in 2017 as the result of the
Proton Improvement Plan (PIP) upgrade. There are plans to further increase the
power to 900 - 1000 kW. The next major upgrade of the FNAL accelerator complex,
called PIP-II, is under development. It aims at 1.2MW beam power on target at
the start of the LBNF/DUNE experiment in the middle of the next decade and
assumes replacement of the existing 40-years old 400 MeV normal-conducting
Linac with a modern 800 MeV superconducting RF linear accelerator. There are
several concepts to further double the beam power to &gt;2.4MW after replacement
of the existing 8 GeV Booster synchrotron. In this article we discuss current
performance of the Fermilab proton accelerator complex, the upgrade plans for
the next two decades and the accelerator R&amp;D program to address cost and
performance risks for these upgrades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03882</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Erol</keyname><forenames>Volkan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Correlations and Bell Inequality Violation under Decoherence</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1411.3208 by other authors without attribution, note from author:
  citation added for arXiv:1411.3208 in v2</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum Correlations are studied extensively in quantum information domain.
Entanglement Measures and Quantum Discord are good examples of these actively
studied correlations. Detection of violation in Bell inequalities is also a
widely active area in quantum information theory world. In this work, we
revisit the problem of analyzing the behavior of quantum correlations and
violation of Bell inequalities in noisy channels. We extend the problem defined
in [1] by observing the changes in negativity measure, quantum discord and a
modified version of Horodecki measure for violation of Bell inequalities under
amplitude damping, phase damping and depolarizing channels. We report different
interesting results for each of these correlations and measures. All these
correlations and measures decrease under decoherence channels, but some changes
are very dramatical comparing to others. We investigate also separability
conditions of example studied states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04319</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhukov</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedotov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouffanais</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous slowing down of individual human activity due to successive
  decision-making processes</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by a host of empirical evidences revealing the bursty character of
human dynamics, we develop a model of human activity based on successive
switching between an hesitation state and a decision-realization state, with
residency times in the hesitation state distributed according to a heavy-tailed
Pareto distribution. This model is particularly reminiscent of an individual
strolling through a randomly distributed human crowd. Using a stochastic model
based on the concept of anomalous and non-Markovian L\'evy walk, we show
exactly that successive decision-making processes drastically slow down the
progression of an individual faced with randomly distributed obstacles.
Specifically, we prove exactly that the average displacement exhibits a
sublinear scaling with time that finds its origins in: (i) the intrinsically
non-Markovian character of human activity, and (ii) the power law distribution
of hesitation times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04330</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Coimbra</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minasian</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author></authors><title>M-theoretic Lichnerowicz formula and supersymmetry</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A suitable generalisation of the Lichnerowicz formula can relate the squares
of supersymmetric operators to the effective action, the Bianchi identities for
fluxes, and some equations of motion. Recently, such formulae have also been
shown to underlie the (generalised) geometry of supersymmetric theories. In
this paper, we derive an M-theoretic Lichnerowicz formula that describes
eleven-dimensional supergravity together with its higher-derivative couplings.
The first corrections to the action appear at eight-derivative level, and the
construction yields two different supersymmetric invariants, each with a free
coefficient. We discuss the restriction of our construction to
seven-dimensional internal spaces, and implications for compactifications on
manifolds of $G_2$ holonomy. Inclusion of fluxes and computation of
contributions with higher than eight derivatives are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04331</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Licitra</keyname><forenames>Rossella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Simona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raichoor</keyname><forenames>Anand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erben</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hildebrandt</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author></authors><title>The RedGOLD Cluster Detection Algorithm and its Cluster Candidate
  Catalogue for the CFHT-LS W1</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Licitra et al. 2016, MNRAS, 455, 3020 Our catalogs are planned to be
  available on ADS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  RedGOLD searches for red-sequence galaxy overdensities while minimizing
contamination from dusty star-forming galaxies. It imposes an NFW profile and
calculates cluster detection significance and richness. We optimize these
latter two parameters using both simulations and X-ray detected cluster
catalogs, and obtain a catalog $\sim 80\%$ pure up to $z \sim 1$, and $\sim
100\%$ ($\sim 70\%$) complete at $z\le 0.6$ ( $z\lesssim1$) for galaxy clusters
with $M \gtrsim 10^{14}\ {\rm M_{\odot}}$ at the CFHT-LS Wide depth. In the
CFHT-LS W1, we detect 11 cluster candidates per $\rm deg^2$ out to $z\sim1.1$.
When we optimize both completeness and purity, RedGOLD obtains a cluster
catalog with higher completeness and purity than other public catalogs,
obtained using CFHT-LS W1 observations, for $M \gtrsim 10^{14}\ {\rm
M_{\odot}}$. We use X-ray detected cluster samples to extend the study of the
X-ray temperature-optical richness relation to a lower mass threshold, and find
a mass scatter at fixed richness of $\sigma_{lnM|\lambda}=0.39\pm0.07$ and
$\sigma_{lnM|\lambda}=0.30\pm0.13$ for the Gozaliasl et al. (2014) and Mehrtens
et al. (2012) samples. When considering similar mass ranges as previous work,
we recover a smaller scatter in mass at fixed richness. We recover $93\%$ of
the redMaPPer detections, and find that its richness estimates is on average
$\sim 40-50\%$ larger than ours at $z&gt;0.3$. RedGOLD recovers X-ray cluster
spectroscopic redshifts at better than $5\%$ up to $z\sim1$, and the centers
within a few tens of arcseconds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04348</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Kloosterman Sums from M2-branes</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kloosterman sums play a special role in analytic number theory, for
expressing the integer Fourier coefficients of modular forms as an infinite sum
of Bessel functions, also known as Rademacher formula. The generalization to
vector-valued modular forms is known as generalized Kloosterman sums. In the
paper arxiv:1404.0033, a remarkable connection between these arithmetic sums
and quantum black hole entropy was found. Nevertheless, the computation was
particular for one-eighth BPS black holes in $\mathcal{N}=8$ string theory,
which have a simple counting formula. Here, we review this construction and
extend it to the case of one-quarter BPS black holes in $\mathcal{N}=4$ string
theory, which are counted by (mock) Jacobi forms of arbitrary index. The main
result is an holographic derivation of the Kloosterman sums which includes the
intricate sum over phases and depends exactly on the spectral flow sectors and
the spectrum of polar states. On the microscopic side we derive an analytic
formula for the Kloosterman sums valid for any index, whereas from the
macroscopic side we reproduce the same formula from the M-theory path integral
on $\mathbb{Z}_c$ orbifolds of $AdS_2\times S^1$. A key aspect of the
derivation is the identification of the spectral flow sectors with the
contribution of M2 branes wrapping cycles on the compactification manifold.
After a careful treatment of the measure, the sum over orbifolds results in the
sum over Bessels, in perfect agreement with the Rademacher expansion at any
order in perturbation theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04354</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wakeford</keyname><forenames>Hannah R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sing</keyname><forenames>David K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataria</keyname><forenames>Tiffany</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deming</keyname><forenames>Drake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>Eric D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremblin</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amundsen</keyname><forenames>David S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Nikole K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandell</keyname><forenames>Avi M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortney</keyname><forenames>Jonathan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>Heather</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benneke</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author></authors><title>HAT-P-26b: A Neptune-Mass Exoplanet with a Well Constrained Heavy
  Element Abundance</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in Science - Report: 13 pages (preprint), 3 figures, 1
  table - Supplementary material: 14 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1126/science.aah4668</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A correlation between giant-planet mass and atmospheric heavy elemental
abundance was first noted in the past century from observations of planets in
our own Solar System, and has served as a cornerstone of planet formation
theory. Using data from the Hubble and Spitzer Space Telescopes from 0.5 to 5
microns, we conducted a detailed atmospheric study of the transiting
Neptune-mass exoplanet HAT-P-26b. We detected prominent H2O absorption bands
with a maximum base-to-peak amplitude of 525ppm in the transmission spectrum.
Using the water abundance as a proxy for metallicity, we measured HAT-P-26b's
atmospheric heavy element content [4.8 (-4.0 +21.5) times solar]. This likely
indicates that HAT-P-26b's atmosphere is primordial and obtained its gaseous
envelope late in its disk lifetime, with little contamination from metal-rich
planetesimals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04359</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ace&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Ericson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llerena</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>An Extreme Rotating Black Hole in New Massive Gravity Theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Revista Polit\'ecnica - Abril 2017, Vol. 39, No. 1</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New Massive Gravity is an alternative theory to General Relativity that is
used to describe the gravitational field in a (2+1)-dimensional spacetime.
Black hole solutions have been found in this theory, in particular an
asymptotically anti-de Sitter rotating black hole. We analyse some features of
this solution as its event horizon, black hole area and distance to the
horizon, specially in the rotating extreme case, showing that they have shared
features with extreme black holes in 4-dimensional General relativity. This
limit case is interesting in the search of geometric inequalities as the ones
found for the Kerr black hole in (3+1)-General Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04363</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Exner</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turek</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum graphs with the Bethe-Sommerfeld property</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>81Q35, 35J10, 34L40</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In contrast to the usual quantum systems which have at most a finite number
of open spectral gaps if they are periodic in more than one direction, periodic
quantum graphs may have gaps arbitrarily high in the spectrum. This property of
graph Hamiltonians, being generic in a sense, inspires the question about the
existence of graphs with a finite and nonzero number of spectral gaps. We show
that the answer depends on the vertex couplings together with commensurability
of the graph edges. A finite and nonzero number of gaps is excluded for graphs
with scale invariant couplings; on the other hand, we demonstrate that graphs
featuring a finite nonzero number of gaps do exist, illustrating the claim on
the example of a rectangular lattice with a suitably tuned $\delta$-coupling at
the vertices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04391</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanches</keyname><forenames>Vitor Hirata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuraoka</keyname><forenames>Dhyan V. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Almeida</keyname><forenames>Pedro R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldman</keyname><forenames>Carla</forenames></author></authors><title>A phenomenological analysis of eco-evolutionary coupling under dilution</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.PE</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Evolutionary dynamics experienced by mixed microbial populations of
cooperators and cheaters has been examined in experiments in the literature
using a protocol of periodic dilution to investigate the properties of
resilience and adaptability to environmental changes. Data depicted on an
appropriate phase diagram indicate, among other features, a stable equilibrium
point at which cooperators and cheaters coexist [A. Sanchez, J. Gore, PLOs
Biology, 11 (4), e1001547 (2013)]. We present here a phenomenological analysis
of these data focusing on an eco-evolutionary-game perspective. To that end, we
work on an extension of the model proposed by Tao and Cressman Y. Tao, R.
Cressman, Bull. Math. Biol. 69, 1377 - 1399 (2007). It's original version takes
into account changes of the total population density while the individuals
experience pairwise Prisoner's Dilemma game. The extension devised here
contains a dilution factor to be conform with the experimental procedure, in
addition of a term accounting for Allee effects. Differently from other
descriptions proposed in similar contexts, however, the model here does not
account for assortative encounters, group or kin selection. Nonetheless, it
describes surprisingly well both qualitatively and quantitatively the features
of the observed phase diagram. We discuss these results in terms of the
behavior of an effective payoff matrix defined accordingly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04394</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Mera</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological response of gapped fermions to a $\text{U}(1)$ Gauge field</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed path integral derivation of the topological response of
gapped free fermions, in $2+1$ dimensions, to an external $\text{U}(1)$ Gauge
field. The well-known Hall response is obtained by identifying the Chern-Simons
term in the effective action with the correct coefficient. We extend the result
to $2d+1$ dimensions in which the response is associated to a Chern-Simons term
with a coefficient related to a characteristic class coming from topological
band theory. We comment on the bulk-to-boundary principle which arises
naturally when one considers the theory on a manifold with boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04397</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Asmodelle</keyname><forenames>Estelle</forenames></author></authors><title>Tests of General Relativity: A Review</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>65 pages, 23 Figures, B.Sc. [hons] dissertation</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This report is a literature review of significant and successful tests of
general relativity [GR]. The GR predicted value for the perihelion advance of
Mercury was Deltaf = 43.03 arcsec century^-1 and fit well with observation,
being the first success of GR. The GR result for the bending of light around
the Sun dGR = 1.75 arcsec, confirmed by observation, marked the second
successful validation of GR. Gravitational Redshift [GvR] was first detected
1925 and is the third successful classical test. The parametrized
post-Newtonian PPN employs b and g for GR testing. Shapiro delay was also
confirmed with g = 1.000021 +/- 0.000023, against GR value g = 1, some consider
this to be the fourth classical test. So too gravitational time dilation GvT
was experimentally confirmed in 1971, while GvT for GPS is a daily validation
of GR. Frame-dragging and the Geodetic effect have also been confirmed. The
strong equivalence principle SEP has been confirmed to h = 4.4 x 10^-4, to GR h
= 0. Gravitational slip has been constrained to EG = 0.48 +/- 0.10 at z = 0.32,
against the GR value, EG = 0.30 +/- 0.07. The first gravitational wave
detection from GW150914, in 2015, has confirmed a long-awaited phenomenon that
has taken GR testing to higher precision. Gravitational lensing has also
confirmed GR to better than 1%. GR continues to be tested, eliminating
competing gravity theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04408</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Yuuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Fumihiko</forenames></author></authors><title>On the asymptotic behavior of Bessel-like diffusions</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the asymptotic behavior of the transition probability density of
the Bessel-like diffusions for &quot;dimension&quot; $\rho = 0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04411</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gourdain</keyname><forenames>P. -A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foy</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mager</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McBride</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spielman</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>HADES: a High Amperage Driver for Extreme States</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Linear transformer drivers (LTD) allow to greatly reduce the size of
pulsed-power drivers while increasing their efficiency and repetition rate.
However, limitations on the capacitors voltage and current exist, mostly driven
by technological imperatives. As a result, LTD required to be connected in
series and in parallel to form a practical pulsed-power generator. The High
Amperage Driver for Extreme States (HADES) proposed here can generate 250 GW of
power, i.e. a 1 MA on current with a rise time of 150 ns into a 20nH load. The
key feature of the driver is its size. The machine footprint is less than 5m2
and its height is less than 1.6m. This reduction in footprint, compared to
other 1 MA LTD based-systems, comes from a compact transmission line geometry
which allow to connect LTDs is series and in parallel efficiently. This paper
summarizes this design and describes HADES operation and maintenance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04412</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04412</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sang A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Jae-Yeol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Eun Sung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Sung Wng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Woo Seok</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly oriented SrTiO3 thin film on graphene substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acsami.6b12258</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Growth of perovskite oxide thin films on Si in crystalline form has long been
a critical obstacle for the integration of multifunctional oxides into Si-based
technologies. In this study, we propose pulsed laser deposition of a
crystalline SrTiO3 thin film on a Si using graphene substrate. The SrTiO3 thin
film on graphene has a highly (00l)-oriented crystalline structure which
results from the partial epitaxy. Moreover, graphene promotes a sharp interface
by highly suppressing the chemical intermixing. The important role of graphene
as a 2D substrate and diffusion barrier allows expansion of device applications
based on functional complex oxides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04413</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Wei-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ye-Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>John W.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Khachaturyan</keyname><forenames>Armen G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Responses of Pre-transitional Materials with Stress-Generating Defects
  to External Stimuli: Superelasticity, Supermagnetostriction, Invar and
  Elinvar Effects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>34 Pages, 10 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We considered a generic case of pre-transitional materials with static
stress-generating defects, dislocations and coherent nano-precipitates, at
temperatures close but above the starting temperature of martensitic
transformation, Ms. Using the Phase Field Microelasticity theory and 3D
simulation, we demonstrated that the local stress generated by these defects
produces equilibrium nano-size martensitic embryos (MEs) in pre-transitional
state, these embryos being orientation variants of martensite. This is a new
type of equilibrium: the thermoelastic equilibrium between the MEs and parent
phase in which the total volume of MEs and their size are equilibrium internal
thermodynamic parameters. This thermoelastic equilibrium exists only in
presence of the stress-generating defects. Cooling the pre-transitional state
towards Ms or applying the external stimuli, stress or magnetic field, results
in a shift of the thermoelastic equilibrium provided by a reversible
anhysteretic growth of MEs that results in a giant ME-generated macroscopic
strain. In particular, this effect can be associated with the diffuse phase
transformations observed in some ferroelectrics above the Curie point. It is
shown that the ME-generated strain is giant and describes a superelasticity if
the applied field is stress. It describes a super magnetostriction if the
martensite (or austenite) are ferromagnetic and the applied field is a magnetic
field. In general, the material with defects can be a multiferroic with a giant
multiferroic response if the parent and martensitic phase have different
ferroic properties. Finally the ME-generated strain may explain or, at least,
contribute to the Invar and Elinvar effects that are typically observed in
pre-transitional austenite. The thermoelastic equilibrium and all these effects
exist only if the interaction between the defects and MEs is infinite-range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04425</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sang A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Seokjae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Jae-Yeol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Minseok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Youn</keyname><forenames>Chulmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Ji Woong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Seo Hyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woo</keyname><forenames>Sungmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bae</keyname><forenames>Jong-Seong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Sungkyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Young-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Suyoun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Taekjib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Sung Wng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Woo Seok</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced electrocatalytic activity via phase transitions in strongly
  correlated SrRuO3 thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>31 pages, 18 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1039/C7EE00628D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition metal oxides have been extensively studied and utilized as
efficient catalysts. However, the strongly correlated behavior which often
results in intriguing emergent phenomena in these materials has been mostly
overlooked in understanding the electrochemical activities. Here, we
demonstrate a close correlation between the phase transitions and oxygen
evolution reaction (OER) in a strongly correlated SrRuO3. By systematically
introducing Ru-O vacancies into the single-crystalline SrRuO3 epitaxial thin
films, we induced phase transition in crystalline symmetry which resulted in
corresponding modification in the electronic structure. The modified electronic
structure significantly affect the electrochemical activities, so a 30%
decrease in the overpotential for the OER activity was achieved. Our study
suggests that a substantial enhancement in the OER activity can be realized
even within single material systems, by rational design and engineering of
their crystal and electronic structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04435</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Cianciara</keyname><forenames>Aleksander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xuelei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhiping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Jingchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jixia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peterson</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Huli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steffel</keyname><forenames>Catherine N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stebbins</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stucky</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Shijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timbie</keyname><forenames>Peter T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yougang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Fengquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Juyong</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation and Testing of a Linear Array of Modified Four-Square Feed
  Antennas for the Tianlai Cylindrical Radio Telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>15 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A wide bandwidth, dual polarized, modified four-square antenna is presented
as a feed antenna for radio astronomical measurements. A linear array of these
antennas is used as a line-feed for cylindrical reflectors for Tianlai, a radio
interferometer designed for 21~cm intensity mapping. Simulations of the feed
antenna beam patterns and scattering parameters are compared to experimental
results at multiple frequencies across the 650 - 1420 MHz range. Simulations of
the beam patterns of the combined feed array/reflector are presented as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04438</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Frampton</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLaughlin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zieve</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Manganin Foil Sensor for Small Uniaxial Stress</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 88, 046106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981247</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a simple manganin foil resistance manometer for uniaxial stress
measurements. The manometer functions at low pressures and over a range of
temperatures. In this design no temperature seasoning is necessary, although
the manometer must be prestressed to the upper end of the desired pressure
range. The prestress pressure cannot be increased arbitrarily; irreversibility
arising from shear stress limits its range. Attempting larger pressures yields
irreproducible resistance measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04439</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Noh</keyname><forenames>Changsuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Stephen R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksch</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angelakis</keyname><forenames>Dimitris G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Out-of-equilibrium physics in driven dissipative coupled resonator
  arrays</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Chapter that appeared in &quot;Quantum Simulations with Photons and
  Polaritons: Merging Quantum Optics with Condensed Matter Physics&quot; edited by
  D.G.Angelakis, Quantum Science and Technology Series, Springer 2017</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-52025-4_3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coupled resonator arrays have been shown to exhibit interesting many- body
physics including Mott and Fractional Hall states of photons. One of the main
differences between these photonic quantum simulators and their cold atoms
coun- terparts is in the dissipative nature of their photonic excitations. The
natural equi- librium state is where there are no photons left in the cavity.
Pumping the system with external drives is therefore necessary to compensate
for the losses and realise non-trivial states. The external driving here can
easily be tuned to be incoherent, coherent or fully quantum, opening the road
for exploration of many body regimes beyond the reach of other approaches. In
this chapter, we review some of the physics arising in driven dissipative
coupled resonator arrays including photon fermionisa- tion, crystallisation, as
well as photonic quantum Hall physics out of equilibrium. We start by briefly
describing possible experimental candidates to realise coupled resonator arrays
along with the two theoretical models that capture their physics, the
Jaynes-Cummings-Hubbard and Bose-Hubbard Hamiltonians. A brief review of the
analytical and sophisticated numerical methods required to tackle these systems
is included.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04440</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>D. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Netrakanti</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conserved charge fluctuations using the $D$-measure in heavy-ion
  collisions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures. Published in Physical Review C</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.054905</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the net-charge fluctuations, $D$-measure variable, in high energy
heavy-ion collisions in heavy-ion jet interaction generator (HIJING),
ultrarelativistic quantum molecular dynamics (UrQMD) and hadron resonance gas
(HRG) models for various center-of-mass energies (\sqsn). The effect of
kinematic acceptance and resonance decay, in the pseudorapidity acceptance
interval ($\Delta\eta$) and lower transverse momentum ($p_{T}^{min}$)
threshold, on fluctuation measures are discussed. A strong dependence of $D$
with the $\Delta\eta$ in HIJING and UrQMD models is observed as opposed to
results obtained from the HRG model. The dissipation of fluctuation signal is
estimated by fitting the $D$-measure as a function of the $\Delta\eta$. An
extrapolated function for higher $\Delta\eta$ values at lower \sqsn is
different from the results obtained from models. Particle species dependence of
$D$ and the effect of the $p_T^{min}$ selection threshold are discussed in
HIJING and HRG models. The comparison of $D$, at midrapidity, of net-charge
fluctuations at various \sqsn obtained from the models with the data from the
ALICE experiment is discussed. The results from the present work as a function
of $\Delta\eta$ and \sqsn will provide a baseline for comparison to
experimental measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04445</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sivadasan</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singha</keyname><forenames>Chirantan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sandip</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface Phonon Modes in the [AlN/GaN]20 and
  [Al0.35Ga0.65N/Al0.55Ga0.45N]20 2D Multi Quantum Well Structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 18 (2016) 29864-29870</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP05520F</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interface phonon (IF) modes of c-plane oriented [AlN/GaN]20 and
Al0.35Ga0.65N/Al0.55Ga0.45N]20 multi quantum well (MQW) structures grown via
plasma assisted molecular beam epitaxy are reported. The effect of variation in
dielectric constant of barrier layers to the IF optical phonon modes of well
layers periodically arranged in the MQWs investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04447</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Maity</keyname><forenames>Achyut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiti</keyname><forenames>Arpan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satpati</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patsha</keyname><forenames>Avinash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sandip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chini</keyname><forenames>Tapas Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Localized Surface Plasmons of Trisoctahedral Gold Nanocrystals
  for Surface Enhanced Raman Scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>39 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C 120 (2016) 27003-27012</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b09296</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Trisoctahedral (TOH) shaped Au nanocrystals (NCs) have emerged as a new class
of metal nanoparticles (MNP) due to its superior catalystic and SERS activities
caused by the presence of high density atomic steps and dangling bonds on their
high index facets. We examine the radiative localized surface plasmon resonance
(LSPR) modes of an isolated single TOH Au NC using cathodoluminescence (CL),
with high resolution spatial information of the local density of optical states
(LDOS) across the visible spectral range. Further we show pronounced
enhancement factor in the Raman scattering by performing Raman spectroscopic
measurements on Rhodamine 6G (R6G) covered TOH Au NPs aggregates on a Si
substrate. We believe that the hot spots between two adjacent MNP surfaces
(nanogaps) can be significantly stronger than single particle LSPRs. Such
nanogaps hotspots may have crucial role on the substantial SERS enhancement
observed in this report. Consequently, the present study indicates that MNPs
aggregates are highly desirable than individual plasmonic nanoparticles for
possible applications in SERS based biosensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04461</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Braeck</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xf8;n</keyname><forenames>&#xd8;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farup</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Cosmic Causal Mass</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Universe, 3, 38 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/universe3020038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to provide a better understanding of rotating universe models, and
in particular the G\&quot;{o}del universe, we discuss the relationship between
cosmic rotation and perfect inertial dragging. In this connection, the concept
of \emph{causal mass} is defined in a cosmological context, and discussed in
relation to the cosmic inertial dragging effect. Then, we calculate the mass
inside the particle horizon of the flat $\Lambda$CDM-model integrated along the
past light cone. The calculation shows that the Schwarzschild radius of this
mass is around three times the radius of the particle horizon. This indicates
that there is close to perfect inertial dragging in our universe. Hence, the
calculation provides an explanation for the observation that the swinging plane
of a Foucault pendulum follows the stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04468</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving quark flavor separation with forward W and Z production at
  LHCb</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the XXV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 3-7
  April 2017, University of Birmingham, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We quantify the constraints on the flavour separation between the quarks and
antiquarks in the proton provided by the recent forward weak gauge boson
production data from the LHCb experiment at $\sqrt{s}=7$ and 8 TeV. Performed
in the framework of the NNPDF3.1 global analysis, this study highlights the key
role that the LHCb W and Z data have in achieving a robust quark flavour
separation in the large-x region, including the strange and charm quarks. We
demonstrate how the LHCb measurements lead to improved determinations of the
the up and down quark PDFs in the region $x\ge 0.1$, with an uncertainty
reduction that can be as large as a factor 2. We also show how the LHCb forward
measurements severely restrict the size of the fitted charm PDF at large x,
imposing stringent constraints on non-perturbative models for the charm content
of the nucleon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04473</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Asai</keyname><forenames>Hidehiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabata</keyname><forenames>Shiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Emission of Circularly Polarized Terahertz Wave from Inhomogeneous
  Intrinsic Josephson Junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Trans. Appl. Supercond. 26 (2016) 1800804</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TASC.2016.2515853</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have theoretically demonstrated the emission of circularly-polarized
terahertz (THz) waves from intrinsic Josephson junctions (IJJs) which is
locally heated by an external heat source such as the laser irradiation. We
focus on a mesa-structured IJJ whose geometry is slightly deviate from a square
and find that the local heating make it possible to emit circularly-polarized
THz waves. In this mesa, the inhomogeneity of critical current density induced
by the local heating excites the electromagnetic cavity modes TM (1,0) and TM
(0,1), whose polarizations are orthogonal to each other. The mixture of these
modes results in the generation of circularly-polarized THz waves. We also show
that the circular polarization dramatically changes with the applied voltage.
The emitter based on IJJs can emit circularly-polarized and continuum THz waves
by the local heating, and will be useful for various technological application.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04478</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Reddy</keyname><forenames>Salla Gangi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Vijay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>Yoko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering of Poincare beams: polarization speckles</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages and 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarization speckle is a fine granular light pattern having spatially
varying random polarization profile. We generate these speckle patterns by
using the scattering of Poincar\'e beams, a special class of vector vortex
beams, through a ground glass plate. Here, the Poincar\'e beams are generated
using a polarization sensitive spatial light modulator displaying an on-axis
hologram corresponding to an optical vortex phase profile. The different
inhomogeneities of the rough surface experience different polarizations, which
control the ability for scattered waves to interfere at the detection plane and
causes a spatially varying polarization profile. We experimentally determined
the spatial variation of local degree of polarization and orientation of the
polarization ellipse for these speckle patterns from the Stokes analysis. We
also determined the size of scalar speckles using the auto-correlation function
of Stokes parameter S0 and the size of polarization speckles using the sum of
auto-correlation functions of remaining three Stokes parameters. We found that
the scalar speckle size is independent of index of the vector beam but the size
of polarization speckles decreases with the increase in index of the vector
beam.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04479</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Benschop</keyname><forenames>H. O. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breugem</keyname><forenames>W. -P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillatory laminar shear flow over a compliant viscoelastic layer on a
  rigid base</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analytical study of oscillatory laminar shear flow over a
compliant viscoelastic layer on a rigid base. This problem relates to
oscillating blood flow in viscoelastic vessels. The deeper motivation for this
study, however, is the possible use of compliant coatings for turbulent drag
reduction. An analytical solution of the fluid and solid velocity is presented,
and five dimensionless parameters emerge. The interaction between fluid and
solid appears to be determined by a single combined dimensionless parameter,
which we call the shear interaction parameter $\chi$. The fluid satisfies a
no-slip boundary condition when $\left|\chi\right| \rightarrow 0$, which occurs
when the solid is heavy, stiff and/or thin. In contrast, the fluid obeys a
free-slip boundary condition when $\left|\chi\right| \rightarrow \infty$, which
corresponds to a lightweight and/or soft solid. Three types of resonance modes
are identified for an elastic solid. Two modes (odd and even) are specific to
the solid. The third mode results from the coupling with the fluid. The three
modes are less pronounced or even absent for a viscoelastic solid. These
findings have a twofold use. First, they help to understand the fluid and solid
dynamics when shear coupling is important. Second, the presented analytical
solution is very useful for validation of numerical fluid-structure-interaction
solvers. Future work might include the extension of the theory to multiple
viscoelastic layers and the dynamic coupling of normal stresses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04498</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gatchell</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delaunay</keyname><forenames>Rudy</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Angelo</keyname><forenames>Giovanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mika</keyname><forenames>Arkadiusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulyk</keyname><forenames>Kostiantyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Domaracka</keyname><forenames>Alicja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rousseau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zettergren</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Bernd A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cederquist</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Ion-Induced Molecular Growth in Clusters of Small Hydrocarbon Chains</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, Accepted for publication in Physical Chemistry
  Chemical Physics 2017</comments><doi>10.1039/C7CP02090B</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on studies of collisions between 3 keV Ar$^+$ projectile ions and
neutral targets of isolated 1,3-butadiene (C$_4$H$_6$) molecules and cold,
loosely bound clusters of these molecules. We identify molecular growth
processes within the molecular clusters that appears to be driven by knockout
processes and that could result in the formation of (aromatic) ring structures.
These types of reactions are not unique to specific projectile ions and target
molecules, but will occur whenever atoms or ions with suitable masses and
kinetic energies collide with aggregates of matter, such as carbonaceous grains
in the interstellar medium or aerosol nanoparticles in the atmosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04511</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Malabirade</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubiak</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Mendoza</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Kan</keyname><forenames>Jeroen A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berret</keyname><forenames>Jean-Franccois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arluison</keyname><forenames>Veronique</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Maarel</keyname><forenames>Johan R. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Compaction and condensation of DNA mediated by the C-terminal domain of
  Hfq</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.BM</categories><comments>10 pages 7 figures 48 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hfq is a bacterial protein that is involved in several aspects of nucleic
acids metabolism. It has been described as one of the nucleoid associated
proteins shaping the bacterial chromosome, although it is better known to
influence translation and turnover of cellular RNAs. Here, we explore the role
of Escherichia coli Hfq C-terminal domain in the compaction of double stranded
DNA. Various experimental methodologies, including fluorescence microscopy
imaging of single DNA molecules confined inside nanofluidic channels, atomic
force microscopy, isothermal titration microcalorimetry, and electrophoretic
mobility assays have been used to follow the assembly of the C-terminal and
N-terminal regions of Hfq on DNA. Results highlight the role of Hfq C-terminal
arms in DNA binding, change in mechanical properties of the double helix and
compaction of DNA into a condensed form. The propensity for bridging and
compaction of DNA by the C-terminal domain might be related to aggregation of
bound protein and may have implications for protein binding related gene
regulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04534</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Botana</keyname><forenames>Antia S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pardo</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickett</keyname><forenames>Warren E.</forenames></author></authors><title>All 3d electron-hole bilayers in CrN/MgO(111) multilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 7, 024002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.7.024002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CrN/MgO(111) multilayers modeled via \textit{ab initio} calculations give
rise to nanoscale, scalable, spatially separated two-dimensional electron and
hole gases (2DEG+2DHG), each confined to its own CrN interface. Due to the Cr
$3d^3$ configuration, both electron and hole gases are based on correlated
transition metal layers involving bands of $3d$ character. Transport
calculations predict each subsystem will have a large thermopower, on the order
of 250 $\mu$$V /K$ at room temperature. These heterostructures combine a large
thermoelectric efficiency with scalable nanoscale conducting sheets; for
example, operating at a temperature difference of 50K, 40 bilayers could
produce a 1 V voltage with a film thickness of 100 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04546</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Pei</keyname><forenames>Songpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Guoqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhibing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Yajuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuen</keyname><forenames>Rai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Jinlu</forenames></author></authors><title>A study of the cross-correlation and time lag in black hole X-ray binary
  XTE J1859+226</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s10509-017-3101-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer (RXTE) data, we systematically study the
cross-correlation and time lag in all spectral states of black hole X-ray
binary (BHXB) XTE J1859+226 in detail during its entire 1999-2000 outburst that
lasted for 166 days. Anti-correlations and positive correlations and their
respective soft and hard X-ray lags are only detected in the first 100 days of
the outburst when the luminosity is high. This suggests that the
cross-correlations may be related to high luminosity. Positive correlations are
detected in every state of XTE J1859+226, viz., hard state, hard-intermediate
state (HIMS), soft-intermediate state (SIMS) and soft state. However,
anti-correlations are only detected in HIMS and SIMS, anti-correlated hard lags
are only detected in SIMS, while anti-correlated soft lags are detected in both
HIMS and SIMS. Moreover, the ratio of the observations with anti-correlated
soft lags to hard lags detected in XTE J1859+226 is significantly different
from that in neutron star low-mass X-ray binaries (NS LMXBs). So far,
anti-correlations are never detected in the soft state of BHXBs but detected in
every branch or state of NS LMXBs. This may be due to the origin of soft seed
photons in BHXBs is confined to the accretion disk and, for NS LMXBs, from both
accretion disk and the surface of the NS. We notice that the timescale of
anti-correlated time lags detected in XTE J1859+226 is similar with that of
other BHXBs and NS LMXBs. We suggest that anti-correlated soft lag detected in
BHXB may result from fluctuation in the accretion disk as well as NS LMXB.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04552</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Fardad</keyname><forenames>Shima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>E. Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salandrino</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Accumulation-layer Surface Plasmons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 42, 2038-2041 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.002038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A rigorous analytical study of the eigenmodes supported by a charge
accumulation layer within a transparent conductive oxide (TCO) is presented.
The new class of surface plasmons termed Accumulation-Layer Surface Plasmon
(ASP) is introduced. Near resonance ASP are tightly bound and display a vast
effective index tunability that could be of great practical interest. The
suppression of ASP in the presence of epsilon-near zero regions is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04563</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Borrow</keyname><forenames>Josh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Galaxy Makers: creating an online component to a science exhibition for
  re-engagement, evaluation and content legacy</title><categories>physics.soc-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in CAPj</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the Royal Society Summer Science Exhibition 2016, the Institute of
Computational Cosmology from Durham University created the Galaxy Makers
exhibit to communicate our computational cosmology and astronomy research. In
addition to the physical exhibit we created an online component to foster
re-engagement, create a permanent home for our content and to allow us to
collect the ever-more important information about participation and impact.
Here we summarise the details of the exhibit and the successes of creating an
online component. We also share suggestions of further uses and improvements
that could be implemented for online components of other science exhibitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04570</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Basak</keyname><forenames>Jyotirmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Bappaditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maitra</keyname><forenames>Arpita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>and Goutam</forenames></author></authors><title>Device Independent Quantum Private Query with Finite Number of Entangled
  Qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, sequel to arXiv:1701.01087</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent work by Maitra et al. (Phys. Rev. A, 2017), it was shown that the
existing Quantum Private Query (QPQ) protocols fail to maintain the database
security if the entangled states shared between Alice and Bob are not of a
certain form. So it is necessary to certify the states a priori. In this
regard, the local CHSH test was proposed. However, the proposed scheme works
perfectly for the asymptotic case when we have infinite number of qubits. In
this brief report, we upgrade the protocol for finite number of qubits and
connect the sample size to the success probability of CHSH test. We also
perform a rigorous security analysis of the proposed protocol.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04578</id><created>2017-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Friedman</keyname><forenames>Yaakov</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic Newtonian Dynamics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>European Physics Letters 116 (2016) 19001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/19001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Planck's formula and General Relativity indicate that potential energy
influences spacetime. Using Einstein's Equivalence Principle and an extension
of his Chock Hypothesis, an explicit description of this influence is derived.
We present a new relativity model by incorporating the influence of the
potential energy on spacetime in Newton's dynamics for motion under a central
force. This model extends the model used by Friedman and Steiner to obtain the
exact precession of Mercury without curving spacetime. We also present a
solution of this model for a hydrogen-like atom, which explains the reason for
a probabilistic description.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04580</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>R&#xf6;diger</keyname><forenames>Jasper</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, AG Nanooptik, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Perlot</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mottola</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, AG Nanooptik, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Elschner</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Weinert</keyname><forenames>Carl-Michael</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Benson</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames><affiliation>Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, AG Nanooptik, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Freund</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames><affiliation>Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Numerical Assessment and Optimization of Discrete-Variable
  Time-Frequency Quantum Key Distribution</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 Pages, 4 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A, 95(5), 052312 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.052312</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discrete variables (DV) time-frequency (TF) quantum key distribution
(QKD) protocol is a BB84 like protocol, which utilizes time and frequency as
complementary bases. As orthogonal modulations, pulse position modulation (PPM)
and frequency shift keying (FSK) are capable of transmitting several bits per
symbol, i.e. per photon. However, unlike traditional binary polarization shift
keying, PPM and FSK do not allow perfectly complementary bases. So information
is not completely deleted when the wrong-basis filters are applied. Since a
general security proof does not yet exist, we numerically assess DV-TF-QKD. We
show that the secret key rate increases with a higher number of symbols per
basis. Further we identify the optimal pulse relations in the two bases in
terms of key rate and resistance against eavesdropping attacks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04594</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bromley</keyname><forenames>Keith M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacPhee</keyname><forenames>Cait E.</forenames></author></authors><title>BslA-stabilised emulsion droplets with designed microstructure</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>23 pages including 6 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Emulsions are a central component of many modern formulations in food,
pharmaceuticals, agrichemicals and personal care products. The droplets in
these formulations are limited to being spherical as a consequence of the
interfacial tension between the dispersed phase and continuous phase. The
ability to control emulsion droplet morphology and stabilise non-spherical
droplets would enable the modification of emulsion properties such as
stability, substrate binding, delivery rate and rheology. One way of
controlling droplet microstructure is to apply an elastic film around the
droplet to prevent it from relaxing into a sphere. We have previously shown
that BslA, an interfacial protein produced by the bacterial genus Bacillus,
forms an elastic film when exposed to an oil- or air-water interface. Here, we
highlight BslA's ability to stabilise anisotropic emulsion droplets. First, we
show that BslA is capable of arresting dynamic emulsification processes leading
to emulsions with variable morphologies depending on the conditions and
emulsification technique applied. We then show that frozen emulsion droplets
can be manipulated to induce partial coalescence. The structure of the
partially coalesced droplets is retained after melting, but only when there is
sufficient free BslA in the continuous phase. That the fidelity of replication
can be tuned by adjusting the amount of free BslA in solution suggests that
freezing BslA-stabilised droplets disrupts the BslA film. Finally, we utilise
BslA's ability to preserve emulsion droplet structural integrity throughout the
melting process to design emulsion droplets with a chosen shape and size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04597</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Dipan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Dipti</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of orbital angular momentum through twisted Variable
  retarders</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polarized light passing through twisted special wave plates show entangled
state of both SAM and OAM. The variable circular and linear retarders (VCR and
VLR) are studied here from the view point of quantum processing of entangled
states. Interestingly the geometric phase in association with twist dependent
gain of OAM has been discussed here. As an application of VLR, the origin of
gradual flattened shape of wave fronts through successive array of antennas
(QHQ) has been explained through new physical approach of the concurrence of
entangled states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04613</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Zaninetti</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Voronoi chords in flat cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages and 6 figures</comments><doi>10.22606/adap.2017.22002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present formulae for chord length distribution in the
framework of Poissonian Voronoi Tessellation (PVT) and non Poissonian Voronoi
Tessellation (NPVT). The introduction of the scale parameter in the obtained
distributions allows us to model the chord for cosmic voids. A graphical
comparison between cosmic voids visible on two catalogs of galaxies, 2dFGRS and
VIPERS, and theoretical random chords is reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04620</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>Lucien</forenames></author></authors><title>Proposal to use Humans to switch settings in a Bell experiment</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper I discuss how we might go about about performing a Bell
experiment in which humans are used to decide the settings at each end. To get
a sufficiently high rate of switching at both ends, I suggest an experiment
over a distance of about 100km with 100 people at each end wearing EEG
headsets, with the signals from these headsets being used to switch the
settings.
  The radical possibility we wish to investigate is that, when humans are used
to decide the settings (rather than various types of random number generators),
we might then expect to see a violation of Quantum Theory in agreement with the
relevant Bell inequality. Such a result, while very unlikely, would be
tremendously significant for our understanding of the world (and I will discuss
some interpretations).
  Possible radical implications aside, performing an experiment like this would
push the development of new technologies. The biggest problem would be to get
sufficiently high rates wherein there has been a human induced switch at each
end before a signal as to the new value of the setting could be communicated to
the other end and, at the same time, a photon pair is detected. It looks like
an experiment like this, while challenging, is just about feasible with current
technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04633</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Roman</keyname><forenames>Sabin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brede</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology-dependent rationality and quantal response equilibria in
  structured populations</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 052310 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.052310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given that the assumption of perfect rationality is rarely met in the real
world, we explore a graded notion of rationality in socioecological systems of
networked actors. We parametrize an actors' rationality via their place in a
social network and quantify system rationality via the average Jensen-Shannon
divergence between the games Nash and logit quantal response equilibria.
Previous work has argued that scale-free topologies maximize a system's overall
rationality in this setup. Here we show that while, for certain games, it is
true that increasing degree heterogeneity of complex networks enhances
rationality, rationality-optimal configurations are not scale-free. For the
Prisoner's Dilemma and Stag Hunt games, we provide analytic arguments
complemented by numerical optimization experiments to demonstrate that
core-periphery networks composed of a few dominant hub nodes surrounded by a
periphery of very low degree nodes give strikingly smaller overall deviations
from rationality than scale-free networks. Similarly, for the Battle of the
Sexes and the Matching Pennies games, we find that the optimal network
structure is also a core-periphery graph but with a smaller difference in the
average degrees of the core and the periphery. These results provide insight on
the interplay between the topological structure of socioecological systems and
their collective cognitive behavior, with potential applications to
understanding wealth inequality and the structural features of the network of
global corporate control.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04637</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kondev</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thoennessen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batchelder</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawano</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelley</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCutchan</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonzogni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>White Paper on Nuclear Data Needs and Capabilities for Basic Science</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>This white paper and copies of the presentations can be found on the
  meeting website at
  http://meetings.nscl.msu.edu/2016ND_workshop/html/home.html</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Workshop on Nuclear Data Needs and Capabilities for Basic Science was
held at the University of Notre Dame on 10-11 August 2016. The purpose of this
targeted workshop was to assemble and prioritize the needs of the nuclear
physics research community for data sets, services and capabilities in areas
including nuclear structure, nuclear reactions, nuclear astrophysics,
fundamental interactions, neutrino physics and nuclear theory. An overview of
nuclear data needs and capabilities identified at this meeting are summarized
in the present document.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04646</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kelkar</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez</keyname><forenames>D. Lozano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pati&#xf1;o</keyname><forenames>Edgar J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time in dissipative tunneling: subtleties and applications</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 382, 11 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.04.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Characteristic features of tunneling times for dissipative tunneling of a
particle through a rectangular barrier are studied within a semiclassical model
involving dissipation in the form of a velocity dependent frictional force. The
average dwell time and traversal time with dissipation are found to be less
than those without dissipation. This counter-intuitive behaviour is reversed if
one evaluates the physically relevant transmission dwell time. Apart from these
observations, we find that the percentage of energy lost by the tunneling
particle is higher for smaller energies. The above observations are tested and
confirmed in a realistic case by applying the dissipation model to study the
current-voltage data in a Al/Al$_2$O$_3$/Al solid state junction at various
temperatures. The friction coefficient for Al$_2$O$_3$ as a function of
temperature is presented. It is found to decrease with increasing temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04677</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04677</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Renardy</keyname><forenames>Yuriko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renardy</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>A singular perturbation study of the Rolie-Poly model</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Rolie-Poly model for entangled polymers, using a singular
perturbation analysis for the limit of large relaxation time. In this limit, it
is shown that the model displays the characteristic features of thixotropic
yield stress fluids, including yield stress hysteresis, delayed yielding and
long term persistence of a decreased viscosity after cessation of flow. We
focus on the startup and cessation of shear flow. We identify dynamic regimes
of fast, slow and yielded dynamics, and show how the combination of these
regimes can be used to describe the flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
