<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:08:40Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-22" from="2017-05-22" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0801.0294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0801.0294</id><created>2008-01-02</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Ying-Qiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Functions and Relations for an Evolving Star with Spherical Symmetry</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, no figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we drive and simplify some important equations and relations
for an evolving star with spherical symmetry, and then give some simple
analysis for their properties and implications. In the light-cone coordinate
system, these equations and relations have a normal and neat form which is much
accessible than the usual Einstein field equation. So they may be helpful for
students to study general relativity and for researchers to do further
discussion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0912.4178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0912.4178</id><created>2009-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Muga</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez</keyname></author><author><keyname>Lizuain</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruschhaupt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transitionless quantum drivings for the harmonic oscillator</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure. Submitted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics B: Atomic, Molecular and Optical Physics,
  Volume 43, Number 8, pages 085509 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/43/8/085509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two methods to change a quantum harmonic oscillator frequency without
transitions in a finite time are described and compared. The first method, a
transitionless-tracking algorithm, makes use of a generalized harmonic
oscillator and a non-local potential. The second method, based on engineering
an invariant of motion, only modifies the harmonic frequency in time, keeping
the potential local at all times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.0886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.0886</id><created>2013-08-05</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Yipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Weipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Peculiar Velocity Decomposition, Redshift Space Distortion and Velocity
  Reconstruction in Redshift Surveys. II. Dark Matter Velocity Statistics</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>21 pages, 17 figures. Accepted by PRD. Equation typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 88, 103510 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.88.103510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive spectroscopic redshift surveys open a promising window to accurately
measure peculiar velocity at cosmological distances through redshift space
distortion (RSD). In paper I of this series of work we proposed to decompose
peculiar velocity into three eigen-modes (v_\delta, v_S and v_B) in order to
facilitate the RSD modeling and peculiar velocity reconstruction. In the
current paper we measure the dark matter RSD related statistics of the velocity
eigen-modes through a set of N-body simulations, including the velocity power
spectra, correlation functions, one-point probability distribution functions,
cumulants and the damping functions describing the Finger of God effect. (1)
The power spectrum measurement shows that these velocity components have
distinctly different spatial distribution and redshift evolution. In
particular, we measure the window function \tilde{W}(k,z), which describes the
impact of nonlinear evolution on the v_\delta-density relation. We confirm that
it can induce a significant systematic error of O(10%) in RSD cosmology. We
demonstrate that \tilde{W} can be accurately described by a simple fitting
formula with one or two free parameters. (2) The correlation function
measurement shows that the correlation length is O(100), O(10) and O(1) Mpc for
v_\delta, v_S and v_B respectively. These correlation lengths determine where
we can treat the velocity fields as spatially uncorrelated. (3) The velocity
PDFs and cumulants quantify non-Gaussianities of the velocity fields. We
confirm speculation in paper I that v_\delta is largely Gaussian, nevertheless
with non-negligible non-Gaussianity, v_B is significantly non-Gaussian. We also
measure the damping functions. Despite the observed non-Gaussianities, the
damping functions and hence the FOG effect are all well approximated as
Gaussian ones at scales of interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1366</id><created>2014-04-04</created><updated>2015-10-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anshu</keyname><forenames>Anurag</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Priyanka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shayeghi</keyname><forenames>Ala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Penghui</forenames></author></authors><title>New one shot quantum protocols with application to communication
  complexity</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>23 pages. Changed title, abstract and presentation of the paper</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Information Theory (Volume: 62, Issue: 12,
  Dec. 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2016.2616125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present the following quantum compression protocol:
  P : Let $\rho,\sigma$ be quantum states such that $S(\rho || \sigma) =
\text{Tr} (\rho \log \rho - \rho \log \sigma)$, the relative entropy between
$\rho$ and $\sigma$, is finite. Alice gets to know the eigen-decomposition of
$\rho$. Bob gets to know the eigen-decomposition of $\sigma$. Both Alice and
Bob know $S(\rho || \sigma)$ and an error parameter $\epsilon$. Alice and Bob
use shared entanglement and after communication of $\mathcal{O}((S(\rho ||
\sigma)+1)/\epsilon^4)$ bits from Alice to Bob, Bob ends up with a quantum
state $\tilde{\rho}$ such that $F(\rho, \tilde{\rho}) \geq 1 - 5\epsilon$,
where $F(\cdot)$ represents fidelity.
  This result can be considered as a non-commutative generalization of a result
due to Braverman and Rao [2011] where they considered the special case when
$\rho$ and $\sigma$ are classical probability distributions (or commute with
each other) and use shared randomness instead of shared entanglement. We use P
to obtain an alternate proof of a direct-sum result for entanglement assisted
quantum one-way communication complexity for all relations, which was first
shown by Jain, Radhakrishnan and Sen [2005,2008]. We also present a variant of
protocol P in which Bob has some side information about the state with Alice.
We show that in such a case, the amount of communication can be further
reduced, based on the side information that Bob has.
  Our second result provides a quantum analogue of the widely used classical
correlated-sampling protocol. For example, Holenstein [2007] used the classical
correlated-sampling protocol in his proof of a parallel-repetition theorem for
two-player one-round games.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.5555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.5555</id><created>2014-05-21</created><updated>2014-06-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wuthrich</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>A quantum-information-theoretic complement to a general-relativistic
  implementation of a beyond-Turing computer</title><categories>physics.hist-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 5 figures. Forthcoming in Synthese. Matches published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Synthese 192 (2015): 1989-2008</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11229-014-0502-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There exists a growing literature on the so-called physical Church-Turing
thesis in a relativistic spacetime setting. The physical Church-Turing thesis
is the conjecture that no computing device that is physically realizable (even
in principle) can exceed the computational barriers of a Turing machine. By
suggesting a concrete implementation of a beyond-Turing computer in a spacetime
setting, Istv\'an N\'emeti and Gyula D\'avid (2006) have shown how an
appreciation of the physical Church-Turing thesis necessitates the confluence
of mathematical, computational, physical, and indeed cosmological ideas. In
this essay, I will honour Istv\'an's seventieth birthday, as well as his
longstanding interest in, and his seminal contributions to, this field going
back to as early as 1987 by modestly proposing how the concrete implementation
in N\'emeti and D\'avid (2006) might be complemented by a
quantum-information-theoretic communication protocol between the computing
device and the logician who sets the beyond-Turing computer a task such as
determining the consistency of Zermelo-Fraenkel set theory. This suggests that
even the foundations of quantum theory and, ultimately, quantum gravity may
play an important role in determining the validity of the physical
Church-Turing thesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.7261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.7261</id><created>2014-06-27</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Jo&#xe3;o L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gir&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>Pedro M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nat&#xe1;rio</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Jorge Drumond</forenames></author></authors><title>On the global uniqueness for the Einstein-Maxwell-scalar field system
  with a cosmological constant. Part 3: Mass inflation and extendibility of the
  solutions</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>48 pages, 5 figures; v2: some presentation changes, mostly in the
  Introduction; v3: substantial changes in Section 5; v4: expanded
  Introduction; some presentation changes; matches final published version</comments><msc-class>83C05 (Primary), 35Q76 (Secondary), 83C22, 83C57, 83C75</msc-class><journal-ref>Ann. PDE (2017) 3: 8</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40818-017-0028-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is the third part of a trilogy dedicated to the following problem:
given spherically symmetric characteristic initial data for the
Einstein-Maxwell-scalar field system with a cosmological constant $\Lambda$,
with the data on the outgoing initial null hypersurface given by a subextremal
Reissner-Nordstrom black hole event horizon, study the future extendibility of
the corresponding maximal globally hyperbolic development as a &quot;suitably
regular&quot; Lorentzian manifold.
  In the first part of this series we established the well posedness of the
characteristic problem, whereas in the second part we studied the stability of
the radius function at the Cauchy horizon.
  In this third and final paper we show that, depending on the decay rate of
the initial data, mass inflation may or may not occur. When the mass is
controlled, it is possible to obtain continuous extensions of the metric across
the Cauchy horizon with square integrable Christoffel symbols. Under slightly
stronger conditions, we can bound the gradient of the scalar field. This allows
the construction of (non-isometric) extensions of the maximal development which
are classical solutions of the Einstein equations. Our results provide evidence
against the validity of the strong cosmic censorship conjecture when
$\Lambda&gt;0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.7280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.7280</id><created>2014-10-27</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ravent&#xf3;s</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gra&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewenstein</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juli&#xe1;-D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author></authors><title>Cold bosons in optical lattices: a tutorial for Exact Diagonalization</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>33 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 50 (2017) 113001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa68b1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exact diagonalization techniques are a powerful method for studying many-body
problems. Here, we apply this method to systems of few bosons in an optical
lattice, and use it to demonstrate the emergence of interesting quantum
phenomena like fragmentation and coherence. Starting with a standard
Bose-Hubbard Hamiltonian, we first revise the characterization of the
superfluid to Mott insulator transitions. We then consider an inhomogeneous
lattice, where one potential minimum is made much deeper than the others. The
Mott insulator phase due to repulsive on-site interactions then competes with
the trapping of all atoms in the deep potential. Finally, we turn our attention
to attractively interacting systems, and discuss the appearance of strongly
correlated phases and the onset of localization for a slightly biased lattice.
The article is intended to serve as a tutorial for exact diagonalization of
Bose-Hubbard models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.3205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.3205</id><created>2014-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Pinaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raju</keyname><forenames>Md.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manna</keyname><forenames>Gargi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Jyoti Prasad</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified Hamiltonian formalism for Regge Teitelboim Cosmology</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 0 figures, Accepted in Physics Research International
  (article in press). arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1307.4920, arXiv:1005.3941 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>Physics Research International Volume 2014, Article ID 606727</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2014/606727</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Ostrogradski approach for the Hamiltonian formalism of higher derivative
theory is not satisfactory because of the reason that the Lagrangian cannot be
viewed as a function on the tangent bundle to coordinate manifold. In this
article, we have used an alternative approach which leads directly to the
Lagrangian which, being a function on the tangent manifold, gives correct
equation of motion; no new coordinate variables need to be added. This approach
can be directly used to the singular (in Ostrogradski sense) Lagrangian. We
have used this method for the Regge Teitelboim (RT) minisuperspace cosmological
model. We have obtained the Hamiltonian of the dynamical equation of the scale
factor of RT model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03126</id><created>2015-05-12</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schweigler</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasper</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erne</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazets</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauer</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cataldini</keyname><forenames>Federica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langen</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasenzer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berges</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmiedmayer</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author></authors><title>On solving quantum many-body problems by experiment</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nature 545, 323 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature22310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Knowledge of all correlation functions of a system is equivalent to solving
the corresponding many-body problem. Already a finite set of correlation
functions can be sufficient to describe a quantum many-body system if
correlations factorise, at least approximately. While being a powerful
theoretical concept, an implementation based on experimental data has so far
remained elusive. Here, this is achieved by applying it to a non-trivial
quantum many-body problem: A pair of tunnel-coupled one-dimensional atomic
superfluids. From measured interference patterns we extract phase correlation
functions up to tenth order and analyse if, and under which conditions, they
factorise. This characterises the essential features of the system, the
relevant quasiparticles, their interactions and possible topologically distinct
vacua. We verify that in thermal equilibrium the physics can be described by
the quantum sine-Gordon model, relevant for a wide variety of disciplines from
particle to condensed-matter physics. Our experiment establishes a general
method to analyse quantum many-body systems in experiments. It represents a
crucial ingredient towards the implementation and verification of quantum
simulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03887</id><created>2015-05-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>Shimon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masson</keyname><forenames>Etienne Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindenstrauss</keyname><forenames>Elon</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Ergodicity and Averaging Operators on the Sphere</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><journal-ref>Int Math Res Notices (2016) 2016 (19): 6034-6064</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove quantum ergodicity for certain orthonormal bases of
$L^2(\mathbb{S}^2)$, consisting of joint eigenfunctions of the Laplacian on
$\mathbb{S}^2$ and the discrete averaging operator over a finite set of
rotations, generating a free group. If in addition the rotations are algebraic
we give a quantified version of this result. The methods used also give a new,
simplified proof of quantum ergodicity for large regular graphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04087</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Peric</keyname><forenames>Robinson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdel-Maksoud</keyname><forenames>Moustafa</forenames></author></authors><title>Reliable Damping of Free Surface Waves in Numerical Simulations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Please cite the published, peer-reviewed article in the journal &quot;Ship
  Technology Research&quot;, Volume 63, 2016 - Issue 1,
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09377255.2015.1119921</comments><doi>10.1080/09377255.2015.1119921</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper generalizes existing approaches for free-surface wave damping via
momentum sinks for flow simulations based on the Navier-Stokes equations. It is
shown in 2D flow simulations that, to obtain reliable wave damping, the
coefficients in the damping functions must be adjusted to the wave parameters.
A scaling law for selecting these damping coefficients is presented, which
enables similarity of the damping in model- and full-scale. The influence of
the thickness of the damping layer, the wave steepness, the mesh fineness and
the choice of the damping coefficients are examined. An efficient approach for
estimating the optimal damping setup is presented. Results of 3D ship
resistance computations show that the scaling laws apply to such simulations as
well, so the damping coefficients should be adjusted for every simulation to
ensure convergence of the solution in both model and full scale. Finally,
practical recommendations for the setup of reliable damping in flow simulations
with regular and irregular free surface waves are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05886</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bourjaily</keyname><forenames>Jacob L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trnka</keyname><forenames>Jaroslav</forenames></author></authors><title>Local Integrand Representations of All Two-Loop Amplitudes in Planar SYM</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Corrections made including an important erratum: merging finite
  integrands does not always result in finite integrals. Language modified to
  reflect this fact, but implications are left to future work. 58 pages, 85
  figures, and a Mathematica package (with a demonstration notebook)</comments><report-no>CALT-TH-2015-026</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2015)119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use generalized unitarity at the integrand-level to directly construct
local, manifestly dual-conformally invariant formulae for all two-loop
scattering amplitudes in planar, maximally supersymmetric Yang-Mills theory
(SYM). This representation separates contributions into manifestly finite and
divergent terms---in a way that makes manifest the exponentiation of infrared
divergences at the integrand-level. These results perfectly match the all-loop
BCFW recursion relations, to which we provide a closed-form solution valid
through two-loop-order. Finally, we describe and document a Mathematica package
which implements these results, available as part of this work's source files
on the arXiv.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03983</id><created>2015-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Fibich</keyname><forenames>Gadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shpigelman</keyname><forenames>Dima</forenames></author></authors><title>Positive and necklace solitary waves on bounded domains</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>43 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physica D 315: 13-32, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physd.2015.09.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new solitarywave solutions of the two-dimensional nonlinear
Schrodinger equation on bounded domains (such as rectangles, circles, and
annuli). These multipeak necklace solitary waves consist of several identical
positive profiles (pearls), such that adjacent pearls have opposite signs. They
are stable at low powers, but become unstable at powers well below the critical
power for collapse Pcr. This is in contrast with the ground-state
(single-pearl) solitary waves on bounded domains, which are stable at any power
below Pcr. On annular domains, the ground state solitary waves are radial at
low powers, but undergo a symmetry breaking at a threshold power well below
Pcr. As in the case of convex bounded domains, necklace solitary waves on the
annulus are stable at low powers and become unstable at powers well below Pcr.
Unlike on convex bounded domains, however, necklace solitarywaves on the
annulus have a second stability regime at powers well above Pcr. For example,
when the ratio of the inner to outer radii is 1:2, four-pearl necklaces are
stable when their power is between 3.1Pcr and 3.7Pcr. This finding opens the
possibility to propagate localized laser beams with substantiallymore power
than was possible until now. The instability of necklace solitary waves is
excited by perturbations that break the antisymmetry between adjacent pearls,
and is manifested by power transfer between pearls. In particular, necklace
instability is unrelated to collapse. In order to compute numerically the
profile of necklace solitary waves on bounded domains, we introduce a
non-spectral variant of Petviashvilis renormalization method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07414</id><created>2015-09-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Koenig</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholz</keyname><forenames>Volkher B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix product approximations to conformal field theories</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.str-el math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>105 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B 920, 32-121 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.04.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish rigorous error bounds for approximating correlation functions of
conformal field theories (CFTs) by certain finite-dimensional tensor networks.
For chiral CFTs, the approximation takes the form of a matrix product state.
For full CFTs consisting of a chiral and an anti-chiral part, the approximation
is given by a finitely correlated state. We show that the bond dimension scales
polynomially in the inverse of the approximation error and sub-exponentially in
the ultraviolett cutoff. We illustrate our findings using Wess-Zumino-Witten
models, and show that there is a one-to-one correspondence between
group-covariant MPS and our approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07240</id><created>2015-10-25</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Holanda</keyname><forenames>R. F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landau</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcaniz</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G.</keyname><forenames>I. E. Sanchez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busti</keyname><forenames>V. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on a possible variation of the fine structure constant from
  galaxy cluster data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, accepted for publication in JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/05/047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new method to probe a possible time evolution of the fine
structure constant $\alpha$ from X-ray and Sunyaev-Zeldovich measurements of
the gas mass fraction ($f_{gas}$) in galaxy clusters. Taking into account a
direct relation between variations of $\alpha$ and violations of the
distance-duality relation, we discuss constraints on $\alpha$ for a class of
dilaton runaway models. Although not yet competitive with bounds from high-$z$
quasar absorption systems, our constraints, considering a sample of 29
measurements of $f_{gas}$, in the redshift interval $0.14 &lt; z &lt; 0.89$, provide
an independent estimate of $\alpha$ variation at low and intermediate
redshifts. Furthermore, current and planned surveys will provide a larger
amount of data and thus allow to improve the limits on $\alpha$ variation
obtained in the present analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01769</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reinhardt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Tina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourassa</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sankey</keyname><forenames>Jack C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultralow-Noise SiN Trampoline Resonators for Sensing and Optomechanics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 021001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.021001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In force sensing, optomechanics, and quantum motion experiments, it is
typically advantageous to create lightweight, compliant mechanical elements
with the lowest possible force noise. Here we report wafer-scale batch
fabrication and characterization of high-aspect-ratio, nanogram-scale
Si$_3$N$_4$ &quot;trampolines&quot; having quality factors above $4 \times 10^7$ and
ringdown times exceeding five minutes (1 mHz linewidth). We measure a thermally
limited force noise sensitivity of 16.2$\pm$0.8 aN/Hz$^{1/2}$ at room
temperature, with a spring constant ($\sim$1 N/m) 2-5 orders of magnitude
larger than those of competing technologies. We also characterize the
suitability of these devices for high-finesse cavity readout and optomechanics
applications, finding no evidence of surface or bulk optical losses from the
processed nitride in a cavity achieving finesse 40,000. These parameters
provide access to a single-photon cooperativity $C_0 \sim 8$ in the
resolved-sideband limit, wherein a variety of outstanding optomechanics goals
become feasible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05308</id><created>2015-12-16</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames><affiliation>UC Santa Cruz</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Hamiltonian Dynamics of Planar Magnetic Confinement</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, quantum comparison added</comments><msc-class>78A30 (Primary), 70H07 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by a question of Colin de Verdi\`{e}re and Truc we study the
dynamics of a classical charged particle moving in a bounded planar domain
$\Omega$ under the influence of a magnetic field $\mathbf{B}$ which blows up at
the boundary of the domain. We prove that under appropriate blow-up conditions
the particle will never reach the boundary. As a corollary we obtain
completeness of the magnetic flow. Our blow-up condition is that $\mathbf{B}$
should not be integrable along normal rays to the boundary, while its
tangential derivative should be integrable along those same rays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07353</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>W. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>F. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antineutrino flux and spectrum calculation for spent nuclear fuel for
  the Daya Bay antineutrino experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spent nuclear fuel (SNF) antineutrino flux is an important source of
uncertainties for a reactor neutrino flux prediction. However, if one want to
determine the contribution of spent fuel, many data are needed, such as the
amount of spent fuel in the pool, the time after discharged from the reactor
core, the burnup of each assembly, and the antineutrino spectrum of the
isotopes in the spend fuel. A method to calculate the contribution of SNF is
proposed in this study. In this method, reactor simulation code verified by
experiment have been used to simulate the fuel depletion by taking into account
more than 2000 isotopes and fission products, the quantity of SNF in each six
spend fuel pool, and the antineutrino spectrum of SNF varying with time after
SNF discharged from core. Results show that the contribution of SNF to the
total antineutrino flux is about 0.26%~0.34%, and the shutdown impact is about
20%. The SNF spectrum would distort the softer part of antineutrino spectra,
and the maximum contribution from SNF is about 3.0%, but there is 18\%
difference between line evaluate method and under evaluate method. In addition,
non-equilibrium effects are also discussed, and the results are compatible with
theirs considering the uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04664</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Colombaro</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giusti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainardi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>A class of linear viscoelastic models based on Bessel functions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><msc-class>74D05, 76A10, 30B50, 33C10, 44A10</msc-class><journal-ref>Meccanica (2017) 52: 825</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11012-016-0456-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate a general class of linear viscoelastic models
whose creep and relaxation memory functions are expressed in Laplace domain by
suitable ratios of modified Bessel functions of contiguous order. In time
domain these functions are shown to be expressed by Dirichlet series (that is
infinite Prony series). It follows that the corresponding creep compliance and
relaxation modulus turn out to be characterized by infinite discrete spectra of
retardation and relaxation time respectively. As a matter of fact, we get a
class of viscoelastic models depending on a real parameter $\nu &gt; -1$. Such
models exhibit rheological properties akin to those of a fractional Maxwell
model (of order $1/2$) for short times and of a standard Maxwell model for long
times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00302</id><created>2016-05-01</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jerby</keyname><forenames>Yochay</forenames></author></authors><title>On Landau-Ginzburg systems and $\mathcal{D}^b(X)$ of various toric Fano
  manifolds with small picard group</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>The following is an extensively extended version of arXiv:1412.2687</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a toric Fano manifold $X$ denote by $Crit(X) \subset
(\mathbb{C}^{\ast})^n$ the solution scheme of the Landau-Ginzburg system of
equations of $X$. Examples of toric Fano manifolds with $rk(Pic(X)) \leq 3$
which admit full strongly exceptional collections of line bundles were recently
found by various authors. For these examples we construct a map $E : Crit(X)
\rightarrow Pic(X)$ whose image $\mathcal{E}=\left \{ E(z) \vert z \in Crit(X)
\right \}$ is a full strongly exceptional collection satisfying the M-aligned
property. That is, under this map, the groups $Hom(E(z),E(w))$ for $z,w \in
Crit(X)$ are naturally related to the structure of the monodromy group acting
on $Crit(X)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03615</id><created>2016-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Fibich</keyname><forenames>Gadi</forenames></author></authors><title>Bass-SIR model for diffusion of new products</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94: 032305, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the diffusion of new products in social networks, where consumers
who adopt the product can later &quot;recover&quot; and stop influencing others to adopt
the product. We show that the diffusion is not described by the SIR model, but
rather by a novel model, the Bass-SIR model, which combines the Bass model for
diffusion of new products with the SIR model for epidemics. The phase
transition of consumers from non-adopters to adopters is described by a
non-standard Kolmogorov-Johnson-Mehl-Avrami model, in which clusters growth is
limited by adopters' recovery. Therefore, diffusion in the Bass-SIR model only
depends on the local structure of the social network, but not on the average
distance between consumers. Consequently, unlike the SIR model, a small-worlds
structure has a negligible effect on the diffusion. Surprisingly, diffusion on
scale-free networks is nearly identical to that on Cartesian ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03736</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buryak</keyname><forenames>Alexandr</forenames></author></authors><title>Double ramification cycles and the $n$-point function for the moduli
  space of curves</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Revised version, 10 pages, to be published in the Moscow Mathematical
  Journal</comments><journal-ref>Moscow Mathematical Journal 17 (2017), no. 1, 1-13</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, using the formula for the integrals of the $\psi$-classes over
the double ramification cycles found by S. Shadrin, L. Spitz, D. Zvonkine and
the author, we derive a new explicit formula for the $n$-point function of the
intersection numbers on the moduli space of curves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03953</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-08-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ihle</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Chapman-Enskog expansion for the Vicsek model of self-propelled
  particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/08/083205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the standard Vicsek model, I show how the macroscopic transport
equations can be systematically derived from microscopic collision rules. The
approach starts with the exact evolution equation for the N-particle
probability distribution, and after making the mean-field assumption of
Molecular Chaos leads to a multi-particle Enskog-type equation. This equation
is treated by a non-standard Chapman-Enskog expansion to extract the
macroscopic behavior. The expansion includes terms up to third order in a
formal expansion parameter $\epsilon$, and involves a fast time scale. A
self-consistent closure of the moment equations is presented that leads to a
continuity equation for the particle density and a Navier-Stokes-like equation
for the momentum density. Expressions for all transport coefficients in these
macroscopic equations are given explicitly in terms of microscopic parameters
of the model. The transport coefficients depend on specific angular integrals
which are evaluated asymptotically in the limit of infinitely many collision
partners, using an analogy to a random walk. The consistency of the
Chapman-Enskog approach is checked by an independent calculation of the shear
viscosity using a Green-Kubo relation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05775</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stoudenmire</keyname><forenames>E. Miles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supervised Learning with Quantum-Inspired Tensor Networks</title><categories>stat.ML cond-mat.str-el cs.LG</categories><comments>11 pages, 15 figures; updated version includes corrections, links to
  sample codes, expanded discussion, and additional references</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 29, 4799 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tensor networks are efficient representations of high-dimensional tensors
which have been very successful for physics and mathematics applications. We
demonstrate how algorithms for optimizing such networks can be adapted to
supervised learning tasks by using matrix product states (tensor trains) to
parameterize models for classifying images. For the MNIST data set we obtain
less than 1% test set classification error. We discuss how the tensor network
form imparts additional structure to the learned model and suggest a possible
generative interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06476</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2016-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Harold Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ofori-Okai</keyname><forenames>Benjamin K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurihara</keyname><forenames>Takayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suemoto</keyname><forenames>Tohru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional terahertz magnetic resonance spectroscopy of collective
  spin waves</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>26 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 207204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.207204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear manipulation of nuclear and electron spins is the basis for all
advanced methods in magnetic resonance including multidimensional nuclear
magnetic and electron spin resonance spectroscopies, magnetic resonance
imaging, and in recent years, quantum control over individual spins. The
methodology is facilitated by the ease with which the regime of strong coupling
can be reached between radiofrequency or microwave magnetic fields and nuclear
or electron spins respectively, typified by sequences of magnetic pulses that
control the magnetic moment directions. The capabilities meet a bottleneck,
however, for far-infrared magnetic resonances characteristic of correlated
electron materials, molecular magnets, and proteins that contain high-spin
transition metal ions. Here we report the development of two-dimensional
terahertz magnetic resonance spectroscopy and its use for direct observation of
the nonlinear responses of collective spin waves (magnons). The spectra show
magnon spin echoes and 2-quantum signals that reveal pairwise correlations
between magnons at the Brillouin zone center. They also show resonance-enhanced
second-harmonic and difference-frequency signals. Our methods are readily
generalizable to multidimensional magnetic resonance spectroscopy and nonlinear
coherent control of terahertz-frequency spin systems in molecular complexes,
biomolecules, and materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03996</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andreon</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raichoor</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Size growth of red-sequence early-type galaxies in clusters in the last
  10 Gyr</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>A&amp;A 593, A2 (2016) after revision of the z=1.63 cluster name,
  mis-typed in previous version. No result of our paper is affected by having
  mis-typed the cluster name</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628442</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We carried out a photometric and structural analysis in the rest-frame $V$
band of a mass-selected ($\log M/M_\odot &gt;10.7$) sample of red-sequence
galaxies in 14 galaxy clusters, 6 of which are at $z&gt;1.45$. To this end, we
reduced/analyzed about 300 orbits of multicolor images taken with the Advanced
Camera for Survey and the Wide Field Camera 3 on the Hubble Space Telescope. We
uniformly morphologically classified galaxies from $z=0.023$ to $z=1.803$, and
we homogeneously derived sizes (effective radii) for the entire sample.
Furthermore, our size derivation allows, and therefore is not biased by, the
presence of the usual variety of morphological structures seen in early-type
galaxies, such as bulges, bars, disks, isophote twists, and ellipiticy
gradients. By using such a mass-selected sample, composed of 244 red-sequence
early-type galaxies, we find that the $\log$ of the galaxy size at a fixed
stellar mass, $\log M/M_\odot= 11$ has increased with time at a rate of
$0.023\pm0.002$ dex per Gyr over the last 10 Gyr, in marked contrast with the
threefold increase found in the literature for galaxies in the general field
over the same period. This suggests, at face value, that secular processes
should be excluded as the primary drivers of size evolution because we observed
an environmental environmental dependent size growth. Using spectroscopic ages
of Coma early-type galaxies we also find that recently quenched early-type
galaxies are a numerically minor population not different enough in size to
alter the mean size at a given mass, which implies that the progenitor bias is
minor, i.e., that the size evolution measured by selecting galaxies at the
redshift of observation is indistinguishable from the one that compares
ancestors and descendents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04426</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2016-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhuvaneswari</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nithyanandan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muruganandam</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porsezian</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation instability in quasi two-dimensional spin-orbit coupled
  Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.PS</categories><comments>11 pages, 17 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 245301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/24/245301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate the dynamics of modulation instability (MI) in
two-dimensional spin-orbit coupled Bose-Einstein condensates (BECs). The
analysis is performed for equal densities of pseudo-spin components. Different
combination of the signs of intra- and inter-component interaction strengths
are considered, with a particular emphasize on repulsive interactions. We
observe that the unstable modulation builds from originally miscible
condensates, depending on the combination of the signs of the intra- and
inter-component interaction strengths. The repulsive intra- and inter-component
interactions admit instability and the MI immiscibility condition is no longer
significant. Influence of interaction parameters such as spin-orbit and Rabi
coupling on MI are also investigated. The spin-orbit coupling (SOC) inevitably
contributes to instability regardless of the nature of the interaction. In the
case of attractive interaction, SOC manifest in enhancing the MI. Thus, a
comprehensive study of MI in two-dimensional spin-orbit coupled binary BECs of
pseudo-spin components is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07090</id><created>2016-07-24</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Korcyl</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bali</keyname><forenames>Gunnar S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-perturbative determination of improvement coefficients using
  coordinate space correlators in $N_f=2+1$ lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, version published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 014505 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.014505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine quark mass dependent order $a$ improvement terms of the form
$b_Jam$ for non-singlet scalar, pseudoscalar, vector and axialvector currents
using correlators in coordinate space on a set of CLS ensembles. These have
been generated employing non-perturbatively improved Wilson Fermions and the
tree-level L\&quot;uscher-Weisz gauge action at $\beta = 3.4, 3.46, 3.55$ and $3.7$,
corresponding to lattice spacings ranging from $a \approx 0.085$ fm down to
$0.05$ fm. In the $N_f=2+1$ flavour theory two types of improvement
coefficients exist: $b_J$, proportional to non-singlet quark mass combinations,
and $\bar{b}_J$ (or $\tilde{b}_J$), proportional to the trace of the quark mass
matrix. Combining our non-perturbative determinations with perturbative
results, we quote Pad\'e approximants parameterizing the $b_J$ improvement
coefficients within the above window of lattice spacings. We also give
preliminary results for $\tilde{b}_J$ at $\beta=3.4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01414</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crump</keyname><forenames>Iain</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of the Extended Graph Permanent</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP math.NT</categories><comments>40 pages, 4 figures, containing corrections from referee reports</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previously, the graph permanent was introduced as a single-valued invariant
for graphs $G$ with $|E(G)| = k(|V(G)|-1)$ for some $k \in \mathbb{Z}_{&gt;0}$.
Herein, we construct the extended graph permanent, an infinite sequence for all
graphs. We prove that, like the graph permanent, the extended graph permanent
is invariant under the graph operations that are known to preserve the period.
Further, the original construction and extension arise from permanents of
matrices, but we construct a novel graph polynomial such that the sequence can
be generated from the point count of this polynomial, as a residue over
prime-order finite fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05154</id><created>2016-08-17</created><updated>2017-02-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Araki</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Differential-geometrical approach to the dynamics of dissipationless
  incompressible Hall magnetohydrodynamics: II. Geodesic formulation and
  Riemannian curvature analysis of hydrodynamic and magnetohydrodynamic
  stabilities</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 6 figures. In this version discussion about comparison of
  the curvature analysis with the energy-Casimir method is fully rewritten
  using a remarkable constant of motion which relates the Riemannian curvature
  to the second variation of the Hamiltonian</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 235501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa60fc</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, the dynamics of a dissipationless incompressible Hall
magnetohydrodynamic (HMHD) medium are formulated as geodesics on a direct
product of two volume-preserving diffeomorphism groups. Formulations are given
for the geodesic and Jacobi equations based on a linear connection with
physically desirable properties, which agrees with the Levi-Civita connection.
Derivations of the explicit normal-mode expressions for the Riemannian metric,
Levi-Civita connection, and related formulae and equations are also provided
using the generalized Els\&quot;asser variables (GEVs). Examinations of the
stabilities of the hydrodynamic (HD, $\alpha=0$) and magnetohydrodynamic (MHD,
$\alpha\to0$) motions and the $O(\alpha)$ Hall-term effect in terms of the
Jacobi equation and the Riemannian sectional curvature tensor are presented,
where $\alpha$ represents the Hall-term strength parameter. It is very
interesting that the sectional curvatures of the MHD and HMHD systems between
two GEV modes were found to take both the positive (stable) and negative
(unstable) values, while that of the HD system between two complex helical
waves was observed to be negative definite. Moreover, for the MHD case,
negative sectional curvatures were found to occur only when mode interaction
was &quot;local,&quot; i.e., the wavenumber moduli of the main flow (say $p$) and
perturbation (say $k$) were close to each other ($k \approx p$). However, in
the nonlocal limit ($k \gg p$ or $k \ll p$), the sectional curvatures were
always positive. This result leads to the conjecture that the MHD interactions
mainly excite wavy or non-growing motions; however, some local interactions
cause dynamical instability that leads to chaotic or turbulent plasma motions.
Additionally, it was found that the tendencies of the $O(\alpha)$ effects are
opposite between the ion cyclotron and whistler modes. Comparison with
energy-Casimir method is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07227</id><created>2016-08-25</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bizo&#x144;</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craps</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evnin</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunik</keyname><forenames>Dominika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luyten</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maliborski</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal flow on $S^3$ and weak field integrability in AdS$_4$</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>22 pages, v2: minor revisions, several references added, v3: typos
  corrected, v4: typos corrected, one reference added, matches version accepted
  by CMP</comments><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 353 (2017) 1179</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2896-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the conformally invariant cubic wave equation on the Einstein
cylinder $\mathbb{R} \times \mathbb{S}^3$ for small rotationally symmetric
initial data. This simple equation captures many key challenges of nonlinear
wave dynamics in confining geometries, while a conformal transformation relates
it to a self-interacting conformally coupled scalar in four-dimensional anti-de
Sitter spacetime (AdS$_4$) and connects it to various questions of AdS
stability. We construct an effective infinite-dimensional time-averaged
dynamical system accurately approximating the original equation in the weak
field regime. It turns out that this effective system, which we call the
conformal flow, exhibits some remarkable features, such as low-dimensional
invariant subspaces, a wealth of stationary states (for which energy does not
flow between the modes), as well as solutions with nontrivial exactly periodic
energy flows. Based on these observations and close parallels to the cubic
Szego equation, which was shown by Gerard and Grellier to be Lax-integrable, it
is tempting to conjecture that the conformal flow and the corresponding weak
field dynamics in AdS$_4$ are integrable as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02180</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-05-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yurovsky</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames><affiliation>School of Chemistry, Tel Aviv University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Phase transitions in definite total spin states of two-component Fermi
  gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>Final submitted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 200403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.200403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Second-order phase transitions have no latent heat and are characterized by a
change in symmetry. In addition to the conventional symmetric and
anti-symmetric states under permutations of bosons and fermions, mathematical
group-representation theory allows for non-Abelian permutation symmetry. Such
symmetry can be hidden in states with defined total spins of spinor gases,
which can be formed in optical cavities. The present work shows that the
symmetry reveals itself in spin-independent or coordinate-independent
properties of these gases, namely as non-Abelian entropy in thermodynamic
properties. In weakly interacting Fermi gases, two phases appear associated
with fermionic and non-Abelian symmetry under permutations of particle states,
respectively. The second-order transitions between the phases are characterized
by discontinuities in specific heat. Unlike other phase transitions, the
present ones are not caused by interactions and can appear even in ideal gases.
Similar effects in Bose gases and strong interactions are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03975</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vovchenko</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorenstein</keyname><forenames>Mark I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoecker</keyname><forenames>Horst</forenames></author></authors><title>van der Waals Interactions in Hadron Resonance Gas: From Nuclear Matter
  to Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, final version published in Physical Review
  Letters, minor misprints corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 182301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.182301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An extension of the ideal hadron resonance gas (HRG) model is constructed
which includes the attractive and repulsive van der Waals (VDW) interactions
between baryons. This VDW-HRG model yields the nuclear liquid-gas transition at
low temperatures and high baryon densities. The VDW parameters $a$ and $b$ are
fixed by the ground state properties of nuclear matter, and the temperature
dependence of various thermodynamic observables at zero chemical potential are
calculated within VDW-HRG model. Compared to the ideal HRG model, the inclusion
of VDW interactions between baryons leads to a qualitatively different behavior
of second and higher moments of fluctuations of conserved charges, in
particular in the so-called crossover region $T\sim 140 - 190$ MeV. For many
observables this behavior resembles closely the results obtained from lattice
QCD simulations. This hadronic model also predicts nontrivial behavior of
net-baryon fluctuations in the region of phase diagram probed by heavy-ion
collision experiments. These results imply that VDW interactions play a crucial
role in thermodynamics of hadron gas. Thus, the commonly performed comparisons
of the ideal HRG model with the lattice and heavy-ion data may lead to
misconceptions and misleading conclusions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08003</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Anufriev</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramiere</keyname><forenames>Aymeric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maire</keyname><forenames>Jeremie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat guiding and focusing using ballistic phonon transport in phononic
  nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1038/ncomms15505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike classical heat diffusion at the macroscale, nanoscale heat transport
can occur without energy dissipation because phonons can travel in straight
lines for hundreds of nanometres. Despite recent experimental evidence of such
ballistic phonon transport, control over its directionality, and thus its
practical use, remains a challenge, as the directions of individual phonons are
chaotic. Here, we show a way to control the directionality of ballistic phonon
transport using silicon thin-films with arrays of holes. First, we demonstrate
the formation of directional heat fluxes in the passages between the holes.
Next, we use these nanostructures as a directional source of ballistic phonons
and couple the emitted phonons into nanowires. Finally, we introduce a
nanoscale thermal lens in which the phonons converge at a focal point, thus
focusing heat into a spot of a few hundred nanometres. These results provide a
basis for ray-like heat manipulations that enable nanoscale heat guiding,
dissipation, localization, confinement and rectification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08592</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Quntao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Elton Yechao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shor</keyname><forenames>Peter W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Additive Classical Capacity of Quantum Channels Assisted by Noisy
  Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5+7 pages</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4835</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 200503 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.200503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a capacity formula for the classical information transmission over a
noisy quantum channel, with separable encoding by the sender and limited
resources provided by the receiver's pre-shared ancilla. Instead of a pure
state, we consider the signal-ancilla pair in a mixed state, purified by a
&quot;witness&quot;. Thus, the signal-witness correlation limits the resource available
from the signal-ancilla correlation. Our formula characterizes the utility of
different forms of resources, including noisy or limited entanglement
assistance, for classical communication. With separable encoding, the sender's
signals across multiple channel uses are still allowed to be entangled, yet our
capacity formula is additive. In particular, for generalized covariant channels
our capacity formula has a simple closed-form. Moreover, our additive capacity
formula upper bounds the general coherent attack's information gain in various
two-way quantum key distribution protocols. For Gaussian protocols, the
additivity of the formula indicates that the collective Gaussian attack is the
most powerful.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00453</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ath&#xe8;nes</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terrier</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating thermodynamic expectations and free energies in expanded
  ensemble simulations: systematic variance reduction through conditioning</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><msc-class>82-04, 82B80</msc-class><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 146, 194101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983164</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Markov chain Monte Carlo methods are primarily used for sampling from a given
probability distribution and estimating multi-dimensional integrals based on
the information contained in the generated samples. Whenever it is possible,
more accurate estimates are obtained by combining Monte Carlo integration and
integration by numerical quadrature along particular coordinates. We show that
this variance reduction technique, referred to as conditioning in probability
theory, can be advantageously implemented in \emph{expanded ensemble}
simulations. These simulations aim at estimating thermodynamic expectations as
a function of an external parameter that is sampled like an additional
coordinate. Conditioning therein entails integrating along the external
coordinate by numerical quadrature. We prove variance reduction with respect to
alternative standard estimators and demonstrate the practical efficiency of the
technique by estimating free energies and characterizing a structural phase
transition between two solid phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04579</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linder</keyname><forenames>Ashley N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plummer</keyname><forenames>George S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaevitz</keyname><forenames>Joshua W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leifer</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Automatically tracking neurons in a moving and deforming brain</title><categories>q-bio.NC cs.CV physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 7 figures, code available</comments><journal-ref>PLoS Comput Biol 13(5): e1005517 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Advances in optical neuroimaging techniques now allow neural activity to be
recorded with cellular resolution in awake and behaving animals. Brain motion
in these recordings pose a unique challenge. The location of individual neurons
must be tracked in 3D over time to accurately extract single neuron activity
traces. Recordings from small invertebrates like C. elegans are especially
challenging because they undergo very large brain motion and deformation during
animal movement. Here we present an automated computer vision pipeline to
reliably track populations of neurons with single neuron resolution in the
brain of a freely moving C. elegans undergoing large motion and deformation. 3D
volumetric fluorescent images of the animal's brain are straightened, aligned
and registered, and the locations of neurons in the images are found via
segmentation. Each neuron is then assigned an identity using a new
time-independent machine-learning approach we call Neuron Registration Vector
Encoding. In this approach, non-rigid point-set registration is used to match
each segmented neuron in each volume with a set of reference volumes taken from
throughout the recording. The way each neuron matches with the references
defines a feature vector which is clustered to assign an identity to each
neuron in each volume. Finally, thin-plate spline interpolation is used to
correct errors in segmentation and check consistency of assigned identities.
The Neuron Registration Vector Encoding approach proposed here is uniquely well
suited for tracking neurons in brains undergoing large deformations. When
applied to whole-brain calcium imaging recordings in freely moving C. elegans,
this analysis pipeline located 150 neurons for the duration of an 8 minute
recording and consistently found more neurons more quickly than manual or
semi-automated approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05368</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Vulis</keyname><forenames>Daryl I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reshef</keyname><forenames>Orad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camayd-Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Mei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kita</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lon&#x10d;ar</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazur</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Monolithic CMOS-compatible zero-index metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Exp. 25 (2017) 12381-12399</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.25.012381</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zero-index materials exhibit exotic optical properties that can be utilized
for integrated-optics applications. However, practical implementation requires
compatibility with complementary metallic-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS)
technologies. We demonstrate a CMOS-compatible zero-index metamaterial
consisting of a square array of air holes in a 220-nm-thick
silicon-on-insulator (SOI) wafer. This design is achieved through a Dirac-cone
dispersion. The metamaterial is entirely composed of silicon and offers
compatibility through low-aspect-ratio structures that can be simply fabricated
in a standard device layer. This platform enables mass adoption and exploration
of zero-index-based photonic devices at low cost and high fidelity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05614</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fehr</keyname><forenames>Serge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvail</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Authentication and Encryption with Key Recycling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This latest version fixes some minor mistakes of previous versions
  and contains a discussion on impersonation attacks (Section 4.6). A
  differently formatted version of (version v2 of) this article is available
  from the proceedings of Advances in Cryptology - EUROCRYPT 2017
  (Springer-Verlag), or from http://eprint.iacr.org/2017/102</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an information-theoretically secure encryption scheme for
classical messages with quantum ciphertexts that offers detection of
eavesdropping attacks, and re-usability of the key in case no eavesdropping
took place: the entire key can be securely re-used for encrypting new messages
as long as no attack is detected. This is known to be impossible for fully
classical schemes, where there is no way to detect plain eavesdropping attacks.
This particular application of quantum techniques to cryptography was
originally proposed by Bennett, Brassard and Breidbart in 1982, even before
proposing quantum-key-distribution, and a simple candidate scheme was suggested
but no rigorous security analysis was given. The idea was picked up again in
2005, when Damgard, Pedersen and Salvail suggested a new scheme for the same
task, but now with a rigorous security analysis. However, their scheme is much
more demanding in terms of quantum capabilities: it requires the users to have
a quantum computer. In contrast, and like the original scheme by Bennett et
al., our new scheme merely requires to prepare and measure single BB84 qubits.
As such, we not only show a provably-secure scheme that is within reach of
current technology, but we also confirm Bennett et al.'s original intuition
that a scheme in the spirit of their original construction is indeed secure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05958</id><created>2016-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Colombaro</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giusti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainardi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>A one parameter class of Fractional Maxwell-like models</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.CV math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>74D05, 76A10, 33C10, 44A10, 26A33, 34A08</msc-class><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. (2017) 1836, 020003-1-020003-6</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981943</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss a one parameter modification of the well known
fractional Maxwell model of viscoelasticity. Such models appear to be
particularly interesting because they describe the short time asymptotic limit
of a more general class of viscoelastic models known in the literature as
Bessel models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08839</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rastegin</keyname><forenames>Alexey E.</forenames></author></authors><title>R\'enyi formulation of entanglement criteria for continuous variables</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures. With final corrections, the paper matches the
  journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042334 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042334</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement criteria for an $n$-partite quantum system with continuous
variables are formulated in terms of R\'{e}nyi entropies. R\'{e}nyi entropies
are widely used as a good information measure due to many nice properties.
Derived entanglement criteria are based on several mathematical results such as
the Hausdorff-Young inequality, Young's inequality for convolution and its
converse. From the historical viewpoint, the formulations of these results with
sharp constants were obtained comparatively recently. Using the position and
momentum observables of subsystems, one can build two total-system measurements
with the following property. For product states, the final density in each
global measurement appears as a convolution of $n$ local densities. Hence,
restrictions in terms of two R\'{e}nyi entropies with constrained entropic
indices are formulated for $n$-separable states of an $n$-partite quantum
system with continuous variables. Experimental results are typically sampled
into bins between prescribed discrete points. For these aims, we give
appropriate reformulations of the derived entanglement criteria.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00624</id><created>2016-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>K&#xfc;rsten</keyname><forenames>R&#xfc;diger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ihle</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical assessment of von Mises distribution and an infinite series
  ansatz for self-propelled particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures, 1 table</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa5ec8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a Vicsek model of self-propelled particles with bounded
confidence, where each particle interacts only with neighbors that have a
similar direction. Depending on parameters, the system exhibits a continuous or
discontinuous polar phase transition from the isotropic phase to a phase with a
preferred direction. In a recent paper [1] the von Mises distribution was
proposed as an ansatz for polar ordering. In the present system the time
evolution of the angular distribution can be solved in Fourier space. We
compare the results of the Fourier analysis with the ones obtained by using the
von Mises distribution ansatz. In the latter case the qualitative behavior of
the system is recovered correctly. However, quantitatively there are serious
deviations. We introduce an extended von Mises distribution ansatz such that a
second term takes care of the next two Fourier modes. With the extended ansatz
we find much better quantitative agreement. As an alternative approach we also
use a Gaussian and a geometric series ansatz in Fourier space. The geometric
series ansatz is analytically handable but fails for very weak noise, the
Gaussian ansatz yields better results but it is not analytically treatable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01894</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yokoshi</keyname><forenames>Nobuhiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odagiri</keyname><forenames>Kazuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishihara</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization dynamics in a designed open system</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 203601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.203601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically propose a unifying expression for synchronization dynamics
between two-level constituents. Although synchronization phenomena require some
substantial mediators, the distinct repercussions of their propagation delays
remain obscure, especially in open systems. Our scheme directly incorporates
the details of the constituents and mediators in an arbitrary environment. As
one example, we demonstrate the synchronization dynamics of optical emitters on
a dielectric microsphere. We reveal that the whispering gallery modes (WGMs)
bridge the well-separated emitters and accelerate the synchronized
fluorescence, known as superfluorescence. The emitters are found to overcome
the significant and nonuniform retardation, and to build up their pronounced
coherence by the WGMs, striking a balance between the roles of resonator and
intermediary. Our work directly illustrates the dynamical aspects of many-body
synchronizations and contributes to the exploration of research paradigms that
consider designed open systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03479</id><created>2016-11-08</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>Kamal K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmailov</keyname><forenames>Ramil N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanbekov</keyname><forenames>Almir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shayakhmetov</keyname><forenames>Azat A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ring-down gravitational waves and lensing observables: How far can a
  wormhole mimic those of a black hole?</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>24 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 104011 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.104011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been argued that the recently detected ring-down gravity waveforms
could be indicative only of the presence of light rings in a horizonless
object, such as a surgical Schwarzschild wormhole, with the frequencies
differing drastically from those of the horizon quasinormal mode frequencies
$\omega _{\text{QNM}}$ at late times. While the possibility of such a
horizonless alternative is novel by itself, we show by the example of
Ellis-Bronnikov wormhole that the differences in $\omega _{\text{QNM}}$ in the
eikonal limit (large $l$) need not be drastic. This result will be reached by
exploiting the connection between $\omega _{\text{QNM}}$ and the Bozza strong
field lensing parameters. We shall also show that the lensing observables of
the Ellis-Bronnikov wormhole can also be very close to those of a black hole
(say, SgrA$^{\ast }$ hosted by our galaxy) of the same mass. This situation
indicates that the ring-down frequencies and lensing observables of the
Ellis-Bronnikov wormhole can remarkably mimic those of a black hole. The
constraint on wormhole parameter $\gamma $ imposed by experimental accuracy is
briefly discussed. We also provide independent arguments supporting the
stability of the Ellis-Bronnikov wormhole proven recently.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04571</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reig</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valle</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; W. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaquera-Araujo</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-family left-right symmetry with low-scale seesaw mechanism</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures. Revised version as accepted by JHEP</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-XX</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)100</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest a new left-right symmetric model implementing a low-scale seesaw
mechanism in which quantum consistency requires three families of fermions. The
symmetry breaking route to the Standard Model determines the profile of the
&quot;next&quot; expected new physics, characterized either by the simplest left-right
gauge symmetry or by the 3-3-1 scenario. The resulting $Z^\prime$ gauge bosons
can be probed at the LHC and provide a production portal for the right-handed
neutrinos. On the other hand, its flavor changing interactions would affect the
K, D and B neutral meson systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04775</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Wenchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Mengqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Xiangyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Fazhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Jiangfeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Demonstration of Uncertainty Relations for the Triple
  Components of Angular Momentum</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 180402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.180402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The uncertainty principle is considered to be one of the most striking
features in quantum mechanics. In the textbook literature, uncertainty
relations usually refer to the preparation uncertainty which imposes a
limitation on the spread of measurement outcomes for a pair of non-commuting
observables. In this work, we study the preparation uncertainty for the angular
momentum, especially in the spin-1/2 representation. We derive uncertainty
relations encompassing the triple components of angular momentum, and show that
compared with the relations involving only two components, a triple constant
$2/\sqrt{3}$ often arises. Intriguingly, this constant is the same for the
position and momentum case. Experimental verification is carried out on a
single spin in diamond, and the results confirm the triple constant in a wide
range of experimental parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05229</id><created>2016-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lizuain</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmero</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muga</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical normal modes for time-dependent Hamiltonians in two dimensions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 022130 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.022130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the theory of time-dependent point transformations to find
independent dynamical normal modes for 2D systems subjected to time-dependent
control in the limit of small oscillations. The condition that determines if
the independent modes can indeed be defined is identified, and a geometrical
analogy is put forward. The results explain and unify recent work to design
fast operations on trapped ions, needed to implement a scalable
quantum-information architecture: transport, expansions, and the separation of
two ions, two-ion phase gates, as well as the rotation of an anisotropic trap
for an ion are treated and shown to be analogous to a mechanical system of two
masses connected by springs with time dependent stiffness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07059</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pedro</keyname><forenames>Francisco G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westphal</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation with a graceful exit in a random landscape</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Published version</comments><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-16-128 DESY-16-224</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1703 (2017) 163</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)163</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a stochastic description of small-field inflationary histories
with a graceful exit in a random potential whose Hessian is a Gaussian random
matrix as a model of the unstructured part of the string landscape. The
dynamical evolution in such a random potential from a small-field inflation
region towards a viable late-time de Sitter (dS) minimum maps to the dynamics
of Dyson Brownian motion describing the relaxation of non-equilibrium
eigenvalue spectra in random matrix theory. We analytically compute the
relaxation probability in a saddle point approximation of the partition
function of the eigenvalue distribution of the Wigner ensemble describing the
mass matrices of the critical points. When applied to small-field inflation in
the landscape, this leads to an exponentially strong bias against small-field
ranges and an upper bound $N\ll 10$ on the number of light fields $N$
participating during inflation from the non-observation of negative spatial
curvature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09038</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-04-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cherkas</keyname><forenames>Sergey L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherkas</keyname><forenames>Nadejda L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extinction by the long dielectric needles</title><categories>physics.optics physics.class-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, Mathematica notbooks associated with this article can be
  found, at http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijleo.2017.04.040</comments><journal-ref>Optik, 140 (2017) 673-679</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijleo.2017.04.040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetic wave extinction by the very long but finite dielectric needle
is compared with that by the infinite dielectric cylinder for an oblique
incidence of the electromagnetic wave. It is shown that the renormalized Hankel
functions without the logarithmic terms should be used for the calculation of
the extinction per unit length of the infinite dielectric cylinder to apply it
for extinction calculations by the finite dielectric cylinder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03877</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Searches for pair production of third-generation squarks in sqrt(s) = 13
  TeV pp collisions</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SUS-16-008/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-SUS-16-008, CERN-EP-2016-284</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 327</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4853-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Searches are presented for direct production of top or bottom squark pairs in
proton-proton collisions at the CERN LHC. Two searches, based on complementary
techniques, are performed in all-jet final states that are characterized by a
significant imbalance in transverse momentum. An additional search requires the
presence of a charged lepton isolated from other activity in the event. The
data were collected in 2015 at a centre-of-mass energy of 13 TeV with the CMS
detector and correspond to an integrated luminosity of 2.3 inverse femtobarns.
No statistically significant excess of events is found beyond the expected
contribution from standard model processes. Exclusion limits are set in the
context of simplified models of top or bottom squark pair production. Models
with top and bottom squark masses up to 830 and 890 GeV, respectively, are
probed for light neutralinos. For models with top squark masses of 675 GeV,
neutralino masses up to 260 GeV are excluded at 95% confidence level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05621</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adri&#xe1;n-Mart&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ageron</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aiello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ameli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anassontzis</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andre</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Androulakis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anghinolfi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anton</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ardid</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avgitas</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbarino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbarito</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baret</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrios-Mart&#xed;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belias</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berbee</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>A. van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beurthey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Beveren</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beverini</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biagi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biagioni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billault</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bond&#xec;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormuth</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouhadef</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourlis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourret</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boutonnet</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouwhuis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozza</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruijn</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buompane</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busto</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cacopardo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caillat</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calamai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capone</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caramete</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cecchini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Celli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Champion</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherubini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiarella</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiarusi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Circella</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Classen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cobas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cocimano</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coelho</keyname><forenames>J. A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coleiro</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colonges</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coniglione</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cordelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cosquer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coyle</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Creusot</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuttone</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Amato</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Amico</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Onofrio</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Bonis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Sio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Palma</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xed;az</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Distefano</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donzaud</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dornic</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorosti-Hasankiadeh</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drakopoulou</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drouhin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durocher</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberl</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichie</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Eijk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bojaddaini</keyname><forenames>I. El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elsaesser</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enzenh&#xf6;fer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Favaro</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fermani</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frascadore</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fusco</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gal</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galat&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garufi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gay</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gebyehu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacomini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gialanella</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giordano</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gizani</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gracia</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graf</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xe9;goire</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grella</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grmek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Haren</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harissopulos</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heid</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heijboer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heine</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henry</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Rey</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hevinga</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofest&#xe4;dt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugon</keyname><forenames>C. M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Illuminati</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansweijer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jongen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Jong</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadler</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalekin</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kappes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katz</keyname><forenames>U. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieft</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kie&#xdf;ling</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koffeman</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kooijman</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kouchner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulikovskiy</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahmann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamare</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larosa</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leisos</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leone</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leonora</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>M. Lindsey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liolios</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>C. D. Llorens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Presti</keyname><forenames>D. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;hner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lonardo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotze</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loucatos</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maccioni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mannheim</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzali</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margiotta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mari&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markou</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Mora</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzaioli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mele</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melis</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michael</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Migliozzi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Migneco</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mijakowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miraglia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mollo</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mongelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morganti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moussa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musico</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musumeci</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navas</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolau</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olcina</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivetto</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orlando</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orzelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papaikonomou</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papaleo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#x103;v&#x103;la&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peek</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pellegrini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pellegrino</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrina</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfutzner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piattelli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pikounis</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pleinert</keyname><forenames>M. -O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poma</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popa</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratolongo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xfc;hlhofer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pulvirenti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quinn</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Racca</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raffaelli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Randazzo</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Real</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Resvanis</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reubelt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riccobene</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salda&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvadori</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samtleben</keyname><forenames>D. F. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>A. S&#xe1;nchez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Losa</keyname><forenames>A. S&#xe1;nchez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanguineti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santangelo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santonocito</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapienza</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimmel</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnabel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciacca</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedita</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seitz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sgura</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simeone</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sipala</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spisso</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spurio</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stavropoulos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steijger</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stellacci</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stransky</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taiuti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tayalati</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terrasi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xe9;zier</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theraube</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timmer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf6;nnis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trasatti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Travaglini</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trovato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsirigotis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzamarias</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzamariudaki</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallage</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Elewyck</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vermeulen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vicini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vivolo</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkert</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiggers</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilms</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Wolf</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zachariadou</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zornoza</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic limits on resolutions in muon- and electron-neutrino
  charged-current events in the KM3NeT/ORCA detector</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>37 pages, 28 figures, JHEP published version</comments><journal-ref>The KM3NeT collaboration, Adri{\'a}n-Mart{\'\i}nez, S., Ageron, M.
  et al. J. High Energ. Phys. (2017) 2017: 8</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studying atmospheric neutrino oscillations in the few-GeV range with a
multimegaton detector promises to determine the neutrino mass hierarchy. This
is the main science goal pursued by the future KM3NeT/ORCA water Cherenkov
detector in the Mediterranean Sea. In this paper, the processes that limit the
obtainable resolution in both energy and direction in charged-current neutrino
events in the ORCA detector are investigated. These processes include the
composition of the hadronic fragmentation products, the subsequent particle
propagation and the photon-sampling fraction of the detector. GEANT simulations
of neutrino interactions in seawater produced by GENIE are used to study the
effects in the 1 - 20 GeV range. It is found that fluctuations in the hadronic
cascade in conjunction with the variation of the inelasticity y are most
detrimental to the resolutions. The effect of limited photon sampling in the
detector is of significantly less importance. These results will therefore also
be applicable to similar detectors/media, such as those in ice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08839</id><created>2016-12-28</created><updated>2017-05-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Endo</keyname><forenames>Motoi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitahara</keyname><forenames>Teppei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishima</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Kei</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting Kaon Physics in General $Z$ Scenario</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures; v2: references added, some contributions
  included in light of gauge invariance; v3: to be published in Phys. Lett. B</comments><report-no>KEK-TH-1950, TTP16-057</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett.B771 (2017) 37-44</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New physics contributions to the $Z$ penguin are revisited in the light of
the recently-reported discrepancy of the direct CP violation in $K\to\pi\pi$.
Interference effects between the standard model and new physics contributions
to $\Delta S = 2$ observables are taken into account. Although the effects are
overlooked in the literature, they make experimental bounds significantly
severer. It is shown that the new physics contributions must be tuned to
enhance $\mathcal{B}(K_L \to \pi^{0} \nu \bar{\nu})$, if the discrepancy of the
direct CP violation is explained with satisfying the experimental constraints.
The branching ratio can be as large as $6 \times 10^{-10}$ when the
contributions are tuned at the 10 % level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08954</id><created>2016-12-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kanno</keyname><forenames>Sugumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Misao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum State of the Dirac Field in de Sitter Space and Entanglement
  Entropy</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>YITP-16-136, KUNS-2659</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1703 (2017) 068</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the entanglement entropy of a free massive Dirac field between two
causally disconnected open charts in de Sitter space. We first derive the
Bunch-Davies vacuum mode functions of the Dirac field. We find there exists no
supercurvature mode for the Dirac field. We then give the Bogoliubov
transformation between the Bunch-Davies vacuum and the open chart vacua that
makes the reduced density matrix diagonal. We find that the Dirac field becomes
more entangled than a scalar field as $m^2/H^2$ becomes small, and the
difference is maximal in the massless limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09231</id><created>2016-12-29</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rastegin</keyname><forenames>Alexey E.</forenames></author></authors><title>R\'enyi and Tsallis entropies related to eigenfunctions of quantum
  graphs</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, no figures. Minor improvements in the version 2. The
  bibliography is extended and updated</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 215204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6b74</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For certain families of finite quantum graphs, we study the question of how
eigenfunctions are distributed over the graph. To characterize properties of
the distribution, generalized entropies of the R\'{e}nyi and Tsallis types are
considered. The presented approach is similar to entropic uncertainty relations
of the Maassen-Uffink type. Using the Riesz theorem, we derive lower bounds on
symmetrized generalized entropies of eigenfunctions. A quality of such
estimates will depend on boundary conditions used at vertices of the given
graph. R\'{e}nyi and Tsallis entropies of eigenfunctions of star graphs are
separately examined. Relations between generalized entropies and variances of
eigenfunctions are considered as well. When such relations remain valid on
average, they may be used in studies of quantum ergodicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09489</id><created>2016-12-30</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Colombaro</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giusti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainardi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>On the propagation of transient waves in a viscoelastic Bessel medium</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.MP physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>74D05, 74H40, 74J99, 76A10, 44A10, 33C10</msc-class><journal-ref>Z. Angew. Math. Phys. (2017) 68: 62</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00033-017-0808-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss the uniaxial propagation of transient waves within a
semi-infinite viscoelastic Bessel medium. First, we provide the analytic
expression for the response function of the material as we approach the
wave-front. To do so, we take profit of a revisited version of the so called
Buchen-Mainardi algorithm. Secondly, we provide an analytic expression for the
long time behavior of the response function of the material. This result is
obtained by means of the Tauberian theorems for the Laplace transform. Finally,
we relate the obtained results to a peculiar model for fluid-filled elastic
tubes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01057</id><created>2017-01-04</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gramsch</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potthoff</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Enforcing conservation laws in nonequilibrium cluster perturbation
  theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures, v2 as published</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205130 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the recently introduced time-local formulation of the nonequilibrium
cluster perturbation theory (CPT), we construct a generalization of the
approach such that macroscopic conservation laws are respected. This is
achieved by exploiting the freedom for the choice of the starting point of the
all-order perturbation theory in the inter-cluster hopping. The proposed
conserving CPT is a self-consistent propagation scheme which respects the
conservation of energy, particle number and spin, which treats short-range
correlations exactly up to the linear scale of the cluster, and which
represents a mean-field-like approach on length scales beyond the cluster size.
Using Green's functions, conservation laws are formulated as local continuity
equations for the local spin-dependent particle and the doublon density. We
consider them as conditional equations to self-consistently fix the
time-dependent intra-cluster one-particle parameters. Thanks to the intrinsic
causality of the CPT, this can be set up as a step-by-step time propagation
scheme with a computational effort scaling linearly with the maximum
propagation time and exponentially in the cluster size. As a proof of concept,
we consider the dynamics of the two-dimensional, particle-hole-symmetric
Hubbard model following a weak interaction quench by simply employing two-site
clusters only. Conservation laws are satisfied by construction. We demonstrate
that enforcing them has strong impact on the dynamics. While the doublon
density is strongly oscillating within plain CPT, a monotonic relaxation is
observed within the conserving CPT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01669</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fibich</keyname><forenames>Gadi</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion of new products with recovering consumers</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the diffusion of new products in the discrete Bass-SIR model, in
which consumers who adopt the product can later &quot;recover&quot; and stop influencing
their peers to adopt the product. To gain insight into the effect of the social
network structure on the diffusion, we focus on two extreme cases. In the
&quot;most-connected&quot; configuration where all consumers are inter-connected
(complete network), averaging over all consumers leads to an aggregate model,
which combines the Bass model for diffusion of new products with the SIR model
for epidemics. In the &quot;least-connected&quot; configuration where consumers are
arranged on a circle and each consumer can only be influenced by his left
neighbor (one-sided 1D network), averaging over all consumers leads to a
different aggregate model which is linear, and can be solved explicitly. We
conjecture that for any other network, the diffusion is bounded from below and
from above by that on a one-sided 1D network and on a complete network,
respectively. When consumers are arranged on a circle and each consumer can be
influenced by his left and right neighbors (two-sided 1D network), the
diffusion is strictly faster than on a one-sided 1D network. This is different
from the case of non-recovering adopters, where the diffusion on one-sided and
on two-sided 1D networks is identical. We also propose a nonlinear model for
recoveries, and show that consumers' heterogeneity has a negligible effect on
the aggregate diffusion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02556</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xe4;dler</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winicour</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation Memory, Boosted Schwarzschild Spacetimes and Supertranslations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>matches published version</comments><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6ca8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate gravitational radiation memory and its corresponding effect on
the asymptotic symmetries of a body whose exterior is a boosted Schwarzschild
spacetime. First, in the context of linearized theory, we consider such a
Schwarzschild body which is initially at rest, then goes through a radiative
stage and finally emerges as a boosted Schwarzschild body. We show that the
proper retarded solution of the exterior Schwarzschild spacetime for this
process can be described in terms of the ingoing Kerr-Schild form of the
Schwarzschild metric for both the initial and final states. An outgoing
Kerr-Schild or time symmetric metric does not give the proper solution. The
special property of Kerr-Schild metrics that their linearized and nonlinear
forms are identical allows us to extend this result to processes in the
nonlinear regime. We then discuss how the nonlinear memory effect, and its
associated supertranslation, affect angular momentum conservation. Our approach
provides a new framework for studying nonlinear aspects of the memory effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04029</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04029</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Quan-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xin-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ya-Dong</forenames></author></authors><title>The $\Lambda_b\to \Lambda(\to p\pi^-)\mu^+\mu^-$ decay in the aligned
  two-Higgs-doublet model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 2 figures, and 4 tables; More discussions added, final
  version published in the journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rare baryonic decay $\Lambda_b\to \Lambda(\to p\pi^-)\mu^+\mu^-$ provides
valuable complementary information compared to the corresponding mesonic $b\to
s\mu^+\mu^-$ transition. In this paper, using the latest high-precision lattice
QCD calculation of the $\Lambda_b\to\Lambda$ transition form factors, we study
this interesting decay within the aligned two-Higgs-doublet model, paying
particularly attention to effects of the chirality-flipped operators generated
by the charged scalars. In order to extract the full set of angular
coefficients in this decay, we consider the following ten angular observables
that can be derived from the analysis of the subsequent parity-violating
$\Lambda\to p\pi^-$ decay: the differential branching fraction ${\rm d}{\cal
B}/{\rm d}q^2$, the longitudinal polarization fraction $F_L$, the lepton-,
hadron- and combined lepton-hadron-side forward-backward asymmetries $A_{\rm
FB}^\ell$, $A_{\rm FB}^\Lambda$ and $A_{\rm FB}^{\ell\Lambda}$, as well as the
other five asymmetry observables $Y_i$~($i={\rm 2,\,3s,\,3sc,\,4s,\,4sc}$).
Detailed numerical comparisons are made between the SM and NP values for these
angular observables. It is found that, under the constraints from the inclusive
$B\to X_s\gamma$ branching fraction and the latest global fit results of $b\to
s\ell\ell$ data, the contributions of right-handed semileptonic operators
$O^{\prime}_{9,10}$, besides reconciling the $P_5^{\prime}$ anomaly observed in
$B^0\to K^{\ast 0}\mu^+\mu^-$ decay, could also enhance the values of ${\rm
d}{\cal B}/{\rm d}q^2$ and $A_{\rm FB}^\ell$ in the bin $[15,20]~{\rm GeV}^2$,
leading to results consistent with the current LHCb measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04670</id><created>2017-01-17</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Awoga</keyname><forenames>Oladunjoye A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bj&#xf6;rnson</keyname><forenames>Kristofer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Black-Schaffer</keyname><forenames>Annica M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disorder robustness and protection of Majorana bound states in
  ferromagnetic chains on conventional superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages and 5 figures + supplemental material 4 pages and 6 figures +
  Minor corrections to the previous version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 184511 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.184511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Majorana bound states (MBS) are well-established in the clean limit in chains
of ferromagnetically aligned impurities deposited on conventional
superconductors with finite spin-orbit coupling. Here we show that these MBS
are very robust against disorder. By performing self-consistent calculations we
find that the MBS are protected as long as the surrounding superconductor show
no large signs of inhomogeneity. We find that longer chains offer more
stability against disorder for the MBS, albeit the minigap decreases, as do
increasing strengths of spin-orbit coupling and superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07003</id><created>2017-01-24</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ayzenberg</keyname><forenames>Dimitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunes</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Black Hole Continuum Spectra as a Test of General Relativity: Quadratic
  Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures, 1 table. Updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 115003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6dbc</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observations of the continuum spectrum emitted by accretion disks around
black holes allows us to infer their properties, including possibly whether
black holes are described by the Kerr metric. Some modified gravity theories do
not admit the Kerr metric as a solution, and thus, continuum spectrum
observations could be used to constrain these theories. We here investigate
whether current and next generation X-Ray observations of the black hole
continuum spectrum can constrain such deviations from Einstein's theory,
focusing on two well-motivated modified quadratic gravity theories: dynamical
Chern-Simons gravity and Einstein-dilaton-Gauss-Bonnet gravity. We do so by
determining whether the non-Kerr deviations in the continuum spectrum
introduced by these theories are larger than the observational error intrinsic
to the observations. We find that dynamical Chern-Simons gravity cannot be
constrained better than current bounds with current or next generation
continuum spectrum observations. Einstein-dilaton-Gauss-Bonnet gravity,
however, may be constrained better than current bounds with next generation
telescopes, as long as the systematic error inherent in the accretion disk
modeling is decreased below the predicted observational error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08093</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scotti</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passaggia</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>A local diagnostic energy to study diabatic effects on a class of
  degenerate Hamiltonian systems with application to mixing in stratified flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Under consideration in Proc. Royal Soc. A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Hamiltonian systems characterized by a degenerate Poisson algebra, we show
how to construct a local energy-like quantity that can be used to study
diabatic effects on the evolution of the Available Energy of the system, the
latter concept formalizing the original idea of Margules'. We calculate the
local diagnostic energy for geophysically relevant flows. For the particular
case of stratified Boussinesq flows, we show that under moderately general
conditions, in inertial frames where the initial distribution of potential
vorticity is even around the origin, our framework recovers the Available
Potential Energy introduced by Holliday and McIntyre \cite{HollidayM81}, and as
such depends only on the mass distribution of the flow. In non-inertial frames,
we show that the local diagnostic energy of flows which are, in an appropriate
sense, characterized by a low-Rossby number ${\rm Ro}$ ground state, has to
lowest order in ${\rm Ro}$, a universal character.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08357</id><created>2017-01-29</created><updated>2017-03-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Joo-Von</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Myoung-Woo</forenames></author></authors><title>Current-driven skyrmion dynamics in disordered films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 132404 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theoretical study of the current-driven dynamics of magnetic skyrmions in
disordered perpendicularly-magnetized ultrathin films is presented. The
disorder is simulated as a granular structure in which the local anisotropy
varies randomly from grain to grain. The skyrmion velocity is computed for
different disorder parameters and ensembles. Similar behavior is seen for
spin-torques due to in-plane currents and the spin Hall effect, where a pinning
regime can be identified at low currents with a transition towards the
disorder-free case at higher currents, similar to domain wall motion in
disordered films. Moreover, a current-dependent skyrmion Hall effect and
fluctuations in the core radius are found, which result from the interaction
with the pinning potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02182</id><created>2017-02-07</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rangel</keyname><forenames>Tonatiuh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamed</keyname><forenames>Samia M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruneval</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neaton</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey B.</forenames></author></authors><title>An assessment of the low-lying excitation energies and triplet
  instabilities of organic molecules with an ab initio Bethe-Salpeter equation
  approach</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 194108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The accurate prediction of singlet and triplet excitation energies is of
significant fundamental interest and is critical for many applications. An area
of intense research, most calculations of singlet and triplet energies use
time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) in conjunction with an
approximate exchange-correlation functional. In this work, we examine and
critically assess an alternative method for predicting low-lying neutral
excitations with similar computational cost, the ab initio Bethe-Salpeter
equation (BSE) approach, and compare results against high-accuracy
wavefunction-based methods. We consider singlet and triplet excitations of 27
prototypical organic molecules, including members of Thiel's set, the acene
series, and several aromatic hydrocarbons exhibiting charge-transfer-like
excitations. Analogous to its impact in TDDFT, we find that the Tamm-Dancoff
approximation (TDA) overcomes triplet instabilities in the BSE approach,
improving both triplet and singlet energetics relatively to higher level
theories. Finally, we find that BSE-TDA calculations built on good DFT starting
points, such as those utilizing optimally-tuned range-separated hybrid
functionals, can yield accurate singlet and triplet excitation energies for
gas-phase organic molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03137</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ronghua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huo</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>Methods for analysis of two-particle rapidity correlation function in
  high-energy heavy-ion collisions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-particle rapidity (or pseudorapidity) correlation function $C(y_1, y_2)$
was used in analysing fluctuation of particle density distribution in rapidity
in high-energy heavy-ion collisions. In our research, we argue that for a
centrality window, some additional correlation may be caused by a centrality
span, when the mean two- and single-particle densities over a centrality window
are used directly in the calculation , just like $\left&lt;N(y_1, y_2) \right&gt; /
\left[\left&lt;N(y_1)\right&gt;\left&lt;N(y_2)\right&gt;\right]$. We concentrate on
removing the influence of collision-centrality span on correlation function,
and two calculation methods are raised. In one method, correlation coefficients
are considered to be the ratios of probabilities (not the particle density). In
the other method, a relative multiplicity is introduced to unity the events of
different centralities. For testing the methods, {\sc ampt} model is used and a
toy granular model is built to simulate the fluctuation of particle density in
rapidity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03771</id><created>2017-02-13</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bekshaev</keyname><forenames>Aleksandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernykh</keyname><forenames>Aleksey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoroshun</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhaylovskaya</keyname><forenames>Lidiya</forenames></author></authors><title>Singular skeleton evolution and topological reactions in edge-diffracted
  circular optical-vortex beams</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures; 2 attachments with 2 figures; 5 illustrative
  videos</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Commun, V. 397, P. 72-83 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.optcom.2017.03.062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Edge diffraction of a circular optical vortex (OV) beam transforms its
singular structure: a multicharged axial OV splits into the set of
single-charged ones that form the 'singular skeleton' of the diffracted beam.
The OV positions in the beam cross section depend on the propagation distance
as well as on the edge position with respect to the incident beam axis, and the
OV cores describe regular trajectories when one or both of these parameters
change. However, the trajectories are not always continuous; they may be
accompanied with topological reactions, including emergence of new
singularities, their interaction and annihilation. Based on the
Kirchhoff-Fresnel integral, we consider the singular skeleton behavior in
diffracted Kummer beams and Laguerre-Gaussian beams with topological charge
|m|=2 and 3. We reveal the nature of the trajectories' discontinuities and
other topological events in the singular skeleton evolution that appear to be
highly sensitive to the incident beam properties and to the diffraction
conditions. Conditions at which the OV trajectory becomes discontinuous and
mechanisms by which this is realized are discussed. The conclusions based on
the numerical calculations are supported by the asymptotic analytical model of
the OV beam diffraction. The results can be useful in the OV metrology and for
the OV beam's diagnostics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04189</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Rui-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yun-He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Weighing neutrinos in the scenario of vacuum energy interacting with
  cold dark matter: application of the parameterized post-Friedmann approach</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures; major revision made</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 05 (2017) 040</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/05/040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We constrain the neutrino mass in the scenario of vacuum energy interacting
with cold dark matter by using current cosmological observations. To avoid the
large-scale instability problem in interacting dark energy models, we employ
the parameterized post-Friedmann (PPF) approach to do the calculation of
perturbation evolution, for the $Q=\beta H\rho_{\rm c}$ and $Q=\beta
H\rho_{\Lambda}$ models. The current observational data sets used in this work
include Planck (cosmic microwave background), BSH (baryon acoustic
oscillations, type Ia supernovae, and Hubble constant), and LSS (redshift space
distortions and weak lensing). According to the constraint results, we find
that $\beta&gt;0$ at more than $1\sigma$ level for the $Q=\beta H\rho_{\rm c}$
model, which indicates that cold dark matter decays into vacuum energy; while
$\beta=0$ is consistent with the current data at $1\sigma$ level for the
$Q=\beta H\rho_{\Lambda}$ model. Taking the $\Lambda$CDM model as a baseline
model, we find that a smaller upper limit, $\sum m_{\nu}&lt;0.11$ eV ($2\sigma$),
is induced by the latest BAO BOSS DR12 data and the Hubble constant measurement
$H_{0} = 73.00 \pm 1.75$ km~s$^{-1}$~Mpc$^{-1}$. For the $Q=\beta H\rho_{\rm
c}$ model, we obtain $\sum m_{\nu}&lt;0.20$ eV ($2\sigma$) from Planck+BSH. For
the $Q=\beta H\rho_{\Lambda}$ model, $\sum m_{\nu}&lt;0.10$ eV ($2\sigma$) and
$\sum m_{\nu}&lt;0.14$ eV ($2\sigma$) are derived from Planck+BSH and
Planck+BSH+LSS, respectively. We show that these smaller upper limits on $\sum
m_{\nu}$ are affected more or less by the tension between $H_{0}$ and other
observational data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05709</id><created>2017-02-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chhikara</keyname><forenames>Manisha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaponenko</keyname><forenames>Iaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paruch</keyname><forenames>Patrycja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmenko</keyname><forenames>Alexey. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of uniaxial strain on the optical Drude scattering in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures + supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4, 025081 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa6c10</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene is a mechanically robust 2D material promising for flexible
optoelectronic applications. However, its electromagnetic properties under
strain are experimentally poorly understood. Here we present the far-infrared
transmission spectra of large-area chemical-vapor deposited monolayer graphene
on a polyethylene terephthalate substrate subjected to uniaxial strain. The
effective strain value is calibrated using the Raman spectroscopy and corrected
for a relaxation of wrinkles and folds seen directly by atomic-force
microscopy. We find that while the Drude weight and the Fermi level remain
constant, the scattering rate increases by more than 10% per 1% of applied
strain, showing a high level of reproducibility during strain cycling. As a
result, the electronic mobility and optical absorption of graphene at terahertz
and lower frequencies appear to also be sensitive to strain, which opens
pathways to control these key parameters mechanically. We suggest that such a
functionality can be potentially used in flexible optoelectronic and
microelectromechanical systems based on graphene. By combining our findings
with existing theoretical models, we discuss the possible mechanisms of
strain-controlled Drude scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07479</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nardini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal phase transition with full 2-loop effective potential</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>42 pages. v3: many clarifications added, published version</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B 920 (2017) 565-600</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.04.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theories with extended Higgs sectors constructed in view of cosmological
ramifications (gravitational wave signal, baryogenesis, dark matter) are often
faced with conflicting requirements for their couplings; in particular those
influencing the strength of a phase transition may be large. Large couplings
compromise perturbative studies, as well as the high-temperature expansion that
is invoked in dimensionally reduced lattice investigations. With the example of
the inert doublet extension of the Standard Model (IDM), we show how a resummed
2-loop effective potential can be computed without a high-T expansion, and use
the result to scrutinize its accuracy. With the exception of Tc, which is
sensitive to contributions from heavy modes, the high-T expansion is found to
perform well. 2-loop corrections weaken the transition in IDM, but they are
moderate, whereby a strong transition remains an option.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08186</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Li-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>A theorem about two-body decay and its application for a doubly-charged
  boson $H^{\pm\pm}$ going to $\tau^{\pm}\tau^{\pm}$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, revised</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a general decay chain $A\to B_1B_2\to C_1C_2\ldots$, we prove that the
angular correlation function $I(\theta_1,\theta_2,\phi_+)$ in the decay of
$B_{1,2}$ is irrelevant to the polarization of the mother particle $A$ at
production. This guarantees that we can use these angular distributions to
determine the spin-parity nature of $A$ without knowing its production details.
As an example, we investigate the decay of a potential doubly-charged boson
$H^{\pm\pm}$ going to same-sign $\tau$ lepton pair.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01269</id><created>2017-03-03</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Teng</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>Expanding Einstein-Yang-Mills by Yang-Mills in CHY frame</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>36 pages, 3 captioned figures; v2: more details added, revised and
  published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the Cachazo-He-Yuan (CHY) formalism, we prove a recursive expansion of
tree level single trace Einstein-Yang-Mills (EYM) amplitudes with arbitrary
number of gluons and gravitons, which is valid for general spacetime dimensions
and any helicity configurations. The recursion is written in terms of
fewer-graviton EYM amplitudes and pure Yang-Mills (YM) amplitudes, which can be
further carried out until we reach an expansion in terms of pure YM amplitudes
in Kleiss-Kuijf (KK) basis. Our expansion then generates naturally a spanning
tree structure rooted on gluons whose vertices are gravitons. We further
propose a set of graph theoretical rules based on spanning trees that evaluate
directly the pure YM expansion coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01871</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duchateau</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical derivation of laser-dressed atomic states by using a fractal
  space</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The derivation of approximate wave functions for an electron submitted to
both a coulomb and a time-dependent laser electric fields, the so-called
Coulomb-Volkov (CV) state, is addressed. Despite its derivation for continuum
states does not exhibit any particular problem within the framework of the
standard theory of quantum mechanics (QM), difficulties arise when considering
an initially bound atomic state. Indeed the natural way of translating the
unperturbed momentum by the laser vector potential is no longer possible since
a bound state does not exhibit a plane wave form including explicitely a
momentum. The use of a fractal space permits to naturally define a momentum for
a bound wave function. Within this framework, it is shown how the derivation of
laser-dressed bound states can be performed. Based on a generalized eikonal
approach, a new expression for the laser-dressed states is also derived, fully
symmetric relative to the continuum or bound nature of the initial unperturbed
wave function. It includes an additional crossed term in the Volkov phase which
was not obtained within the standard theory of quantum mechanics. The
derivations within this fractal framework have highlighted other possible ways
to derive approximate laser-dressed states in QM. After comparing the various
obtained wave functions, an application to the prediction of the ionization
probability of hydrogen targets by attosecond XUV pulses within the sudden
approximation is provided. This approach allows to make predictions in various
regimes depending on the laser intensity, going from the non-resonant
multiphoton absorption to tunneling and barrier-suppression ionization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02062</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vinciguerra</keyname><forenames>Serena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veitch</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandel</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author></authors><title>Accelerating gravitational wave parameter estimation with multi-band
  template interpolation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Classical and Quantum Gravity, Volume 34, Number 11, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6d44</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Parameter estimation on gravitational wave signals from compact binary
coalescence (CBC) requires the evaluation of computationally intensive waveform
models, typically the bottleneck in the analysis. This cost will increase
further as low frequency sensitivity in later second and third generation
detectors motivates the use of longer waveforms.
  We describe a method for accelerating parameter estimation by exploiting the
chirping behaviour of the signals to sample the waveform sparsely for portions
where the full frequency resolution is not required. We demonstrate that the
method can reproduce the original results with a waveform mismatch of $\leq
5\times 10^{-7}$, but with a waveform generation cost up to $\sim 50$ times
lower for computationally costly frequency-domain waveforms starting from below
8 Hz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03879</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Freedman</keyname><forenames>Daniel Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kallosh</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murli</keyname><forenames>Divyanshu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Proeyen</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Absence of U(1) Anomalous Superamplitudes in $\mathcal{N}\geq 5$
  Supergravities</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>32 pages, v2:typo corrected, reference added, v3:typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1705 (2017) 067</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We list all potential candidates for U(1) anomalous non-local 1-loop 4-point
amplitudes and higher loop UV divergences in $\mathcal{N}\geq 5$
supergravities. The relevant chiral superinvariants are constructed from
linearized chiral superfields and define the corresponding superamplitudes. The
anomalous amplitudes, of the kind present in $\mathcal{N}=4$, are shown to be
absent in $\mathcal{N} \geq 5$. In $\mathcal{N}=6$ supergravity the result is
deduced from the double-copy $\mathcal{N}=4_{YM} \times (\mathcal{N}=2)_{YM}$
model, whereas in $\mathcal{N}=5,8$ the result on absence of anomalous
amplitudes is derived in supergravities as well as in the $(\mathcal{N}=4)_{YM}
\times (\mathcal{N}-4)_{YM}$ double-copy models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06004</id><created>2017-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Zi-Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Angular Momentum of Proton Spin Puzzle in Complex Octonion Spaces</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Geometric Methods in Modern Physics, Vol.
  14, No.7, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021988781750102X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper focuses on considering some special precessional motions as the
spin motions, separating the octonion angular momentum of a proton into six
components, elucidating the proton angular momentum in the proton spin puzzle,
especially the proton spin, decomposition, quarks and gluons, and polarization
and so forth. J. C. Maxwell was the first to use the quaternions to study the
electromagnetic fields. Subsequently the complex octonions are utilized to
depict the electromagnetic field, gravitational field, and quantum mechanics
and so forth. In the complex octonion space, the precessional equilibrium
equation infers the angular velocity of precession. The external
electromagnetic strength may induce a new precessional motion, generating a new
term of angular momentum, even if the orbital angular momentum is zero. This
new term of angular momentum can be regarded as the spin angular momentum, and
its angular velocity of precession is different from the angular velocity of
revolution. The study reveals that the angular momentum of the proton must be
separated into more components than ever before. In the proton spin puzzle, the
orbital angular momentum and magnetic dipole moment are independent of each
other, and they should be measured and calculated respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09917</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-04-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilatela</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina-Aldaregu&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LLorca</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural composites for multifunctional applications: current
  challenges and future trends</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Progress in Materials Science, 89, 194-251, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.pmatsci.2017.04.005</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This review paper summarizes the current state-of-art and challenges for the
future developments of fiber-reinforced composites for structural applications
with multifunctional capabilities. After a brief analysis of the reasons of the
successful incorporation of fiber-reinforced composites in many different
industrial sectors, the review analyzes three critical factors that will define
the future of composites. The first one is the application of novel
fiber-deposition and preforming techniques together with innovative liquid
moulding strategies, which will be combined by optimization tools based on
novel multiscale modelling approaches, so fiber-reinforced composites with
optimized properties can be designed and manufactured for each application. In
addition, composite applications will be enhanced by the incorporation of
multifunctional capabilities. Among them, electrical conductivity, energy
storage (structural supercapacitors and batteries) and energy harvesting
(piezoelectric and solar energy) seem to be the most promising ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00094</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Naohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Hall Effect and Spontaneous Orbital Magnetization in
  Antiferromagnetic Weyl Metal</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 063703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.063703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the anomalous Hall effect and orbital magnetization in chiral
antiferromagnets, constructing a simple tight-binding model on a stacked Kagome
lattice structure with spin-orbit coupling and the exchange interaction between
the localized spins and itinerant electrons. It is shown that the ground state
is an orbital ferromagnet with the easy-plane anisotropy. The relation between
the orbital magnetization and the configuration of the Weyl points are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02240</id><created>2017-04-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Zi-Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Color Confinement and Spatial Dimensions in the Complex-sedenion Space</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics, Vol. 2017, Article ID: 9876464,
  2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2017/9876464</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper aims to apply the complex-sedenions to explore the wavefunctions
and field equations of non-Abelian gauge fields, considering the spatial
dimensions of a unit vector as the color degrees of freedom in the
complex-quaternion wavefunctions, exploring the physical properties of the
color confinement essentially. J. C. Maxwell was the first to employ the
quaternions to study the physical properties of electromagnetic fields. His
method inspires some subsequent scholars to introduce the quaternions,
octonions, and sedenions to research the electromagnetic field, gravitational
field, nuclear field, quantum mechanics, and gauge field. The application of
complex-sedenions is capable of depicting not only the field equations of the
classical mechanics on the macroscopic scale, but also the field equations of
the quantum mechanics on the microscopic scale. The latter can be degenerated
into the Dirac equation and Yang-Mills equation. In contrast to the
complex-number wavefunction, the wavefunction in the complex-quaternion space
possesses three new degrees of freedom, that is, three color degrees of
freedom. One complex-quaternion wavefunction is equivalent to three
conventional wavefunctions with the complex-numbers. It means that the three
spatial dimensions of unit vector in the complex-quaternion wavefunction can be
considered as the `three colors', naturally the color confinement will be
effective. In other words, in the complex-quaternion space, the `three colors'
are only the spatial dimensions, rather than any property of physical
substance. The existing `three colors' can be merged into the wavefunction,
described with the complex-quaternions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02933</id><created>2017-04-10</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ambrus</keyname><forenames>Victor E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum non-equilibrium effects in rigidly-rotating thermal states</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, accepted for publication in Physics Letters B</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on known analytic results, the thermal expectation value of the
stress-energy tensor (SET) operator for the massless Dirac field is analyzed
from a hydrodynamic perspective. Key to this analysis is the Landau
decomposition of the SET, with the aid of which we find terms which are not
present in the ideal SET predicted by kinetic theory. Moreover, the quantum
corrections become dominant in the vicinity of the speed of light surface
(SOL). While rigidly-rotating thermal states cannot be constructed for the
Klein-Gordon field, we perform a similar analysis at the level of quantum
corrections previously reported in the literature and we show that the Landau
frame is well-defined only when the system is enclosed inside a boundary
located inside or on the SOL. We discuss the relevance of these results for
accretion disks around rapidly-rotating pulsars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04829</id><created>2017-04-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kallosh</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrase</keyname><forenames>Timm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal Supersymmetry and B-Mode Targets</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1704 (2017) 144</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extending the work of Ferrara and one of the authors, we present dynamical
cosmological models of $\alpha$-attractors with plateau potentials for
$3\alpha=1,2,3,4,5,6,7$. These models are motivated by geometric properties of
maximally supersymmetric theories: M-theory, superstring theory, and maximal $N
= 8$ supergravity. After a consistent truncation of maximal to minimal
supersymmetry in a seven-disk geometry, we perform a two-step procedure: 1) we
introduce a superpotential, which stabilizes the moduli of the seven-disk
geometry in a supersymmetric minimum, 2) we add a cosmological sector with a
nilpotent stabilizer, which breaks supersymmetry spontaneously and leads to a
desirable class of cosmological attractor models. These models with $n_s$
consistent with observational data, and with tensor-to-scalar ratio $r \approx
10^{-2}- 10^{-3}$, provide natural targets for future B-mode searches. We
relate the issue of stability of inflationary trajectories in these models to
tessellations of a hyperbolic geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04881</id><created>2017-04-17</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimojo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastian</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwai</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>First ALMA Observation of a Solar Plasmoid Ejection from an X-ray Bright
  Point</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 page, 5 figures, accepted for publication in Astrophysical Journal
  Letter. The movie can be seen at the following link:
  http://hinode.nao.ac.jp/user/shimojo/data_area/plasmoid/movie5.mp4</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal Letter, Vol. 841, L5 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa70e3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Eruptive phenomena such as plasmoid ejections or jets are an important
feature of solar activity with the potential for improving our understanding of
the dynamics of the solar atmosphere. Such ejections are often thought to be
signatures of the outflows expected in regions of fast magnetic reconnection.
The 304 A EUV line of Helium, formed at around 10^5 K, is found to be a
reliable tracer of such phenomena, but the determination of physical parameters
from such observations is not straightforward. We have observed a plasmoid
ejection from an X-ray bright point simultaneously at millimeter wavelengths
with ALMA, at EUV wavelengths with AIA, in soft X-rays with Hinode/XRT. This
paper reports the physical parameters of the plasmoid obtained by combining the
radio, EUV and X-ray data. As a result, we conclude that the plasmoid can
consist either of (approximately) isothermal 10^5 K plasma that is optically
thin at 100 GHz, or else a 10^4 K core with a hot envelope. The analysis
demonstrates the value of the additional temperature and density constraints
that ALMA provides, and future science observations with ALMA will be able to
match the spatial resolution of space-borne and other high-resolution
telescopes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05527</id><created>2017-04-14</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ansari</keyname><forenames>Mohammad H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy production in a photovoltaic cell</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 174302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.174302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate entropy production in a photovoltaic cell that is modeled by four
electronic levels resonantly coupled to thermally populated field modes at
different temperatures. We use a formalism recently proposed, the so-called
multiple parallel worlds, to consistently address the nonlinearity of entropy
in terms of density matrix. Our result shows that entropy production is the
difference between two flows: a semiclassical flow that linearly depends on
occupational probabilities, and another flow that depends nonlinearly on
quantum coherence and has no semiclassical analog. We show that entropy
production in the cells depends on environmentally induced decoherence time and
energy detuning. We characterize regimes where reversal flow of information
takes place from a cold to hot bath. Interestingly, we identify a lower bound
on entropy production, which sets limitations on the statistics of dissipated
heat in the cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00476</id><created>2017-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Meifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Lingfang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shaozhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Qingzhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garlea</keyname><forenames>V. Ovidiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Yunlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chengliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Zhibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiuzhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Cycloidal magnetism driven ferroelectricity in double tungstate
  LiFe(WO$_4$)$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 95, 195134 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tungstates $A$WO$_4$ with the wolframite structure characterized by the
$A$O$_6$ octahedral zigzag chains along the $c$-axis, can be magnetic if
$A$=Mn, Fe, Co, Cu, Ni. Among them, MnWO$_4$ is a unique member with a cycloid
Mn$^{2+}$ spin order developed at low temperature, leading to an interesting
type-II multiferroic behavior. However, so far no other multiferroic material
in the tungstate family has been found. In this work, we present the synthesis
and the systematic study of the double tungstate LiFe(WO$_4$)$_2$. Experimental
characterizations including structural, thermodynamic, magnetic, neutron powder
diffraction, and pyroelectric measurements, unambiguously confirm that
LiFe(WO$_4$)$_2$ is the secondly found multiferroic system in the tungstate
family. The cycloidal magnetism driven ferroelectricity is also verified by
density functional theory calculations. Although here the magnetic couplings
between Fe ions are indirect, namely via the so-called super-super-exchanges,
the temperatures of magnetic and ferroelectric transitions are surprisingly
much higher than those of MnWO$_4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03051</id><created>2017-05-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Rudresh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Amritesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanne</keyname><forenames>Atresh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Kyounghwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movva</keyname><forenames>Hema C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Rik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Tanmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chowdhury</keyname><forenames>Sayema</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tutuc</keyname><forenames>Emanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sanjay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Intra-Domain Periodic Defects in Monolayer MoS$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>To appear in Appl. Phys. Lett. 13 pages, 3 figures. Includes
  Supplementary Material</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 201905 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983789</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an ultra-high vacuum scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) study of
structural defects in molybdenum disulfide thin films grown on silicon
substrates by chemical vapor deposition. A distinctive type of grain boundary
periodically arranged inside an isolated triangular domain, along with other
inter-domain grain boundaries of various types, is observed. These periodic
defects, about 50 nm apart and a few nanometers in width, remain hidden in
optical or low-resolution microscopy studies. We report a complex growth
mechanism that produces 2D nucleation and spiral growth features that can
explain the topography in our films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04202</id><created>2017-05-11</created><authors><author><keyname>B&#xf6;ttcher</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woolley-Meza</keyname><forenames>Olivia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brockmann</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal dynamics of online petitions</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>PLoS ONE 12(5):e0178062. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0178062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Online petitions are an important avenue for direct political action, yet the
dynamics that determine when a petition will be successful are not well
understood. Here we analyze the temporal characteristics of online-petition
signing behavior in order to identify systematic differences between popular
petitions, which receive a high volume of signatures, and unpopular ones. We
find that, in line with other temporal characterizations of human activity, the
signing process is typically non-Poissonian and non-homogeneous in time.
However, this process exhibits anomalously high memory for human activity,
possibly indicating that synchronized external influence or contagion play and
important role. More interestingly, we find clear differences in the
characteristics of the inter-event time distributions depending on the total
number of signatures that petitions receive, independently of the total
duration of the petitions. Specifically, popular petitions that attract a large
volume of signatures exhibit more variance in the distribution of inter-event
times than unpopular petitions with only a few signatures, which could be
considered an indication that the former are more bursty. However, petitions
with large signature volume are less bursty according to measures that consider
the time ordering of inter-event times. Our results, therefore, emphasize the
importance of accounting for time ordering to characterize human activity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04446</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Facheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shaobo</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular gas toward the Gemini OB1 Giant Molecular Cloud Complex I:
  Observation data</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>51 pages, 23 figures. Accepted by ApJS</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa6c6b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a large-scale mapping toward the GEM OB1 association in the
galactic anti-center direction. The 9^deg * 6.5^deg area was mapped in 12CO,
13CO, and C18O with 50&quot; angular resolution at 30&quot; sampling. The region was
divided into four main components based on spatial distribution and velocity:
the Gemini OB1 Giant Molecular Cloud (GGMC) Complex, the Lynds Dark Clouds and
the West Front Clouds, the Swallow and Horn, and the Remote Clouds. The GGMC
Complex is located in the Perseus arm, while the Lynds Dark Clouds and the West
Front Clouds are located in the Local arm. Swallow and Horn are revealed for
the first time in this paper. The two clouds have a similar velocity interval
([11, 21] km s^-1) and have similar sizes (0.6 and 0.8 deg^2). We analyzed the
structure of these clouds in detail and calculated their parameters (mass,
temperature, etc.). Two elongated structures were discovered in a
longitude-velocity map in the velocity interval [11, 30] km s^-1. We also found
an interesting filament that shows a 0.8 km s^-1 pc^-1 gradient perpendicular
to the direction of the long axis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04826</id><created>2017-05-13</created><updated>2017-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pruna</keyname><forenames>Giovanni Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Charged lepton flavour violation: precise background calculation and
  effective field theoretical interpretation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages,
  LaTeX</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Pruna, PSI-PR-17-09</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This note reviews recent theoretical developments in the study of charged
lepton flavour violation. The first part illustrates the status of precise
next-to-leading order quantum electrodynamics calculations for the background
of charged lepton flavour-violating processes, with a focus on the muonic
&quot;rare&quot; and &quot;radiative&quot; decays. Phenomenological implications of these
computations and their impact on present and future experiments will be
discussed. The second part describes the recent progress in the effective field
theory interpretation of charged lepton-flavour violating observables in
connection with different energy scales. A systematic approach is briefly
presented and applications on muonic and tauonic observables are reported. This
note is submitted as part of the conference proceedings for &quot;NuPhys2016:
Prospects in Neutrino Physics&quot;.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05707</id><created>2017-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Diaconescu</keyname><forenames>Duiliu-Emanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Local curves, wild character varieties, and degenerations</title><categories>math.AG hep-th</categories><comments>40 pages plus appendix</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conjectural results for cohomological invariants of wild character varieties
are obtained by counting curves in degenerate Calabi-Yau threefolds. A
conjectural formula for E-polynomials is derived from the Gromov-Witten theory
of local Calabi-Yau threefolds with normal crossing singularities. A refinement
is also conjectured, generalizing existing results of Hausel, Mereb and Wong as
well as recent joint work of Donagi, Pantev and the author for weighted
Poincar\'e polynomials of wild character varieties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06461</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pezzullo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the Mu2e Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Mu2e experiment at Fermilab: a search for lepton flavor violation</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>proceeding for FPCapri 2016 Preprint number: FERMILAB-CONF-17-167-E</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear and Particle Physics Proceedings, Volumes 285-286,
  April-May 2017, Pages 3-7</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2017.03.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Mu2e experiment at Fermilab will search for the charged lepton flavor
violating process of neutrino-less $\mu \to e$ coherent conversion in the field
of an aluminum nucleus. About $7 \cdot 10^{17}$ muons, provided by a dedicated
muon beam line in construction at Fermilab, will be stopped in 3 years in the
aluminum target. The corresponding single event sensitivity will be $2.5\cdot
10^{-17}$. In this paper a brief overview of the physics explored by the $\mu
\to e$ conversion is given, followed by a description of the Mu2e experimental
apparatus and the expected detector performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06731</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Obradovic</keyname><forenames>Borna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakshit</keyname><forenames>Titash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wei-E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Dennis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waldron</keyname><forenames>Niamh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaert</keyname><forenames>Nadine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodder</keyname><forenames>Mark S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parasitic Bipolar Leakage in III-V FETs: Impact of Substrate
  Architecture</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  InGaAs-based Gate-all-Around (GAA) FETs with moderate to high In content are
shown experimentally and theoretically to be unsuitable for low-leakage
advanced CMOS nodes. The primary cause for this is the large leakage penalty
induced by the Parasitic Bipolar Effect (PBE), which is seen to be particularly
difficult to remedy in GAA architectures. Experimental evidence of PBE in
In70Ga30As GAA FETs is demonstrated, along with a simulation-based analysis of
the PBE behavior. The impact of PBE is investigated by simulation for
alternative device architectures, such as bulk FinFETs and
FinFETs-on-insulator. PBE is found to be non-negligible in all standard InGaAs
FET designs. Practical PBE metrics are introduced and the design of a substrate
architecture for PBE suppression is elucidated. Finally, it is concluded that
the GAA architecture is not suitable for low-leakage InGaAs FETs; a bulk FinFET
is better suited for the role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06733</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Amritesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Taegon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sanjay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Junction Depth and Abruptness on the Activation and the
  Leakage Current in Germanium n$^{+}$/p Junctions</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phosphorous activation in Ge n$^{+}$/p junctions is compared in terms of
junction depth, by using laser spike annealing at 860{\deg}C for 400$\mu$s. The
reverse junction leakage is found to strongly depend on the abruptness of
dopant profiles. A shallow and abrupt junction is shown to have lower
phosphorous activation level, due to surface dose loss, and higher band-to-band
tunneling (BTBT) leakage, when compared to the deep junction. Simulations were
carried out to evaluate the lowest achievable OFF-state currents (I$_{OFF}$)
for Ge double-gate FETs when using such an abrupt junction. Our results
indicate that a Ge body thickness smaller than 5 nm is required to suppress the
BTBT leakage and meet the requirement for the high performance devices defined
by the International Technology Roadmap for Semiconductors (I$_{OFF}$ =
10$^{-7}$ A/$\mu$m).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06735</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Katsika-Tsigourakou</keyname><forenames>Vassiliki</forenames></author></authors><title>Boron-doped diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boron-doped diamond undergoes an insulator-metal transition at some critical
value (around 2.21 at %) of the dopand concentration. Here, we report a simple
method for the calculation of its bulk modulus, based on the thermodynamical
model, by Varotsos and Alexopoulos, that has been originally suggested for the
interconnection between the defect formation parameters in solids and bulk
properties. The results obtained at the doping level of 2.6 at %, which was
later improved at the level 0.5 at %, are in agreement with the experimental
values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06754</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Giannopoulou</keyname><forenames>Konstantina-Stavroula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makrakis</keyname><forenames>George N.</forenames></author></authors><title>An approximate series solution of the semiclassical Wigner equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new approximate series solution of the semiclassical Wigner
equation by uniformization of WKB approximations of the Schr\&quot;odinger
eigenfunctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06767</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>Carl M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brody</keyname><forenames>Dorje C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Markus P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on 'Comment on &quot;Hamiltonian for the zeros of the Riemann zeta
  function&quot; '</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP math.NT</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is in response to a recent comment by Bellissard
[arXiv:1704.02644] on the paper [Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 130201 (2017)]. It is
explained that the issues raised in the comment have already been discussed in
the paper and do not affect the conclusions of the paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06768</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wiesner</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The careless use of language in quantum information</title><categories>physics.soc-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An imperative aspect of modern science is that scientific institutions act
for the benefit of a common scientific enterprise, rather than for the personal
gain of individuals within them. This implies that science should not
perpetuate existing or historical unequal social orders. Some scientific
terminology, though, gives a very different impression. I will give two
examples of terminology invented recently for the field of quantum information
which use language associated with subordination, slavery, and racial
segregation: 'ancilla qubit' and 'quantum supremacy'.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06773</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>V. M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trigo</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaquero</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unusual rainbows as auroral candidates: another point of view</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, accepted for publication in Publ. Astron. Soc. Jpn</comments><doi>10.1093/pasj/psw127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several auroral events that occurred in the past have not been catalogued as
such due to fact that they were described in the historical sources with
different terminology. Hayakawa et al. (2016) have reviewed historical oriental
chronicles and have proposed the terms &quot;unusual rainbow&quot; and &quot;white rainbow&quot; as
candidates to auroras. In this work, we present three events that took place in
the 18th century in two different settings (the Iberian Peninsula and Brazil)
that were originally described with similar definition/wording used by the
oriental chronicles, despite the inherent differences in terms associated to
oriental and Latin languages. We show that these terms are indeed applicable to
the three case studies from Europe and South America. Thus, the auroral
catalogues available can be extended for occidental sources with this new
terminology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06776</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06776</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Chastain</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelz</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comparison of EIT and TRACE Loop Widths</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study we have compared coronal loops in the Extreme ultraviolet
Imaging Telescope (EIT) on-board the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO)
with coronal loops from the Transition Region and Coronal Explorer (TRACE). The
purpose of which is to quantitatively and qualitatively examine the effects of
spatial resolution on the width of coronal loops and implications for how a
coronal loop is defined. Out of twenty-two loop sections analyzed, we find that
none of them were resolved in EIT and none of them were close to the width of
the TRACE loops. These findings suggest that coronal loops are unresolved in
EIT. We also find examples of how unresolved loops can be quite misleading. We
have also found that many of the TRACE loops that we have analyzed may be
unresolved as well. Our findings emphasize the importance of studying loop
width in order to better understand coronal loops and also emphasize the need
for instruments with higher spatial resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06780</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoodifar</keyname><forenames>Simin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strohmayer</keyname><forenames>Tod</forenames></author></authors><title>Where Are the r-modes? Chandra Observations of Millisecond Pulsars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 840, Number 2, article id. 94, 8
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6d62</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of {\it Chandra} observations of two non-accreting
millisecond pulsars, PSRs J1640$+$2224 (J1640) and J1709$+$2313 (J1709), with
low inferred magnetic fields and spin-down rates in order to constrain their
surface temperatures, obtain limits on the amplitude of unstable $r$-modes in
them, and make comparisons with similar limits obtained for a sample of
accreting low-mass X-ray binary (LMXB) neutron stars. We detect both pulsars in
the X-ray band for the first time. They are faint, with inferred soft X-ray
fluxes ($0.3-3$ keV) of $\approx$ $6\times10^{-15}$ and $3\times 10^{-15}$ erg
cm$^{-2}$ s$^{-1}$ for J1640 and J1709, respectively. Spectral analysis
assuming hydrogen atmosphere emission gives global effective temperature upper
limits ($90\%$ confidence) of $3.3 - 4.3 \times 10^5$ K for J1640 and $3.6 -
4.7 \times 10^5$ K for J1709, where the low end of the range corresponds to
canonical neutron stars ($M=1.4 M_{\odot}$), and the upper end corresponds to
higher-mass stars ($M=2.21 M_{\odot}$). Under the assumption that $r$-mode
heating provides the thermal support, we obtain dimensionless $r$-mode
amplitude upper limits of $3.2 - 4.8 \times 10^{-8}$ and $1.8 - 2.8 \times
10^{-7}$ for J1640 and J1709, respectively, where again the low end of the
range corresponds to lower-mass, canonical neutron stars ($M=1.4 M_{\odot}$).
These limits are about an order of magnitude lower than those we derived
previously for a sample of LMXBs, except for the accreting millisecond X-ray
pulsar (AMXP) SAX J1808.4$-$3658, which has a comparable amplitude limit to
J1640 and J1709.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06818</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Barchi</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Costa</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sautter</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moura</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stalder</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosa</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Carvalho</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving galaxy morphology with machine learning</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Computacional Interdisciplinary Sciences, v. 7, p. 114.
  2016</journal-ref><doi>10.6062/jcis.2016.07.03.0114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents machine learning experiments performed over results of
galaxy classification into elliptical (E) and spiral (S) with morphological
parameters: concetration (CN), assimetry metrics (A3), smoothness metrics (S3),
entropy (H) and gradient pattern analysis parameter (GA). Except concentration,
all parameters performed a image segmentation pre-processing. For supervision
and to compute confusion matrices, we used as true label the galaxy
classification from GalaxyZoo. With a 48145 objects dataset after preprocessing
(44760 galaxies labeled as S and 3385 as E), we performed experiments with
Support Vector Machine (SVM) and Decision Tree (DT). Whit a 1962 objects
balanced dataset, we applied K- means and Agglomerative Hierarchical
Clustering. All experiments with supervision reached an Overall Accuracy OA &gt;=
97%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06832</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gassenq</keyname><forenames>Alban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guilloy</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauc</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouchon</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widiez</keyname><forenames>Julie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rothman</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartmann</keyname><forenames>Jean-Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelnokov</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reboud</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly strained Ge micro-blocks bonded on Si platform for Mid-Infrared
  photonic applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adding sufficient tensile strain to Ge can turn the material to a direct
bandgap group IV semiconductor emitting in the mid-infrared wavelength range.
However, highly strained-Ge cannot be directly grown on Si due to its large
lattice mismatch. In this work, we have developed a process based on Ge
micro-bridge strain redistribution intentionally landed to the Si substrate.
Traction arms can be then partially etched to keep only localized strained-Ge
micro-blocks. Large tunable uniaxial stresses up to 4.2% strain were
demonstrated bonded on Si. Our approach allows to envision integrated
strained-Ge on Si platform for mid-infrared integrated optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06836</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Qiuxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Zhiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihalache</keyname><forenames>Dumitru</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jingsong</forenames></author></authors><title>Smooth positon solutions of the focusing modified Korteweg-de Vries
  equation</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures. This is the accepted version by Nonlinear
  Dynamics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $n$-fold Darboux transformation $T_{n}$ of the focusing real mo\-di\-fied
Kor\-te\-weg-de Vries (mKdV) equation is expressed in terms of the determinant
representation. Using this representation, the $n$-soliton solutions of the
mKdV equation are also expressed by determinants whose elements consist of the
eigenvalues $\lambda_{j}$ and the corresponding eigenfunctions of the
associated Lax equation. The nonsingular $n$-positon solutions of the focusing
mKdV equation are obtained in the special limit
$\lambda_{j}\rightarrow\lambda_{1}$, from the corresponding $n$-soliton
solutions and by using the associated higher-order Taylor expansion.
Furthermore, the decomposition method of the $n$-positon solution into $n$
single-soliton solutions, the trajectories, and the corresponding &quot;phase
shifts&quot; of the multi-positons are also investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06844</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Raman</keyname><forenames>V. Venkata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anandarao</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janardhan</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Infrared Photometric and Spectroscopic Study of Post-AGB Stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>45 Pages, 24 figures, Accepted in MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present here $Spitzer$ mid-infrared (IR) spectra and modeling of the
spectral energy distribution (SED) of a selection of post-Asymptotic Giant
Branch (PAGB) stars. The mid-IR spectra of majority of these sources showed
spectral features such as polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and silicates
in emission. Our results from SED modeling showed interesting trends of
dependency between the photospheric and circumstellar parameters. A trend of
dependency is also noticed between the ratios of equivalent widths (EWs) of
various vibrational modes of PAHs and the photospheric temperature T$_{*}$ and
model-derived stellar parameters for the sample stars. The PAGB mass loss rates
derived from the SED models are found to be higher than those for the AGB
stars. In a few objects, low and high excitation fine structure emission lines
were identified, indicating their advanced stage of evolution. Further, IR
vibration modes of fullerene (C$_{60}$) were detected for the first time in the
PAGB star IRAS 21546+4721.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06865</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Mizev</keyname><forenames>Aleksey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shmyrova</keyname><forenames>Anastasia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizeva</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peleneva</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames></author></authors><title>Exhaled breath barbotage: a new method for pulmonary surfactant
  dysfunction assessment</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exhaled air contains aerosol of submicron droplets of the alveolar lining
fluid (ALF), which are generated in the small airways of a human lung. Since
the exhaled particles are micro-samples of the ALF, their trapping opens up an
opportunity to collect non-invasively a native material from respiratory tract.
Recent studies of the particle characteristics (such as size distribution,
concentration and composition) in healthy and diseased subjects performed under
various conditions have demonstrated a high potential of the analysis of
exhaled aerosol droplets for identifying and monitoring pathological processes
in the ALF. In this paper we present a new method for sampling of aerosol
particles during the exhaled breath barbotage (EBB) through liquid. The
barbotage procedure results in accumulation of the pulmonary surfactant, being
the main component of ALF, on the liquid surface, which makes possible the
study its surface properties. We also propose a data processing algorithm to
evaluate the surface pressure ($\pi$) -- surface concentration ($\Gamma$)
isotherm from the raw data measured in a Langmuir trough. Finally, we analyze
the $(\pi-\Gamma)$ isotherms obtained for the samples collected in the groups
of healthy volunteers and patients with pulmonary tuberculosis and compare them
with the isotherm measured for the artificial pulmonary surfactant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06889</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kavyashree</keyname></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Manvendra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mittal</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractal analysis of BaF2 thin films deposited on different substrates</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Barrium fluoride (BaF2) thin films were prepared by electron beam evaporation
technique at room temperature, on glass, Silicon and Aluminum substrates having
thickness of 20 nm each. Its structural property and surface morphology were
studied using glancing angle X-ray diffraction (GAXRD) and atomic force
microscopy (AFM) respectively. It was found that grain size, average surface
roughness and interface width changes with different substrates. Higuchi
algorithm is applied for the fractal measure on AFM images.It was observed
found that the fractal dimension varied from substrate to substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06896</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Xiangyu</forenames></author></authors><title>Disordered statistical physics in low dimensions: extremes, glass
  transition, and localization</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Ph.D. thesis, 154 pages, 47 figures</comments><report-no>NNT 2017-SACLS-067</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis presents original results in two domains of disordered
statistical physics: logarithmic correlated Random Energy Models (logREMs), and
localization transitions in long-range random matrices.
  In the first part devoted to logREMs, we show how to characterise their
common properties and model--specific data. Then we develop their replica
symmetry breaking treatment, which leads to the freezing scenario of their free
energy distribution and the general description of their minima process, in
terms of decorated Poisson point process. We also report a series of new
applications of the Jack polynomials in the exact predictions of some
observables in the circular model and its variants. Finally, we present the
recent progress on the exact connection between logREMs and the Liouville
conformal field theory.
  The goal of the second part is to introduce and study a new class of banded
random matrices, the broadly distributed class, which is characterid an
effective sparseness. We will first study a specific model of the class, the
Beta Banded random matrices, inspired by an exact mapping to a recently studied
statistical model of long--range first--passage percolation/epidemics dynamics.
Using analytical arguments based on the mapping and numerics, we show the
existence of localization transitions with mobility edges in the
&quot;stretch--exponential&quot; parameter--regime of the statistical models. Then, using
a block--diagonalization renormalization approach, we argue that such
localization transitions occur generically in the broadly distributed class.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06915</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Murray</keyname><forenames>W. J</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs with Hadronic Signatures</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>4 page Moriond QCD 2017 writeup</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The decay of the Higgs boson to b quarks should be the dominant decay mode,
but it has not yet been conclusively established. The LHC run 1 results are
recalled and the current status of the LHC Run 2 studies is reviewed. The
analysis is approaching decisive sensitivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06919</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bellm</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gieseke</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grellscheid</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirchgae&#xdf;er</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loshaj</keyname><forenames>Frash&#xeb;r</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nail</keyname><forenames>Graeme</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papaefstathiou</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pl&#xe4;tzer</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podskubka</keyname><forenames>Radek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuschle</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schichtel</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seymour</keyname><forenames>Michael H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si&#xf3;dmok</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webster</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author></authors><title>Herwig 7.1 Release Note</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures. Herwig is available from
  https://herwig.hepforge.org/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-TH-2017-109, MAN/HEP/2017/08, UWTHPH-2017-10,
  IFJPAN-IV-2017-7, NIKHEF 2017-026, HERWIG-2017-02, KA-TP-19-2017,
  MCnet-17-08, IPPP/17/40</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new release of the Monte Carlo event generator Herwig (version 7.1) is now
available. This version introduces a number of improvements, notably: multi-jet
merging with the dipole shower at LO and NLO QCD; a new model for soft
interactions and diffraction; improvements to mass effects and top decays in
the dipole shower, as well as a new tune of the hadronisation parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06930</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Karmakar</keyname><forenames>Subhajeet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Airapetian</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Kuntal</forenames></author></authors><title>X-Ray Superflares on CC Eri</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6cb0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an in-depth study of two superflares (F1 and F2) detected on an
active binary star CC Eridani by the Swift observatory. These superflares
triggered the Burst Alert Telescope (BAT) in the hard X-ray band on 2008
October 16 and 2012 February 24. The rise phases of both the flares were
observed only with BAT, whereas the decay phases were observed simultaneously
with the X-ray Telescope. It has been found that the flares decay faster in the
hard X-ray band than in the soft X-ray band. Both flares F1 and F2 are highly
energetic with respective peak X-ray luminosities of $\sim$$10^{32.2}$ and
$\sim$$10^{31.8}$ erg s$^{-1}$ in 0.3--50 keV energy band, which are larger
than any other flares previously observed on CC Eri. The time-resolved spectral
analysis during the flares shows the variation in the coronal temperature,
emission measure, and abundances. The elemental abundances are enhanced by a
factor of $\sim$8 to the minimum observed in the post-flare phase for the flare
F1. The observed peak temperatures in these two flares are found to be 174 MK
and 128 MK. Using the hydrodynamic loop modeling, we derive loop lengths for
both the flares as 1.2$\pm$0.1$\times$10$^{10}$ cm and
2.2$\pm$0.6$\times$10$^{10}$ cm, respectively. The Fe K$\alpha$ emission at 6.4
keV is also detected in the X-ray spectra and we model the K$\alpha$ emission
feature as fluorescence from the hot flare source irradiating the photospheric
iron. These superflares are the brightest, hottest, and shortest in duration
observed thus far on CC Eri.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06938</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hess</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linearity of the solid-electrolyte-interphase overpotential</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, 1x Suppl Info with 25pages</comments><doi>10.1016/j.electacta.2017.05.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In today's modeling and analysis of electrochemical cycling of Li- and Na-ion
batteries, an assumption is often made regarding the interphase that forms
between the active material and liquid electrolyte at low potentials, the
so-called solid-electrolyte interphase (SEI). The SEI is generally assumed to
act like an Ohmic resistor despite its complex chemical composition and
porosity distribution. Here, one reports that this assumption does not hold for
alkali-ion batteries. The SEI possesses a non-linear overpotential
characteristic which saturates already at low current density of 0.1 mAcm-2
giving only 3.3$\pm$1 mV for Li-metal electrodes in different electrolytes. For
Na- and K-metal electrodes, these SEI overpotentials become dominating with 31
mV and 72 mV at the same low current densities giving significant disadvantages
over Li-ion batteries for commercial applications. With the introduction of a
new term, one achieves agreement between the parameters from galvanostatic
cycling and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy for the first time. The
discovery of the non-linear SEI overpotential disrupts the general believes
about the role of the SEI for today's batteries as it is basically negligible
for Li-ion batteries at room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06955</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Roma&#x144;czukiewicz</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation pressure in the Coupled Nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger Equation
  exerted on the solitons</title><categories>nlin.PS hep-th</categories><comments>3 figures, supplementary material: 4 movies</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the paper an interaction between a soliton and a traveling wave in the
Coupled Nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger Equation (CNLSE) is considered. The force
acting on the soliton can both push or pull the soliton depending on parameters
of the equation, structure of the soliton and the incident wave. In special
cases analytical results are presented and in general numerical solutions of
both linearized and the full problem are shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06973</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of Statistical Associating Fluid Theory for Aqueous Ionic
  Liquid Solutions by Implementing Monte Carlo Simulations and Ornstein-Zernike
  Integral Equation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>PhD thesis, Univ Wyoming (2014)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A recent version of statistical associating fluid theory (SAFT), namely
SAFT2, is coupled with the van der Waals and Platteeuw theory to study the
alkane hydrate phase equilibrium conditions. The model is found to provide an
accurate representation of the alkane hydrate dissociation conditions with and
without inhibitors, such as salts, alcohols, as well as mixed salts and
alcohol. Based on SAFT2, a heterosegmented SAFT equation of state is developed
to model the thermodynamic properties of aqueous ionic liquid (IL) solutions,
which is recently discovered as dual function gas hydrate inhibitors. With
transferrable model parameters, the heterosegmented SAFT generally well
represents the liquid density, activity coefficient, and osmotic coefficient of
aqueous imidazolium IL solutions. The inhibition effects of imidazolium IL on
methane hydrate is also studied by the heterosegmented SAFT and the van der
Waals and Platteeuw theory.
  The heterosegmented SAFT is then modified to better represent the
thermodynamic properties of aqueous IL solutions with the help of Monte Carlo
simulation and the solutions of Ornstein-Zernike integral equation. A simple
modification of MSA, referred to as KMSA, is proposed to accurately predict the
excess energies of electrolyte system in mixture with neutral component. Monte
Carlo simulations are also conducted on flexible charged hard-sphere chain
molecules, and a SAFT model which implements either a dimer or a dimer-monomer
approach to account for the charged chain connectivity is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06986</id><created>2017-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Bucher</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;On the nature of magnetic stripes in cuprate
  superconductors,&quot; by H. Jacobsen et al., arXiv:1704.08528v2</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamics reduces the orthorhombicity of magnetic stripes in La_2CuO_4+y. The
measured stripe incommensuration can be used to determine the oxygen content of
the sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06988</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Kausar</keyname><forenames>Hafiza Rizwana</forenames></author></authors><title>Behaviour of Charged Collapsing Fluids after Hydrostatic Equilibrium in
  R^n Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in European Physical Journal C</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to study the transport equation and its coupling
with Maxwell equation in the framework of R^n gravity. Using
Muller-Israel-Stewart theory for the conduction of dissipative fluids, we
analyze the temperature, heat flux, viscosity and thermal conductivity in the
scenario of relaxation time. All these thermodynamical variables are appeared
in the form of a single factor whose influence is discussed on the evolution of
relativistic model for the heat conducting collapsing star.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06999</id><created>2017-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Doubrov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferapontov</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruglikov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable systems in 4D associated with sixfolds in Gr(4,6)</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1503.02274</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $Gr(d,n)$ be the Grassmannian of $d$-dimensional linear subspaces of an
$n$-dimensional vector space $V$. A submanifold $X\subset Gr(d, n)$ gives rise
to a differential system $\Sigma(X)$ that governs $d$-dimensional submanifolds
of $V$ whose Gaussian image is contained in $X$. We investigate a special case
of this construction where $X$ is a sixfold in $Gr(4, 6)$. The corresponding
system $\Sigma(X)$ reduces to a pair of first-order PDEs for 2 functions of 4
independent variables. Equations of this type arise in self-dual Ricci-flat
geometry. Our main result is a complete description of integrable systems
$\Sigma(X)$. These naturally fall into two subclasses.
  (1) Systems of Monge-Amp\`ere type. The corresponding sixfolds $X$ are
codimension 2 linear sections of the Pl\&quot;ucker embedding
$Gr(4,6)\subset\mathbb{P}^{14}$.
  (2) General linearly degenerate systems. The corresponding sixfolds $X$ are
the images of quadratic maps $\mathbb{P}^6- Gr(4, 6)$ given by a version of the
classical construction of Chasles.
  We prove that integrability is equivalent to the requirement that the
characteristic variety of system $\Sigma(X)$ gives rise to a conformal
structure which is self-dual on every solution. In fact, all solutions carry
hyper-Hermitian geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07004</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotti</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macculi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piro</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Argan</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>Flavio</forenames></author></authors><title>The Cryogenic AntiCoincidence detector for ATHENA X-IFU: a scientific
  assessment of the observational capabilities in the hard X-ray band</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Accepted for publication on Experimental Astronomy</comments><doi>10.1007/s10686-017-9543-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ATHENA is a large X-ray observatory, planned to be launched by ESA in 2028
towards an L2 orbit. One of the two instruments of the payload is the X-IFU: a
cryogenic spectrometer based on a large array of TES microcalorimeters, able to
perform integral field spectrography in the 0.2-12 keV band (2.5 eV FWHM at 6
keV). The X-IFU sensitivity is highly degraded by the particle background
expected in the L2 orbit, which is induced by primary protons of both galactic
and solar origin, and mostly by secondary electrons. To reduce the particle
background level and enable the mission science goals, the instrument
incorporates a Cryogenic AntiCoincidence detector (CryoAC). It is a 4 pixel TES
based detector, placed &lt;1 mm below the main array. In this paper we report a
scientific assessment of the CryoAC observational capabilities in the hard
X-ray band (E&gt;10 keV). The aim of the study has been to understand if the
present detector design can be improved in order to enlarge the X-IFU
scientific capability on an energy band wider than the TES array. This is
beyond the CryoAC baseline, being this instrument aimed to operate as
anticoincidence particle detector and not conceived to perform X-ray
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07013</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Aditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>Indranil</forenames></author></authors><title>Limits on quantum deletion from no signaling principle</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the fundamental restrictions that quantum mechanics imposes is the &quot;No
deletion Theorem&quot; which tells us that given two identical unknown quantum
states, it is impossible to delete one of them. But nevertheless if not
perfect, people have tried to delete it approximately. In these approximate
deleting processes our basic target is to delete one of the two identical
copies as much as possible while preserving the other copy. In this brief
report, by using the No communication theorem (NCT) (impossibility of sending
signal faster than light using a quantum resource) as a guiding principle, we
obtain a bound on the sum of the fidelity of deletion and the fidelity of
preservation. Our result not only brings out the complementary relation between
these two fidelities but also predicts the optimal value of the fidelity of
deletion achievable for a given fidelity of preservation under no signaling
constraint. This work eventually saturates the quest for finding out the
optimal value of deletion within the NCT framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07014</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Balz</keyname><forenames>Ben N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reimann</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Typical Relaxation of Isolated Many-Body Systems Which Do Not Thermalize</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Phys Rev. Lett. 118, 190601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.190601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider isolated many-body quantum systems which do not thermalize, i.e.,
expectation values approach an (approximately) steady longtime limit which
disagrees with the microcanonical prediction of equilibrium statistical
mechanics. A general analytical theory is worked out for the typical temporal
relaxation behavior in such cases. The main prerequisites are initial
conditions which appreciably populate many energy levels and do not give rise
to significant spatial inhomogeneities on macroscopic scales. The theory
explains very well the experimental and numerical findings in a trapped-ion
quantum simulator exhibiting many-body localization, in ultracold atomic gases,
and in integrable hard-core boson and XXZ models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07035</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanke</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buhl</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bihlmayer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wortmann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;gel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokrousov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum spin Hall effect and topological phase transitions in honeycomb
  antiferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While the quantum spin Hall (QSH) effect and antiferromagnetic order
constitute two of the most promising phenomena for embedding basic spintronic
concepts into future technologies, almost all of the QSH insulators known to
date are non-magnetic. Here, based on tight-binding arguments and
first-principles theory, we predict two-dimensional antiferromagnets with
honeycomb lattice structure to exhibit the QSH effect due to the combined
symmetry of time reversal and spatial inversion. We identify functionalized Sn
films as experimentally feasible examples which reveal large band gaps
rendering these systems ideal for energy efficient spintronics applications.
Remarkably, we discover that tensile strain can tune the magnetic order in
these materials, accompanied by a topological phase transition from the QSH to
the quantum anomalous Hall phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07045</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Carbonell-Sanrom&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hieulle</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilas-Varela</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandimarte</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iraola</keyname><forenames>Mikel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrag&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jingcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abadia</keyname><forenames>Mikel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corso</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Portal</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pe&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascual</keyname><forenames>Jose Ignacio</forenames></author></authors><title>Doping of Graphene Nanoribbons via Functional Group Edge Modification</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the on-surface synthesis of 7 armchair graphene nanoribbons
(7-AGNRs) substituted with nitrile (CN) functional groups. The CN groups are
attached to the GNR backbone by modifying the 7-AGNR precursor. While many of
these groups survive the on-surface synthesis, the reaction process causes the
cleavage of some CN from the ribbon backbone and the on-surface
cycloisomerization of few nitriles onto pyridine rings. Scanning Tunneling
Spectroscopy and Density Functional Theory reveal that CN groups behave as very
efficient n-dopants, significantly downshifting the bands of the ribbon, and
introducing deep impurity levels associated to the nitrogen electron lone
pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07054</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ermolli</keyname><forenames>Ilaria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibasaki</keyname><forenames>Kiyoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tlatov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Driel-Gesztelyi</keyname><forenames>Lidia</forenames></author></authors><title>Solar cycle indices from the photosphere to the corona: measurements and
  underlying physics</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Space Science Reviews, Volume 186, Issue 1-4, 2014, pp. 105-135</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11214-014-0089-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A variety of indices have been proposed in order to represent the many
different observables modulated by the solar cycle. Most of these indices are
highly correlated with each other owing to their intrinsic link with the solar
magnetism and the dominant eleven year cycle, but their variations may differ
in fine details, as well as on short- and long-term trends. In this paper we
present an overview of the indices that are often employed to describe the many
features of the solar cycle, moving from the ones referring to direct
observations of the inner solar atmosphere, the photosphere and chromosphere,
to those deriving from measurements of the transition region and solar corona.
For each index, we summarize existing measurements {\bf and typical use}, and
for those that quantify physical observables, we describe the underlying
physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07060</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Welchman</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thonhauser</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>H4-Alkanes: A new class of hydrogen storage material?</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 42, 2223 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijhydene.2016.12.144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The methane-based material (H$_2$)$_4$CH$_4$, also called H4M for short, is
in essence a methane molecule with 4 physisorbed H$_2$ molecules. While H4M has
exceptionally high hydrogen storage densities when it forms a molecular solid,
unfortunately, this solid is only stable at impractically high pressures and/or
low temperatures. To overcome this limitation, we show through simulations that
longer alkanes (methane is the shortest alkane) also form stable structures
that still physisorb 4 H$_2$ molecules per carbon atom; we call those
structures H4-alkanes. We further show via molecular dynamics simulations that
the stability field of molecular solids formed from H4-alkanes increases
remarkably with chain length compared to H4M, just as it does for regular
alkanes. From our simulations of H4-alkanes with lengths 1, 4, 10, and 20, we
see that e.g. for the 20-carbon the stability field is doubled at higher
pressures. While even longer chains show only insignificant improvements, we
discuss various other options to stabilize H4-alkanes more. Our
proof-of-principle results lay the groundwork to show that H4-alkanes can
become viable hydrogen storage materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07071</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Barriga</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivenkov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golias</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varykhalov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romualdi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashina</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornilov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebert</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-picosecond spin dynamics of excited states in the topological
  insulator Bi$_2$Te$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 125405 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.125405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using time-, spin- and angle-resolved photoemission, we investigate the
ultrafast spin dynamics of hot electrons on the surface of the topological
insulator Bi$_2$Te$_3$ following optical excitation by fs-infrared pulses. We
observe two surface-resonance states above the Fermi level coexisting with a
transient population of Dirac fermions that relax in about $\sim$2 ps. One
state is located below $\sim$0.4 eV just above the bulk continuum, the other
one at $\sim$0.8 eV inside a projected bulk band gap. At the onset of the
excitation, both states exhibit a reversed spin texture with respect to that of
the transient Dirac bands, in agreement with our one-step photoemission
calculations. Our data reveal that the high-energy state undergoes spin
relaxation within $\sim$0.5 ps, a process that triggers the subsequent spin
dynamics of both the Dirac cone and the low-energy state, which behave as two
dynamically-locked electron populations. We discuss the origin of this behavior
by comparing the relaxation times observed for electrons with opposite spins to
the ones obtained from a microscopic Boltzmann model of ultrafast band cooling
introduced into the photoemission calculations. Our results demonstrate that
the nonequilibrium surface dynamics is governed by electron-electron rather
than electron-phonon scattering, with a characteristic time scale unambiguously
determined by the complex spin texture of excited states above the Fermi level.
Our findings reveal the critical importance of detecting momentum and
energy-resolved spin textures with fs resolution to fully understand the sub-ps
dynamics of transient electrons on the surface of topological insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07072</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Charbonneau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>Lecture Notes on the Statistical Mechanics of Disordered Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This material complements David Chandler's Introduction to Modern Statistical
Mechanics (Oxford University Press, 1987) in a graduate-level, one-semester
course I teach in the Department of Chemistry at Duke University. Students
enter this course with some knowledge of statistical thermodynamics and quantum
mechanics, usually acquired from undergraduate physical chemistry at the level
of D. A. McQuarrie &amp; J. D. Simon's Physical Chemistry: A Molecular Approach
(University Science Books, 1997). These notes, which introduce students to a
modern treatment of glassiness and to the replica method, build on the material
and problems contained in the eight chapters of Chandler's textbook.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07078</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Barriga</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golias</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varykhalov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashina</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornilov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rader</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser-induced persistent photovoltage on the surface of a ternary
  topological insulator at room temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 141605 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979596</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using time- and angle-resolved photoemission, we investigate the ultrafast
response of excited electrons in the ternary topological insulator (Bi$_{1
x}$Sb$_{x}$)$_2$Te$_3$ to fs-infrared pulses. We demonstrate that at the
critical concentration $x$=0.55, where the system becomes bulk insulating, a
surface voltage can be driven at room temperature through the topological
surface state solely by optical means. We further show that such a photovoltage
persists over a time scale that exceeds $\sim$6 $\mu$s, i.e, much longer than
the characteristic relaxation times of bulk states. We attribute the origin of
the photovoltage to a laser-induced band-bending effect which emerges near the
surface region on ultrafast time scales. The photovoltage is also accompanied
by a remarkable increase in the relaxation times of excited states as compared
to undoped topological insulators. Our findings are relevant in the context of
applications of topological surface states in future optical devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07093</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Tejeda</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Incompressible wind accretion</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures. Submitted. Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple, analytic model for the accretion flow of an
incompressible wind onto a gravitating object. This solution corresponds to the
Newtonian limit of a previously known relativistic model for a fluid obeying a
stiff equation of state for which the sound speed is constant everywhere and
equal to the speed of light. The new solution should be useful as a benchmark
test for numerical hydrodynamics codes and, moreover, it can be used as an
illustrative example in a gas dynamics course.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-22</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07101</id><created>2017-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Debdipta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Subhankar</forenames></author></authors><title>Feature-rich bifurcations in a simple electronic circuit</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><comments>5 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple electronic circuit with a voltage controlled current source is
investigated. The circuit exhibits rich dynamics upon varying the circuit
elements such as L,C and R, and the control factor of the current source. Among
several other interesting features, the circuit demonstrates two local
bifurcations, namely, node to spiral and Hopf bifurcation, and a global
homoclinic bifurcation. Phase-portraits corresponding to these bifurcations are
presented and the implications of these bifurcations on system stability are
discussed. In particular, the circuit parameters corresponding to the onset of
Hopf bifurcation may be exploited to design an oscillator with stable frequency
and amplitude. The circuit may be easily implemented with nonlinear resistive
elements such as diodes or transistors in saturation and a gyrator block as the
voltage controlled current source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
