<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:33:15Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-11-06" from="2016-11-06" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04447</id><created>2015-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaudhuri</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadhukhan</keyname><forenames>Jhilam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meena</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rana</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Evidence of Washing out of Nuclear Shell Effects</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, Physical Review C (in press)</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.91.044620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Constraining excitation energy at which nuclear shell effect washes out has
important implications on the production of super heavy elements and many other
fields of nuclear physics research. We report the fission fragment mass
distribution in alpha induced reaction on an actinide target for wide
excitation range in close energy interval and show direct evidence that nuclear
shell effect washes out at excitation energy ~40 MeV. Calculation shows that
second peak of the fission barrier also vanishes around similar excitation
energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05855</id><created>2015-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Alloul</keyname><forenames>Henri</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly Correlated Electrons in Solids</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages , 4 figures published in Scholarpedia</comments><journal-ref>Strongly Correlated Electrons in Solids, Scholarpedia, 9(7):32067
  (2014)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most emergent properties of the materials discovered since the 1980s are
related to the existence of electron-electron interactions which are large with
respect to the kinetic energies and could not be thoroughly studied before. The
occurrence of metal insulator transitions, of exotic magnetic and/or
superconducting properties in many new compounds have stimulated a large series
of ex- perimental and theoretical developments to grasp their physical
significance. We present here a simple introduction to the elementary aspects
of the physics of electron-electron interactions, which could be a starting
point for typical undergraduate students.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05264</id><created>2015-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yingjin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Haibo</forenames></author></authors><title>Density-Matrix Renormalization Group Algorithm with Multi-Level Active
  Space</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 034105 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4926833</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The density-matrix renormalization group (DMRG) method, which can deal with a
large active space composed of tens of orbitals, is nowadays widely used as an
efficient addition to traditional complete active space (CAS)-based approaches.
In this paper, we present the DMRG algorithm with a multi-level (ML) control of
the active space based on chemical intuition-based hierarchical orbital
ordering, which is called as ML-DMRG with its self-consistent field variant
ML-DMRG-SCF. Ground and excited state calculations of H2O, N2, indole, and Cr2
with comparisons to DMRG references using fixed number of kept states (M)
illustrate that MLtype DMRG calculations can obtain noticeable efficiency
gains. It is also shown that the orbital re-ordering based on hierarchical
multiple active subspaces may be beneficial for reducing computational time for
not only ML-DMRG calculations but also DMRG ones with fixed M values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06924</id><created>2015-07-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Antoniadis</keyname><forenames>Ignatios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knoops</keyname><forenames>Rob</forenames></author></authors><title>MSSM soft terms from supergravity with gauged R-symmetry in de Sitter
  vacuum</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2015.11.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We work out the phenomenology of a model of supersymmetry breaking in the
presence of a tiny (tunable) positive cosmological constant, proposed by the
authors in arXiv:1403.1534. It utilises a single chiral multiplet with a gauged
shift symmetry, that can be identified with the string dilaton (or an
appropriate compactification modulus). The model is coupled to the MSSM,
leading to calculable soft supersymmetry breaking masses and a distinct low
energy phenomenology that allows to differentiate it from other models of
supersymmetry breaking and mediation mechanisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04963</id><created>2015-10-16</created><updated>2016-02-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Bennett E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xuezhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roder</keyname><forenames>Paden B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramson</keyname><forenames>Evan H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauzauskie</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recovery of Si-IV nanowires from extreme GPa pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4948576</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use Raman spectroscopy in tandem with transmission electron microscopy and
DFT simulations to show that extreme (GPa) pressure converts the phase of
silicon nanowires from cubic (Si-I) to hexagonal (Si-IV) while preserving the
nanowire's cylindrical morphology. In situ Raman scattering of the TO mode
demonstrates the high-pressure Si-I to Si-II phase transition near 9 GPa. Raman
signal of the TO phonon shows a decrease in intensity in the range 9 to 14 GPa.
Then, at 17 GPa, it is no longer detectable, indicating a second phase change
(Si-II to Si-V) in the 14 to 17 GPa range. Recovery of exotic phases in
individual silicon nanowires from diamond anvil cell experiments reaching 17
GPa is also shown. Raman measurements indicate Si-IV as the dominant phase in
pressurized nanowires after decompression. Transmission electron microscopy and
electron diffraction confirm crystalline Si-IV domains in individual nanowires.
Computational electromagnetic simulations suggest that heating from the Raman
laser probe is negligible and that near-hydrostatic pressure is the primary
driving force for the formation of hexagonal silicon nanowires.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05678</id><created>2015-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Herbut</keyname><forenames>Fedor</forenames></author></authors><title>Does Unitary Measurement Theory Lead to an Everettian Interpretation?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum-mechanical interpretation-related implications of the theory of
unitary premeasurement [1] on complete measurement (objectification or collapse
included) are investigated in the present article with a view to give an
affirmative answer to the question in the title. It is argued that both Bohr's
and von Neumann's ideas lead to those of Everett. Hence, the latter can be, in
some sense, considered to be a continuation and elaboration of both former
approaches. The importance of the idea of relativeness in Everett's theory is
emphasized. To free the relative-state theory from its roots both of
classicalness and of subjective observation in the argument of this study, the
general or unfolded version of Everett's theory is sketched.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07432</id><created>2015-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Yuwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cristescu</keyname><forenames>Simona M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harren</keyname><forenames>Frans J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandon</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author></authors><title>Vernier effect within a versatile femtosecond optical parametric
  oscillator for broad-tunable, high-repetition-rate oscillator</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within a synchronously pumped optical parametric oscillator (SPOPO), the
inherent synchronism between the pump and the resonating signal is the magic to
partly transfer the coherence property of the pump to the signal. In our
demonstration, Vernier effect is observed within a femtosecond SPOPO by simply
detuning the FSR of the cavity, generating signal pulses at tunable repetition
rate from several GHz to 1 THz with a maximum 22.58 nm full width half maximum
(FWHM) bandwidth supporting 160 fs pulses covering the C- and L-bands of the
telecom wavelength region. This technique offers a simple method of active
filtering of dense frequency comb lines instead of using Fabry-P\'erot (FP)
cavities with complex locking system for astro-comb generation. Beside, as a
promising source for frequency combs with tunable and large comb-spacing, it
offers potential opportunities for applications such as high speed coherent
data transmission, line-by-line pulse shaping, optical clocks and precision
metrology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
