<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:33:33Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-03-27" from="2017-03-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0711.4339</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0711.4339</id><created>2007-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Dyer</keyname><forenames>Matthew S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>Mats</forenames></author></authors><title>The nature of highly anisotropic free-electron-like states in a
  glycinate monolayer on Cu(100)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Cond. Matter 20, 312002 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/20/31/312002</doi><abstract>  The free-electron-like state observed in a scanning tunneling spectroscopy
study of a chiral p(2x4) monolayer of glycinate ions on the Cu(100) surface [K.
Kanazawa et al, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 129, 740 (2007)] is shown from density
functional theory calculations to originate from a Cu Shockley surface state at
the surface Brillouin zone boundary of the clean surface with highly
anisotropic dispersion. The presence of the glycinate ions on the surface
causes a dramatically enhanced tunneling into this surface state that is
otherwise not observed in tunneling on the bare surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.5031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.5031</id><created>2013-07-18</created><updated>2016-09-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oeckl</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames><affiliation>CCM-UNAM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Towards state locality in quantum field theory: free fermions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, LaTeX + AMS + Xy-pic; v2: abstract rewritten, references
  updated; v3: discussion extended, references added</comments><report-no>UNAM-CCM-2013-2</report-no><journal-ref>Quantum Stud.: Math. Found. 4 (2017) 59-77</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40509-016-0086-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hilbert spaces of states can be constructed in standard quantum field theory
only for infinitely extended spacelike hypersurfaces, precluding a more local
notion of state. In fact, the Reeh-Schlieder Theorem prohibits the localization
of states on pieces of hypersurfaces in the standard formalism. From the point
of view of geometric quantization the problem lies in the non-locality of the
complex structures associated to hypersurfaces in standard quantization. We
show that using a weakened version of the positive formalism puts this problem
into a new perspective. This is a local TQFT type formalism based on
super-operators and mixed state spaces rather than on amplitudes and pure state
spaces as the one of Atiyah-Segal. In particular, we show that in the case of
purely fermionic degrees of freedom the complex structure can be dispensed with
when the notion of state is suitably generalized. These generalized states do
localize on compact hypersurfaces with boundaries. For the simplest case of
free fermionic fields we embed this in a rigorous and functorial quantization
scheme yielding a local description of the quantum theory. Crucially, no
classical data is needed beyond the structures evident from a Lagrangian
setting. When the classical data is augmented with complex structures on
hypersurfaces, the quantum data correspondingly augment to the full positive
formalism. This scheme is applicable to field theory in curved spacetime, but
also to field theories without metric background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.8476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.8476</id><created>2013-10-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Scivetti</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>Mats</forenames></author></authors><title>A simplified density functional theory method for charged adsorbates on
  an ultrathin, insulating film supported by a metal substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter 26, 135003 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/25/35/355006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simplified density functional theory (DFT) method for charged adsorbates on
an ultrathin, insulating film supported by a metal substrate is developed and
presented. This new method is based on a previous DFT development that uses a
perfect conductor (PC) model to approximate the electrostatic response of the
metal substrate, while the film and the adsorbate are both treated fully within
DFT [I. Scivetti and M. Persson, Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter 25,
355006 (2013)]. The missing interactions between the metal substrate and the
insulating film in the PC approximation are modelled by a simple force field
(FF). The parameters of the PC model and the force field are obtained from DFT
calculations of the film and the substrate, here shown explicitly for a NaCl
bilayer supported by a Cu(100) surface. In order to obtain some of these
parameters and the polarisability of the force field, we have to include an
external, uniformly charged plane in the DFT calculations, which has required
the development of a periodic DFT formalism to include such a charged plane in
the presence of a metal substrate. This extension and implementation should be
of more general interest and applicable to other challenging problems, for
instance, in electrochemistry. As illustrated for the gold atom on the NaCl
bilayer supported by a Cu(100) surface, our new DFT-PC-FF method allows us to
handle different charge states of adsorbates in a controlled and accurate
manner with a considerable reduction of the computational time. In addition, it
is now possible to calculate vertical transition and reorganisation energies
for charging and discharging of adsorbates that cannot be obtained by current
DFT methodologies that include the metal substrate. We find that the computed
vertical transition energy for charging of the gold adatom is in good agreement
with experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3011</id><created>2014-08-13</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andric</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonke</keyname><forenames>Larisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurman</keyname><forenames>Danijel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Holger Bech</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical and Quenched Random Matrices and Homolumo Gap</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 2 figures; v2. substantial improvements, published in IJMPA</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500464</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a rather general type of matrix model, where the matrix M
represents a Hamiltonian of the interaction of a bosonic system with a single
fermion. The fluctuations of the matrix are partly given by some fundamental
randomness and partly dynamically, even quantum mechanically. We then study the
homolumo-gap effect, which means that we study how the level density for the
single-fermion Hamiltonian matrix M gets attenuated near the Fermi surface. In
the case of the quenched randomness (the fundamental one) dominating the
quantum mechanical one we show that in the first approximation the homolumo gap
is characterized by the absence of single-fermion levels between two steep gap
boundaries. The filled and empty level densities are in this first
approximation just pushed, each to its side. In the next approximation these
steep drops in the spectral density are smeared out to have an error-function
shape. The studied model could be considered as a first step towards the more
general case of considering a whole field of matrices - defined say on some
phase space - rather than a single matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03512</id><created>2015-03-11</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pechenick</keyname><forenames>Eitan Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danforth</keyname><forenames>Christopher M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodds</keyname><forenames>Peter Sheridan</forenames></author></authors><title>Is language evolution grinding to a halt? The scaling of lexical
  turbulence in English fiction suggests it is not</title><categories>cs.CL cs.IT math.IT physics.soc-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>17 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Of basic interest is the quantification of the long term growth of a
language's lexicon as it develops to more completely cover both a culture's
communication requirements and knowledge space. Here, we explore the usage
dynamics of words in the English language as reflected by the Google Books 2012
English Fiction corpus. We critique an earlier method that found decreasing
birth and increasing death rates of words over the second half of the 20th
Century, showing death rates to be strongly affected by the imposed time cutoff
of the arbitrary present and not increasing dramatically. We provide a robust,
principled approach to examining lexical evolution by tracking the volume of
word flux across various relative frequency thresholds. We show that while the
overall statistical structure of the English language remains stable over time
in terms of its raw Zipf distribution, we find evidence of an enduring `lexical
turbulence': The flux of words across frequency thresholds from decade to
decade scales superlinearly with word rank and exhibits a scaling break we
connect to that of Zipf's law. To better understand the changing lexicon, we
examine the contributions to the Jensen-Shannon divergence of individual words
crossing frequency thresholds. We also find indications that scholarly works
about fiction are strongly represented in the 2012 English Fiction corpus, and
suggest that a future revision of the corpus should attempt to separate
critical works from fiction itself.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07060</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2015-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osca</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Lloren&#xe7;</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-particle current in planar Majorana nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Submitted to Edison19</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 647 (2015) 012063</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/647/1/012063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the local quasi-particle current of a Majorana state in a planar
hybrid (superconductor-semiconductor) nanowire. In absence of perpendicular
components of the magnetic field the current flows in circular trajectories
without a preferred orientation. On the other hand, when a perpendicular
component of the magnetic field is present the quasi-particle current
circulates surrounding the Majorana density peak with an orientation
established by the magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07280</id><created>2015-06-24</created><updated>2015-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osca</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Lloren&#xe7;</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic absorption of quasi-1D Majorana nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Submitted to E-MRS Spring Meeting 2015 ( Only acknowledgement update
  )</comments><journal-ref>Physica Status Solidi C 12(12): 1409-1411 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssc.201510131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the electromagnetic absorption cross section of long and narrow
nanowires, in the so-called quasi-1D limit. We consider only two transverse
bands and compute the dipole absorption cross section taking into account
quasiparticle transitions from negative to positive energy eigenstates of the
Bogoliubov-de Gennes Hamiltonian. The presence of the zero energy (Majorana)
state manifests in the different absorption spectra for $x$ (parallel) and $y$
(transverse) polarizations of the electromagnetic field.
  In the $y$-polarized case, the Majorana state causes a low energy absorption
plateau extending from mid-gap up to full-gap energy. Increasing further the
energy, the plateau is followed by a region of enhanced absorption due to
transitions across the full gap. For $x$ polarization the low energy absorption
plateau is not observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02603</id><created>2015-09-08</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Montillet</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiplicity of Solutions for Linear Partial Differential Equations
  Using (Generalized) Energy Operators</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures. Accepted for publication in Bulletin of
  Mathematical Analysis and Applications</comments><msc-class>26A99, 34L30, 46A11</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Families of energy operators and generalized energy operators have recently
been introduced in the definition of the solutions of linear Partial
Differential Equations (PDEs) with a particular application to the wave
equation [Montillet, 2014, doi: 10.1007/s10440-014-9978-9]. To do so, the
author has introduced the notion of energy spaces included in the Schwartz
space $\mathbf{S}^-(\mathbb{R})$. In this model, the key is to look at which
ones of these subspaces are reduced to {0} with the help of energy operators
(and generalized energy operators). It leads to define additional solutions for
a nominated PDE. Beyond that, this work intends to develop the concept of
multiplicity of solutions for a linear PDE through the study of these energy
spaces (i.e. emptiness). The main concept is that the PDE is viewed as a
generator of solutions rather than the classical way of solving the given
equation with a known form of the solutions together with boundary conditions.
The theory is applied to the wave equation with the special case of the
evanescent waves. The work ends with a discussion on another concept, the
duplication of solutions and some applications in a closed cavity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05804</id><created>2015-10-20</created><updated>2016-10-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Illing</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frischi</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>Herbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klix</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maret</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keim</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Mermin-Wagner fluctuations in 2D amorphous solids</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 114, 2440 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1612964114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent comment, M. Kosterlitz described how the discrepancy about the
lack of broken translational symmetry in two dimensions - doubting the
existence of 2D crystals - and the first computer simulations foretelling 2D
crystals at least in tiny systems, motivated him and D. Thouless to investigate
melting and suprafluidity in two dimensions [Jour. of Phys. Cond. Matt.
\textbf{28}, 481001 (2016)]. The lack of broken symmetries proposed by D.
Mermin and H. Wagner is caused by long wavelength density fluctuations. Those
fluctuations do not only have structural impact but additionally a dynamical
one: They cause the Lindemann criterion to fail in 2D and the mean squared
displacement not to be limited. Comparing experimental data from 3D and 2D
amorphous solids with 2D crystals we disentangle Mermin-Wagner fluctuations
from glassy structural relaxations. Furthermore we can demonstrate with
computer simulations the logarithmic increase of displacements predicted by
Mermin and Wagner: periodicity is not a requirement for Mermin-Wagner
fluctuations which conserve the homogeneity of space on long scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04453</id><created>2015-11-13</created><updated>2016-11-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pilosof</keyname><forenames>Shai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>Mason A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascual</keyname><forenames>Mercedes</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe9;fi</keyname><forenames>Sonia</forenames></author></authors><title>The Multilayer Nature of Ecological Networks</title><categories>q-bio.QM cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.AO physics.data-an q-bio.PE</categories><comments>A revised version</comments><journal-ref>Nature Ecology and Evolution 2017, 1:0101</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41559-017-0101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although networks provide a powerful approach to study a large variety of
ecological systems, their formulation does not typically account for multiple
interaction types, interactions that vary in space and time, and interconnected
systems such as networks of networks. The emergent field of `multilayer
networks' provides a natural framework for extending analyses of ecological
systems to include such multiple layers of complexity, as it specifically
allows one to differentiate and model `intralayer' and `interlayer'
connectivity. The framework provides a set of concepts and tools that can be
adapted and applied to ecology, facilitating research on high-dimensional,
heterogeneous systems in nature. Here, we formally define ecological multilayer
networks based on a review of previous and related approaches, illustrate their
application and potential with analyses of existing data, and discuss
limitations, challenges, and future applications. The integration of multilayer
network theory into ecology offers largely untapped potential to further
address ecological complexity, to ultimately provide new theoretical and
empirical insights into the architecture and dynamics of ecological systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00352</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00352</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Wenbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Zongqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yongchang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaolin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Shi Xue</forenames></author></authors><title>Transition from insulator to superconductor and significant enhancement
  of superconductivity in FeSe films via tuning Fe-vacancy disorders</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author for the reason that some
  updated results was found</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In contrast to its bulk crystals, the FeSe film or layer exhibits better
superconductivity performance, which attract much interest in its fundamental
research as well as potential application. In present work, transition from
insulator to superconductor and significant enhancement of superconductivity
were achieved in the high quality (00l) oriented FeSe films via controlling the
thickness as well as the Fe/Se ratio. The highest Tc up to 15.2 K (almost 2
times higher than those of bulk crystals) and Hc2 up to 35.5 T are obtained in
our atmosphere-stable FeSe thin film with practical thickness (240 nm),
implying their great potential application in the electronic devices at high
magnetic fields. More importantly, it was found that the Fe-vacancy disorder in
FeSe films is the intrinsic factor determining the evolution of the
superconductivity, rather than thickness effect. In our non-superconducting
FeSe film with Fe/Se ratio of 1.00:1.09, insulating \b{eta}-Fe1-xSe phase with
iron-vacancy disorders is the main phase and more likely to be the parent phase
of FeSe superconducting system. Tuning the Fe-vacancy disorders via changing
the Fe/Se ratio can dramatically vary the concentration of charge carrier and
introduce proper electron doping, which finally leads to the transition from
insulator to superconductor and further enhancement in the superconductivity.
Intriguingly, our results also indicate that when the Fe/Se ratio of film is
beyond a critical value, superconducting FeSe films will become instable, and
phase separation occurs with new non-superconducting phase precipitating in the
superconducting matrix, causing the degradation in the superconductivity. The
results in present work help us to well understand the intrinsic mechanism of
superconductivity among Fe-Se superconducting system and provide a new strategy
to further pursue higher Tc in these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03137</id><created>2015-12-09</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thrane</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Russell P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levin</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Lincoln D</forenames></author></authors><title>Suspending test masses in terrestrial millihertz gravitational-wave
  detectors: a case study with a magnetic assisted torsion pendulum</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current terrestrial gravitational-wave detectors operate at frequencies above
10 Hz. There is strong astrophysical motivation to construct low-frequency
gravitational-wave detectors capable of observing 10 mHz - 10Hz signals. While
space-based detectors provide one means of achieving this end, one may also
consider terretrial detectors. However, there are numerous technological
challenges. In particular, it is difficult to isolate test masses so that they
are both seismically isolated and freely falling under the influence of gravity
at millihertz frequencies. We investigate the challenges of low-frequency
suspension in a hypothetical terrestrial detector. As a case study, we consider
a Magnetically Assisted Gravitational-wave Pendulum Intorsion (MAGPI)
suspension design. We construct a noise budget to estimate some of the required
specifications. In doing so, we identify what are likely to be a number of
generic limiting noise sources for terrestrial millihertz gravitational-wave
suspension systems (as well as some peculiar to the MAGPI design). We highlight
significant experimental challenges in order to argue that the development of
millihertz suspensions will be a daunting task. Any system that relies on
magnets faces even greater challenges. Entirely mechanical designs such as
Zollner pendulums may provide the best path forward.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05799</id><created>2016-01-21</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alhambra</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvaro M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masanes</keyname><forenames>Lluis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oppenheim</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perry</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>The second law of quantum thermodynamics as an equality</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11+3 pages. V4: Updated to match published version. Discussion of
  thermo-majorization and implementing arbitary unitaries added. V3: Added
  funding information. V2: Expanded discussion on relation to fluctuation
  theorems</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 041017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.041017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the connection between recent results in quantum
thermodynamics and fluctuation relations by adopting a fully quantum mechanical
description of thermodynamics. By including a work system whose energy is
allowed to fluctuate, we derive a set of equalities which all thermodynamical
transitions have to satisfy. This extends the condition for maps to be
Gibbs-preserving to the case of fluctuating work, providing a more general
characterisation of maps commonly used in the information theoretic approach to
thermodynamics. For final states, block diagonal in the energy basis, this set
of equalities are necessary and sufficient conditions for a thermodynamical
state transition to be possible. The conditions serves as a parent equation
which can be used to derive a number of results. These include writing the
second law of thermodynamics as an equality featuring a fine-grained notion of
the free energy. It also yields a generalisation of the Jarzynski fluctuation
theorem which holds for arbitrary initial states, and under the most general
manipulations allowed by the laws of quantum mechanics. Furthermore, we show
that each of these relations can be seen as the quasi-classical limit of three
fully quantum identities. This allows us to consider the free energy as an
operator, and allows one to obtain more general and fully quantum fluctuation
relations from the information theoretic approach to quantum thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06796</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciampini</keyname><forenames>Mario A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mancino</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orieux</keyname><forenames>Adeline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vigliar</keyname><forenames>Caterina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mataloni</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paternostro</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbieri</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental entanglement-enhanced work extraction based on a Maxwell's
  demon</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, RevTex4-1</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 3, Article number: 10 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0011-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relation between the theory of entanglement and thermodynamics is very
tight: a thermodynamic theory of quantum entanglement, as well as the
establishment of rigorous formal connections between the laws of thermodynamics
and the phenomenology of entanglement are currently open areas of
investigation. In this quest, an interesting problem is embodied by the role
played by entanglement in processes of work extraction from a working medium
embodied by quantum information carriers. In this work, we experimentally
address the question &quot;Is there any intrinsic advantage for work extraction
given by the use of an entangled working medium?&quot;. By addressing
work-extraction protocols based on a mechanism intimately linked to the
paradigm of Maxwell's daemon, and implementing suitably designed multi-photon
optical interferometers, we demonstrate experimentally the intrinsic advantages
for such tasks provided by bipartite and genuine multipartite entanglement. We
highlight the unique nature of such tests by comparing their performance to
standard tests for the inseparability of multi-photon state resources. Our work
contributes strongly to the ongoing efforts in establishing photonic systems as
a platform for experiments for information thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03229</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2017-03-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miao</keyname><forenames>Yan-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transition and entropy inequality of noncommutative black holes in
  a new extended phase space</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>v1: 13 pages, 2 figures; v2: 14 pages, clarifications and references
  added; v3: 16 pages, more clarifications and references added, the final
  version to appear in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 03 (2017) 046 (14 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/03/046</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the thermodynamics of the noncommutative high-dimensional
Schwarzschild-Tangherlini AdS black hole with the non-Gaussian smeared matter
distribution by regarding a noncommutative parameter as an independent
thermodynamic variable named as the noncommutative pressure. In the new
extended phase space that includes this noncommutative pressure and its
conjugate variable, we reveal that the noncommutative pressure and the original
thermodynamic pressure related to the negative cosmological constant make the
opposite effects in the phase transition of the noncommutative black hole, i.e.
the former dominates the UV regime while the latter does the IR regime,
respectively. In addition, by means of the reverse isoperimetric inequality, we
indicate that only the black hole with the Gaussian smeared matter distribution
holds the maximum entropy for a given thermodynamic volume among the
noncommutative black holes with various matter distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04722</id><created>2016-04-16</created><updated>2016-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heemskerk</keyname><forenames>Eelke M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takes</keyname><forenames>Frank W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Bernardo</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huijzer</keyname><forenames>M. Jouke</forenames></author></authors><title>Where is the global corporate elite? A large-scale network study of
  local and nonlocal interlocking directorates</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><journal-ref>Sociologica 2016(2): 1-31, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.2383/85292</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Business elites reconfigure their locus of organization over time, from the
city level, to the national level, and beyond. We ask what the current level of
elite organization is and propose a novel theoretical and empirical approach to
answer this question. Building on the universal distinction between local and
nonlocal ties we use network analysis and community detection to dissect the
global network of interlocking directorates among over five million firms. We
find that elite orientation is indeed changing from the national to the
transnational plane, but we register a considerable heterogeneity across
different regions in the world. In some regions the business communities are
organized along national borders, whereas in other areas the locus of
organization is at the city level or international level. London dominates the
global corporate elite network. Our findings underscore that the study of
corporate elites requires an approach that is sensitive to levels of
organization that go beyond the confines of nation states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05133</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05133</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Hai-Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Lan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial dependent spontaneous emission of an atom in a semi-infinite
  waveguide of rectangular cross section</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a quantum electrodynamics (QED) system made of an two-level atom and
a semi-infinite rectangular waveguide, which behaves as a perfect mirror in one
end. The spatial dependence of the atomic spontaneous emission has been
included in the coupling strength relevant to the eigenmodes of the waveguide.
The role of retardation is studied for the atomic transition frequency far away
from the cutoff frequencies. The atom-mirror distance introduces different
phases and retardation times into the dynamics of the atom interacting
resonantly with the corresponding transverse modes. It is found that the upper
state population decreases from its initial as long as the atom-mirror distance
does not vanish, and is lowered and lowered when more and more transverse modes
are resonant with the atom. The atomic spontaneous emission can be either
suppressed or enhanced by adjusting the atomic location for short retardation
time. There are partial revivals and collapses due to the photon reabsorbed and
re-emitted by the atom for long retardation time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08089</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2017-03-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moreira</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author></authors><title>Hot scalar radiation around a cosmic string setting bounds on the
  coupling parameter $\xi$</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure. The material has been expanded and the manuscript
  matches the published version (JHEP)</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 03 (2017) 105</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, by investigating the low temperature behaviour of a scalar
field around a cosmic string, and assuming stable thermodynamic equilibrium, it
is shown that the coupling parameter of the field with curvature must be
restricted to a certain range of values whose bounds are determined by the
deficit angle of the associated conical geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08197</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Takes</keyname><forenames>Frank W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heemskerk</keyname><forenames>Eelke M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Centrality in the Global Network of Corporate Control</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><journal-ref>Social Network Analysis and Mining 6(1): article 97, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s13278-016-0402-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Corporations across the world are highly interconnected in a large global
network of corporate control. This paper investigates the global board
interlock network, covering 400,000 firms linked through 1,700,000 edges
representing shared directors between these firms. The main focus is on the
concept of centrality, which is used to investigate the embeddedness of firms
from a particular country within the global network. The study results in three
contributions. First, to the best of our knowledge for the first time we can
investigate the topology as well as the concept of centrality in corporate
networks at a global scale, allowing for the largest cross-country comparison
ever done in interlocking directorates literature. We demonstrate, amongst
other things, extremely similar network topologies, yet large differences
between countries when it comes to the relation between economic prominence
indicators and firm centrality. Second, we introduce two new metrics that are
specifically suitable for comparing the centrality ranking of a partition to
that of the full network. Using the notion of centrality persistence we propose
to measure the persistence of a partition's centrality ranking in the full
network. In the board interlock network, it allows us to assess the extent to
which the footprint of a national network is still present within the global
network. Next, the measure of centrality ranking dominance tells us whether a
partition (country) is more dominant at the top or the bottom of the centrality
ranking of the full (global) network. Finally, comparing these two new measures
of persistence and dominance between different countries allows us to classify
these countries based the their embeddedness, measured using the relation
between the centrality of a country's firms on the national and the global
scale of the board interlock network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00578</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takeyama</keyname><forenames>Yoshihiro</forenames></author></authors><title>On the eigenfunctions for the multi-species q-Boson system</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>We added an explanation of the relation between our result and the
  previous results due to Borodin, and Motegi and Sakai in Section 5.1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous paper a multi-species version of the q-Boson stochastic
particle system is introduced and the eigenfunctions of its backward generator
are constructed by using a representation of the Hecke algebra. In this article
we prove a formula which expresses the eigenfunctions by means of the
q-deformed bosonic operators, which are constructed from the L-operator of
higher rank found in the recent work by Garbali, de Gier and Wheeler. The
L-operator is obtained from the universal R-matrix of the quantum affine
algebra of type A_{r}^{(1)} by the use of the q-oscillator representation. Thus
our formula may be regarded as a bridge between two approaches to studying
integrable stochastic systems by means of the quantum affine algebra and the
affine Hecke algebra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03769</id><created>2016-06-12</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Siringo</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispersion relations for unphysical particles</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 13017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713713017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generalized dispersion relations are discussed for unphysical particles, e.g.
confined degrees of freedom that are not present in the physical spectra but
can give rise to observable bound states. While in general the propagator of
the unphysical particles can have complex poles and cannot be reconstructed
from the knowledge of the imaginary part, under reasonable assumptions the
missing piece of information is shown to be in the rational function that
contains the poles and must be added to the integral representation. For pure
Yang-Mills theory, the rational part and the spectral term are identified in
the explicit analytical expressions provided by the massive expansion of the
gluon propagator. The multi particle spectral term turns out to be very small
and the simple rational part provides, from first principles, an approximate
propagator that is equivalent to the tree-level result of simple
phenomenological models like the refined Gribov-Zwanziger model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05860</id><created>2016-06-19</created><updated>2017-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krishna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>N= 4 Supersymmetric Quantum Mechanical Model: Novel Symmetries</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX file, 18 pages, version to appear in IJMPA</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 32: 1750055 [p01--p18], 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500555</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a set of novel discrete symmetry transformations of the N = 4
supersymmetric quantum mechanical model of a charged particle moving on a
sphere in the background of Dirac magnetic monopole. The usual five continuous
symmetries (and their conserved Noether charges) and two discrete symmetries
together provide the physical realizations of the de Rham cohomological
operators of differential geometry. We have also exploited the supervariable
approach to derive the nilpotent N = 4 SUSY transformations and provided the
geometrical interpretation in the language of translational generators along
the Grassmannian directions onto (1, 4)-dimensional supermanifold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06013</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Herbrych</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokalj</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective realization of random magnetic fields in compounds with large
  single-ion anisotropy</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 125129 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.125129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that spin $S=1$ system with large and random single--ion anisotropy
can be at low energies mapped to a $S=1/2$ system with random magnetic fields.
This is for example realized in
\mbox{Ni(Cl$_{1-x}$Br$_{x}$)$_2$-4SC(NH$_2$)$_2$} compound (DTNX) and therefore
it represents a long sought realization of random local (on-site) magnetic
fields in antiferromagnetic systems. We support the mapping by numerical study
of $S=1$ and effective $S=1/2$ anisotropic Heisenberg chains and find excellent
agreement for static quantities and also for the spin conductivity. Such
systems can therefore be used to study the effects of local random magnetic
fields on transport properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07790</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Del Popolo</keyname><forenames>Antonino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delliou</keyname><forenames>Morgan Le</forenames></author></authors><title>Small scale problems of the $\Lambda$CDM model: a short review</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>48pp 19 figs, invited review, accepted by Galaxies</comments><doi>10.3390/galaxies5010017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $\Lambda$CDM model, or concordance cosmology, as it is often called, is a
paradigm at its maturity. It is clearly able to describe the universe at large
scale, even if some issues remain open, such as the cosmological constant
problem , the small-scale problems in galaxy formation, or the unexplained
anomalies in the CMB. $\Lambda$CDM clearly shows difficulty at small scales,
which could be related to our scant understanding, from the nature of dark
matter to that of gravity; or to the role of baryon physics, which is not well
understood and implemented in simulation codes or in semi-analytic models. At
this stage, it is of fundamental importance to understand whether the problems
encountered by the $\Lambda$DCM model are a sign of its limits or a sign of our
failures in getting the finer details right. In the present paper, we will
review the small-scale problems of the $\Lambda$CDM model, and we will discuss
the proposed solutions and to what extent they are able to give us a theory
accurately describing the phenomena in the complete range of scale of the
observed universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00018</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-02-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Estes</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavic</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippert</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonetti</keyname><forenames>John H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shining Light on Quantum Gravity with Pulsar-Black Hole Binaries</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure; v2: references added; v3: improved discussion of
  lensing and reference added, to be published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 837 (2017) no.1, 87</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa610e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pulsars are some of the most accurate clocks found in nature, while black
holes offer a unique arena for the study of quantum gravity. As such,
pulsar-black hole (PSR-BH) binaries provide ideal astrophysical systems for
detecting the effects of quantum gravity. With the success of aLIGO and the
advent of instruments like the SKA and eLISA, the prospects for the discovery
of such PSR-BH binaries are very promising. We argue that PSR-BH binaries can
serve as ready-made testing grounds for proposed resolutions to the black hole
information paradox. We propose using timing signals from a pulsar beam passing
through the region near a black hole event horizon as a probe of quantum
gravitational effects. In particular, we demonstrate that fluctuations of the
geometry outside a black hole lead to an increase in the measured root mean
square deviation of the arrival times of pulsar pulses traveling near the
horizon. This allows for a clear observational test of the nonviolent
nonlocality proposal for black hole information escape. For a series of pulses
traversing the near-horizon region, this model predicts an rms in pulse arrival
times of $\sim30\ \mu$s for a $3 M_\odot$ black hole, $\sim0.3\, $ms for a $30
M_\odot$ black hole, and $\sim40\, $s for Sgr A*. The current precision of
pulse time-of-arrival measurements is sufficient to discern these rms
fluctuations. This work is intended to motivate observational searches for
PSR-BH systems as a means of testing models of quantum gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00705</id><created>2016-07-03</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ita</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards a Numerical Unitarity Approach for Two-loop Amplitudes in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Proceedings for Loops and Legs in Quantum Field Theory, 24-29 April
  2016, Leipzig, Germany, v2 added references</comments><report-no>FR-PHENO-2016-011</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The numerical unitarity approach has been important for obtaining reliable
QCD predictions for the LHC. Here I discuss the extension of the approach
beyond the leading quantum corrections for computing multi-loop amplitudes. The
numerical unitarity approach requires a suitable parametrisation of the loop
integrands as a sum of terms that integrate to zero (surface terms) and master
integrands. The construction and classification of suitable surface terms which
match the propagators structures of Feynman amplitudes is the main technical
advance discussed. A number of spin-offs for integral reduction and further
formal questions are briefly reviewed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02040</id><created>2016-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Siringo</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal scaling of gluon and ghost propagators in the infrared</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 13016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713713016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A universal behavior is predicted for ghost and gluon propagators in the
infrared. The universal behavior is shown to be a signature of a one-loop
approximation and emerges naturally by the massive expansion that predicts
universal analytical functions for the inverse dressing functions that do not
depend on any parameter or color number. By a scaling of units and by adding an
integration constant, all lattice data, for different color numbers (and even
quark content for the ghosts), collapse on the same universal curves predicted
by the massive expansion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04283</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bourne</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlop</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merlin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiber</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellano</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conselice</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coppin</keyname><forenames>K. E. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrah</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontana</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geach</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knudsen</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michalowski</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mortlock</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>X. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>D. J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Werf</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of cosmic star formation in the SCUBA-2 Cosmology Legacy
  Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>MNRAS Accepted 2017 January 5. 29 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 467 (2): 1360-1385</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new exploration of the cosmic star-formation history and dust
obscuration in massive galaxies at redshifts $0.5&lt; z&lt;6$. We utilize the deepest
450 and 850$\mu$m imaging from SCUBA-2 CLS, covering 230arcmin$^2$ in the
AEGIS, COSMOS and UDS fields, together with 100-250$\mu$m imaging from
Herschel. We demonstrate the capability of the T-PHOT deconfusion code to reach
below the confusion limit, using multi-wavelength prior catalogues from
CANDELS/3D-HST. By combining IR and UV data, we measure the relationship
between total star-formation rate (SFR) and stellar mass up to $z\sim5$,
indicating that UV-derived dust corrections underestimate the SFR in massive
galaxies. We investigate the relationship between obscuration and the UV slope
(the IRX-$\beta$ relation) in our sample, which is similar to that of
low-redshift starburst galaxies, although it deviates at high stellar masses.
Our data provide new measurements of the total SFR density (SFRD) in
$M_\ast&gt;10^{10}M_\odot$ galaxies at $0.5&lt;z&lt;6$. This is dominated by obscured
star formation by a factor of $&gt;10$. One third of this is accounted for by
450$\mu$m-detected sources, while one fifth is attributed to UV-luminous
sources (brighter than $L^\ast_{UV}$), although even these are largely
obscured. By extrapolating our results to include all stellar masses, we
estimate a total SFRD that is in good agreement with previous results from IR
and UV data at $z\lesssim3$, and from UV-only data at $z\sim5$. The cosmic
star-formation history undergoes a transition at $z\sim3-4$, as predominantly
unobscured growth in the early Universe is overtaken by obscured star
formation, driven by the build-up of the most massive galaxies during the peak
of cosmic assembly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04916</id><created>2016-07-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Metwally</keyname><forenames>Nasser</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing entanglement, local and non-local information of accelerated
  two-qubit and two- qutrit systems via weak-reverse measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>EPL, 116 (2016) 60006</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/60006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The possibility of recovering and protecting the entanglement of accelerated
2-qubit and 2-qutrit systems is discussed using weak-reverse measurements. The
accelerated partial entangled states are more responsive to be protected than
the accelerated maximum entangled states. The accelerated coded local
information in qutrit system is more robust than that encoded in a 2-qubit
system, and it can be conserved even for larger values of accelerations.
Meanwhile, the non-accelerated information in qubit system is not affected by
the local operation compared with that depicted on qutrit system. For larger
values of accelerations, the weak-reverse measurements can improve the coherent
information at the expanse of the accelerated information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00539</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2017-02-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nemzer</keyname><forenames>Louis R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Binary Representation of the Genetic Code</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.OT</categories><doi>10.1016/j.biosystems.2017.03.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article introduces a novel binary representation of the canonical
genetic code based on both the structural similarities of the nucleotides, as
well as the physicochemical properties of the encoded amino acids. Each of the
four mRNA bases is assigned a unique 2-bit identifier, so that the 64 triplet
codons are each indexed by a 6-bit label. The ordering of the bits reflects the
hierarchical organization manifested by the DNA replication/repair and tRNA
translation systems. In this system, transition and transversion mutations are
naturally expressed as binary operations, and the severities of the different
point mutations can be analyzed. Using a principal component analysis, it is
shown that the physicochemical properties of amino acids related to protein
folding also correlate with certain bit positions of their respective labels.
Thus, the likelihood for a point mutation to be conservative, and less likely
to cause a change in protein functionality, can be estimated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00585</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dor&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagache</keyname><forenames>Guilaine</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissecting the high-z interstellar medium through intensity mapping
  cross-correlations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 table, 7 figures, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 833, Issue 2, article id. 153,
  13 pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/833/2/153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the detection, with upcoming spectroscopic surveys, of
three-dimensional power spectra of emission line fluctuations produced in
different phases of the Interstellar Medium (ISM) by ionized carbon, ionized
nitrogen and neutral oxygen at redshift z&gt;4. The emission line [CII] from
ionized carbon at 157.7 micron, and multiple emission lines from carbon
monoxide, are the main targets of planned ground-based surveys, and an
important foreground for future space-based surveys like the Primordial
Inflation Explorer (PIXIE). However, the oxygen [OI] (145.5 micron) line, and
the nitrogen [NII] (121.9 micron and 205.2 micron) lines, might be detected in
correlation with [CII] with reasonable signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). These lines
are important coolants of both the neutral and the ionized medium, and probe
multiple phases of the ISM. We compute predictions of the three-dimensional
power spectra for two surveys designed to target the [CII] line, showing that
they have the required sensitivity to detect cross-power spectra with the [OI]
line, and the [NII] lines with sufficient SNR. The importance of
cross-correlating multiple lines is twofold. On the one hand, we will have
multiple probes of the different phases of the ISM, which is key to understand
the interplay between energetic sources, the gas and dust at high redshift.
This kind of studies will be useful for a next-generation space observatory
such as the NASA Far-IR Surveyor. On the other end, emission lines from
external galaxies are an important foreground when measuring spectral
distortions of the Cosmic Microwave Background spectrum with future space-based
experiments like PIXIE; measuring fluctuations in the intensity mapping regime
will help constraining the mean amplitude of these lines, and will allow us to
better handle this important foreground.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03681</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03681</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ganguly</keyname><forenames>Samiran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camsari</keyname><forenames>Kerem Yunus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Supriyo</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluating Spintronic Devices Using The Modular Approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cs.ET</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures. Includes supplementary at the end</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Journal on Exploratory Solid-State Computational Devices and
  Circuits, vol. 2, pp. 51-60, Dec. 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/JXCDC.2016.2644199</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Over the past decade a large family of spintronic devices have been proposed
as candidates for replacing CMOS for future digital logic circuits. Using the
recently developed Modular Approach framework, we investigate and identify the
physical bottlenecks and engineering challenges facing current spintronic
devices. We then evaluate how systematic advancements in material properties
and device design innovations impact the performance of spintronic devices, as
a possible continuation of Moore's Law, even though some of these projections
are speculative and may require technological breakthroughs. Lastly, we
illustrate the use of the Modular Approach as an exploratory tool for
probabilistic networks, using superparamagnetic magnets as building blocks for
such networks. These building blocks leverage the inherent physics of
stochastic spin-torque switching and could provide ultra-compact and efficient
hardware for beyond-Boolean computational paradigms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00637</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sticlet</keyname><forenames>Doru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nijholt</keyname><forenames>Bas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akhmerov</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Robustness of Majorana bound states in the short junction limit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115421 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of strong coupling between a superconductor and a
semiconductor nanowire on the creation of the Majorana bound states, when the
quasiparticle dwell time in the normal part of the nanowire is much shorter
than the inverse superconducting gap. This &quot;short junction&quot; limit is relevant
for the recent experiments using the epitaxially grown aluminum characterized
by a transparent interface with the semiconductor and a small superconducting
gap. We find that the small superconducting gap does not have a strong
detrimental effect on the Majorana properties. Specifically, both the critical
magnetic field required for creating a topological phase and the size of the
Majorana bound states are independent of the superconducting gap. The critical
magnetic field scales with the wire cross section, while the relative
importance of the orbital and Zeeman effects of the magnetic field is
controlled by the material parameters only: $g$-factor, effective electron
mass, and the semiconductor-superconductor interface transparency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01474</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01474</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucha</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Goldstone-Type Pseudoscalar Mesons: Instantaneous Bethe-Salpeter Models</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, contributed to &quot;Quark Confinement and the Hadron
  Spectrum XII&quot; (28 August - 3 September 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece)</comments><report-no>HEPHY-PUB 974/16 (2016)</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137 (2017) 13009</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713713009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A nontrivial instantaneous variant of the Bethe-Salpeter formalism allows us
to discuss massless pseudoscalar mesons from a configuration-space-potential
point of view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01536</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mik&#xf3;czi</keyname><forenames>Bal&#xe1;zs</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin supplementary conditions for spinning compact binaries</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>15 two-column pages, 3 figures, 1 tables; corrected version, a new
  subsection 3.A ('Canonical structure') and some references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 064023 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.064023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider different spin supplementary conditions (SSC) for a spinning
compact binary with the leading-order spin-orbit (SO) interaction. The
Lagrangian of the binary system can be constructed but it is
acceleration-dependent in two cases of SSC. We rewrite the generalized
Hamiltonian formalism proposed by Ostrogradsky and compute the conserved
quantities and the dissipative part of relative motion during the gravitational
radiation of each SSC. We give the orbital elements and observed quantities of
the SO dynamics, for instance the energy and the orbital angular momentum
losses and waveforms and discuss their SSC dependence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02359</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delabays</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coletta</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacquod</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Multistability of Phase-Locking in Equal-Frequency Kuramoto Models on
  Planar Graphs</title><categories>nlin.AO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 58, 032703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4978697</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The number $\mathcal{N}$ of stable fixed points of locally coupled Kuramoto
models depends on the topology of the network on which the model is defined. It
has been shown that cycles in meshed networks play a crucial role in
determining $\mathcal{N}$, because any two different stable fixed points differ
by a collection of loop flows on those cycles. Since the number of different
loop flows increases with the length of the cycle that carries them, one
expects $\mathcal{N}$ to be larger in meshed networks with longer cycles.
Simultaneously, the existence of more cycles in a network means more freedom to
choose the location of loop flows differentiating between two stable fixed
points. Therefore, $\mathcal{N}$ should also be larger in networks with more
cycles. We derive an algebraic upper bound for the number of stable fixed
points of the Kuramoto model with identical frequencies, under the assumption
that angle differences between connected nodes do not exceed $\pi/2$. We obtain
$\mathcal{N}\leq\prod_{k=1}^c\left[2\cdot{\rm Int}(n_k/4)+1\right]$, which
depends both on the number $c$ of cycles and on the spectrum of their lengths
$\{n_k\}$. We further identify network topologies carrying stable fixed points
with angle differences larger than $\pi/2$, which leads us to conjecture an
upper bound for the number of stable fixed points for Kuramoto models on any
planar network. Compared to earlier approaches that give exponential upper
bounds in the total number of vertices, our bounds are much lower and therefore
much closer to the true number of stable fixed points.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04651</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucha</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sazdjian</keyname><forenames>Hagop</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simula</keyname><forenames>Silvano</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong Couplings of Three Mesons with Charm(ing) Involvement</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, contributed to &quot;Quark Confinement and the Hadron
  Spectrum XII&quot; (28 August - 3 September 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece)</comments><report-no>HEPHY-PUB 975/16</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137 (2017) 13010</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713713010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the strong couplings of three mesons that involve, at least, one
$\eta_c$ or $J/\psi$ meson, within the framework of a constituent-quark model
by means of relativistic dispersion formulations. For strong couplings of
$J/\psi$ mesons to two charmed mesons, our approach leads to predictions
roughly twice as large as those arising from QCD sum rules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09388</id><created>2016-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucha</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simula</keyname><forenames>Silvano</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy-Meson Decay Constants: Isospin Breaking from QCD Sum Rules</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, talk presented at &quot;Quark Confinement and the
  Hadron Spectrum XII&quot; (28 August - 3 September 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece)</comments><report-no>HEPHY-PUB 976/16</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137 (2017) 06017</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713706017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Compared with lattice QCD, isospin breaking of heavy-meson decay constants
from QCD sum rules agrees for $D$ mesons but disagrees (by a factor of four)
for $B$ mesons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04978</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>KT</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhat</keyname><forenames>Shruthi S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subramaniam</keyname><forenames>Annapurni</forenames></author></authors><title>Short-term H{\alpha} line variations in Classical Be stars: 59 Cyg and
  OT Gem</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, Accepted for publication in Journal of
  Astrophysics and Astronomy. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1602.02933</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Astrophysics and Astronomy (2017) 38: 6</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12036-017-9426-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the optical spectroscopic study of two Classical Be stars, 59 Cyg
and OT Gem obtained over a period of few months in 2009. We detected a rare
triple-peak H$\alpha$ emission phase in 59 Cyg and a rapid decrease in the
emission strength of H$\alpha$ in OT Gem, which are used to understand their
circumstellar disks. We find that 59 Cyg is likely to be rapid rotator,
rotating at a fractional critical rotation of $\sim$ 0.80. The radius of the
H$\alpha$ emission region for 59 Cyg is estimated to be $R_d/R_*$ $\sim$ 10.0,
assuming a Keplerian disk, suggesting that it has a large disk. We classify
stars which have shown triple-peaks into two groups and find that the
triple-peak emission in 59 Cyg is similar to $\zeta$ Tau. OT Gem is found to
have a fractional critical rotation of $\sim$ 0.30, suggesting that it is
either a slow rotator or viewed in low inclination. In OT Gem, we observed a
large reduction in the radius of the H$\alpha$ emission region from $\sim$ 6.9
to $\sim$ 1.7 in a period of three months, along with the reduction in the
emission strength. Our observations suggest that the disk is lost from outside
to inside during this disk loss phase in OT Gem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05639</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05639</id><created>2016-10-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge engineering and propagators</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, Conference: XIIth Quark Confinement and the
  Hadron Spectrum, August 28-September 04, 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece,
  submitted to the proceedings</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 03012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713703012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Beyond perturbation theory gauge-fixing becomes more involved due to the
Gribov-Singer ambiguity: The appearance of additional gauge copies requires to
define a procedure how to handle them. For the case of Landau gauge the
structure and properties of these additional gauge copies will be investigated.
Based on these properties gauge conditions are constructed to account for these
gauge copies.
  The dependence of the propagators on the choice of these complete
gauge-fixings will then be investigated using lattice gauge theory for
Yang-Mills theory. It is found that the implications for the infrared, and to
some extent mid-momentum behavior, can be substantial. In going beyond the
Yang-Mills case it turns out that the influence of matter can generally not be
neglected. This will be briefly discussed for various types of matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08315</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Caselle</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panero</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vadacchino</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Squared width and profile of the confining flux tube in the U(1) LGT in
  3D</title><categories>hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures,Talk presented at the 34th International Symposium
  on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016, Southampton, UK</comments><journal-ref>PoS Lattice 2016 (2017) 347</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dual formulation of the compact U(1) lattice gauge theory in three
spacetime dimensions allows to finely study the squared width and the profile
of the confining flux tube on a wide range of physical interquark distances.
The results obtained in Monte Carlo simulations are compared with the
predictions of the effective bosonic-string model and with the dual
superconductor model. While the former fails at describing the data from a
quantitative point of view, the latter is in good agreement with it. An
interpretation of these results is proposed in light of the particular features
of the U(1) lattice gauge theory in 3D and a comparison with non-Abelian gauge
theories in four spacetime dimensions is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09017</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Nada</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caselle</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costagliola</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panero</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toniato</keyname><forenames>Arianna</forenames></author></authors><title>Applications of Jarzynski's relation in lattice gauge theories</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, presented at the 34th International Symposium on
  Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016, Southampton, UK</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2016-045 DNRF90</report-no><journal-ref>PoS Lattice 2016 (2017) 262</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Jarzynski's equality is a well-known result in statistical mechanics,
relating free-energy differences between equilibrium ensembles with
fluctuations in the work performed during non-equilibrium transformations from
one ensemble to the other. In this work, an extension of this relation to
lattice gauge theory will be presented, along with numerical results for the
$\mathbb{Z}_2$ gauge model in three dimensions and for the equation of state in
$\mathrm{SU}(2)$ Yang-Mills theory in four dimensions. Then, further
applications will be discussed, in particular for the Schr\&quot;odinger functional
and for the study of QCD in strong magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01388</id><created>2016-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Krinner</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames><affiliation>for the COMPASS collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Light-Meson Spectroscopy at COMPASS</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings for the CONF12 conference from 28 August 2016 to 4
  September 2016, 9 pages, 22 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf., 137 (2017) 05012</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713705012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The goal of the COMPASS experiment at CERN is to study the structure and
spectroscopy of hadrons. The two-stage spectrometer has large acceptance and
covers a wide kinematic range for charged as well as neutral particles allowing
to access a wide range of reactions. Light mesons are studied with negative
(mostly $\pi^-$) and positive ($p$, $\pi^+$) hadron beams with a momentum of
$190\,\text{GeV}/c$.
  The light-meson spectrum is measured in different final states produced in
diffractive dissociation reactions with squared four-momentum transfer $t$ to
the target between $0.1$ and $1.0\,(\text{GeV}/c)^2$. The flagship channel is
the $\pi^-\pi^+\pi^-$ final state, for which COMPASS has recorded the currently
world's largest data sample. These data not only allow us to measure the
properties of known resonances with high precision, but also to search for new
states. Among these is a new axial-vector signal, the $a_1(1420)$, with unusual
properties. The findings are confirmed by the analysis of the $\pi^-\pi^0\pi^0$
final state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01885</id><created>2016-11-06</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coley</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devi</keyname><forenames>N. Chandrachani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcaniz</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing averaged cosmology with type Ia supernovae and BAO data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures, 4 tables. Published to JCAP. Corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 02 (2017) 047</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/02/047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An important problem in precision cosmology is the determination of the
effects of averaging and backreaction on observational predictions,
particularly in view of the wealth of new observational data and improved
statistical techniques. In this paper, we discuss the observational viability
of a class of averaged cosmologies which consist of a simple parametrized
phenomenological two-scale backreaction model with decoupled spatial curvature
parameters. We perform a Bayesian model selection analysis and find that this
class of averaged phenomenological cosmological models is favored with respect
to the standard $\Lambda$CDM cosmological scenario when a joint analysis of
current SNe Ia and BAO data is performed. In particular, the analysis provides
observational evidence for non-trivial spatial curvature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02720</id><created>2016-11-08</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Samanta</keyname><forenames>Rickmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Rishi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trivedi</keyname><forenames>Sandip P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Proposal for measuring Anisotropic Shear Viscosity in Unitary Fermi
  Gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas hep-th</categories><comments>Shorter version of arXiv:1607.04799</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a proposal to measure anisotropic shear viscosity in a strongly
interacting, ultra-cold, unitary Fermi gas confined in a harmonic trap. We
introduce anisotropy in this setup by strongly confining the gas in one of the
directions with relatively weak confinement in the remaining directions. This
system has a close resemblance to anisotropic strongly coupled field theories
studied recently in the context of gauge-gravity duality. Computations in such
theories (which have gravity duals) revealed that some of the viscosity
components of the anisotropic shear viscosity tensor can be made much smaller
than the entropy density, thus parametrically violating the bound proposed by
Kovtun, Son and Starinets (KSS): $\frac {\eta} {s} \geq \frac{1}{4 \pi}$. A
Boltzmann analysis performed in a system of weakly interacting particles in a
linear potential also shows that components of the viscosity tensor can be
reduced. Motivated by these exciting results, we propose two hydrodynamic modes
in the unitary Fermi gas whose damping is governed by the component of shear
viscosity expected to violate the KSS bound. One of these modes is the well
known scissor mode. We estimate trap parameters for which the reduction in the
shear viscosity is of order unity and find that the trap geometry, the damping
timescales, and mode amplitudes are within the range of existing experimental
setups on ultra-cold Fermi gases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03460</id><created>2016-11-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Metwally</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimation of teleported and gained parameters in a non-inertial frame</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Laser Phys. Lett. 14 (2017) 045202</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1612-202X/aa5d2a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We estimate the teleported and the gained parameters by means of Fisher
information in a non-inertial frame. The sender and the receiver share an
accelerated maximum or partial entangled state. The estimation degree of these
parameters depends on Unruh acceleration, the used single mode
approximation(within/ beyond), the structure of the initial teleported state,
and the entanglement of the initial communication channel. The maximization and
minimization estimation degree of the teleported parameters depend on the
initial encoded information. The estimation degree of the parameters can be
maximized if the partners teleport classical information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03708</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03708</id><created>2016-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Antonov</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gulitskiy</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostenko</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu&#x10d;ivjansk&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Advection of a passive scalar field by turbulent compressible fluid:
  renormalization group analysis near $d = 4$</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11pages, 6 figures, LATEX2e. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1611.00327; text overlap with arXiv:1611.01302</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 1000 3 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713710003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The field theoretic renormalization group (RG) and the operator product
expansion (OPE) are applied to the model of a density field advected by a
random turbulent velocity field. The latter is governed by the stochastic
Navier-Stokes equation for a compressible fluid. The model is considered near
the special space dimension $d = 4$. It is shown that various correlation
functions of the scalar field exhibit anomalous scaling behaviour in the
inertial-convective range. The scaling properties in the RG+OPE approach are
related to fixed points of the renormalization group equations. In comparison
with physically interesting case $d = 3$, at $d = 4$ additional Green function
has divergences which affect the existence and stability of fixed points. From
calculations it follows that a new regime arises there and then by continuity
moves into $d = 3$. The corresponding anomalous exponents are identified with
scaling dimensions of certain composite fields and can be systematically
calculated as series in $y$ (the exponent, connected with random force) and
$\epsilon=4-d$. All calculations are performed in the leading one-loop
approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04332</id><created>2016-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucha</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author></authors><title>On the description of exotic hadron states within QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, talk presented at &quot;Quark Confinement and the
  Hadron Spectrum XII&quot; (28 August - 3 September 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece)</comments><report-no>HEPHY-PUB 977/16</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137 (2017) 05014</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713705014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Revisiting the QCD sum-rule description of exotic hadron states, we argue
that, in order to arrive at trustable analyses of, for instance, strong decay
widths of multiquarks, it is inevitable to adopt the QCD sum-rule approach
beyond the leading perturbative level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04646</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Danilkin</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanderhaeghen</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-by-light scattering sum rules in light of new data</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 014019 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.014019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate the light-quark meson contributions to three exact light-by-light
scattering sum rules in light of new data by the Belle Collaboration, which
recently has extracted the transition form factors of the tensor meson
$f_2(1270)$ as well as of the scalar meson $f_0(980)$. We confirm a previous
finding that the $\eta, \eta^\prime$ and helicity-2 $f_2(1270)$ contributions
saturate one of these sum rules up to photon virtualities around 1 GeV$^2$. At
larger virtualities, our sum rule analysis shows an important contribution of
the $f_2(1565)$ meson and provides a first empirical extraction of its
helicity-2 transition form factor. Two further sum rules allow us to predict
the helicity-0 and helicity-1 transition form factors of the $f_2(1270)$ meson.
Furthermore, our analysis also provides an update for the scalar and tensor
meson hadronic light-by-light contributions to the muon's anomalous magnetic
moment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04791</id><created>2016-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ba&#xf1;uls</keyname><forenames>Mari Carmen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cichy</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirac</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Hana</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards overcoming the Monte Carlo sign problem with tensor networks</title><categories>hep-lat cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures; proceedings of XIIth Quark Confinement and the
  Hadron Spectrum, Thessaloniki 2016</comments><report-no>DESY 16-212</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 04001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713704001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of lattice gauge theories with Monte Carlo simulations is hindered
by the infamous sign problem that appears under certain circumstances, in
particular at non-zero chemical potential. So far, there is no universal method
to overcome this problem. However, recent years brought a new class of
non-perturbative Hamiltonian techniques named tensor networks, where the sign
problem is absent. In previous work, we have demonstrated that this approach,
in particular matrix product states in 1+1 dimensions, can be used to perform
precise calculations in a lattice gauge theory, the massless and massive
Schwinger model. We have computed the mass spectrum of this theory, its thermal
properties and real-time dynamics. In this work, we review these results and we
extend our calculations to the case of two flavours and non-zero chemical
potential. We are able to reliably reproduce known analytical results for this
model, thus demonstrating that tensor networks can tackle the sign problem of a
lattice gauge theory at finite density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05056</id><created>2016-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Strickland</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent progress in anisotropic hydrodynamics</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures; Proceedings contribution for &quot;12th Conference on
  Quark Confinement and the Hadron Spectrum&quot;</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 07026 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713707026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quark-gluon plasma created in a relativistic heavy-ion collisions
possesses a sizable pressure anisotropy in the local rest frame at very early
times after the initial nuclear impact and this anisotropy only slowly relaxes
as the system evolves. In a kinetic theory picture, this translates into the
existence of sizable momentum-space anisotropies in the underlying partonic
distribution functions, &lt;p_L^2&gt; &lt;&lt; &lt;p_T^2&gt;. In such cases, it is better to
reorganize the hydrodynamical expansion by taking into account momentum-space
anisotropies at leading-order in the expansion instead of as a perturbative
correction to an isotropic distribution. The resulting anisotropic
hydrodynamics framework has been shown to more accurately describe the dynamics
of rapidly expanding systems such as the quark-gluon plasma. In this
proceedings contribution, I review the basic ideas of anisotropic
hydrodynamics, recent progress, and present a few preliminary phenomenological
predictions for identified particle spectra and elliptic flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05470</id><created>2016-11-16</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gorbar</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miransky</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shovkovy</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhachov</keyname><forenames>P. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral magnetic plasmons in anomalous relativistic matter</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 multi-panel figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115202 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The chiral plasmon modes of relativistic matter in background magnetic and
strain-induced pseudomagnetic fields are studied in detail using the consistent
chiral kinetic theory. The results reveal a number of anomalous features of
these chiral magnetic and pseudomagnetic plasmons that could be used to
identify them in experiment. In a system with nonzero electric (chiral)
chemical potential, the background magnetic (pseudomagnetic) fields not only
modify the values of the plasmon frequencies in the long-wavelength limit, but
also affect the qualitative dependence on the wave vector. Similar
modifications can be also induced by the chiral shift parameter in Weyl
materials. Interestingly, even in the absence of the chiral shift and external
fields, the chiral chemical potential alone leads to a splitting of plasmon
energies at linear order in the wave vector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07355</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>O&#x142;dziejewski</keyname><forenames>Rafa&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jachymski</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of strongly dipolar Bose gases beyond the Born approximation</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>slight corrections &amp; extensions</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063638 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063638</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strongly dipolar Bose gases can form liquid droplets stabilized by quantum
fluctuations. In theoretical description of this phenomenon, low energy
scattering amplitude is utilized as an effective potential. We show that for
magnetic atoms corrections with respect to Born approximation arise, and derive
modified pseudopotential using realistic interaction model. We discuss the
resulting changes in collective mode frequencies and droplet stability diagram.
Our results are relevant for recent experiments with erbium and dysprosium
atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08265</id><created>2016-11-24</created><updated>2017-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Aaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glass</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gustafson</keyname><forenames>H. Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>Craig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamai</keyname><forenames>Brittany L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Ohkyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanza</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCuller</keyname><forenames>Lee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Stephan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoughton</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomlin</keyname><forenames>Ray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>The Holometer: An Instrument to Probe Planckian Quantum Geometry</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Matches the version accepted in Classical and Quantum Gravity</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-528</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 065005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa5e5c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes the Fermilab Holometer, an instrument for measuring
correlations of position variations over a four-dimensional volume of
space-time. The apparatus consists of two co-located, but independent and
isolated, 40m power-recycled Michelson interferometers, whose outputs are
cross-correlated to 25 MHz. The data are sensitive to correlations of
differential position across the apparatus over a broad band of frequencies up
to and exceeding the inverse light crossing time, 7.6 MHz. A noise model
constrained by diagnostic and environmental data distinguishes among physical
origins of measured correlations, and is used to verify shot-noise-limited
performance. These features allow searches for exotic quantum correlations that
depart from classical trajectories at spacelike separations, with a strain
noise power spectral density sensitivity smaller than the Planck time. The
Holometer in current and future configurations is projected to provide
precision tests of a wide class of models of quantum geometry at the Planck
scale, beyond those already constrained by currently operating gravitational
wave observatories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09334</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xie</forenames></author></authors><title>Twisted gauge theories in 3D Walker-Wang models</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115142 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three dimensional gauge theories with a discrete gauge group can emerge from
spin models as a gapped topological phase with fractional point excitations
(gauge charge) and loop excitations (gauge flux). It is known that 3D gauge
theories can be &quot;twisted&quot;, in the sense that the gauge flux loops can have
nontrivial braiding statistics among themselves and such twisted gauge theories
are realized in models discovered by Dijkgraaf and Witten. A different
framework to systematically construct three dimensional topological phases was
proposed by Walker and Wang and a series of examples have been studied. Can the
Walker Wang construction be used to realize the topological order in twisted
gauge theories? This is not immediately clear because the Walker-Wang
construction is based on a loop condensation picture while the Dijkgraaf-Witten
theory is based on a membrane condensation picture. In this paper, we show that
the answer to this question is Yes, by presenting an explicit construction of
the Walker Wang models which realize both the twisted and untwisted gauge
theories with gauge group $\mathbb{Z}_2 \times \mathbb{Z}_2$. We identify the
topological order of the models by performing modular transformations on the
ground state wave functions and show that the modular matrices exactly match
those for the $\mathbb{Z}_2 \times \mathbb{Z}_2$ gauge theories. By relating
the Walker-Wang construction to the Dijkgraaf-Witten construction, our result
opens up a way to study twisted gauge theories with fermonic charges, and
correspondingly strongly interacting fermionic symmetry protected topological
phases and their surface states, through exactly solvable models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00140</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Ayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preis</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author></authors><title>Semiholography for heavy ion collisions</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages; 3 figures; Proceedings of Confinement XII @ Thessaloniki,
  Greece -- August 28 to September 4, 2016</comments><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713707015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation of QGP in heavy ion collisions gives us a great opportunity for
learning about nonperturbative dynamics of QCD. Semiholography provides a new
consistent framework to combine perturbative and non-perturbative effects in a
coherent way and can be applied to obtain an effective description for heavy
ion collisions. In particular, it allows us to include nonperturbative effects
in existing glasma effective theory and QCD kinetic theory for the weakly
coupled saturated degrees of freedom liberated by the collisions in the initial
stages in a consistent manner. We argue why the full framework should be able
to confront experiments with only a few phenomenological parameters and present
feasibility tests for the necessary numerical computations. Furthermore, we
discuss that semiholography leads to a new description of collective flow in
the form of a generalised non-Newtonian fluid. We discuss some open questions
which we hope to answer in the near future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00473</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Serna</keyname><forenames>Fernando E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krein</keyname><forenames>Gast&#xe3;o</forenames></author></authors><title>Charmed mesons at finite temperature and chemical potential</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713713015</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the masses of the pseudoscalar mesons $\pi^+$ , $K^0$ and $D^+$ at
finite temperature and baryon chemical potential. The computations are based on
a symmetry- preserving Dyson-Schwinger equation treatment of a vector-vector
four quark contact interaction. The results found for the temperature
dependence of the meson masses are in qualitative agreement with lattice QCD
data and QCD sum rules calculations. The chemical potential dependence of the
masses provide a novel prediction of the present computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00605</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2017-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ejima</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fehske</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author></authors><title>Anyonic Haldane insulator in one dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures + 1 page supplemental material, accepted for
  publication in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 120401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.120401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate numerically the existence of a nontrivial topological Haldane
phase for the one-dimensional extended ($U$-$V$) Hubbard model with a mean
density of one particle per site, not only for bosons but also for anyons,
despite a broken reflection parity symmetry. The Haldane insulator, surrounded
by superfluid, Mott insulator and density-wave phases in the $V$-$U$ parameter
plane, is protected by combined (modified) spatial-inversion and time-reversal
symmetries, which is verified within our matrix-product-state based infinite
density-matrix renormalization group scheme by analyzing generalized transfer
matrices. With regard to an experimental verification of the anyonic Haldane
insulator state the calculated asymmetry of the dynamical density structure
factor should be of particular importance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00674</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2017-03-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arroja</keyname><forenames>Frederico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Che-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pisin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeom</keyname><forenames>Dong-han</forenames></author></authors><title>Singular Instantons in Eddington-inspired-Born-Infeld Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, version accepted in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 03 (2017) 044</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/03/044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we investigate $O(4)$-symmetric instantons within the
Eddington-inspired-Born-Infeld gravity theory (EiBI). We discuss the regular
Hawking-Moss instanton and find that the tunneling rate reduces to the General
Relativity (GR) value, even though the action value is different by a constant.
We give a thorough analysis of the singular Vilenkin instanton and the
Hawking-Turok instanton with a quadratic scalar field potential in the EiBI
theory. In both cases, we find that the singularity can be avoided in the sense
that the physical metric, its scalar curvature and the scalar field are regular
under some parameter restrictions, but there is a curvature singularity of the
auxiliary metric compatible with the connection. We find that the on-shell
action is finite and the probability does not reduce to its GR value. We also
find that the Vilenkin instanton in the EiBI theory would still cause the
instability of the Minkowski space, similar to that in GR, and this is
observationally inconsistent. This result suggests that the singularity of the
auxiliary metric may be problematic at the quantum level and that these
instantons should be excluded from the path integral.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01151</id><created>2016-12-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Prochazka</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwicky</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>${\cal N}$ = $1$ Euler Anomaly from RG-dependent metric-Background</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings for Confinement and Hadron Spectroscopy 2016, 6 pages</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2016-053 DNRF90</report-no><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf. Volume 137, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713710009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider ${\cal N}=1$ supersymmetric gauge theories in the conformal
window. By applying a suitable matter superfield rescaling and a
Weyl-transformation the renormalisation group running (matter and gauge field
$Z$-factors) are absorbed into the metric. The latter becomes a function of the
$Z$-factors. The Euler flow $\Delta a \equiv a_{\rm UV} - a_{\rm IR} |_{{\cal
N}=1}$ is then obtained by free field theory computation with the non-trivial
dynamics coming from expanding the Euler invariant in the flow dependent
metric. The result is therefore directly obtained in terms of the infrared
anomalous dimension confirming an earlier result using the matching of
conserved currents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03099</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Donker</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Raedt</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoherence and pointer states in small antiferromagnets: A benchmark
  test</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 2, 010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.2.2.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the decoherence process of a four spin-1/2 antiferromagnet that is
coupled to an environment of spin-1/2 particles. The preferred basis of the
antiferromagnet is discussed in two limiting cases and we identify two
$\it{exact}$ pointer states. Decoherence near the two limits is examined
whereby entropy is used to quantify the $\it{robustness}$ of states against
environmental coupling. We find that close to the quantum measurement limit,
the self-Hamiltonian of the system of interest can become dynamically relevant
on macroscopic timescales. We illustrate this point by explicitly constructing
a state that is more robust than (generic) states diagonal in the
system-environment interaction Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05797</id><created>2016-12-17</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hassan</keyname><forenames>Sultan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dave</keyname><forenames>Romeel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finlator</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Mario G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Epoch of Reionisation 21cm Forecasting From MCMC-Constrained
  Semi-Numerical Models</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 figues, matches the accepted version for publication in
  MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 468 (1): 122-139</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx420</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent low value of Planck (2016) integrated optical depth to Thomson
scattering suggests that the reionization occurred fairly suddenly, disfavoring
extended reionization scenarios. This will have a significant impact on the
21cm power spectrum. Using a semi-numerical framework, we improve our model
from Hassan et al. (2016) to include time-integrated ionisation and
recombination effects, and find that this leads to more sudden reionisation. It
also yields larger HII bubbles which leads to an order of magnitude more 21cm
power on large scales, while suppressing the small scale ionization power.
Local fluctuations in the neutral hydrogen density play the dominant role in
boosting the 21cm power spectrum on large scales, while recombinations are
subdominant. We use a Monte Carlo Markov Chain approach to constrain our model
to observations of the star formation rate functions at z = 6,7,8 from Bouwens
et al. (2015), the Planck (2016) optical depth measurements, and the Becker &amp;
Bolton (2013) ionising emissivity data at z~5. We then use this constrained
model to perform 21cm forecasting for LOFAR, HERA, and SKA in order to
determine how well such data can characterise the sources driving reionisation.
We find that the 21cm power spectrum alone can somewhat constrain the halo mass
dependence of ionising sources, the photon escape fraction and ionising
amplitude, but combining the 21cm data with other current observations enables
us to separately constrain all these parameters. Our framework illustrates how
21cm data can play a key role in understanding the sources and topology of
reionisation as observations improve.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05999</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haba</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of diffusive DM/DE systems</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><journal-ref>Gen.Relativ.Gravit (2017) 49:58</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2224-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the energy density,temperature and entropy of dark matter (DM) and
dark energy (DE) as functions of the scale factor $a$ in an expanding universe.
In a model of non-interacting dark components we repeat a derivation from
thermodynamics of the well-known relations between the energy density,entropy
and temperature. In particular, the entropy is constant as a consequence of the
energy conservation. We consider a model of the DM/DE interaction where DM
energy density increase is proportional to the particle density. In such a
model the dependence of the energy density and the temperature on the scale
factor $a$ is substantially modified. We discuss (as a realization of the
model) DM which consists of relativistic particles diffusing in an environment
of DE. The energy gained by the dark matter comes from a cosmological fluid
with a negative pressure. We define the entropy and free energy of such a
non-equilibrium system. We show that during the universe evolution the entropy
of DM is increasing whereas the entropy of DE is decreasing. The total entropy
can increase (in spite of the energy conservation) as DM and DE temperatures
are different. We discuss non-equilibrium thermodynamics on the basis of the
notion of relative entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06183</id><created>2016-12-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Dvornikov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames><affiliation>IZMIRAN, Tomsk State University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Generation of strong magnetic fields in hybrid and quark stars driven by
  the electroweak interaction of quarks</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 eps figures, J. Phys. Conf. Ser. LaTeX style; submitted to
  proceedings of 2nd international conference on particle physics and
  astrophysics, October 10-14, 2016, Moscow, Russia</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 798, 012051 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/798/1/012051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the generation of strong large scale magnetic fields in compact
stars containing degenerate quark matter with unbroken chiral symmetry. The
magnetic field growth is owing to the magnetic field instability driven by the
electroweak interaction of quarks. In this system we predict the enhancement of
the seed magnetic field $10^{12}\,\text{G}$ to the strengths
$(10^{14}-10^{15})\,\text{G}$. In our analysis we use the typical parameters of
the quark matter in the core of a hybrid star or in a quark star. We also apply
of the obtained results to model the generation of magnetic fields in
magnetars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06957</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakamula</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Shin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takesue</keyname><forenames>Koki</forenames></author></authors><title>Atiyah-Manton Construction of Skyrmions in Eight Dimensions</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 03 (2017) 076</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)076</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the eight-dimensional instanton solution, which satisfies the
self-duality equation $F \wedge F = *_8 F \wedge F$, realizes the static
Skyrmion configuration in eight dimensions through the Atiyah-Manton
construction. The relevant energy functional of the Skyrme field is obtained by
the formalism developed by Sutcliffe. By comparing the Skyrmion olution
associated with the extreme of the energy, with the Atiyah-Manton solution
constructed by the instantons, we find that they agree with high accuracy. This
is a higher-dimensional analogue of the Atiyah-Manton construction of Skyrmions
in four dimensions. Our result indicates that the instanton/Skyrmion
correspondence seems to be an universal property in $4k \ (k=1, 2, \ldots)$
dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07032</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Varotsos</keyname><forenames>Panayiotis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlis</keyname><forenames>Nicholas V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skordas</keyname><forenames>Efthimios S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal correlations between the earthquake magnitudes before major
  mainshocks in Japan</title><categories>physics.geo-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures, 5 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A characteristic change of seismicity has been recently uncovered when the
precursory Seismic Electric Signals activities initiate before an earthquake
occurrence. In particular, the fluctuations of the order parameter of
seismicity exhibit a simultaneous distinct minimum upon analyzing the seismic
catalogue in a new time domain termed natural time and employing a sliding
natural time window comprising a number of events that would occur in a few
months. Here, we focus on the minima preceding all earthquakes of magnitude 8
(and 9) class that occurred in Japanese area from 1 January 1984 to 11 March
2011 (the day of the M9 Tohoku earthquake). By applying Detrended Fluctuation
Analysis to the earthquake magnitude time series, we find that each of these
minima is preceded as well as followed by characteristic changes of temporal
correlations between earthquake magnitudes. In particular, we identify the
following three main features. The minima are observed during periods when long
range correlations have been developed, but they are preceded by a stage in
which an evident anti-correlated behavior appears. After the minima, the long
range correlations break down to an almost random behavior turning to
anti-correlation. The minima that precede M$\geq$7.8 earthquakes are
distinguished from other minima which are either non-precursory or followed by
smaller earthquakes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07056</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Varotsos</keyname><forenames>Panayiotis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlis</keyname><forenames>Nicholas V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skordas</keyname><forenames>Efthimios S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazaridou</keyname><forenames>Mary S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seismic Electric Signals: A physical interconnection with seismicity</title><categories>physics.geo-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By applying natural time analysis to the time series of earthquakes, we find
that the order parameter of seismicity exhibits a unique change approximately
at the date(s) at which Seismic Electric Signals (SES) activities have been
reported to initiate. In particular, we show that the fluctuations of the order
parameter of seismicity in Japan exhibits a clearly detectable minimum
approximately at the time of the initiation of the SES activity observed almost
two months before the onset of the Volcanic-seismic swarm activity in 2000 in
the Izu Island region, Japan. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first
time that, well before the occurrence of major earthquakes, anomalous changes
are found to appear almost simultaneously in two independent datasets of
different geophysical observables (geoelectrical measurements, seismicity). In
addition, we show that these two phenomena are also linked closely in space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07327</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Tianci</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luitz</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Operator entanglement entropy of the time evolution operator in chaotic
  systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>18 pages, 14 figures. Revised version has added a refined argument
  and numerical evidence for the deficit value in the disordered Heisenberg
  model</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 094206 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.094206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the growth of the operator entanglement entropy (EE) of the time
evolution operator in chaotic, many-body localized and Floquet systems. In the
random field Heisenberg model we find a universal power law growth of the
operator EE at weak disorder, a logarithmic growth at strong disorder, and
extensive saturation values in both cases. In a Floquet spin model, the
saturation value after an initial linear growth is identical to the value of a
random unitary operator (the Page value). We understand these properties by
mapping the operator EE to a global quench problem evolved with a similar
parent-Hamiltonian in an enlarged Hilbert space with the same chaotic, MBL and
Floquet properties as the original Hamiltonian. The scaling and saturation
properties reflect the spreading of the state EE of the corresponding time
evolution. We conclude that the EE of the evolution operator should
characterize the propagation of information in these systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08006</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dusseault</keyname><forenames>Marisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boninsegni</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic displacements in quantum crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures in color</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 104518 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.104518</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Displacements of atoms and molecules away from lattice sites in helium and
parahydrogen solids at low temperature have been studied by means of Quantum
Monte Carlo simulations. In the bcc phases of He-3 and He-4, atomic
displacements are largely quantum-mechanical in character, even at melting. The
computed Lindemann ratio at melting is found to be in good agreement with
experimental results for He-4. Unlike the case of helium, in solid parahydrogen
there exists near melting a significant thermal contribution to molecular
vibrations, accounting for roughly half of the total effect. Although the
Lindemann ratio at melting is in quantitative agreement with experiment,
computed molecular mean square fluctuations feature a clear temperature
dependence, in disagreement with recent experimental observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08063</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-03-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Strauss</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaganskiy</keyname><forenames>Arsenty</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voigt</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnauber</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulze</keyname><forenames>Jan-Hindrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodt</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strittmatter</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reitzenstein</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonance fluorescence of a site-controlled quantum dot realized by the
  buried-stressor growth technique</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 111101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4978428</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Site-controlled growth of semiconductor quantum dots (QDs) represents a major
advancement to achieve scalable quantum technology platforms. One immediate
benefit is the deterministic integration of quantum emitters into optical
microcavities. However, site-controlled growth of QDs is usually achieved at
the cost of reduced optical quality. Here, we show that the buried-stressor
growth technique enables the realization of high-quality site-controlled QDs
with attractive optical and quantum optical properties. This is evidenced by
performing excitation power dependent resonance fluorescence experiments at
cryogenic temperatures showing QD emission linewidths down to 10 $\mu$eV.
Resonant excitation leads to the observation of the Mollow triplet under CW
excitation and enables coherent state preparation under pulsed excitation.
Under resonant $\pi$-pulse excitation we observe clean single photon emission
associated with $g^{(2)}(0)=0.12$ limited by non-ideal laser suppression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09074</id><created>2016-12-29</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Ujjal Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maity</keyname><forenames>Tarak Nath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Tirtha Sankar</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Dark Matter through Assisted Annihilation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures; minor changes in the text, typos fixed, added
  references; matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP03(2017)045</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/03/045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate light dark matter scenarios where annihilation
to Standard Model particles at tree-level is kinematically forbidden. In such
cases annihilation can be aided by massive Standard Model-like species, called
{\it assisters}, in the initial state that enhances the available phase space
opening up novel tree-level processes. We investigate the feasibility of such
non-standard {\it assisted annihilation} processes to reproduce the observed
relic density of dark matter. We present a simple scalar dark matter - scalar
assister model where this is realised. We find that if the dark matter and
assister are relatively degenerate the required relic density can be achieved
for a keV-MeV scale dark matter. We briefly discuss the cosmological
constraints on such dark matter scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00678</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Nesterenko</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispersive approach to QCD and hadronic contributions to electroweak
  observables</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>Talk given at 12th International Conference on Quark Confinement and
  the Hadron Spectrum, 29 August - 3 September 2016, Thessaloniki, Greece; 10
  pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf. 137, 05021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713705021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dispersive approach to QCD is briefly overviewed and its application to
the assessment of hadronic contributions to electroweak observables is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05391</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Odderskov</keyname><forenames>Io</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannestad</keyname><forenames>Steen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandbyge</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>The variance of the locally measured Hubble parameter explained with
  different estimators</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures. v2: Minor corrections in text; results unchanged</comments><journal-ref>JCAP03(2017)022</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/03/022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the expected variance of measurements of the Hubble constant, $H_0$,
as calculated in either linear perturbation theory or using non-linear velocity
power spectra derived from $N$-body simulations. We compare the variance with
that obtained by carrying out mock observations in the N-body simulations, and
show that the estimator typically used for the local Hubble constant in studies
based on perturbation theory is different from the one used in studies based on
N-body simulations. The latter gives larger weight to distant sources, which
explains why studies based on N-body simulations tend to obtain a smaller
variance than that found from studies based on the power spectrum. Although
both approaches result in a variance too small to explain the discrepancy
between the value of $H_0$ from CMB measurements and the value measured in the
local universe, these considerations are important in light of the percent
determination of the Hubble constant in the local universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05825</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhatia</keyname><forenames>Disha</forenames><affiliation>Tata Inst.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sabyasachi</forenames><affiliation>Tata Inst.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dighe</keyname><forenames>Amol</forenames><affiliation>Tata Inst.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Neutrino mixing and $R_K$ anomaly in $U(1)_X$ models: a bottom-up
  approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 6 figures, minor typos corrected, one comment and
  references added, matches with the version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>TIFR/TH/17-06</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP03 (2017) 117</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We identify a class of $U(1)_X$ models which can explain the $R_K$ anomaly
and the neutrino mixing pattern, by using a bottom-up approach. The different
$X$-charges of lepton generations account for the lepton universality violation
required to explain $R_K$. In addition to the three right-handed neutrinos
needed for the Type-I seesaw mechanism, these minimal models only introduce an
additional doublet Higgs and a singlet scalar. While the former helps in
reproducing the quark mixing structure, the latter gives masses to neutrinos
and the new gauge boson $Z^\prime$. Our bottom-up approach determines the
$X$-charges of all particles using theoretical consistency and experimental
constraints. We find the parameter space allowed by the constraints from
neutral meson mixing, rare $b\to s$ decays and direct collider searches for
$Z^\prime$. Such a $Z^\prime$ may be observable at the ongoing run of the Large
Hadron Collider with a few hundred fb$^{-1}$ of integrated luminosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01577</id><created>2017-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Takae</keyname><forenames>Kyohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onuki</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferroelectric glass of spheroidal dipoles with impurities: Polar
  nanoregions, response to applied electric field, and ergodicity breakdown</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 165401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa6184</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using molecular dynamics simulation, we study dipolar glass in crystals
composed of slightly spheroidal, polar particles and spherical, apolar
impurities between metal walls. We present physical pictures of ferroelectric
glass, which have been observed in relaxors, mixed crystals (such as
KCN$_x$KBr$_{1-x}$), and polymers. Our systems undergo a diffuse transition in
a wide temperature range, where we visualize polar nanoregions (PNRs)
surrounded by impurities. In our simulation, the impurities form clusters and
their space distribution is heterogeneous. The polarization fluctuations are
enhanced at relatively high $T$ depending on the size of the dipole moment.
They then form frozen PNRs as $T$ is further lowered into the nonergodic
regime. As a result, the dielectric permittivity exhibits the characteristic
features of relaxor ferroelectrics. We also examine nonlinear response to
cyclic applied electric field and nonergodic response to cyclic temperature
changes (ZFC$/$FC), where the polarization and the strain change collectively
and heterogeneously. We also study antiferroelectric glass arising from
molecular shape asymmetry. We use an Ewald scheme of calculating the dipolar
interaction in applied electric field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04150</id><created>2017-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>McGilligan</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffin</keyname><forenames>Paul F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elvin</keyname><forenames>Rachel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ingleby</keyname><forenames>Stuart J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riis</keyname><forenames>Erling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Aidan S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Grating chips for quantum technologies</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 384 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-00254-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have laser cooled 3$\times10^6$ $^{87}$Rb atoms to 3$\mu$K in a
micro-fabricated grating magneto-optical trap (GMOT), enabling future
mass-deployment in highly accurate compact quantum sensors. We magnetically
trap the atoms, and use Larmor spin precession for magnetic sensing in the
vicinity of the atomic sample. Finally, we demonstrate an array of
magneto-optical traps with a single laser beam, which will be utilised for
future cold atom gradiometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04223</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cremers</keyname><forenames>Theo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chefdeville</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Niek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sweers</keyname><forenames>Edwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koot</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claus</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>van de Meerakker</keyname><forenames>Sebastiaan Y. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new concept multi-stage Zeeman decelerator: experimental
  implementation</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>This article has been merged with the article found at
  arXiv:1702.05477</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the successful experimental implementation of a multi-stage
Zeeman decelerator utilizing the new concept described in the accompanying
paper. The decelerator consists of an array of 25 hexapoles and 24 solenoids.
The performance of the decelerator in acceleration, deceleration and guiding
modes is characterized using beams of metastable Helium ($^3S$) atoms. Up to
60% of the kinetic energy was removed for He atoms that have an initial
velocity of 520 m/s. The hexapoles consist of permanent magnets, whereas the
solenoids are produced from a single hollow copper capillary through which
cooling liquid is passed. The solenoid design allows for excellent thermal
properties, and enables the use of readily available and cheap electronics
components to pulse high currents through the solenoids. The Zeeman decelerator
demonstrated here is mechanically easy to build, can be operated with
cost-effective electronics, and can run at repetition rates up to 10 Hz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06560</id><created>2017-02-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Engle</keyname><forenames>Scott G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guinan</keyname><forenames>Edward F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harper</keyname><forenames>Dr. Graham M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuntz</keyname><forenames>Prof. Manfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Dr. Nancy R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neilson</keyname><forenames>Dr. Hilding</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fawzy</keyname><forenames>Dr. Diaa E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Secret Lives of Cepheids: $\delta$ Cep -- the Prototype of a New
  Class of Pulsating X-ray Variable Stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables, accepted for publication in the
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 838 (2017), 67</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6159</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From our Secret Lives of Cepheids program, the prototype Classical Cepheid,
$\delta$ Cep, is found to be an X-ray source with periodic pulsation-modulated
X-ray variations. This finding complements our earlier reported phase-dependent
FUV--UV emissions of the star that increase $\sim$10--20 times with highest
fluxes at $\sim0.90-0.95\phi$, just prior to maximum brightness. Previously,
$\delta$ Cep was found as potentially X-ray variable, using XMM-Newton
observations (Engle et al. 2014). Additional phase-constrained data were
secured with Chandra near X-ray emission peak, to determine if the emission and
variability were pulsation-phase-specific to $\delta$ Cep and not transient or
due to a possible coronally-active, cool companion. The Chandra data were
combined with prior XMM-Newton observations, and very closely match the
previously observed X-ray behavior. From the combined dataset, a
$\sim$4$\times$ increase in X-ray flux is measured, reaching a peak $L_X$ = 1.7
$\times$ 10$^{29}$ erg s$^{-1}$ near 0.45$\phi$. The precise X-ray flux phasing
with the star's pulsation indicates that the emissions arise from the Cepheid
and not a companion. However, it is puzzling that maximum X-ray flux occurs
$\sim$0.5$\phi$ ($\sim$3 days) later than the FUV--UV maximum. There are
several other potential Cepheid X-ray detections with properties similar to
$\delta$ Cep, and comparable X-ray variability is indicated for two other
Cepheids: $\beta$ Dor and V473 Lyr. X-ray generating mechanisms in $\delta$ Cep
and other Cepheids are discussed. If additional Cepheids are confirmed to show
phased X-ray variations, then $\delta$ Cep will be the prototype of new class
of pulsation-induced X-ray variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07742</id><created>2017-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Kolobov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giese</keyname><forenames>Enno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemieux</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fickler</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling induced coherence for quantum imaging</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optics 19, 054003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8986/aa64a2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Induced coherence in parametric down-conversion between two coherently pumped
nonlinear crystals that share a common idler mode can be used as an imaging
technique. Based on the interference between the two signal modes of the
crystals, an image can be reconstructed. By obtaining an expression for the
interference pattern that is valid in both the low- and the high-gain regimes
of parametric down-conversion, we show how the coherence of the light emitted
by the two crystals can be controlled. With our comprehensive analysis we
provide deeper insight into recent discussions about the application of induced
coherence to imaging in different regimes. Moreover, we propose a scheme for
optimizing the visibility of the interference pattern so that it directly
corresponds to the degree of coherence of the light generated in the two
crystals. We find that this scheme leads in the high-gain regime to a
visibility arbitrarily close to unity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00051</id><created>2017-02-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Abbas</keyname><forenames>Chahine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guizal</keyname><forenames>Brahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antezza</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong thermal and electrostatic manipulation of the Casimir force in
  graphene multilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, Phys. Rev. Lett. in press</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 126101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.126101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that graphene-dielectric multilayers give rise to an unusual
tunability of the Casimir-Lifshitz forces, and allow to easily realize
completely different regimes within the same structure. Concerning thermal
effects, graphene-dielectric multilayers take advantage from the anomalous
features predicted for isolated suspended graphene sheets, even though they are
considerably affected by the presence of the dielectric substrate. They can
also archive the anomalous non-monotonic thermal metallic behavior by
increasing the graphene sheets density and their Fermi energy. In addition to a
strong thermal modulation occurring at short separations, in a region where the
force is orders of magnitude larger than the one occurring at large distances,
the force can be also adjusted by varying the number of graphene layers as well
as their Fermi energy levels, allowing for relevant force amplifications which
can be tuned, very rapidly and in-situ, by simply applying an electric
potential. Our predictions can be relevant for both Casimir experiments and
micro/nano electromechanical systems and in new devices for technological
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00179</id><created>2017-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Lepri</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trono</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacomelli</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex active optical networks as a new laser concept</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.CD</categories><comments>To be published in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 123901 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.123901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex optical networks containing one or more gain sections are
investigated and the evidence of lasing action is reported; the emission
spectrum reflects the topological disorder induced by the connections. A
theoretical description well compares with the measurements, mapping the
networks to directed graphs and showing the analogies with the problem of
quantum chaos on graphs. We show that the interplay of chaotic diffusion and
amplification leads to an emission statistics with characteristic heavy-tails:
for different topologies, an unprecedented experimental demonstration of Levy
statistics expected for random lasers is here provided for a continuous-wave
pumped system. This result is also supported by a Monte-Carlo simulation based
on ray random walk on the graph.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00627</id><created>2017-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Siddhartha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bera</keyname><forenames>Apurba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bharadwaj</keyname><forenames>Somnath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhat</keyname><forenames>N. D. Ramesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chengalur</keyname><forenames>Jayaram N.</forenames></author></authors><title>FRB event rate predictions for the Ooty Wide Field Array</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To appear in the Special Section of the JAA on the Ooty Wide Field
  Array</comments><journal-ref>J Astrophys Astron (2017) 38:17</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12036-017-9431-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We developed a generic formalism to estimate the event rate and the redshift
distribution of Fast Radio Bursts (FRBs) in our previous publication (Bera et
al. 2016), considering FRBs are of an extragalactic origin. In this paper we
present (a) the predicted pulse widths of FRBs by considering two different
scattering models, (b) the minimum total energy required to detect events, (c)
the redshift distribution and (d) the detection rates of FRBs for the Ooty Wide
Field Array (OWFA). The energy spectrum of FRBs is modelled as a power law with
an exponent $-\alpha$ and our analysis spans a range $-3\leq \alpha \leq 5$. We
find that OWFA will be capable of detecting FRBs with $\alpha\geq 0$. The
redshift distribution and the event rates of FRBs are estimated by assuming two
different energy distribution functions; a Delta function and a Schechter
luminosity function with an exponent $-2\le \gamma \le 2$. We consider an
empirical scattering model based on pulsar observations (model I) as well as a
theoretical model (model II) expected for the intergalactic medium. The
redshift distributions peak at a particular redshift $z_p$ for a fixed value of
$\alpha$, which lie in the range $0.3\leq z_p \leq 1$ for the scattering model
I and remain flat and extend up to high redshifts ($z\lesssim 5$) for the
scattering model II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00858</id><created>2017-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Grete</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlaykov</keyname><forenames>Dimitar G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Wolfram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schleicher</keyname><forenames>Dominik R G</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparative statistics of selected subgrid-scale models in large eddy
  simulations of decaying, supersonic MHD turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA physics.comp-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in PRE</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 033206 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.033206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large eddy simulations (LES) are a powerful tool in understanding processes
that are inaccessible by direct simulations due to their complexity, for
example, in the highly turbulent regime. However, their accuracy and success
depends on a proper subgrid-scale (SGS) model that accounts for the unresolved
scales in the simulation. We evaluate the applicability of two traditional SGS
models, namely the eddy-viscosity (EV) and the scale-similarity (SS) model, and
one recently proposed nonlinear (NL) SGS model in the realm of compressible MHD
turbulence. Using 209 simulations of decaying, supersonic (initial sonic Mach
number of ~3) MHD turbulence with a shock-capturing scheme and varying
resolution, SGS model and filter, we analyze the ensemble statistics of kinetic
and magnetic energy spectra and structure functions. Furthermore, we compare
the temporal evolution of lower and higher order statistical moments of the
spatial distributions of kinetic and magnetic energy, vorticity, current
density, and dilatation magnitudes. We find no statistical influence on the
evolution of the flow by any model if grid-scale quantities are used to
calculate SGS contributions. In addition, the SS models, which employ an
explicit filter, have no impact in general. On the contrary, both EV and NL
models change the statistics if an explicit filter is used. For example, they
slightly increase the dissipation on the smallest scales. We demonstrate that
the nonlinear model improves higher order statistics already with a small
explicit filter, i.e. a three-point stencil. The results of e.g. the structure
functions or the skewness and kurtosis of the current density distribution are
closer to the ones obtained from simulations at higher resolution. We conclude
that the nonlinear model with a small explicit filter is suitable for
application in more complex scenarios when higher order statistics are
important.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01000</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Wenlong</forenames><affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Shiyuan</forenames><affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Macri</keyname><forenames>Lucas M.</forenames><affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>James</forenames><affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jianhua Z.</forenames><affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University</affiliation></author></authors><title>The M33 Synoptic Stellar Survey. II. Mira Variables</title><categories>astro-ph.SR stat.AP</categories><comments>Includes small corrections to match the published version</comments><journal-ref>The Astronomical Journal, 153:170 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/aa63f1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the discovery of 1847 Mira candidates in the Local Group galaxy
M33 using a novel semi-parametric periodogram technique coupled with a Random
Forest classifier. The algorithms were applied to ~2.4x10^5 I-band light curves
previously obtained by the M33 Synoptic Stellar Survey. We derive preliminary
Period-Luminosity relations at optical, near- &amp; mid-infrared wavelengths and
compare them to the corresponding relations in the Large Magellanic Cloud.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01394</id><created>2017-03-03</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xuepeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shaobo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Miaomiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Xinyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Wenshan</forenames></author></authors><title>CO~($J = 1-0$) Observations of a Filamentary Molecular Cloud in the
  Galactic Region Centered at $l = 150\arcdeg, b = 3.5\arcdeg$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>48 pages, 24 figures, 3 tables. Published by Astrophysical Journal</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6443</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present large-field (4.25~$\times$~3.75 deg$^2$) mapping observations
toward the Galactic region centered at $l = 150\arcdeg, b = 3.5\arcdeg$ in the
$J = 1-0$ emission line of CO isotopologues ($^{12}$CO, $^{13}$CO, and
C$^{18}$O), using the 13.7 m millimeter-wavelength telescope of the Purple
Mountain Observatory. Based on the $^{13}$CO observations, we reveal a
filamentary cloud in the Local Arm at a velocity range of $-$0.5 to
6.5~km~s$^{-1}$. This molecular cloud contains 1 main filament and 11
sub-filaments, showing the so-called &quot;ridge-nest&quot; structure. The main filament
and three sub-filaments are also detected in the C$^{18}$O line. The velocity
structures of most identified filaments display continuous distribution with
slight velocity gradients. The measured median excitation temperature, line
width, length, width, and linear mass of the filaments are $\sim$9.28~K,
0.85~km~s$^{-1}$, 7.30~pc, 0.79~pc, and 17.92~$M_\sun$~pc$^{-1}$, respectively,
assuming a distance of 400~pc. We find that the four filaments detected in the
C$^{18}$O line are thermally supercritical, and two of them are in the
virialized state, and thus tend to be gravitationally bound. We identify in
total 146 $^{13}$CO clumps in the cloud, about 77$\%$ of the clumps are
distributed along the filaments. About 56$\%$ of the virialized clumps are
found to be associated with the supercritical filaments. Three young stellar
object (YSO) candidates are also identified in the supercritical filaments,
based on the complementary infrared (IR) data. These results indicate that the
supercritical filaments, especially the virialized filaments, may contain
star-forming activities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02178</id><created>2017-03-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou-juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Wei-xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chang-wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pei-ji</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Dimensional Large Gap Topological Insulators with Large Rashba
  Spin-Orbit Coupling in Group-IV films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>31 pages and 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci, Rep, 7: 45923 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep45923</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rashba spin orbit coupling in topological insulators has attracted much
interest due to its exotic properties closely related to spintronic devices.
The coexistence of nontrivial topology and giant Rashba splitting, however, has
rare been observed in two-dimensional films, limiting severely its potential
applications at room temperature. Here, we propose a series of inversion
asymmetric group IV films, ABZ2, whose stability are confirmed by phonon
spectrum calculations. The analyses of electronic structures reveal that they
are intrinsic 2D TIs with a bulk gap as large as 0.74 eV, except for GeSiF2,
SnSiCl2, GeSiCl2 and GeSiBr2 monolayers which can transform from normal to
topological phases under appropriate tensile strains. Another prominent
intriguing feature is the giant Rashba spin splitting with a magnitude reaching
0.15 eV, the largest value reported in 2D films. These results present a
platform to explore 2D TIs for room temperature device applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03980</id><created>2017-03-11</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Md. Lokman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Md. Zahidur</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation on different physical aspects such as structural, elastic,
  mechanical, optical properties and Debye temperature of Fe2ScM (M = P and As)
  semiconductors: a DFT based first principles study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages with 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the help of first principles calculation method based on the density
functional theory we have investigated the structural, elastic, mechanical
properties and Debye temperature of Fe2ScM (M = P and As) compounds under
pressure up to 60 GPa. The optical properties have been investigated under zero
pressure. Our calculated optimized structural parameters of both the compounds
are in good agreement with the other theoretical results. The calculated
elastic constants show that Fe2ScM (M = P and As) compounds are mechanically
stable up to 60 GPa.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04719</id><created>2017-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Graziela R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Aisheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Xiaoxiong</forenames></author></authors><title>Aqua MODIS Band 24 Crosstalk Striping</title><categories>physics.ao-ph astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Published in IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters ( Volume:
  14, Issue: 4, April 2017 )</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/LGRS.2016.2647441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aqua MODIS, unlike its predecessor on board the Terra spacecraft, had always
been thought to have been spared from significant deleterious impacts of
electronic crosstalk on its imagery. However, recent efforts brought to our
attention the presence of striping artifacts in Aqua MODIS images from band 24
(4.47$\mu$m), which upon further inspection proved to have a noticeable impact
on the quality of the L1B product and to have been present since the beginning
of the mission, in 2002. Using images of the Moon from scheduled lunar
observations, we linked the artifacts with electronic crosstalk contamination
of the response of detector 1 of band 24 by signal sent from the detector 10 of
band 26 (1.375$\mu$m), a neighboring band in the same focal plane assembly. In
this paper, we report on these findings, the artifact mitigation strategy
adopted by us, and on our success in restoring band 24 detector 1 behavior and
image quality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07378</id><created>2017-03-18</created><updated>2017-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Varotsos</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlis</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skordas</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Natural Time Analysis of Seismicity in California: The epicenter of an
  impending mainshock</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>7 pages including 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Upon employing the analysis in a new time domain, termed natural time, it has
been recently demonstrated that a remarkable change of seismicity emerges
before major mainshocks in California. What constitutes this change is that the
fluctuations of the order parameter of seismicity exhibit a clearly detectable
minimum. This is identified by using a natural time window sliding event by
event through the time series of the earthquakes in a wide area and comprising
a number of events that would occur on the average within a few months or so.
Here, we suggest a method to estimate the epicentral area of an impending
mainshock by an additional study of this minimum using an area window sliding
through the wide area. We find that when this area window surrounds (or is
adjacent to) the future epicentral area, the minimum of the order parameter
fluctuations in this area appears at a date very close to the one at which the
minimum is observed in the wide area. The method is applied here to major
earthquakes that occurred in California during the recent decades including the
largest one, i.e., the 1992 Landers earthquake.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07837</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiaopeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Changbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Dechang</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimentally Study the Deep Dirac Levels with High-Intensity Lasers</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Various theories have predicted the deep Dirac levels (DDLs) in atoms for
many years. However, the existence of the DDL is still under debating, and need
to be confirmed experimentally. With the development of high intensive lasers,
nowadays, electrons can been accelerated to relativistic energy by high
intensive lasers, electron-positron pairs can be created, and nuclear reactions
can been ignited, which provide a new tool to explore the DDL related fields.
In this paper, we propose a new experimental method to study the DDL levels by
monitoring nuclei's orbital electron capture life time in plasma induced by
high intensive lasers. If a DDL exists, a nuclear electron capture rate could
be enhanced by factor of over $10^7$, which makes it practically detectable in
nowadays high intensive laser environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08174</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>Biswajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Anjana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roychoudhury</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative nonlinear waves in a gravitating quantum fluid</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear wave propagation is studied analytically in a dissipative,
self-gravitating Bose Einstein condensate, in the framework of Gross-Pitaevskii
model. The linear dispersion relation shows that the effect of dissipation is
to suppress dynamical instabilities that destabilize the system. The small
amplitude analysis using reductive perturbation technique is found to yield a
modified form of KdV equation. The soliton energy, amplitude and velocity are
found to decay with time, whereas the soliton width increases, such that the
soliton exists for a finite time only
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08176</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Straumann</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Einstein in 1916: &quot;On the Quantum Theory of Radiation&quot;</title><categories>physics.hist-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the Communications of the Swiss Physical Society, N
  r.51, Section: History of Physics, p.26 (2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this contribution I discuss a peak in Einstein's endeavor to extract as
much information as possible about the nature of radiation from the Planck
distribution is his paper &quot;On the Quantum Theory of Radiation&quot; of 1916. This is
one of the most important contributions of Einstein to quantum theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08177</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Shahverdyan</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Red'kov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishkhanyan</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Expansions of the solutions of the general Heun equation in terms of the
  incomplete Beta functions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1505.02178</comments><journal-ref>Nonlinear Phenomena in Complex Systems 19, 395-402 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Applying the approach based on the equation for the derivative, we construct
several expansions of the solutions of the general Heun equation in terms of
the incomplete Beta functions. Several expansions in terms of the Appell
generalized hypergeometric functions of two variables of the fist kind are also
presented. The constructed expansions are applicable for arbitrary sets of the
involved parameters. The coefficients of the expansions obey four-, five- or
six-term recurrence relations. However, there exist several sets of the
parameters for which the recurrence relations involve fewer terms, not
necessarily successive. The conditions for deriving finite-sum solutions via
termination of the series are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08183</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kakkad</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainieri</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brusa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padovani</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carniani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feruglio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sargent</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husemann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bongiorno</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonzini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piconcelli</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silverman</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rujopakarn</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>ALMA observations of cold molecular gas in AGN hosts at z~1.5 - Evidence
  of AGN feedback?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx726</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Similarly to the cosmic star formation history, the black hole accretion rate
density of the Universe peaked at 1&lt;z&lt;3. This cosmic epoch is hence best suited
for investigating the effects of radiative feedback from AGN. Observational
efforts are underway to quantify the impact of AGN feedback, if any, on their
host galaxies. Here we present a study of the molecular gas content of AGN
hosts at z~1.5 using CO[2-1] line emission observed with ALMA for a sample of
10 AGNs. We compare this with a sample of galaxies without an AGN matched in
redshift, stellar mass, and star formation rate. We detect CO in 3 AGNs with
$\mathrm{L_{CO} \sim 6.3-25.1\times 10^{9} L_{\odot}}$ which translates to a
molecular hydrogen gas mass of $\mathrm{2.5-10\times 10^{10} M_{\odot}}$
assuming conventional conversion factor of $\mathrm{\alpha_{CO}}\sim3.6$. Our
results indicate a &gt;99% probability of lower depletion time scales and lower
molecular gas fractions in AGN hosts with respect to the non-AGN comparison
sample. We discuss the implications of these observations on the impact that
AGN feedback may have on star formation efficiency of z&gt;1 galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08210</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Caciagli</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Darshana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotar</keyname><forenames>Jurij</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eiser</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical trapping of colloids at a liquid-liquid interface</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the realization of (laterally) optically bounded colloidal
structures on a liquid-liquid interface of an emulsion droplet. We use DNA
tethers to graft the particles to the droplet surface, effectively confining
them to a quasi-2D plane with minimum constraints on the lateral movement even
when optically trapped in a common single-beam configuration. We show that
relatively weak interactions such as depletion can be measured in the optically
bounded crystals by video-microscopy imaging and analysis. This illustrates the
possible use of our system as template to study optically controlled quasi
two-dimensional colloidal assembly on liquid-liquid interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08229</id><created>2017-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Fallica</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirchner</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mailly</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ekinci</keyname><forenames>Yasin</forenames></author></authors><title>A comparative study of resists and lithographic tools using the Lumped
  Parameter Model</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>EIPBN 2016 Conference</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology B, Nanotechnology and
  Microelectronics: Materials, Processing, Measurement, and Phenomena 34,
  06K702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1116/1.4967183</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A comparison of the performance of high resolution lithographic tools is
presented here. We use extreme ultraviolet interference lithography, electron
beam lithography, and He ion beam lithography tools on two different resists
that are processed under the same conditions. The dose-to-clear and the
lithographic contrast are determined experimentally and are used to compare the
relative efficiency of each tool. The results are compared to previous studies
and interpreted in the light of each tool-specific secondary electron yield. In
addition, the patterning performance is studied by exposing dense line/spaces
patterns and the relation between critical dimension and exposure dose is
discussed. Finally, the Lumped Parameter Model is employed in order to
quantitatively estimate the critical dimension of line/spaces, using each tool
specific aerial image. Our implementation is then validated by fitting the
model to the experimental data from interference lithography exposures, and
extracting the resist contrast.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08250</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Zimbovskaya</keyname><forenames>Natalya A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling of a self-sustaining ignition in a solid energetic material</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work we analyze some necessary conditions for ignition of
solid energetic materials by low velocity impact ignition mechanism. Basing on
reported results of {\it ab initio} computations we assume that the energetic
activation barriers for the primary endothermic dissociation in some energetic
materials may be locally lowered due to the effect of shear strain caused by
the impact. We show that the ignition may be initiated in regions with the
reduced activation barriers, even at moderately low exothermicity of the
subsequent exothermic reactions thus suggesting that the above regions may
serve as &quot;hot spots&quot; for the ignition. We apply our results to analyze initial
steps of ignition in DADNE and TATB molecular crystals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08259</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Moored</keyname><forenames>Keith W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unsteady three-dimensional boundary element method for self-propelled
  bio-inspired locomotion</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>24 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An unsteady three-dimensional boundary element method is developed to provide
fast calculations of biological and bio-inspired self-propelled locomotion. The
approach uniquely combines an unsteady three-dimensional boundary element
method, a boundary layer solver and self-propelled equations of motion. This
novel implementation allows for the self-propelled speed, power, efficiency and
economy to be accurately calculated. A Dirichlet formulation is used with a
combination of constant strength source and doublet elements to represent a
deforming body with a nonlinearly deforming wake. The wake elements are
desingularized to numerically stabilize the evolution of the wake vorticity.
Weak coupling is used in solving the equations of motion and in the boundary
layer solution. The boundary layer solver models both laminar and turbulent
behavior along the deforming body to estimate the total skin friction drag
acting on the body. The results from the method are validated with analytical
solutions, computations and experiments. Finally, a bio-inspired self-propelled
undulatory fin is modeled. The computed self-propelled speeds and wake
structures agree well with previous experiments. The computations go beyond the
experiments to gain further insight into the propulsive efficiency for
self-propelled undulating fins. It is found that the undulating fin produces a
time-averaged momentum jet at 76% of the span that accelerates fluid in the
streamwise direction and in turn generates thrust. Additionally, it is
discovered that high amplitude motions suppress the formation of a bifurcating
momentum jet and instead form a single core jet. Consequently, this maximizes
the amount of streamwise momentum compared to the amount of wasted lateral
momentum and leads to a propulsive efficiency of 78% during self-propelled
locomotion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08264</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Takahisa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ejiri</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akimune</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matumiya</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shima</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yosoi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double charge exchange ($^{11}$B,$^{11}$Li) reaction for double beta
  decay response</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ($^{11}$B,$^{11}$Li) double charge-exchange reaction (DCER) at
$E(^{11}$B)/$A$=80 MeV was measured for the first time to demonstrate the
feasibility of the reaction for studying neutrino nuclear responses for double
beta decays (DBD). The $^{13}$C($^{11}$B,$^{11}$Li)$^{13}$O reaction shows
strengths at the ground state and low and high excitation giant resonance
regions. The $^{56}$Fe ($^{11}$B,$^{11}$Li) $^{56}$Ni reaction shows the large
strengths in the possible double giant resonance region and beyond, but shows
no strengths in the low excitation region below 5 MeV, suggesting strong
concentration of the DBD strength at the high excitation region. The DCER is
used to evaluate the spin isospin strengths relevant to DBD responses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08276</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Boyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaikie</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic Gas Sensing based on Cavity-Coupled Metallic Nanoparticles</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we demonstrate the gas sensing ability of cavity-coupled metallic
nanoparticle systems, comprising gold nanoparticles separated from a gold
mirror with a polymer spacer. An increase in relative humidity (RH) causes the
spacer to expand, which induces a significant reduction of nanoparticle
scattering intensity, as the scattering is highly dependent on the
cavity-nanoparticle coupling that closely relates to the nanoparticle-mirror
distance. This lithography-free structure enables a remarkable averaging
sensitivity at 0.12 dB/% RH and 0.25 dB/% RH over RH range (45-75%), possessing
an estimated resolution better than 0.5% RH with full reversibility and almost
zero-hysteresis, exhibiting notable gas sensing potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08290</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jinn-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Dexuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenberg</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames></author></authors><title>Poisson-Fermi Formulation of Nonlocal Electrostatics in Electrolyte
  Solutions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a nonlocal electrostatic formulation of nonuniform ions and water
molecules with interstitial voids that uses a Fermi-like distribution to
account for steric and correlation effects in electrolyte solutions. The
formulation is based on the volume exclusion of hard spheres leading to a
steric potential and Maxwell's displacement field with Yukawa-type interactions
resulting in a nonlocal electric potential. The classical Poisson-Boltzmann
model fails to describe steric and correlation effects important in a variety
of chemical and biological systems, especially in high field or large
concentration conditions found in and near binding sites, ion channels, and
electrodes. Steric effects and correlations are apparent when we compare
nonlocal Poisson-Fermi results to Poisson-Boltzmann calculations in electric
double layer and to experimental measurements on the selectivity of potassium
channels for K+ over Na+. The present theory links atomic scale descriptions of
the crystallized KcsA channel with macroscopic bulk conditions. Atomic
structures and macroscopic conditions determine complex functions of great
importance in biology, nanotechnology, and electrochemistry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08296</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Eroglu</keyname><forenames>Deniz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamb</keyname><forenames>Jeroen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Tiago</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization of Chaos</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical networks are important models for the behaviour of complex systems,
modelling physical, biological and societal systems, including the brain, food
webs, epidemic disease in populations, power grids and many other. Such
dynamical networks can exhibit behaviour in which deterministic chaos,
exhibiting unpredictability and disorder, coexists with synchronization, a
classical paradigm of order. We survey the main theory behind complete,
generalized and phase synchronization phenomena in simple as well as complex
networks and discuss applications to secure communications, parameter
estimation and the anticipation of chaos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08299</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhatia</keyname><forenames>Disha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sabyasachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dighe</keyname><forenames>Amol</forenames></author></authors><title>Addressing $R_K$ and neutrino mixing in a class of $U(1)_X$ models</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, talk presented at the 9th International Workshop
  on the CKM Unitarity Triangle</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a class of minimal $U(1)_X$ models as a plausible solution to the
$R_K$ anomaly that can also help reproduce the neutrino mixing pattern. The
symmetries and the corresponding $X$-charges of the fields are determined in a
bottom-up approach demanding both theoretical and experimental consistencies.
The breaking of $U(1)_X$ symmetry results in a massive $Z^{\prime}$, whose
couplings with leptons and quarks are necessarily non-universal to address the
$R_K$ anomaly. In the process, an additional Higgs doublet is introduced to
generate quark mixings. The mixings in the neutrino sector are generated
through Type-I seesaw mechanism by the addition of three right handed neutrinos
and a scalar singlet. The $Z^{\prime}$ can be probed with a few hundred
fb$^{-1}$ of integrated luminosity at the 13 TeV LHC in the di-muon channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08310</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Piotrovich</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnedin</keyname><forenames>Yu. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natsvlishvili</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buliga</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization of broad line emission from AGNs with determined virial
  factors</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx568</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculated the polarization degree of hydrogen Balmer broad emission lines
from a number of active galactic nuclei (AGNs) with determined virial factors.
The objects were selected from the sample presented by Decarli et al.(2008). In
our calculations, we used the model of the flattened disc-like structure of the
broad-line emission region (BLR). In this model, the expression for the virial
factor makes it possible to determine the inclination angle for the flattened
BLR, which in turn yields the polarization degree of the broad emission lines.
As a result, we obtained the direct relation between the polarization degree
and the virial factor. We also compared the determined values of the
polarization degree with those obtained in polarimetric observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08333</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Romao</keyname><forenames>Miguel Crispim</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Stephen F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Starobinsky-like inflation in no-scale supergravity Wess-Zumino model
  with Polonyi term</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple modification of the no-scale supergravity Wess-Zumino
model of Starobinsky-like inflation to include a Polonyi term in the
superpotential. The purpose of this term is to provide an explicit mechanism
for supersymmetry breaking at the end of inflation. We show how successful
inflation can be achieved for a gravitino mass satisfying the strict upper
bound $m_{3/2}&lt; 10^3$ TeV, with favoured values $m_{3/2}\lesssim\mathcal{O}(1)$
TeV. The model suggests that SUSY may be discovered in collider physics
experiments such as the LHC or the FCC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08346</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucia</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability and area law for rapidly mixing quantum dissipative systems</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>PhD Thesis (Universidad Complutense de Madrid, July 2016). 87 pages.
  Same content in English and in Spanish. Chapters 4, 5 and 6 are not included,
  as they are the published versions of arXiv:1303.4744, arXiv:1409.7809,
  arXiv:1505.02776 (respectively)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this thesis we study properties of open quantum dissipative evolutions of
spin systems on lattices described by Lindblad generators, in a particular
regime that we denote rapid mixing. We consider dissipative evolutions with a
unique fixed point, and which compress the whole space of input states into
increasingly small neighborhoods of the fixed point. The time scale at which
this compression takes place, or in other words the time we have to wait for
any input state to become almost indistinguishable from the fixed point, is
called the mixing time of the process. Rapid mixing is a condition on the
scaling of this mixing time with the system size: if it is logarithmic, then we
have rapid mixing.
  The main contribution of this thesis is to show that rapid mixing has
profound implications for the corresponding system: it is stable against
external perturbations and its fixed point satisfies an area law for mutual
information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08391</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Vladimirov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ihle</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plakida</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin excitations and thermodynamics of the antiferromagnetic Heisenberg
  model on the layered honeycomb lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 90, 48 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-70720-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a spin-rotation-invariant Green-function theory for the dynamic
spin susceptibility in the spin-1/2 antiferromagnetic Heisenberg model on a
stacked honeycomb lattice. Employing a generalized mean-field approximation for
arbitrary temperatures, the thermodynamic quantities (two-spin correlation
functions, internal energy, magnetic susceptibility, staggered magnetization,
N'eel temperature, correlation length) and the spin-excitation spectrum are
calculated by solving a coupled system of self-consistency equations for the
correlation functions. The temperature dependence of the magnetic (uniform
static) susceptibility is ascribed to antiferromagnetic short-range order. The
N\'{e}el temperature is calculated for arbitrary interlayer couplings. Our
results are in a good agreement with numerical computations for finite clusters
and with available experimental data on the \beta-Cu2V2O2 compound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08400</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Los</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fasolino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanics of thermally fluctuating membranes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>to appear in npj 2D Materials and Applications</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Besides having unique electronic properties, graphene is claimed to be the
strongest material in nature. In the press release of the Nobel committee it is
claimed that a hammock made of a squared meter of one-atom thick graphene could
sustain the wight of a 4 kg cat. More practically important are applications of
graphene like scaffolds and sensors which are crucially dependent on the
mechanical strength. Meter-sized graphene is even being considered for the
lightsails in the starshot project to reach the star alpha centaury. The
predicted strength of graphene is based on its very large Young modulus which
is, per atomic layer, much larger than that of steel. This reasoning however
would apply to conventional thin plates but does not take into account the
peculiar properties of graphene as a thermally fluctuating crystalline
membrane. It was shown recently both experimentally and theoretically that
thermal fluctuations lead to a dramatic reduction of the Young modulus and
increase of the bending rigidity for micron-sized graphene samples in
comparison with atomic scale values. This makes the use of the standard
F\&quot;oppl-von Karman elasticity (FvK) theory for thin plates not directly
applicable to graphene and other single atomic layer membranes. This fact is
important because the current interpretation of experimental results is based
on the FvK theory. In particular, we show that the FvK-derived Schwerin
equation, routinely used to derive the Young modulus from indentation
experiments has to be essentially modified for graphene at room temperature and
for micron sized samples. Based on scaling analysis and atomistic simulation we
investigate the mechanics of graphene under transverse load up to breaking. We
determine the limits of applicability of the FvK theory and provide
quantitative estimates for the different regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08422</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Leksin</keyname><forenames>Pavel V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamashev</keyname><forenames>Andrey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataev</keyname><forenames>Vladislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gemming</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chner</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garifullin</keyname><forenames>Ilgiz A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the degree of spin polarization of a ferromagnet with
  ferromagnet/superconductor proximity effect</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>submitted to Nano Research</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconductor/ferromagnet proximity effect has been studied for
Pb/Co$_2$Cr$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$Al bilayers. Different substrate temperatures allowed
us to prepare the Heusler alloy Co$_2$Cr$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$Al films with different
degree of spin polarization of conduction band of the Heusler layer. We obtain
a strong correlation between the dependence of the superconducting transition
temperature on the Pb-layer thickness at fixed thickness of the Heusler layer
and the degree of spin polarization in the ferromagnetic layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08424</id><created>2017-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author></authors><title>Green Function Theory of Strongly Correlated Electron Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel effective Hamiltonian in the subspace of singly occupied states is
obtained by applying the Gutzwiller projection approach to a generalized
Hubbard model with the interactions between two nearest- neighbor sites. This
model provides a more complete description of the physics of strongly
correlated electron systems. The system is not necessarily in a ferromagnetic
state as temperature approaches zero at any doping level. The system, however,
must be in an antiferromagnetic state at the origin of the doping-temperature
plane. Moreover, the model exhibits superconductivity in a doped region at
sufficiently low temperatures. We summarize the studies and provide a phase
diagram of the antiferromagnetism and the superconductivity of the model in the
doping-temperature plane here. Details will be presented in subsequent papers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08443</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bergeron</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curado</keyname><forenames>Evaldo M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gazeau</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Ligia M. C. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Weyl-Heisenberg integral quantization(s): a compendium</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>50 pages</comments><msc-class>81S05, 81R10, 81S30, 81R30, 76M60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a list of formulae useful for Weyl-Heisenberg integral
quantizations, with arbitrary weight, of functions or distributions on the
plane. Most of these formulae are known, others are original. The list
encompasses particular cases like Weyl-Wigner quantization (constant weight)
and coherent states (CS) or Berezin quantization (Gaussian weight). The
formulae are given with implicit assumptions on their validity on appropriate
space(s) of functions (or distributions). One of the aims of the document is to
accompany a work in progress on Weyl-Heisenberg integral quantization of
dynamics for the motion of a point particle on the line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08449</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ishkhanyan</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krainov</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Maslov index for power-law potentials</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>JETP Lett. 105, 43-46 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364017010106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Maslov index in the semiclassical Bohr-Sommerfeld quantization rule is
calculated for one-dimensional power-law potentials. The result for the inverse
square root potential is compared with the recently reported exact solution.
The case of a spherically symmetric power-law potential is also considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08484</id><created>2017-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Jechow</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koll&#xe1;th</keyname><forenames>Zolt&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lerner</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;nel</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shashar</keyname><forenames>Nadav</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;lker</keyname><forenames>Franz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyba</keyname><forenames>Christopher C. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring Light Pollution with Fisheye Lens Imagery from A Moving Boat,
  A Proof of Concept</title><categories>q-bio.OT astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, accepted at International Journal of Sustainable
  Lighting</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Near all-sky imaging photometry was performed from a boat on the Gulf of
Aqaba to measure the night sky brightness in a coastal environment. The boat
was not anchored, and therefore drifted and rocked. The camera was mounted on a
tripod without any inertia/motion stabilization. A commercial digital single
lens reflex (DSLR) camera and fisheye lens were used with ISO setting of 6400,
with the exposure time varied between 0.5 s and 5 s. We find that despite
movement of the vessel the measurements produce quantitatively comparable
results apart from saturation effects. We discuss the potential and limitations
of this method for mapping light pollution in marine and freshwater systems.
This work represents the proof of concept that all-sky photometry with a
commercial DSLR camera is a viable tool to determine light pollution in an
ecological context from a moving boat.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08488</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Landowski</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zepp</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wingerter</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Freymann</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widera</keyname><forenames>Artur</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct laser written polymer waveguides with out of plane couplers for
  optical chips</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical technologies call for waveguide networks featuring high integration
densities, low losses, and simple operation. Here, we present polymer
waveguides fabricated from a negative tone photoresist via
two-photon-lithography in direct laser writing, and show a detailed parameter
study of their performance. Specifically, we produce waveguides featuring bend
radii down to 40 {\mu}m, insertion losses of the order of 10 dB, and loss
coefficients smaller than 0.81 dB/mm, facilitating high integration densities
in writing fields of 300 {\mu}m x 300 {\mu}m. A novel three-dimensional coupler
design allows for coupling control as well as direct observation of outputs in
a single field of view through a microscope objective. Finally, we present
beam-splitting devices to construct larger optical networks, and we show that
the waveguide material is compatible with the integration of quantum emitters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08491</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Candy</keyname><forenames>Adam S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A consistent approach to unstructured mesh generation for geophysical
  models</title><categories>physics.geo-ph cs.CG physics.ao-ph physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>22 pages, 15 figures, 1 table. Submitted for publication and under
  review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geophysical model domains typically contain irregular, complex fractal-like
boundaries and physical processes that act over a wide range of scales.
Constructing geographically constrained boundary-conforming spatial
discretizations of these domains with flexible use of anisotropically, fully
unstructured meshes is a challenge. The problem contains a wide range of scales
and a relatively large, heterogeneous constraint parameter space. Approaches
are commonly ad hoc, model or application specific and insufficiently
described. Development of new spatial domains is frequently time-consuming,
hard to repeat, error prone and difficult to ensure consistent due to the
significant human input required. As a consequence, it is difficult to
reproduce simulations, ensure a provenance in model data handling and
initialization, and a challenge to conduct model intercomparisons rigorously.
Moreover, for flexible unstructured meshes, there is additionally a greater
potential for inconsistencies in model initialization and forcing parameters.
This paper introduces a consistent approach to unstructured mesh generation for
geophysical models, that is automated, quick-to-draft and repeat, and provides
a rigorous and robust approach that is consistent to the source data
throughout. The approach is enabling further new research in complex
multi-scale domains, difficult or not possible to achieve with existing
methods. Examples being actively pursued in a range of geophysical modeling
efforts are presented alongside the approach, together with the implementation
library Shingle and a selection of its verification test cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08494</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Contopoulos</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzemos</keyname><forenames>Athanasios C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efthymiopoulos</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial Integrability of 3-d Bohmian Trajectories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 3 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa685d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the integrability of 3-d Bohmian trajectories of a
system of quantum harmonic oscillators. We show that the initial choice of
quantum numbers is responsible for the existence (or not) of an integral of
motion which confines the trajectories on certain invariant surfaces. We give a
few examples of orbits in cases where there is or there is not an integral and
make some comments on the impact of partial integrability in Bohmian Mechanics.
Finally, we make a connection between our present results for the integrability
in the 3-d case and analogous results found in the 2-d and 4-d cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08499</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gresnigt</keyname><forenames>Niels G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillard</keyname><forenames>Adam B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic moments of octet baryons with deformed Uq(su(3)) flavor
  symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of a q-deformation of flavor symmetry on octet baryon magnetic
moments is investigated by taking the quantum group Uq(su(3)) as a flavor
symmetry and calculating expressions for the magnetic moments of the octet
baryons. Using the experimental values for the magnetic moments of the proton,
neutron, and Lambda baryons as input, the magnetic moments of the up, down, and
strange quarks, and by extension those of the remaining octet baryons, depend
on the value of the deformation parameter q. Plotting the least square error as
a function of q we find the undeformed value q=1 is a local maximum. Nearby are
a relative minimum (at q=0.610) and an absolute minimum (at q=1.774). The value
q=1.774 gives an approximately 10% decrease in the least square error compared
to the undeformed case. For this value of q the quark masses of the up and down
quarks are calculated to be 331 MeV and 305 MeV respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08504</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Candy</keyname><forenames>Adam S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietrzak</keyname><forenames>Julie D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shingle 2.0: generalising self-consistent and automated domain
  discretisation for multi-scale geophysical models</title><categories>physics.geo-ph cs.CG physics.ao-ph physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures, 1 table. Submitted for publication and under
  review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The approaches taken to describe and develop spatial discretisations of the
domains required for geophysical simulation models are commonly ad hoc, model
or application specific and under-documented. This is particularly acute for
simulation models that are flexible in their use of multi-scale, anisotropic,
fully unstructured meshes where a relatively large number of heterogeneous
parameters are required to constrain their full description. As a consequence,
it can be difficult to reproduce simulations, ensure a provenance in model data
handling and initialisation, and a challenge to conduct model intercomparisons
rigorously. This paper takes a novel approach to spatial discretisation,
considering it much like a numerical simulation model problem of its own. It
introduces a generalised, extensible, self-documenting approach to carefully
describe, and necessarily fully, the constraints over the heterogeneous
parameter space that determine how a domain is spatially discretised. This
additionally provides a method to accurately record these constraints, using
high-level natural language based abstractions, that enables full accounts of
provenance, sharing and distribution. Together with this description, a
generalised consistent approach to unstructured mesh generation for geophysical
models is developed, that is automated, robust and repeatable, quick-to-draft,
rigorously verified and consistent to the source data throughout. This
interprets the description above to execute a self-consistent spatial
discretisation process, which is automatically validated to expected discrete
characteristics and metrics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08508</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Vidick</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Parallel DIQKD from parallel repetition</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an arguably simpler and more direct proof of a recent result by
Miller, Jain and Shi, who proved device-independent security of a protocol for
quantum key distribution in which the devices can be used in parallel. Our
proof combines existing results on immunization (Kempe et al., SICOMP 2011) and
parallel repetition (Bavarian et al., STOC 2017) of entangled games.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08530</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rezaev</keyname><forenames>Roman O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levchenko</keyname><forenames>Evgenii A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimm</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Oliver G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting Micro- and Nanohelices</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>27 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconducting micro- and nanohelices are proposed for the first time. A
theoretical investigation of the superconducting state in the helical coils at
the micro- and nanoscale is performed within the time-dependent Ginzburg-Landau
approach. The pattern and number of vortices in a stationary distribution are
determined by their confinement to the ultrathin helical spiral and can
therefore be efficiently controlled by the helical stripe width and the helical
pitch distance for both dense and sparse helices. Quasi-degeneracy of vortex
patterns is manifested in the helical spiral when the number of vortices is
incommensurable with the total number of half-turns. With increasing radius,
superconducting helical spirals provide a physical realization of a transition
from the vortex pattern peculiar to an open tube to that of a planar stripe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08536</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Barachati</keyname><forenames>F&#xe1;bio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Janos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Getmanenko</keyname><forenames>Yulia A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Getmanenko</keyname><forenames>Yulia A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marder</keyname><forenames>Seth R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe9;na-Cohen</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable third-harmonic generation from polaritons in the ultrastrong
  coupling regime</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.quant-gas physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong inter-particle interactions between polaritons have traditionally
stemmed from their exciton component. In this work, we impart a strong photonic
nonlinearity to a polaritonic mode by embedding a nonlinear polymethine dye
within a high-Q all-metal microcavity. We demonstrate nonlinear microcavities
operating in the ultrastrong coupling regime with a normalized coupling ratio
of 62\%, the highest reported to date. When pumping the lower polariton branch,
we observe tunable third-harmonic generation spanning the entire visible
spectrum, with internal conversion enhancements more than three orders of
magnitude larger than in bare films. Transfer matrix calculations indicate that
the observed enhancements are consistent with the enhanced pump electric field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0511211</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-03-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0511211</id><created>2005-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Dengke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheffler</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>Mats</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum size effect in Pb(100) films: the role of symmetry and
  implication for film growth</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev B. 74, 113401 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.74.113401</doi><abstract>  We show from density-functional calculations that Pb(100) thin films exhibit
quantum size effect with a bilayer periodicity in film energies, film
relaxations, and work functions, which originate from different symmetry of the
stacking geometry of odd and even layer films. The bilayer periodicity of the
film energy is argued to survive on a semiconductor substrate, which should
allow the growth of ``magically'' thick even-layer Pb(100) films. Furthermore,
it is found that the quantum well states in a simple metal film can be
classified into $\sigma$-bonded and $\pi$-bonded states, which quantize
independently.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
