<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:09:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-05-02" from="2016-05-01" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1003.4486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1003.4486</id><created>2010-03-23</created><updated>2010-09-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardner</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiderlen</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase retrieval for characteristic functions of convex bodies and
  reconstruction from covariograms</title><categories>math.MG physics.data-an</categories><comments>Version accepted on the Journal of the American Mathematical Society.
  With respect to version 1 the noise model has been greatly extended and an
  appendix has been added, with a discussion of rates of convergence and
  implementation issues. 56 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>42-04, 42B10, 52-04, 52A20 (Primary), 52B11 62H35 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of the American Math. Soc. 24 (2011), 293-343</journal-ref><doi>10.1090/S0894-0347-2010-00683-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose strongly consistent algorithms for reconstructing the
characteristic function 1_K of an unknown convex body K in R^n from possibly
noisy measurements of the modulus of its Fourier transform \hat{1_K}. This
represents a complete theoretical solution to the Phase Retrieval Problem for
characteristic functions of convex bodies. The approach is via the closely
related problem of reconstructing K from noisy measurements of its covariogram,
the function giving the volume of the intersection of K with its translates. In
the many known situations in which the covariogram determines a convex body, up
to reflection in the origin and when the position of the body is fixed, our
algorithms use O(k^n) noisy covariogram measurements to construct a convex
polytope P_k that approximates K or its reflection -K in the origin. (By recent
uniqueness results, this applies to all planar convex bodies, all
three-dimensional convex polytopes, and all symmetric and most (in the sense of
Baire category) arbitrary convex bodies in all dimensions.) Two methods are
provided, and both are shown to be strongly consistent, in the sense that,
almost surely, the minimum of the Hausdorff distance between P_k and K or -K
tends to zero as k tends to infinity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.4304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.4304</id><created>2012-04-19</created><updated>2012-05-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanczuk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author></authors><title>Active Brownian particles with velocity-alignment and active
  fluctuations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 figures, 22 pages, submitted to New Journal of Physics</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 14 (2012) 073033</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/14/7/073033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a model of active Brownian particles with velocity-alignment in
two spatial dimensions with passive and active fluctuations. Hereby, active
fluctuations refers to purely non-equilibrium stochastic forces correlated with
the heading of an individual active particle. In the simplest case studied
here, they are assumed as independent stochastic forces parallel (speed noise)
and perpendicular (angular noise) to the velocity of the particle. On the other
hand, passive fluctuations are defined by a noise vector independent of the
direction of motion of a particle, and may account for example for thermal
fluctuations.
  We derive a macroscopic description of the active Brownian particle gas with
velocity-alignment interaction. Hereby, we start from the individual based
description in terms of stochastic differential equations (Langevin equations)
and derive equations of motion for the coarse grained kinetic variables
(density, velocity and temperature) via a moment expansion of the corresponding
probability density function.
  We focus here in particular on the different impact of active and passive
fluctuations on the onset of collective motion and show how active fluctuations
in the active Brownian dynamics can change the phase-transition behaviour of
the system. In particular, we show that active angular fluctuation lead to an
earlier breakdown of collective motion and to emergence of a new bistable
regime in the mean-field case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.5890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.5890</id><created>2013-01-24</created><updated>2013-04-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanczuk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-propelled particles with selective attraction-repulsion interaction
  - From microscopic dynamics to coarse-grained theories</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>revised version, 37pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 15 (2013) 085014</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/15/8/085014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we derive and analyze coarse-grained descriptions of
self-propelled particles with selective attraction-repulsion interaction, where
individuals may respond differently to their neighbours depending on their
relative state of motion (approach versus movement away). Based on the
formulation of a nonlinear Fokker-Planck equation, we derive a kinetic
description of the system dynamics in terms of equations for the Fourier modes
of a one-particle density function. This approach allows effective numerical
investigation of the stability of possible solutions of the system. The
detailed analysis of the interaction integrals entering the equations
demonstrates that divergences at small wavelengths can appear at arbitrary
expansion orders.
  Further on, we also derive a hydrodynamic theory by performing a closure at
the level of the second Fourier mode of the one-particle density function. We
show that the general form of equations is in agreement with the theory
formulated by Toner and Tu.
  Finally, we compare our analytical predictions on the stability of the
disordered homogeneous solution with results of individual-based simulations.
They show good agreement for sufficiently large densities and non-negligible
short-ranged repulsion. Disagreements of numerical results and the hydrodynamic
theory for weak short-ranged repulsion reveal the existence of a previously
unknown phase of the model consisting of dense, nematically aligned filaments,
which cannot be accounted for by the present Toner and Tu type theory of polar
active matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.5454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.5454</id><created>2013-08-25</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sontz</keyname><forenames>Stephen Bruce</forenames></author></authors><title>Toeplitz Quantization for Non-commutating Symbol Spaces such as
  $SU_q(2)$</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.OA quant-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, a new title and a new example using the quantum group
  $SU_q(2)$</comments><msc-class>47B35, 81S99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Toeplitz quantization is defined in a general setting in which the symbols
are the elements of a possibly non-commutative algebra with a conjugation and a
possibly degenerate inner product. We show that the quantum group $SU_q(2)$ is
such an algebra. Unlike many quantization schemes, this Toeplitz quantization
does not require a measure. The theory is based on the mathematical structures
defined and studied in several recent papers of the author; those papers dealt
with some specific examples of this new Toeplitz quantization. Annihilation and
creation operators are defined as densely defined Toeplitz operators acting in
a quantum Hilbert space, and their commutation relations are discussed. At this
point Planck's constant is introduced into the theory. Due to the possibility
of non-commuting symbols, there are now two definitions for anti-Wick
quantization; these two definitions are equivalent in the commutative case. The
Toeplitz quantization introduced here satisfies one of these definitions, but
not necessarily the other. This theory should be considered as a second
quantization, since it quantizes non-commutative (that is, already quantum)
objects. The quantization theory presented here has two essential features of a
physically useful quantization: Planck's constant and a Hilbert space where
natural, densely defined operators act.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7762</id><created>2014-01-30</created><updated>2016-02-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Imai</keyname><forenames>Shotaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suganuma</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-perturbative Analysis of Various Mass Generation by Gluonic Dressing
  Effect with the Schwinger-Dyson Formalism in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>J.Mod.Phys. 7 (2016) 790-805</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jmp.2016.78073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As a topic of &quot;quantum color dynamics&quot;, we study various mass generation of
colored particles and gluonic dressing effect in a non-perturbative manner,
using the Schwinger-Dyson (SD) formalism in (scalar) QCD. First, we review
dynamical quark-mass generation in QCD in the SD approach as a typical
fermion-mass generation via spontaneous chiral-symmetry breaking. Second, using
the SD formalism for scalar QCD, we investigate the scalar diquark, a
bound-state-like object of two quarks, and its mass generation, which is
clearly non-chiral-origin. Here, the scalar diquark is treated as an extended
colored scalar field, like a meson in effective hadron models, and its
effective size $R$ is introduced as a form factor. As a diagrammatical
difference, the SD equation for the scalar diquark has an additional 4-point
interaction term, in comparison with the single quark case. The diquark size
$R$ is taken to be smaller than a hadron, $R\sim 1$ fm, and larger than a
constituent quark, $R\sim 0.3$ fm. We find that the compact diquark with
$R\simeq 0.3$ fm has a large effective mass of about 900 MeV, and therefore
such a compact diquark is not acceptable in effective models for hadrons. We
also consider the artificial removal of 3- and 4-point interaction,
respectively, to see the role of each term, and find that the 4-point
interaction plays the dominant role of the diquark self-energy. From the above
two different cases, quarks and diquarks, we guess that the mass generation of
colored particles is a general result of non-perturbative gluonic dressing
effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.3816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.3816</id><created>2014-03-15</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carlen</keyname><forenames>Eric A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lieb</keyname><forenames>Elliott H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuvers</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy and entanglement bounds for reduced density matrices of
  fermionic states</title><categories>math.OA quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages. This version of the paper is a substantial revision of the
  previous version</comments><msc-class>81V99, 82B10, 94A17</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike bosons, fermions always have a non-trivial entanglement. Intuitively,
Slater determinantal states should be the least entangled states. To make this
intuition precise we investigate entropy and entanglement of fermionic states
and prove some extremal and near extremal properties of reduced density
matrices of Slater determinantal states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.7111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.7111</id><created>2014-04-28</created><updated>2014-05-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanczuk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;r</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex arrays and meso-scale turbulence of self-propelled particles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 113 (2014) 258104</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.258104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by the Turing mechanism for pattern formation, we propose a simple
self-propelled particle model with short-ranged alignment and anti-alignment at
larger distances. It is able to produce orientationally ordered states,
periodic vortex patterns as well as meso-scale turbulence. The latter phase
resembles observations in dense bacterial suspensions. The model allows a
systematic derivation and analysis of a kinetic theory as well as hydrodynamic
equations for density and momentum fields. A phase diagram with regions of such
pattern formation as well as spatially homogeneous orientational order and
disorder is obtained from a linear stability analysis of these continuum
equations. Microscopic Langevin simulations of the self-propelled particle
system are in agreement with these findings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.6563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.6563</id><created>2014-08-27</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>Rasmus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuryak</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical interactions of the instanton-dyons with antidyons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. A {\bf 950}, 110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.03.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Instanton-dyons, also known as instanton-monopoles or instanton-quarks, are
topological constituents of the instantons at nonzero temperature and nonzero
expectation value of $A_4$. While the interaction between instanton-dyons has
been calculated to one-loop order by a number of authors, that for
dyon-antidyon pairs remains unknown even at the classical level. In this work
we are filling this gap, by solving the gradient flow equation on a 3d lattice.
We start with two well separated objects. We find that, after initial rapid
relaxation, the configurations follow &quot;streamline&quot; set of configurations, which
is basically independent on the initial configurations used. In striking
difference to instanton-antiinstanton streamlines, in this case it ends at a
quasi-stationary configuration, with an abrupt drop to perturbative fields. We
parameterize the action of the streamline configurations, which is to be used
in future many-body calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.05672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.05672</id><created>2015-01-22</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Simanek</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>An Electrostatic Interpretation of the Zeros of Paraorthogonal
  Polynomials on the Unit Circle</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures; version 2: Scope of Theorem 1.2 expanded, minor
  revisions throughout, references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that if m is a probability measure with infinite support on the unit
circle having no singular component and a differentiable weight, then the
corresponding paraorthogonal polynomial P_n(z;B) solves an explicit second
order linear differential equation. We also show that if T and B are distinct,
then the pair {P_n(z;B),P_n(z;T)} solves an explicit first order linear system
of differential equations. One can use these differential equations to deduce
that the zeros of every paraorthogonal polynomial mark the locations of a set
of particles that are in electrostatic equilibrium with respect to a particular
external field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.04975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.04975</id><created>2015-02-17</created><updated>2016-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Metcalf</keyname><forenames>Mekena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chern</keyname><forenames>Gia-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Ventra</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chien</keyname><forenames>Chih-Chun</forenames></author></authors><title>Matter-wave propagation in optical lattices: geometrical and flat-band
  effects</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><report-no>LA-UR-15-21107</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49, 075301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/7/075301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The geometry of optical lattices can be engineered allowing the study of
atomic transport along paths arranged in patterns that are otherwise difficult
to probe in the solid state. A question readily accessible to atomic systems is
related to the speed of propagation of matter-waves as a function of the
lattice geometry. To address this issue, we have investigated theoretically the
quantum transport of non-interacting and weakly-interacting ultracold fermionic
atoms in several 2D optical lattice geometries. We find that the triangular
lattice has a higher propagation velocity compared to the square lattice,
despite supporting longer paths. The body-centered square lattice has even
longer paths, nonetheless the propagation velocity is yet faster. This apparent
paradox arises from the mixing of the momentum states which leads to different
group velocities in quantum systems. Standard band theory provides an
explanation and allows for a systematic way to search and design systems with
controllable matter-wave propagation. Moreover, the presence of a flat band
such as in a two-leg ladder geometry leads to a dynamical density
discontinuity, which contrasts the behavior of mobile and localized atoms in
quantum transport. Our predictions are realizable with present experimental
capability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03451</id><created>2015-03-11</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Exponential Family Models from Bayes' Theorem under Expectation
  Constraints</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that a consistent application of Bayesian updating from a prior
probability density to a posterior using evidence in the form of expectation
constraints leads to exactly the same results as the application of the maximum
entropy principle, namely a posterior belonging to the exponential family. The
Bayesian updating procedure presented in this work is not expressed as a
variational principle, and does not involve the concept of entropy. Therefore
it conceptually constitutes a complete alternative to entropic methods of
inference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06807</id><created>2015-03-23</created><updated>2015-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gerosa</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veronesi</keyname><forenames>Benedetta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lodato</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosotti</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin alignment and differential accretion in merging black hole binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables. MNRAS accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. Roy. Astron. Soc. 451 (2015) 3941-3954</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1214</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interactions between a supermassive black hole binary and the surrounding
accretion disc can both assist the binary inspiral and align the black hole
spins to the disc angular momentum. While binary migration is due to
angular-momentum transfer within the circumbinary disc, the spin-alignment
process is driven by the mass accreting on to each black hole. Mass transfer
between different disc components thus couples the inspiral and the alignment
process together. Mass is expected to leak through the cavity cleared by the
binary, and preferentially accretes on to the lighter (secondary) black hole
which orbits closer to the disc edge. Low accretion rate on to the heavier
(primary) black hole slows the alignment process down. We revisit the problem
and develop a semi-analytical model to describe the coupling between gas-driven
inspiral and spin alignment, finding that binaries with mass ratio q&lt;~0.2
approach the gravitational-wave driven inspiral in differential misalignment:
light secondaries prevent primaries from aligning. Binary black holes with
misaligned primaries are ideal candidates for precession effects in the
strong-gravity regime and may suffer from moderately large (~1500 km/s) recoil
velocities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08236</id><created>2015-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>C</keyname><forenames>David J. Fernandez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex oscillator and Painlev\'e IV equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 359 (2015) 213-229</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2015.04.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetric quantum mechanics is a powerful tool for generating exactly
solvable potentials departing from a given initial one. In this article the
first- and second- order supersymmetric transformations will be used to obtain
new exactly solvable potentials departing from the complex oscillator. The
corresponding Hamiltonians turn out to be ruled by polynomial Heisenberg
algebras. By applying a mechanism to reduce to second the order of these
algebras, the connection with the Painlev\'{e} IV equation is achieved, thus
giving place to new solutions for the Painlev\'{e} IV equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01368</id><created>2015-04-06</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kleineberg</keyname><forenames>Kaj-Kolja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boguna</keyname><forenames>Marian</forenames></author></authors><title>Competition between global and local online social networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>Supplementary Material is available at:
  http://www.nature.com/article-assets/npg/srep/2016/160427/srep25116/extref/srep25116-s3.pdf
  See videos at https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z3dP3PD7ueA and
  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XkZTxnJd-eI</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 25116 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep25116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The overwhelming success of online social networks, the key actors in the Web
2.0 cosmos, has reshaped human interactions globally. To help understand the
fundamental mechanisms which determine the fate of online social networks at
the system level, we describe the digital world as a complex ecosystem of
interacting networks. In this paper, we study the impact of heterogeneity in
network fitnesses on the competition between an international network, such as
Facebook, and local services. The higher fitness of international networks is
induced by their ability to attract users from all over the world, which can
then establish social interactions without the limitations of local networks.
In other words, inter-country social ties lead to increased fitness of the
international network. To study the competition between an international
network and local ones, we construct a 1:1000 scale model of the digital world,
consisting of the 80 countries with the most Internet users. Under certain
conditions, this leads to the extinction of local networks; whereas under
different conditions, local networks can persist and even dominate completely.
In particular, our model suggests that, with the parameters that best reproduce
the empirical overtake of Facebook, this overtake could have not taken place
with a significant probability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03034</id><created>2015-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gro&#xdf;mann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanczuk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;r</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author></authors><title>Pattern formation in active particle systems due to competing alignment
  interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.other</categories><comments>23 pages, 13 figures, submitted to EPJST</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J.: Spec. Top. 224 (2015) 1325-1347</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2015-02462-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, we proposed a self-propelled particle model with competing
alignment interactions: nearby particles tend to align their velocities whereas
they anti-align their direction of motion with particles which are further away
[R. Grossmann et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 258104 (2014)]. Here, we extend our
previous numerical analysis of the high density regime considering low particle
densities too. We report on the emergence of various macroscopic patterns such
as vortex arrays, mesoscale turbulence as well as the formation of polar
clusters, polar bands and nematically ordered states. Furthermore, we study
analytically the instabilities leading to pattern formation in mean-field
approximation. We argue that these instabilities are well described by a
reduced set of hydrodynamic equations in the limit of high density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05923</id><created>2015-03-18</created><updated>2015-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grandou</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal ground state and nonthermal probes</title><categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, no figures, v2: moderate changes in text</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics Volume 2015 (2015), Article ID
  197197</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Euclidean formulation of SU(2) Yang-Mills thermodynamics admits periodic,
(anti)selfdual solutions to the fundamental, classical equation of motion which
possess one unit of topological charge: (anti)calorons. A spatial coarse
graining over the central region in a pair of such localised field
configurations with trivial holonomy generates an inert adjoint scalar field
$\phi$, effectively describing the pure quantum part of the thermal ground
state in the induced quantum field theory. Here we show for the limit of zero
holonomy how (anti)calorons associate a temperature independent electric
permittivity and magnetic permeability to the thermal ground state of
SU(2)$_{\tiny\mbox{CMB}}$, the Yang-Mills theory conjectured to underlie photon
propagation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07462</id><created>2015-05-27</created><updated>2015-09-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Horbatsch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Hector O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerosa</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berti</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gualtieri</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperhake</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Tensor-multi-scalar theories: relativistic stars and 3+1 decomposition</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>32 pages, 8 figures, 1 table, invited contribution to the Classical
  and Quantum Gravity Focus Issue &quot;Black holes and fundamental fields&quot;. v3:
  version in press in CQG, with various improvements in response to the
  referees' comments. In particular, the 3+1 decomposition now allows for
  matter</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 32, 20, 204001 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/32/20/204001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitational theories with multiple scalar fields coupled to the metric and
each other --- a natural extension of the well studied single-scalar-tensor
theories --- are interesting phenomenological frameworks to describe deviations
from general relativity in the strong-field regime. In these theories, the
$N$-tuple of scalar fields takes values in a coordinate patch of an
$N$-dimensional Riemannian target-space manifold whose properties are poorly
constrained by weak-field observations. Here we introduce for simplicity a
non-trivial model with two scalar fields and a maximally symmetric target-space
manifold. Within this model we present a preliminary investigation of
spontaneous scalarization for relativistic, perfect fluid stellar models in
spherical symmetry. We find that the scalarization threshold is determined by
the eigenvalues of a symmetric scalar-matter coupling matrix, and that the
properties of strongly scalarized stellar configurations additionally depend on
the target-space curvature radius. In preparation for numerical relativity
simulations, we also write down the $3+1$ decomposition of the field equations
for generic tensor-multi-scalar theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01191</id><created>2015-06-03</created><updated>2016-02-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>S. McKeown</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamai</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ristic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>F. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Torre</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricc&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plumb</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hlawenka</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Barriga</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varykhalov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoesch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>P. D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meevasana</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diebold</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesot</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moritz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devereaux</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radovic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumberger</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tailoring the nature and strength of electron-phonon interactions in the
  SrTiO$_3$(001) two-dimensional electron liquid</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Nature Materials (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4623</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surfaces and interfaces offer new possibilities for tailoring the many-body
interactions that dominate the electrical and thermal properties of transition
metal oxides. Here, we use the prototypical two-dimensional electron liquid
(2DEL) at the SrTiO$_3$(001) surface to reveal a remarkably complex evolution
of electron-phonon coupling with the tunable carrier density of this system. At
low density, where superconductivity is found in the analogous 2DEL at the
LaAlO$_3$/SrTiO$_3$ interface, our angle-resolved photoemission data show
replica bands separated by 100\,meV from the main bands. This is a hallmark of
a coherent polaronic liquid and implies strong long-range coupling to a single
longitudinal optical phonon mode. In the overdoped regime the preferential
coupling to this mode decreases and the 2DEL undergoes a crossover to a more
conventional metallic state with weaker short-range electron-phonon
interaction. These results place constraints on the theoretical description of
superconductivity and allow for a unified understanding of the transport
properties in SrTiO$_3$-based 2DELs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07157</id><created>2015-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ki Youl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beha</keyname><forenames>Katja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Daniel C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Xu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del'Haye</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hansuek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Dong Yoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diddams</keyname><forenames>Scott A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papp</keyname><forenames>Scott B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vahala</keyname><forenames>Kerry J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Broadband dispersion engineered microresonator on-a-chip</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 10 (5), pp.316 - 320, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2016.36</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Control of dispersion in fibre optical waveguides is of critical importance
to optical fibre communications systems and more recently for continuum
generation from the ultraviolet to the mid-infrared. The wavelength at which
the group velocity dispersion crosses zero can be set by varying fibre core
diameter or index step. Moreover, sophisticated methods to manipulate
higher-order dispersion so as shape and even flatten dispersion over wide
bandwidths are possible using multi-cladding fibre. Here we introduce design
and fabrication techniques that allow analogous dispersion control in
chip-integrated optical microresonators, and thereby demonstrate higher-order,
wide-bandwidth dispersion control over an octave of spectrum. Importantly, the
fabrication method we employ for dispersion control simultaneously permits
optical Q factors above 100 million, which is critical for efficient operation
of nonlinear optical oscillators. Dispersion control in high Q systems has
taken on greater importance in recent years with increased interest in
chip-integrable optical frequency combs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02127</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2015-10-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Muehlemann</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koumatos</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author></authors><title>The morphology of lath martensite: a new perspective</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>ESOMAT15</comments><msc-class>74A50, 74N05, 74N15</msc-class><doi>10.1051/matecconf/20153307003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mathematical framework is proposed to predict the features of the (5 5 7)
lath transformation in low-carbon steels based on energy minimisation. This
theory generates a one-parameter family of possible habit planes and a
selection mechanism then identifies the (5 5 7) normals as those arising from a
deformation with small atomic movement and maximal compatibility. While the
calculations bear some resemblance to those of double shear theories, the
assumptions and conclusions are different. Interestingly, the predicted
microstructure morphology resembles that of plate martensite, in the sense that
a type of twinning mechanism is involved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05997</id><created>2015-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Muehlemann</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Interior Nucleation of Martensite in a Cubic-to-Tetragonal Phase
  Transformation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>ICOMAT 2014</comments><msc-class>74A50, 74N05, 74N15</msc-class><doi>10.1016/j.matpr.2015.07.357</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a variational model based on non-linear elasticity we investigate
whether in a cubic-to-tetragonal phase transformation it is energetically
preferable to nucleate martensite within austenite. Under minimal growth
assumptions on the free energy density $W$ away from the wells, we derive
explicit upper bounds on $W^{qc}({\mathbb{I}})$, i.e. on the macroscopic free
energy density of a region that has been macroscopically deformed by the
identity map. The bounds only depend on material parameters, the temperature
difference and the growth of $W$ away from the wells. By comparing
$W^{qc}({\mathbb{I}})$ and $W({\mathbb{I}})$ we conclude that nucleation is
always energetically preferable and are able to provide quantitative upper
bounds for the gain in negative energy due to nucleation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07920</id><created>2015-07-28</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aczel</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cook</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calder</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christianson</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G. -X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandrus</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paramekanti</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dominant Kitaev interactions on the fcc lattice in iridate double
  perovskites La2BIrO6 (B=Mg, Zn)</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Superseded by significantly extended version with additional
  data+theory --- http://arxiv.org/abs/1604.08431</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed inelastic neutron scattering experiments to investigate the
magnetic excitations in the quasi-face-centered-cubic (fcc) iridate double
perovskites La2ZnIrO6 and La2MgIrO6, which are characterized by A-type
antiferromagnetic ground states. The neutron scattering data, which reveal
gapped spin wave excitations with a very weak dispersion, are shown to be
well-described by theoretical calculations on a model Hamiltonian with dominant
Kitaev interactions. Our surprising finding shows that in contrast to honeycomb
materials, where the Kitaev interaction manifests itself via complex magnetic
order, even conventional magnetic orders in certain geometrically frustrated
systems might owe their existence to unconventional Kitaev exchange.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01671</id><created>2015-08-07</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ilnicka</keyname><forenames>Agnieszka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krawczyk</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robens</keyname><forenames>Tania</forenames></author></authors><title>Inert Doublet Model in light of LHC Run I and astrophysical data</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 19 figures; v2: 39 pages, 2 figures and tables added,
  references modified, title changed; corresponds to published journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 055026 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.055026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the parameter space of the Inert Doublet Model, a two Higgs
doublet model with a dark matter candidate. An extensive set of theoretical and
experimental constraints on this model is considered, where both collider as
well as astroparticle data limits, the latter in the form of dark matter relic
density as well as direct detection, are taken into account. We discuss the
effects of these constraints on the parameter space of the model. In
particular, we do not require the IDM to provide the full dark matter content
of the universe, which opens up additional regions in the parameter space
accessible at collider experiments. The combination of all constraints leads to
a relatively strong mass degeneracy in the dark scalar sector for masses &lt; 200
GeV, and to a minimal scale ~ 45 GeV for the dark scalar masses. We also
observe a stringent mass hierarchy MH &gt; MA. We propose benchmark points and
benchmark planes for dark scalar pair-production for the current LHC run being
in compliance with all theoretical as well as experimental bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04361</id><created>2015-08-18</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buballa</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carignano</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Inhomogeneous chiral symmetry breaking in dense neutron-star matter</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>Invited contribution to the EPJA Topical Issue &quot;Exotic Matter in
  Neutron Stars&quot;. v2: extended discussion on strange quarks, updated
  mass-radius section, other small changes; matches published version. 16
  pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16057-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An increasing number of model results suggests that chiral symmetry is broken
inhomogeneously in a certain window at intermediate densities in the QCD phase
diagram. This could have significant effects on the properties of compact
stars, possibly leading to new astrophysical signatures. In this contribution
we discuss this idea by reviewing recent results on inhomogeneous chiral
symmetry breaking under an astrophysics-oriented perspective. After introducing
two commonly studied spatial modulations of the chiral condensate, the chiral
density wave and the real kink crystal, we focus on their properties and their
effect on the equation of state of quark matter. We also describe how these
crystalline phases are affected by different elements which are required for a
realistic description of a compact star, such as charge neutrality, the
presence of magnetic fields, vector interactions and the interplay with
color-superconductivity. Finally, we discuss possible signatures of
inhomogeneous chiral symmetry breaking in the core of compact stars,
considering the cases of mass-radius relations and neutrino emissivity
explicitly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05226</id><created>2015-08-21</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mvogo</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tambue</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ben-Bolie</keyname><forenames>Germain Hubert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kofane</keyname><forenames>Timoleon Crepin</forenames></author></authors><title>Localized modulated wave solutions in diffusive glucose-insulin systems</title><categories>q-bio.TO physics.bio-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.04.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate intercellular insulin dynamics in an array of diffusively
coupled pancreatic islet \b{eta}-cells. The cells are connected via gap
junction coupling, where nearest neighbor interactions are included. Through
the multiple scale expansion in the semi-discrete approximation, we show that
the insulin dynamics can be governed by the complex Ginzburg-Landau equation.
The localized solutions of this equation are reported. The results suggest from
the biophysical point of view that the insulin propagates in pancreatic islet
\b{eta}-cells using both temporal and spatial dimensions in the form of
localized modulated waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06611</id><created>2015-08-26</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schuetrumpf</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarewicz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Twist-averaged boundary conditions for nuclear pasta Hartree-Fock
  calculations</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 92, 045806 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.92.045806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: Nuclear pasta phases, present in the inner crust of neutron
stars, are associated with nucleonic matter at sub-saturation densities
arranged in regular shapes. Those complex phases, residing in a layer which is
approximately 100 m thick, impact many features of neutron stars. Theoretical
quantum-mechanical simulations of nuclear pasta are usually carried out in
finite 3D boxes assuming periodic boundary conditions (PBC). The resulting
solutions are affected by spurious finite-size effects.
  Purpose: In order to remove spurious finite-size effects, it is convenient to
employ twist-averaged boundary conditions (TABC) used in condensed matter,
nuclear matter, and lattice QCD applications. In this work, we study the
effectiveness of TABC in the context of pasta phases simulations within nuclear
density functional theory.
  Methods: We perform Skyrme-Hartree-Fock calculations in three dimensions by
implementing Bloch boundary conditions. The TABC averages are obtained by means
of Gauss-Legendre integration over twist angles.
  Results: We benchmark the TABC for a free nucleonic gas and apply it to
simple cases such as the rod and slab phases, as well as to more elaborate
P-surface and gyroidal phases.
  Conclusions: We demonstrate that by applying TABC reliable results can be
obtained from calculations performed in relatively small volumes. By studying
various contributions to the total energy, we gain insights into pasta phases
in mid-density range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02497</id><created>2015-09-08</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cavecchi</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levin</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watts</keyname><forenames>Anna L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braithwaite</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast and slow magnetic deflagration fronts in Type I X-ray bursts</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Pubblished on MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw728</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type I X-ray bursts are produced by thermonuclear runaways that develop on
accreting neutron stars. Once one location ignites, the flame propagates across
the surface of the star. Flame propagation is fundamental in order to
understand burst properties like rise time and burst oscillations. Previous
work quantified the effects of rotation on the front, showing that the flame
propagates as a deflagration and that the front strongly resembles a hurricane.
However the effect of magnetic fields was not investigated, despite the fact
that magnetic fields strong enough to have an effect on the propagating flame
are expected to be present on many bursters. In this paper we show how the
coupling between fluid layers introduced by an initially vertical magnetic
field plays a decisive role in determining the character of the fronts that are
responsible for the Type I bursts. In particular, on a star spinning at 450 Hz
(typical among the bursters) we test seed magnetic fields of $10^{7} - 10^{10}$
G and find that for the medium fields the magnetic stresses that develop during
the burst can speed up the velocity of the burning front, bringing the
simulated burst rise time close to the observed values. By contrast, in a
magnetic slow rotator like IGR J17480--2446, spinning at 11 Hz, a seed field
$\gtrsim 10^9$ G is required to allow localized ignition and the magnetic field
plays an integral role in generating the burst oscillations observed during the
bursts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04180</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weerasinghe</keyname><forenames>Amila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazaheri</keyname><forenames>Tahereh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidel</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounds for low-energy spectral properties of center-of-mass conserving
  positive two-body interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 155135 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.155135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the low-energy spectral properties of positive center-of-mass
conserving two-body Hamiltonians as they arise in models of fractional quantum
Hall states. Starting from the observation that positive many-body Hamiltonians
must have ground-state energies that increase monotonously in particle number,
we explore what general additional constraints can be obtained for two-body
interactions with &quot;center-of-mass conservation&quot; symmetry, both in the presence
and absence of particle-hole symmetry. We find general bounds that constrain
the evolution of the ground-state energy with particle number, and in
particular, constrain the chemical potential at $T=0$. Special attention is
given to Hamiltonians with zero modes, in which case similar bounds on the
first excited state are also obtained, using a duality property. In this case,
in particular, an upper bound on the charge gap is also obtained. We further
comment on center of mass and relative decomposition in disk geometry within
the framework of second quantization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05585</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ulmanis</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;fner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pires</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhnle</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidem&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal three-body recombination and Efimov resonances in an ultracold
  Li-Cs mixture</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 022707 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.022707</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study Efimov resonances via three-body loss in an ultracold two-component
gas of fermionic $^6$Li and bosonic $^{133}$Cs atoms close to a Feshbach
resonance at 843~G, extending results reported previously [Pires \textit{et
al.}, Phys. Rev. Lett. 112, 250404 (2014)] to temperatures around 120~nK. The
experimental scheme for reaching lower temperatures is based upon compensating
the gravity-induced spatial separation of the mass-imbalanced gases with
bichromatic optical dipole traps. We observe the first and second excited
Li-Cs-Cs Efimov resonance in the magnetic field dependence of the three-body
event rate constant, in good agreement with the universal zero-range theory at
finite temperature [Petrov and Werner, Phys. Rev. A 92, 022704 (2015)].
Deviations are found for the Efimov ground state, and the inelasticity
parameter $\eta$ is found to be significantly larger than those for
single-species systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06579</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Gracia</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Brito</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple prescription for computing the nonrelativistic interparticle
  potential energy related to dual models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16500706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following a procedure recently utilized by Accioly et al. to obtain the
D-dimensional interparticle potential energy for electromagnetic models in the
nonrelativistic limit, and relaxing the condition assumed by the authors
concerning the conservation of the external current, the prescription found out
by them is generalized so that dual models can also be contemplated. Specific
models in which the interaction is mediated by a spin-0 particle described
first by a vector field and then by a higher-derivative vector field, are
analyzed. Systems mediated by spin-1 particles described, respectively, by
symmetric rank-2 tensors, symmetric rank-2 tensors augmented by higher
derivatives, and antisymmetric rank-2 tensors, are considered as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08460</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deck</keyname><forenames>Katherine M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agol</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Transit timing variations for planets near eccentricity-type mean motion
  resonances</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>revised to be consistent with the accepted version (pre- journal
  editing proof stage)</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 821, Issue 2, article id. 96, 13
  pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/821/2/96</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the transit timing variations (TTVs) of two planets near a second
order mean motion resonance on nearly circular orbits. We show that the TTVs of
each planet are given by sinusoids with a frequency of $j n_2-(j-2)n_1$, where
$j \ge 3$ is an integer characterizing the resonance and $n_2$ and $n_1$ are
the mean motions of the outer and inner planets, respectively. The amplitude of
the TTV depends on the mass of the perturbing planet, relative to the mass of
the star, and on both the eccentricities and longitudes of pericenter of each
planet. The TTVs of the two planets are approximated anti-correlated, with
phases of $\phi$ and $\approx \phi+\pi$, where the phase $\phi$ also depends on
the eccentricities and longitudes of pericenter. Therefore, the TTVs caused by
proximity to a second order mean motion resonance do not in general uniquely
determine both planet masses, eccentricities, and pericenters. This is
completely analogous to the case of TTVs induced by two planets near a first
order mean motion resonance. We explore how other TTV signals, such as the
short-period synodic TTV or a first order resonant TTV, in combination with the
second order resonant TTV, can break degeneracies. Lastly, we derive
approximate formulae for the TTVs of planets near any order eccentricity-type
mean motion resonance; this shows that the same basic sinusoidal TTV structure
holds for all eccentricity-type resonances. Our general formula reduces to
previously derived results near first order mean motion resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07243</id><created>2015-10-25</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moscibrodzka</keyname><forenames>Monika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falcke</keyname><forenames>Heino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiokawa</keyname><forenames>Hotaka</forenames></author></authors><title>General relativistic magnetohydrodynamical simulations of the jet in M87</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>15 pages, 14 figures, accepted to Astronomy and Astrophysics, after
  language proofs, with correct title</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 586, A38 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526630</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  (abridged) The connection between black hole, accretion disk, and radio jet
can be best constrained by fitting models to observations of nearby low
luminosity galactic nuclei, in particular the well studied sources Sgr~A* and
M87. There has been considerable progress in modeling the central engine of
active galactic nuclei by an accreting supermassive black hole coupled to a
relativistic plasma jet. However, can a single model be applied to a range of
black hole masses and accretion rates? Here we want to compare the latest
three-dimensional numerical model, originally developed for Sgr A* in the
center of the Milky Way, to radio observations of the much more powerful and
more massive black hole in M87. We postprocess three-dimensional GRMHD models
of a jet-producing radiatively inefficient accretion flow around a spinning
black hole using relativistic radiative transfer and ray-tracing to produce
model spectra and images. As a key new ingredient to these models, we allow the
proton-electron coupling in these simulations depend on the magnetic properties
of the plasma. We find that the radio emission in M87 is well described by a
combination of a two-temperature accretion flow and a hot single-temperature
jet. The model fits the basic observed characteristics of the M87 radio core.
The best fit model has a mass-accretion rate of Mdot approx 9x10^{-3} MSUN/YR
and a total jet power of P_j \sim 10^{43} erg/s. Emission at 1.3mm is produced
by the counter jet close to the event horizon. Its characteristic crescent
shape surrounding the black hole shadow could be resolved by future
millimeter-wave VLBI experiments. The model was successfully derived from one
for the supermassive black hole in center of the Milky Way by appropriately
scaling mass and accretion rate. This suggests the possibility that this model
could also apply to a larger range of low-luminosity black holes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02237</id><created>2015-11-06</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>Rasmus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuryak</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Instanton-dyon Ensemble with two Dynamical Quarks: the Chiral Symmetry
  Breaking</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 054029 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.054029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second paper of the series aimed at understanding the ensemble of
instanton-dyons, now with two flavors of light dynamical quarks. The partition
function is appended by the fermionic factor, $(det T)^{N_f}$ and Dirac
eigenvalue spectra at small values are derived from the numerical simulation of
64 and 128 dyons. Those spectra show clear chiral symmetry breaking pattern at
high dyon density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02382</id><created>2015-11-07</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ares</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esteve</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falceto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Queiroz</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the M\&quot;obius transformation in the entanglement entropy of fermionic
  chains</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 5 figures. Final version published in JSTAT. Two new
  figures. Some comments and references added. Typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 043106</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/04/043106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is an intimate relation between entanglement entropy and Riemann
surfaces. This fact is explicitly noticed for the case of quadratic fermionic
Hamiltonians with finite range couplings. After recollecting this fact, we make
a comprehensive analysis of the action of the M\&quot;obius transformations on the
Riemann surface. We are then able to uncover the origin of some symmetries and
dualities of the entanglement entropy already noticed recently in the
literature. These results give further support for the use of entanglement
entropy to analyse phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02594</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lilin</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Jiaxue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jincheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface instability modes in freezing colloidal suspensions - revealed
  from onset of planar instability</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>published by Scientific Reports 2016 | 6:23358 | DOI:
  10.1038/srep23358</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep23358</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Freezing colloidal suspensions widely exists in nature and industry.
Interface instability has attracted much attention for the understandings of
the pattern formation in freezing colloidal suspensions. However, the interface
instability modes, the origin of the ice banding or ice lamellae, are still
unclear. In-situ experimental observation of the onset of interface instability
is still absent up to now. Here, by directly imaging the initial transient
stage of planar interface instability in directional freezing colloidal
suspensions, we proposed three interface instability modes, Mullins-Sekerka
instability, global split instability and local split instability. All the
three instability modes come from the competition of the solute boundary layer
and the particle boundary layer, which only can be revealed from the initial
transient stage of planar instability in directional freezing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04465</id><created>2015-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuptsov</keyname><forenames>Pavel V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuptsova</keyname><forenames>Anna V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster synchronization of starlike networks with normalized Laplacian
  coupling: master stability function approach</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9917, Saratov Fall Meeting 2015, 99173O</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2229780</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generalized model of starlike network is suggested that takes into account
non-additive coupling and nonlinear transformation of coupling variables. For
this model a method of analysis of synchronized cluster stability is developed.
Using this method three starlike networks based on Ikeda, predator-prey and
H\'enon maps are studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06788</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paula</keyname><forenames>Fagner M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Obando</keyname><forenames>Paola C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarandy</keyname><forenames>Marcelo S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovianity through Multipartite Correlation Measures</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, v2: Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042337 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042337</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a characterization of memory effects in non-Markovian system-bath
interactions from a quantum information perspective. More specifically, we
establish sufficient conditions for which generalized measures of multipartite
quantum, classical, and total correlations can be used to quantify the degree
of non-Markovianity of a local quantum decohering process. We illustrate our
results by considering the dynamical behavior of the trace-distance
correlations in multi-qubit systems under local dephasing and generalized
amplitude damping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08891</id><created>2015-11-28</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carbone</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierro</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Recchia</keyname><forenames>Giuseppina</forenames></author></authors><title>Loading-unloading hysteresis loop of randomly rough adhesive contacts</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures, published on Physical Review E, Volume 92, Issue
  6, 8 December 2015, Article number 062404</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.92.062404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate the loading and unloading behavior of soft
solids in adhesive contact with randomly rough profiles. The roughness is
assumed to be described by a self-affine fractal on a limited range of
wave-vectors. A spectral method is exploited to generate such randomly rough
surfaces. The results are statistically averaged, and the calculated contact
area and applied load are shown as a function of the penetration, for loading
and unloading conditions. We found that the combination of adhesion forces and
roughness leads to a hysteresis loading-unloading loop. This shows that energy
can be lost simply as a consequence of roughness and van der Waals forces, as
in this case a large number of local energy minima exist and the system may be
trapped in metastable states. We numerically quantify the hysteretic loss and
assess the influence of the surface statistical properties and the energy of
adhesion on the hysteresis process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01817</id><created>2015-12-06</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>Jafar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shajiee</keyname><forenames>Vahid Reza</forenames></author></authors><title>The Schwarzschild/CFT Correspondence: Weyl Rescaled Case</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the CFT dual of the Schwarzschild black hole is investigated. A
Weyl rescaling factor is presented, so that the Weyl rescaled Schwarzschild
metric, after a coordinate transformation, has an $AdS_{2} \times S_{2}$
geometry at vicinity of its origin. Since the near origin spacetime admits an
$AdS_{2}$ factor, it is dealt with a 2D effective gravity which is
dimensionally reduced from the near origin solution. It is exhibited that the
dual CFT has a central charge $c=96 M^3$ which is an asymptotic conserved
charge of the effective solution. Finally, the microscopic entropy of
Schwarzschild black hole is achieved by using Cardy formula. It is revealed
that the microscopic entropy exactly reproduces the Bekenstein-Hawking entropy
of the Schwarzschild black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03802</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Binder</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ekstr&#xf6;m</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papenbrock</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendt</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective field theory in the harmonic oscillator basis</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 044332 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.044332</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop interactions from chiral effective field theory (EFT) that are
tailored to the harmonic oscillator basis. As a consequence, ultraviolet
convergence with respect to the model space is implemented by construction and
infrared convergence can be achieved by enlarging the model space for the
kinetic energy. In oscillator EFT, matrix elements of EFTs formulated for
continuous momenta are evaluated at the discrete momenta that stem from the
diagonalization of the kinetic energy in the finite oscillator space. By
fitting to realistic phase shifts and deuteron data we construct an effective
interaction from chiral EFT at next-to-leading order. Many-body coupled-cluster
calculations of nuclei up to 132Sn exhibit a fast convergence of ground-state
energies and radii in feasible model spaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05906</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nissimagoudar</keyname><forenames>Arun S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manjanath</keyname><forenames>Aaditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Abhishek K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusive nature of thermal transport in stanene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5CP07957H</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Using the phonon Boltzmann transport formalism and density functional theory
based calculations, we show that stanene has a low thermal conductivity. For a
sample size of 1$\times$1 $\mu$m$^{2}$ ($L\times W$), the lattice thermal
conductivities along the zigzag and armchair directions are 10.83 W/m-K and 9.2
W/m-K respectively, at room temperature, indicating anisotropy in the thermal
transport. The low values of thermal conductivity are due to large
anharmonicity in the crystal resulting in high Gr\&quot;{u}neisen parameters, and
low group velocities. The room temperature effective phonon mean free path is
found to be around 17 nm indicating that the thermal transport in stanene is
completely diffusive in nature. Furthermore, our study brings out the relative
importance of the contributing phonon branches and reveals that, at very low
temperatures, the contribution to lattice thermal conductivity comes from the
flexural acoustic (ZA) branch and at higher temperatures it is dominated by the
longitudinal acoustic (LA) branch. We also show that lattice thermal
conductivity of stanene can further be reduced by tuning the sample size and
creating rough surfaces at the edges. Such tunability in the lattice thermal
conductivity in stanene suggests its applications in thermoelectric devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06462</id><created>2015-12-20</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Melko</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herdman</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iouchtchenko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>P. -N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Maestro</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entangling qubit registers via many-body states of ultracold atoms</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures; typos fixed</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042336 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042336</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by the experimental measurement of the Renyi entanglement entropy in
a lattice of ultracold atoms by Islam et al., [Nature 528, 77 (2015)] we
propose a method to entangle two spatially-separated qubits using the quantum
many-body state as a resource. Through local operations accessible in an
experiment, entanglement is transferred to a qubit register from atoms at the
ends of a one-dimensional chain. We compute the operational entanglement, which
bounds the entanglement physically transferable from the many-body resource to
the register, and discuss a protocol for its experimental measurement. Finally,
we explore measures for the amount of entanglement available in the register
after transfer, suitable for use in quantum information applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07674</id><created>2015-12-23</created><updated>2016-03-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Shung-Ichi</forenames><affiliation>Sunmoon U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hypernuclei in Halo/Cluster Effective Field Theory</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>review article for special issue on &quot;Effective Field Theory in
  Nuclear Physics&quot; in Int. J. Mod. Phys. E; 16 pages and 8 eps figures, version
  accepted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. E 25, 1641005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218301316410056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The light double $\Lambda$ hypernuclei, ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\ \ 4}$H and
${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\ \ 6}$He, are studied as three-body $\Lambda\Lambda d$
and $\Lambda\Lambda\alpha$ cluster systems in halo/cluster effective field
theory at leading order. We find that the $\Lambda\Lambda d$ system in spin-0
channel does not exhibit a limit cycle whereas the $\Lambda\Lambda d$ system in
spin-1 channel and the $\Lambda\Lambda\alpha$ system in spin-0 channel do. The
limit cycle is associated with the formation of bound states, known as Efimov
states, in the unitary limit. For the $\Lambda\Lambda d$ system in the spin-0
channel we estimate the scattering length $a_0$ for $S$-wave $\Lambda$
hyperon-hypertriton scattering as $a_0=16.0\pm 3.0$ fm. We also discuss that
studying the cutoff dependences in the $\Lambda\Lambda d$ and
$\Lambda\Lambda\alpha$ systems, the bound state of ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\ \
4}$H is not an Efimov state but formed due to a high energy mechanism whereas
that of ${}_{\Lambda\Lambda}^{\ \ 6}$He may be regarded as an Efimov state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09023</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#x160;ubelj</keyname><forenames>Lovro</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Eck</keyname><forenames>Nees Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waltman</keyname><forenames>Ludo</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering scientific publications based on citation relations: A
  systematic comparison of different methods</title><categories>cs.DL cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><comments>24 pages, 7 figures, 7 tables</comments><journal-ref>PLoS ONE 11(4), e0154404 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0154404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Clustering methods are applied regularly in the bibliometric literature to
identify research areas or scientific fields. These methods are for instance
used to group publications into clusters based on their relations in a citation
network. In the network science literature, many clustering methods, often
referred to as graph partitioning or community detection techniques, have been
developed. Focusing on the problem of clustering the publications in a citation
network, we present a systematic comparison of the performance of a large
number of these clustering methods. Using a number of different citation
networks, some of them relatively small and others very large, we extensively
study the statistical properties of the results provided by different methods.
In addition, we also carry out an expert-based assessment of the results
produced by different methods. The expert-based assessment focuses on
publications in the field of scientometrics. Our findings seem to indicate that
there is a trade-off between different properties that may be considered
desirable for a good clustering of publications. Overall, map equation methods
appear to perform best in our analysis, suggesting that these methods deserve
more attention from the bibliometric community.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00342</id><created>2016-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Damtie</keyname><forenames>Fikeraddis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wacker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Time Dependent Study of Multiple Exciton Generation in Nanocrystal
  Quantum Dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Submitted to the conference &quot;Progress in
  Nonequilibrium Green's Functions VI Proceedings&quot; at Lund University, Sweden,
  August 17th - 21st, 2015. To be published in the Journal of Physics:
  Conference Series</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 696, 012012 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/696/1/012012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the exciton dynamics in an optically excited nanocrystal quantum
dot. Multiple exciton formation is more efficient in nanocrystal quantum dots
compared to bulk semiconductors due to enhanced Coulomb interactions and the
absence of conservation of momentum. The formation of multiple excitons is
dependent on different excitation parameters and the dissipation. We study this
process within a Lindblad quantum rate equation using the full many-particle
states. We optically excite the system by creating a single high energy exciton
$E_{SX}$ in resonance to a double exciton $E_{DX}$. With Coulomb
electron-electron interaction, the population can be transferred from the
single exciton to the double exciton state by impact ionisation (inverse Auger
process). The ratio between the recombination processes and the absorbed
photons provide the yield of the structure. We observe a quantum yield of
comparable value to experiment assuming typical experimental conditions for a
$4$ nm PbS quantum dot.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00915</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-01-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Winge</keyname><forenames>David O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Francki&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wacker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Superlattice gain in positive differential conductivity region</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>AIP Advances 6, 045025 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4948538</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze theoretically a superlattice structure proposed by A. Andronov et
al. [JETP Lett 102, 207 (2015)] to give Terahertz gain for an operation point
with positive differential conductivity. Here we confirm the existence of gain
and show that an optimized structure displays gain above 20 cm$^{-1}$ at low
temperatures, so that lasing may be observable. Comparing a variety of
simulations, this gain is found to be strongly affected by elastic scattering.
It is shown that the dephasing modifies the nature of the relevant states, so
that the common analysis based on Wannier-Stark states is not reliable for a
quantitative description of the gain in structures with extremely diagonal
transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07397</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Risti&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Ramir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zadro</keyname><forenames>Kre&#x161;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paji&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Damir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Figueroa</keyname><forenames>Ignacio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author></authors><title>On the origin of bulk glass forming ability in Cu-Hf, Zr alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 114 (2016) 17006</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/17006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the formation of bulk metallic glasses (BMG) in metallic
systems and finding a reliable criterion for selection of BMG compositions are
among the most important issues in condensed matter physics and material
science. Using the results of magnetic susceptibility measurements performed on
both amorphous and crystallized Cu-Hf alloys (30-70 at% Cu) we find a
correlation between the difference in magnetic susceptibilities of
corresponding glassy and crystalline alloys and the variation in the glass
forming ability (GFA) in these alloys. Since the same correlation can be
inferred from data for the properties associated with the electronic structure
of Cu-Zr alloys, it seems quite general and may apply to other glassy alloys
based on early and late transition metals. This correlation is plausible from
the free energy considerations and provides a simple way to select the
compositions with high GFA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00537</id><created>2016-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>R&#xf6;sch</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scalari</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villares</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosco</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>Mattias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faist</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author></authors><title>On-chip, self-detected THz dual-comb spectrometer</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4948358</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a directly generated on-chip dual-comb source at THz frequencies.
The multi-heterodyne beating signal of two free-running THz quantum cascade
laser frequency combs is measured electrically using one of the combs as a
detector, fully exploiting the unique characteristics of quantum cascade active
regions. Up to 30 modes can be detected corresponding to a spectral bandwidth
of 630 GHz, being the available bandwidth of the dual comb configuration. The
multi-heterodyne signal is used to investigate the equidistance of the comb
modes showing an accuracy of $10^{-12}$ at the carrier frequency of 2.5 THz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01222</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author></authors><title>The leading term of the Yang-Mills free energy</title><categories>math-ph hep-lat hep-th math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>49 pages, 4 figures. To appear in J. Funct. Anal</comments><msc-class>70S15, 81T13, 81T25, 82B20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article gives an explicit formula for the leading term of the free
energy of three-dimensional $U(N)$ lattice gauge theory for any $N$, as the
lattice spacing tends to zero. The proof is based on a novel technique that
avoids phase cell renormalization. The technique also yields a similar formula
for the four-dimensional theory, but only in the weak coupling~limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01287</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tretyakov</keyname><forenames>Petr V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical stability of extended teleparallel gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>some results was corrected, journal's ref. was added</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 14 (2016) 1650085</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316500851</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss modified teleparallel gravity with function $f(T,T_G)$ in the
action, where function depend on two arguments: torsion scalar $T$ and analogue
of Gauss-Bonnet invariant $T_G$. In contradistinction to usual teleparallel
gravity $f(T)$, this theory contains higher derivative terms, which may produce
different instabilities. We discuss Minkowski stability problem in such kind of
theories and explicitly demonstrate that for stability must be $f_T(0,0)&lt;0$,
$f_{T_GT_G}&gt;0$. We apply these restrictions for the few types of functions
discussed by the early authors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01801</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-04-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Shao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Hong-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xianyu</keyname><forenames>Zhong-Zhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Realizing Dark Matter and Higgs Inflation in Light of LHC Diphoton
  Excess</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Phys.Lett.B Final Version. 16pp (7 Figs + 2 Tables). Only minor text
  refinements, references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 757 (2016) 480-492</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.04.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  LHC Run-2 has provided intriguing di-photon signals of a new resonance around
750GeV, which, if not due to statistical fluctuations, must call for new
physics beyond the standard model (SM) at TeV scale. We propose a minimal
extension of the SM with a complex singlet scalar $\mathcal{S}$ and a doublet
of vector-like quarks. The scalar sector respects CP symmetry, with its CP-odd
imaginary component $\chi$ providing a natural dark matter (DM) candidate. The
real component of $\mathcal{S}$ serves as the new resonance (750GeV) and
explains the diphoton excess of the LHC Run-2. The new scalar degrees of
freedom of $\mathcal{S}$ help to stabilize the Higgs vacuum, and can realize
the Higgs inflation around GUT scale, consistent with the current cosmology
observations. We construct two representative samples A and B of our model for
demonstration. We study the mono-jet signals of the DM production from
invisible decays Re$(\mathcal{S}) \to \chi\chi$ at the LHC Run-2. We further
derive the DM relic density bound, and analyze the constraints from direct and
indirect DM detections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02309</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02309</id><created>2016-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Ertem</keyname><forenames>&#xdc;mit</forenames></author></authors><title>Supergravity backgrounds and symmetry superalgebras</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, short review, to appear in Turk. J. Phys. special issue on
  General Relativity and Related Topics</comments><report-no>EMPG 16-04</report-no><journal-ref>Turk. J. Phys. 40 (2016), 113-126</journal-ref><doi>10.3906/fiz-1510-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the bosonic sectors of supergravity theories in ten and eleven
dimensions which correspond to the low energy limits of string theories and
M-theory. The solutions of supergravity field equations are known as
supergravity backgrounds and the number of preserved supersymmetries in those
backgrounds are determined by Killing spinors. We provide some examples of
supergravity backgrounds which preserve different fractions of supersymmetry.
An important invariant for the characterization of supergravity backgrounds is
their Killing superalgebras which are constructed out of Killing vectors and
Killing spinors of the background. After constructing Killing superalgebras of
some special supergravity backgrounds, we discuss about the possibilities of
the extensions of these superalgebras to include the higher degree hidden
symmetries of the background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03514</id><created>2016-02-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subramanian</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerhold</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDermott</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enterkin</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hieckel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moewes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castell</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diebold</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marks</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transition from reconstruction towards thin film on the (110) surface of
  strontium titanate</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett.16, 2407 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b05211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The surfaces of metal oxides often are reconstructed with a geometry and
composition that is considerably different from a simple termination of the
bulk. Such structures can also be viewed as ultrathin films, epitaxed on a
substrate. Here, the reconstructions of the SrTiO3 (110) surface are studied
combining scanning tunneling microscopy, transmission electron diffraction, and
X-ray absorption spectroscopy, and analyzed with density functional theory
calculations. While SrTiO3 (110) invariably terminates with an overlayer of
titania, with increasing density its structure switches from nx1 and 2xn. At
the same time the coordination of the Ti atoms changes from a network of
corner-sharing tetrahedra to a double layer of edge-shared octahedra with
bridging units of octahedrally coordinated strontium. This transition from the
nx1 to 2xn reconstructions is a transition from a pseudomorphically stabilized
tetrahedral network towards an octahedral titania thin film with stress-relief
from octahedral strontia units at the surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03997</id><created>2016-02-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Winge</keyname><forenames>David O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Francki&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verdozzi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wacker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Mauro F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple electron-electron scattering in non-equilibrium Green's function
  simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, proceeding of the PNGF6 workshop in Lund, Sweden
  2015</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 696 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/696/1/012013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we include electron-electron interaction beyond Hartree-Fock
level in our non-equilibrium Green's function approach by a crude form of GW
through the Single Plasmon Pole Approximation. This is achieved by treating all
conduction band electrons as a single effective band screening the Coulomb
potential. We describe the corresponding self-energies in this scheme for a
multi-subband system. In order to apply the formalism to heterostructures we
discuss the screening and plasmon dispersion in both 2D and 3D systems. Results
are shown for a four well quantum cascade laser with different doping
concentration where comparisons to experimental findings can be made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06325</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gherib</keyname><forenames>Rami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Liyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryabinkin</keyname><forenames>Ilya G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmaylov</keyname><forenames>Artur F.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the inclusion of the diagonal Born-Oppenheimer correction in surface
  hopping methods</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 16 figures, the version is aligned with the J. Chem. Phys.
  publication</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144 (2016) 154103</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4945817</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The diagonal Born-Oppenheimer correction (DBOC) stems from the diagonal
second derivative coupling term in the adiabatic representation, and it can
have an arbitrary large magnitude when a gap between neighbouring
Born-Oppenheimer (BO) potential energy surfaces (PESs) is closing.
Nevertheless, DBOC is typically neglected in mixed quantum-classical methods of
simulating nonadiabatic dynamics (e.g., fewest-switch surface hopping (FSSH)
method). A straightforward addition of DBOC to BO PESs in the FSSH method,
FSSH+D, has been shown to lead to numerically much inferior results for models
containing conical intersections. More sophisticated variation of the DBOC
inclusion, phase-space surface-hopping (PSSH) was more successful than FSSH+D
but on model problems without conical intersections. This work comprehensively
assesses the role of DBOC in nonadiabatic dynamics of two electronic state
problems and the performance of FSSH, FSSH+D, and PSSH methods in variety of
one- and two-dimensional models. Our results show that the inclusion of DBOC
can enhance the accuracy of surface hopping simulations when two conditions are
simultaneously satisfied: 1) nuclei have kinetic energy lower than DBOC and 2)
PESs are not strongly nonadiabatically coupled. The inclusion of DBOC is
detrimental in situations where its energy scale becomes very high or even
diverges, because in these regions PESs are also very strongly coupled. In this
case, the true quantum formalism heavily relies on an interplay between
diagonal and off-diagonal nonadiabatic couplings while surface hopping
approaches treat diagonal terms as PESs and off-diagonal ones stochastically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01274</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karananas</keyname><forenames>Georgios K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaposhnikov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Scale invariant alternatives to general relativity. II. Dilaton
  properties</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 084052 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.084052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper, we revisit gravitational theories which are invariant
under TDiffs -- transverse (volume preserving) diffeomorphisms and global scale
transformations. It is known that these theories can be rewritten in an
equivalent diffeomorphism-invariant form with an action including an
integration constant (cosmological constant for the particular case of
non-scale-invariant unimodular gravity). The presence of this integration
constant, in general, breaks explicitly scale invariance and induces a runaway
potential for the (otherwise massless) dilaton, associated with the determinant
of the metric tensor. We show, however, that if the metric carries mass
dimension $\left[\text{GeV}\right]^{-2}$, the scale invariance of the system is
preserved, unlike the situation in theories in which the metric has mass
dimension different from $-2$. The dilaton remains massless and couples to
other fields only through derivatives, without any conflict with observations.
We observe that one can define a specific limit for fields and their
derivatives (in particular, the dilaton goes to zero, potentially related to
the small distance domain of the theory) in which the only singular terms in
the action correspond to the Higgs mass and the cosmological constant. We
speculate that the self-consistency of the theory may require the regularity of
the action, leading to the absence of the bare Higgs mass and cosmological
constant, whereas their small finite values may be generated by nonperturbative
effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01304</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Hari Mohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Rajesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagdeo</keyname><forenames>Pankaj R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaiswal</keyname><forenames>Neeraj K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Pankaj</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on Half metallicity along the edge of zigzag boron nitride
  nanoribbons (Phys. Rev. B 78, 205415 (2008)</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We would like to comment that the prediction of Half-mtallicity in only B
edge H-passivated zigzag boron nitride nanoribbons (ZBNNR-BH), by Zheng et
al.1, is not correct as their interpretation is erroneous. Since it is well
known that for a material, to be a half-metal, as a primary condition one type
of spin channels or bands (either spin up or spin down) are conducting and the
opposite ones are insulating. In commented article 1, ZBNNR-BH shows insulating
behavior for spin up bands (Eg=4.5 eV) whereas conducting nature for spin down
electrons. They claim1 through the electronic band structure of 8-ZBNNR-BH [as
shown in figure 2 (b)]1, that spin down - Alpha (conduction band minimum - CBM)
and Beta (valence band maximum - VBM) bands are crossing each other at the
Fermi level (green dotted line) and thus the ribbons are conducting for spin
down electrons. But this crossing of two same spin bands is impossible because
according to well-known Paulis exclusion principle- Two identical fermions
(particles with half-integer spin) cannot occupy the same quantum state
simultaneously.In the case of electrons, it is impossible for two electrons of
a poly-electron atom to have the same values of the four quantum numbers (n, l,
ml and ms). Thus for two electrons residing in the same orbital (same energy
level e.g. above stated crossing point 1), n, l, and ml are the same, so ms
must be different and the electrons must have opposite spins.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04699</id><created>2016-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Allard</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fadel</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmied</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treutlein</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author></authors><title>Sideband Rabi spectroscopy of finite-temperature trapped Bose gases</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 043624 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.043624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use Rabi spectroscopy to explore the low-energy excitation spectrum of a
finite-temperature Bose gas of rubidium atoms across the phase transition to a
Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC). To record this spectrum, we coherently drive
the atomic population between two spin states. A small relative displacement of
the spin-specific trapping potentials enables sideband transitions between
different motional states. The intrinsic non-linearity of the motional
spectrum, mainly originating from two-body interactions, makes it possible to
resolve and address individual excitation lines. Together with sensitive
atom-counting, this constitutes a feasible technique to count single excited
atoms of a BEC and to determine the temperature of nearly pure condensates. As
an example, we show that for a nearly pure BEC of N = 800 atoms the first
excited state has a population of less than 5 atoms, corresponding to an upper
bound on the temperature of 30 nK.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02708</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02708</id><created>2016-04-10</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Irajizad</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames></author></authors><title>Vesicle adhesion reveals novel universal relationships for biophysical
  characterization</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.CB</categories><comments>6 page, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adhesion plays an integral role in diverse biological functions ranging from
cellular transport to tissue development. Estimation of adhesion strength,
therefore, becomes important to gain biophysical insight into these phenomena.
In this Letter, we use curvature elasticity to present non-intuitive, yet
remarkably simple, universal relationships that capture vesicle-substrate
interactions. Our study reveals that the inverse of the height, exponential of
the contact area, and the force required to detach the vesicle from the
substrate vary linearly with the square root of the adhesion energy. These
relationships not only provide efficient strategies to tease out adhesion
energy of biological molecules but can also be used to characterize the
physical properties of elastic biomimetic nanoparticles. We validate the
modeling predictions with experimental data from two previous studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02927</id><created>2016-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Yunlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Naihuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li-Jost</keyname><forenames>Xianqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Teng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Xi</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong entropic uncertainty relations for multiple measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study entropic uncertainty relations on a
finite-dimensional Hilbert space and provide several tighter bounds for
multi-measurements, with some of them also valid for R\'{e}nyi and Tsallis
entropies besides the Shannon entropy. We employ majorization theory and
actions of the symmetric group to obtain an {\it admixture bound} for entropic
uncertainty relations for multi-measurements. Comparisons among all bounds for
multi-measurements are shown in figures in our favor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03436</id><created>2016-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinograd</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayaffre</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonn</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loew</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porras</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haug</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinkov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keimer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julien</keyname><forenames>M. -H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cu-NMR study of oxygen disorder in ortho-II YBa2Cu3Oy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 134518 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.134518</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that 63Cu NMR spectra place strong constraints on both the nature and
the concentration of oxygen defects in ortho-II YBa2Cu3Oy. Systematic deviation
from ideal ortho-II order is revealed by the presence of inequivalent Cu sites
in either full or empty chains. The results can be explained by two kinds of
defects: oxygen clustering into additional chains, or fragments thereof, most
likely present at all concentrations (6.4&lt;y&lt;6.6) and oxygen vacancies randomly
distributed in the full chains for y&lt;6.50 only. Furthermore, the remarkable
reproducibility of the spectra in different samples with optimal ortho-II order
(y=6.55) shows that chain-oxygen disorder, known to limit electronic coherence,
is ineluctable because it is inherent to these compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04531</id><created>2016-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jinchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>Songxue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez-Baca</keyname><forenames>Jaime A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Huibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gooch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poudel</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yaqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure effects on magnetic ground states in cobalt doped multiferroic
  Mn$_{1-x}$Co$_{x}$WO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, to be published in Physical Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 155164 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.155164</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using ambient pressure x-ray and high pressure neutron diffraction, we
studied the pressure effect on structural and magnetic properties of
multiferroic Mn$_{1-x}$Co$_x$WO$_4$ single crystals ($x=0, 0.05, 0.135$ and
$0.17$), and compared it with the effects of doping. Both Co doping and
pressure stretch the Mn-Mn chain along the $c$~direction. At high doping level
($x=0.135$ and $0.17$), pressure and Co doping drive the system in a similar
way and induce a spin-flop transition for the $x=0.135$ compound. In contrast,
magnetic ground states at lower doping level ($x=0$ and $0.05$) are robust
against pressure but experience a pronounced change upon Co substitution. As Co
introduces both chemical pressure and magnetic anisotropy into the frustrated
magnetic system, our results suggest the magnetic anisotropy is the main
driving force for the Co induced phase transitions at low doping level, and
chemical pressure plays a more significant role at higher Co concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04542</id><created>2016-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Maucher</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutcliffe</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Untangling knots via reaction-diffusion dynamics of vortex strings</title><categories>nlin.PS cond-mat.soft hep-th math-ph math.GT math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, 3 movies. To appear in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><report-no>DCPT-16/09</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev.Lett. 116, 178101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.178101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce and illustrate a new approach to the unknotting problem via the
dynamics of vortex strings in a nonlinear partial differential equation of
reaction-diffusion type. To untangle a given knot, a Biot-Savart construction
is used to initialize the knot as a vortex string in the FitzHugh-Nagumo
equation. Remarkably, we find that the subsequent evolution preserves the
topology of the knot and can untangle an unknot into a circle. Illustrative
test case examples are presented, including the untangling of a hard unknot
known as the culprit. Our approach to the unknotting problem has two novel
features, in that it applies field theory rather than particle mechanics and
uses reaction-diffusion dynamics in place of energy minimization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07331</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kulik</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlik</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oseledchik</keyname><forenames>Yu. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron wave packet evolution under the influence of random electric
  field</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an electron wave packet evolution in the external deterministic
electric field with Gaussian white noise addition. An explicit expression was
given for the averaged probability flux with Gaussian initial wave function. We
show that the noise addition increases wave packet spreading rate, which has a
significant influence on flux amplitude and may play both destructive and
constructive role. This depends on the form and amplitude of external
deterministic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07823</id><created>2016-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Botteon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gastaldello</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunetti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dallacasa</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>A shock at the radio relic position in Abell 115</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS Letters</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyzed a deep Chandra observation (334 ks) of the galaxy cluster Abell
115 and detected a shock co-spatial with the radio relic. The X-ray surface
brightness profile across the shock region presents a discontinuity,
corresponding to a density compression factor $\mathcal{C}=2.0\pm0.1$ leading
to a Mach number $\mathcal{M}=1.7\pm0.1$ ($\mathcal{M}=1.4-2$ including
systematics). Temperatures measured in the upstream and downstream regions are
consistent with what expected for such a shock:
$T_u=4.3^{+1.0}_{-0.6}\:\rm{keV}$ and $T_d=7.9^{+1.4}_{-1.1}\:\rm{keV}$
respectively, implying a Mach number $\mathcal{M}=1.8^{+0.5}_{-0.4}$. So far,
only few other shocks discovered in galaxy clusters are consistently detected
from both density and temperature jumps. The spatial coincidence between this
discontinuity and the radio relic edge strongly supports the view that shocks
play a crucial role in powering these synchrotron sources. We suggest that the
relic is originated by shock re-acceleration of relativistic electrons rather
than acceleration from the thermal pool. The position and curvature of the
shock and the associated relic are consistent with an off-axis merger with
unequal mass ratio where the shock is expected to bend around the core of the
less massive cluster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08247</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Korkina</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopteva</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>The mass function method for obtaining exact solutions of Einstein
  equations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Space, Time and Fundamental Interactions. 2012. V. 1, p. 38 - 47</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the mass function method makes it much easier to obtain the
exact solutions of Einstein equations. The known solutions for empty space and
for the universe filled with dust-like matter are considered from the point of
view of the method and new exact solutions are obtained. Generalized solutions
for the Schwarzschild type black holes are considered. It is shown that such
black holes always contain non-baryonic matter. New exact solution for the
black hole embedded into dust matter cosmological background is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08317</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Huabin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Wenshuai</forenames></author></authors><title>On the deformation of inversive distance circle packings</title><categories>math.GT math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we generalize Chow-Luo's combinatorial Ricci flow to inversive
distance circle packing setting. Although the solution to the generalized flow
may develop singularities in finite time, we can always extend the solution so
as it exists for all time and converges exponentially fast. Thus the
generalized flow can be used to deform any inversive distance circle packing to
a unique packing with prescribed cone angle. We also give partial results on
the range of all admissible cone angles, which generalize the classical
Andreev-Thurston's theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08530</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Branchina</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Domenico</keyname><forenames>Manlio</forenames></author></authors><title>Simultaneous observation of gravitational and electromagnetic waves</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assuming that the short gamma-ray burst detected by the Fermi Gamma-Ray Space
Telescope about 0.4 seconds after the gravitational waves observed by the LIGO
and VIRGO Collaborations originated from the same black hole merger event, we
perform a model-independent analysis of different quantum gravity scenarios
based on (modified) dispersion relations (typical of quantum gravity models)
for the graviton and the photon. We find that only scenarios where at least one
of the two particles is luminal (the other being sub- or super-luminal) are
allowed, while scenarios where none of the two particles is luminal are ruled
out. Moreover, the physical request of having acceptable values for the quantum
gravity scale imposes stringent bounds on the difference between the velocities
of electromagnetic and gravitational waves, much more stringent than any
previously known bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08575</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez-Castillo</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klahn</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal symmetry energy contribution to the neutron star equation of
  state</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures, one figure (Fig. 6) and descriptive text added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the observation that under neutron star conditions of charge
neutrality and $\beta-$equilibrium the contribution from the symmetry energy to
the equation of state (EoS) follows a universal behaviour. We call this
behaviour the conjecture of a Universal Symmetry Energy Contribution (USEC). We
find that an USEC holds provided the density dependence of the symmetry energy
$E_s(n)$ follows a behaviour that limits the proton fraction $x(n)$ to values
below the threshold for the direct Urca (DU) cooling process. The absence of DU
cooling in typical mass neutron stars appears to be supported by the
phenomenology of neutron star cooling data and allows to constrain the
behaviour of $E_s(n)$ at high densities. Two classes of symmetry energy
functions are investigated more in detail to elucidate the USEC. We derive an
analytic formula for the USEC to the neutron star EoS based on the result for
the symmetry energy extracted from isobaric analog states of nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08583</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Barth</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betancourt</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloch</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;gelspacher</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Boer</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daniels</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dierlamm</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eber</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckerlin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckstein</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichhorn</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erfle</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feld</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garutti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregor</keyname><forenames>I. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guthoff</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartmann</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauser</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husemann</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobs</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Junkes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpinski</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacker</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahboubi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mussgiller</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xfc;rnberg</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parzefall</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poehlsen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poley</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preuten</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rehnisch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sammet</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schleper</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuwalow</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperlich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanitzki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinbr&#xfc;ck</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wlochal</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enabling Technologies for Silicon Microstrip Tracking Detectors at the
  HL-LHC</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While the tracking detectors of the ATLAS and CMS experiments have shown
excellent performance in Run 1 of LHC data taking, and are expected to continue
to do so during LHC operation at design luminosity, both experiments will have
to exchange their tracking systems when the LHC is upgraded to the
high-luminosity LHC (HL-LHC) around the year 2024. The new tracking systems
need to operate in an environment in which both the hit densities and the
radiation damage will be about an order of magnitude higher than today. In
addition, the new trackers need to contribute to the first level trigger in
order to maintain a high data-taking efficiency for the interesting processes.
Novel detector technologies have to be developed to meet these very challenging
goals. The German groups active in the upgrades of the ATLAS and CMS tracking
systems have formed a collaborative &quot;Project on Enabling Technologies for
Silicon Microstrip Tracking Detectors at the HL-LHC&quot; (PETTL), which was
supported by the Helmholtz Alliance &quot;Physics at the Terascale&quot; during the years
2013 and 2014. The aim of the project was to share experience and to work
together on key areas of mutual interest during the R&amp;D phase of these
upgrades. The project concentrated on five areas, namely exchange of
experience, radiation hardness of silicon sensors, low mass system design,
automated precision assembly procedures, and irradiations. This report
summarizes the main achievements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08593</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Pinto</keyname><forenames>Ciro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Middleton</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabian</keyname><forenames>Andrew C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resolved atomic lines reveal outflows in two ultraluminous X-ray sources</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures, 2 tables, published by Nature on 27 April 2016</comments><doi>10.1038/nature17417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultraluminous X-ray sources are extragalactic, off-nucleus, point sources in
galaxies with an X-ray luminosity above 3x10^39 erg/s, thought to be powered by
accretion onto a compact object. Possible explanations include accretion onto
neutron stars with strong magnetic fields, stellar-mass black holes (&lt; 20
Msolar) at or in excess of the classical Eddington limit or intermediate-mass
black holes (10^3-5 Msolar). The lack of sufficient energy resolution in
previous analyses has hitherto prevented an unambiguous identification of any
emission or absorption lines in the X-ray band, thereby precluding a detailed
analysis of the accretion flow. Here we report the presence of X-ray emission
lines arising from highly ionized iron, oxygen and neon with a cumulative
significance &gt; 5 sigma, and blueshifted (~0.2c) absorption lines (5 sigma) in
the high-resolution X-ray spectrum of the ultraluminous X-ray source NGC 1313
X-1. In a similar source, NGC 5408 X-1, we also detect emission lines at rest
and blueshifted absorption. The blueshifted absorption lines must occur in a
fast outflowing gas, whereas the emission lines originate in slow-moving gas
around the source. We conclude that the compact object is surrounded by
powerful winds with an outflow velocity of about 0.2c as predicted by models of
accreting supermassive black holes and hyper-accreting stellar mass black
holes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08607</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Dziatkowski</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staszewski</keyname><forenames>W. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bo&#x17c;ek</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczytko</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gosk</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Twardowski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furdyna</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetization Saturation Process in the Magnonic Anti-dot Structures
  Based on (Ga,Mn)As: A Magnetometric Study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Applicability of dilute magnetic semiconductors (DMS) in electronic devices
relies upon the understanding and control of their magnetic anisotropy. This
paper explores one of the ways in engineering magnetic anisotropy in epitaxial
layers of DMS by forming them into magnonic structures. For this purpose the
canonical ferromagnetic DMS, namely (Ga,Mn)As, is employed. The anti-dot
systems based on (Ga,Mn)As layers of various thicknesses are fabricated with
focused ion beam apparatus and studied by means of microscopy as well as
magnetometry. The magnetometric data - collected along two nonequivalent
in-plane crystallographic directions of (Ga,Mn)As: [110] and [1-10] - shows the
effect of structuring on high-field magnetization process, whereas no
significant change of the width of hysteresis loop in anti-dot samples is
observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08615</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesaros</keyname><forenames>Andrej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ran</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetism and d+id superconductivity in 1/2 doped correlated
  systems on triangular lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the quantum phase diagram of t-J model on triangular lattice
at 1/2 doping with various lattice sizes by using a combination of density
matrix renormalization group (DMRG), variational Monte Carlo and quantum field
theories. To sharply distinguish different phases, we calculated the symmetry
quantum numbers of the ground state wave functions, and the results are further
confirmed by studying correlation functions. Our results show there is a first
order phase transition from ferromagnetism to d+id superconductivity, with the
transition taking place at $J/t=0.4\pm0.2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08624</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Riley</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McPherson</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agiorgousis</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baugher</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowry</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cottle</keyname><forenames>P. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeVone</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gade</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glowacki</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregory</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haldeman</keyname><forenames>E. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemper</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunderberg</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noji</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Recchia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadler</keyname><forenames>B. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weisshaar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zegers</keyname><forenames>R. G. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Octupole strength in the neutron-rich calcium isotopes</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 044327 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.044327</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-lying excited states of the neutron-rich calcium isotopes $^{48-52}$Ca
have been studied via $\gamma$-ray spectroscopy following inverse-kinematics
proton scattering on a liquid hydrogen target using the GRETINA $\gamma$-ray
tracking array. The energies and strengths of the octupole states in these
isotopes are remarkably constant, indicating that these states are dominated by
proton excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08631</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Giuppone</keyname><forenames>Cristian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leiva</keyname><forenames>Alejandro M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Secular models and Kozai resonance for planets in coorbital non-coplanar
  motion</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>15 pages. 20 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw938</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we construct and test an analytical and a semianalytical
secular models for two planets locked in a coorbital non-coplanar motion,
comparing some results with the case of restricted three body problem.
  The analytical average model replicates the numerical N-body integrations,
even for moderate eccentricities ($\lesssim$ 0.3) and inclinations
($\lesssim10^\circ$), except for the regions corresponding to quasi-satellite
and Lidov-Kozai configurations. Furthermore, this model is also useful in the
restricted three body problem, assuming very low mass ratio between the
planets. We also describe a four-degree-of-freedom semianalytical model valid
for any type of coorbital configuration in a wide range of eccentricities and
inclinations.
  {Using a N-body integrator, we have found that the phase space of the General
Three Body Problem is different to the restricted case for inclined systems,
and establish the location of the Lidov-Kozai equilibrium configurations
depending on mass ratio. We study the stability of periodic orbits in the
inclined systems, and find that apart from the robust configurations $L_4$,
$AL_4$, and $QS$ is possible to harbour two Earth-like planets in orbits
previously identified as unstable $U$ and also in Euler $L_3$ configurations,
with bounded chaos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08646</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Maulik</keyname><forenames>Romit</forenames></author><author><keyname>San</keyname><forenames>Omer</forenames></author></authors><title>A dynamic subgrid-scale modeling framework for large eddy simulation
  using approximate deconvolution</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We put forth a dynamic modeling framework for sub-grid parametrization of
large eddy simulation of turbulent flows based upon the use of the approximate
deconvolution procedure to compute the Smagorinsky constant self-adaptively
from the resolved flow quantities. Our numerical assessments for solving the
Burgers turbulence problem shows that the proposed approach could be used as a
viable tool to address the turbulence closure problem due to its flexibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08648</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Khovritchev</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames><affiliation>Pulkovo Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kulikova</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames><affiliation>Pulkovo Observatory</affiliation></author></authors><title>{\Delta}{\mu} Binaries among Stars with Large Proper Motions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>27 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, Volume 41, Issue 12, pp.833-847, 12/2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773715120063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on observations performed with the Pulkovo normal astrograph in
2008-2015 and data from sky surveys (DSS, 2MASS, SDSS DR12, WISE), we have
investigated the motions of 1308 stars with proper motions larger than 300
mas/yr down to magnitude 17. The main idea of our search for binary stars based
on this material is reduced to comparing the quasi-mean (POSS2-POSS1; an epoch
difference of $\approx$50 yr) and quasi-instantaneous (2MASS, SDSS, WISE,
Pulkovo; an epoch difference of $\approx$10 yr) proper motions. If the
difference is statistically significant compared to the proper motion errors,
then the object may be considered as a {\Delta}{\mu}-binary candidate. One
hundred and twenty one stars from among those included in the observational
program satisfy this requirement. Additional confirmations of binarity for a
number of stars have been obtained by comparing the calculated proper motions
with the data from several programs of stellar trigonometric parallax
determinations and by analyzing the asymmetry of stellar images on sky-survey
CCD frames. Analysis of the highly accurate SDSS photometric data for four
stars (J0656+3827, J0838+3940, J1229+5332, J2330+4639) allows us to reach a
conclusion about the probability that these {\Delta}{\mu} binaries are white
dwarf + M dwarf pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08650</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kharazmi</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zayernouri</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karniadakis</keyname><forenames>George Em</forenames></author></authors><title>Petrov-Galerkin and Spectral Collocation Methods for distributed Order
  Differential Equations</title><categories>math.NA math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Distributed order fractional operators offer a rigorous tool for mathematical
modelling of multi-physics phenomena, where the differential orders are
distributed over a range of values rather than being just a fixed
integer/fraction as it is in standard/fractional ODEs/PDEs. We develop two
spectrally-accurate schemes, namely a Petrov-Galerkin spectral method and a
spectral collocation method for distributed order fractional differential
equations. These schemes are developed based on the fractional Sturm-Liouville
eigen-problems (FSLPs). In the Petrov-Galerkin method, we employ fractional
(non-polynomial) basis functions, called \textit{Jacobi poly-fractonomials},
which are the eigenfunctions of the FSLP of first kind, while, we employ
another space of test functions as the span of poly-fractonomial eigenfunctions
of the FSLP of second kind. We define the underlying \textit{distributed
Sobolev space} and the associated norms, where we carry out the corresponding
discrete stability and error analyses of the proposed scheme. In the
collocation scheme, we employ fractional (non-polynomial) Lagrange interpolants
satisfying the Kronecker delta property at the collocation points.
Subsequently, we obtain the corresponding distributed differentiation matrices
to be employed in the discretization of the strong problem. We perform
systematic numerical tests to demonstrate the efficiency and conditioning of
each method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08652</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Nesterov</keyname><forenames>Alexander I</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berman</keyname><forenames>Gennady P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>M&#xf3;nica F</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical model of the kinesin protein motor</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>LA-UR-16-22931</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We model and simulate the stepping dynamics of the kinesin motor including
electric and mechanical forces, environmental noise, and the complicated
potentials produced by tracking and neighboring protofilaments. Our dynamical
model supports the hand-over-hand mechanism of the kinesin stepping. Our
theoretical predictions and numerical simulations include the off-axis
displacements of the kinesin heads while the steps are performed. The results
obtained are in a good agreement with recent experiments on the kinesin
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08665</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yan-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Mao-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zhu-Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Connecting the UMEB in $\mathbb{C}^{d}\bigotimes\mathbb{C}^{d}$ with
  partial Hadamard matrices</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the unextendible maximally entangled bases (UMEB) in
$\mathbb{C}^{d}\bigotimes\mathbb{C}^{d}$ and connect it with the partial
Hadamard matrix. Firstly, we show that for a given special UMEB in
$\mathbb{C}^{d}\bigotimes\mathbb{C}^{d}$, there is a partial Hadamard matrix
can not extend to a complete Hadamard matrix in $\mathbb{C}^{d}$. As a
corollary, any $(d-1)\times d$ partial Hadamard matrix can extend to a complete
Hadamard matrix. Then we obtain that for any $d$ there is an UMEB except $d=p\
\text{or}\ 2p$, where $p\equiv 3\mod 4$ and $p$ is a prime. Finally, we argue
that there exist different kinds of constructions of UMEB in
$\mathbb{C}^{nd}\bigotimes\mathbb{C}^{nd}$ for any $n\in \mathbb{N}$ and
$d=3\times5 \times7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08673</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bilu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yuqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Anyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbas</keyname><forenames>Ahmad N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yihang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Chenfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Haochuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Chongwu</forenames></author></authors><title>High Performance WSe2 Field-Effect Transistors via Controlled Formation
  of In-Plane Heterojunctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>26 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Monolayer WSe2 is a two dimensional (2D) semiconductor with a direct bandgap,
and it has been recently explored as a promising material for electronics and
optoelectronics. Low field effect mobility is the main constraint preventing
WSe2 from becoming one of the competing channel materials for field-effect
transistors (FETs). Recent results have demonstrated that chemical treatments
can modify the electrical properties of transition metal dichalcogenides
(TMDCs) including MoS2 and WSe2. Here, we report that controlled heating in air
significantly improves device performance of WSe2 FETs in terms of on-state
currents and field-effect mobilities. Specifically, after heating at optimized
conditions, chemical vapor deposition grown monolayer WSe2 FETs showed an
average FET mobility of 31 cm2/Vs and on/off current ratios up to 5*108. For
few-layer WSe2 FETs, after the same treatment applied, we achieved a high
mobility up to 92 cm2/Vs. These values are significantly higher than FETs
fabricated using as-grown WSe2 flakes without heating treatment, demonstrating
the effectiveness of air heating on the performance improvements of WSe2 FETs.
The underlying chemical processes involved during air heating and the formation
of in-plane heterojunctions of WSe2 and WO3-x, which is believed to be the
reason for the improved FET performance, were studied by spectroscopy and
transmission electron microscopy. We further demonstrated that by combining air
heating method developed in this work with supporting 2D materials on BN
substrate, we achieved a noteworthy field effect mobility of 83 cm2/Vs for
monolayer WSe2 FETs. This work is a step towards controlled modification of the
properties of WSe2 and potentially other TMDCs, and may greatly improve device
performance for future applications of 2D materials in electronics and
optoelectronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08674</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Mikami</keyname><forenames>Keita</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric Scattering for Schr\&quot;odinger Operators with Asymptotically
  Homogeneous Potentials of Order Zero</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><msc-class>58J50, 35P25, 81U05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we consider Schr\&quot;oodinger operators with potentials of order
zero on asymptotically conic manifolds. We prove the existence and the
completeness of the wave operators with a naturally defined free Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08686</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Yongliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Wenhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chuhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Jianhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity and abnormal pressure effect in Sr0.5La0.5FBiSe2
  superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Superconductor Science and Technology, 29, 04LT03, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-2048/29/4/04LT03</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Through the solid state reaction method, we synthesized a new BiSe2-based
superconductor Sr0:5La0:5FBiSe2 with superconducting transition temperature
Tc?3.8 K. A strong diamagnetic signal below Tc in susceptibility ?(T) is
observed indicating the bulk nature of superconductivity. Different to most
BiS2-based compounds where superconductivity develops from a
semiconducting-like normal state, the present compound exhibits a metallic
behavior down to Tc. Under weak magnetic field or pressure, however, a
remarkable crossover from metallic to insulating behaviors takes place around
Tmin where the resistivity picks up a local minimum. With increasing pressure,
Tc decreases monotonously and Tmin shifts to high temperatures, while the
absolute value of the normal state resistivity at low temperatures first
decreases and then increases with pressure up to 2.5 GPa. These results imply
that the electronic structure of Sr0:5La0:5FBiSe2 may be different to those in
the other BiS2-based systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08689</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rafelski</keyname><forenames>Johann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birrell</keyname><forenames>Jeremiah</forenames></author></authors><title>The hot Hagedorn Universe</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages; EPJ Web of Conferences; presented at 4th International
  Conference on New Frontiers in Physics (ICNFP 2015) 23-30 Aug 2015,Kolymbari,
  Greece</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of the half-centenary of Hagedorn temperature and the
statistical bootstrap model (SBM) we present a short account of how these
insights coincided with the establishment of the hot big-bang model (BBM) and
helped resolve some of the early philosophical difficulties. We then turn
attention to the present day context and show the dominance of strong
interaction quark and gluon degrees of freedom in the early stage, helping to
characterize the properties of the hot Universe. We focus attention on the
current experimental insights about cosmic microwave background (CMB)
temperature fluctuation, and develop a much improved understanding of the
neutrino freeze-out, in this way paving the path to the opening of a direct
connection of quark-gluon plasma (QGP) physics in the early Universe with the
QCD-lattice, and the study of the properties of QGP formed in the laboratory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08690</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rafelski</keyname><forenames>Johann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirsch</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Berndt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinhardt</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing QED Vacuum with Heavy Ions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>40 pages, Presented by JR at the International Symposium on&quot;New
  Horizons in Fundamental Physics: From Neutrons Nuclei via Superheavy Elements
  and Supercritical Fields to Neutron Stars and Cosmic Rays,&quot; held to honor
  Walter Greiner on his 80th birthday at Makutsi Safari Farm, South Africa,
  November 23-29, 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recall how nearly half a century ago the proposal was made to explore the
structure of the quantum vacuum using slow heavy-ion collisions. Pursuing this
topic we review the foundational concept of spontaneous vacuum decay
accompanied by observable positron emission in heavy-ion collisions and
describe the related theoretical developments in strong fields QED.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08707</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Hua</keyname><forenames>Congyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yi-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Deterministic remote preparation of an arbitrary qubit state using a
  partially entangled state and finite classical communication</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages,2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a deterministic remote state preparation (RSP) scheme for
preparing an arbitrary (including pure and mixed) qubit, where a partially
entangled state and finite classical communication are used. To our knowledge,
our scheme is the first RSP scheme that fits into this category. One other RSP
scheme proposed by Berry shares close features, but can only be used to prepare
an arbitrary pure qubit. Even so, our scheme saves classical communication by
approximate 1 bit per prepared qubit under equal conditions. When using a
maximally entangled state, the classical communication for our scheme is 2
bits, which agrees with Lo's conjecture on the resource cost. Furthermore Alice
can switch between our RSP scheme and a standard teleportation scheme without
letting Bob know, which makes the quantum channel multipurpose.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08718</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Mal</keyname><forenames>Shiladitya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Home</keyname><forenames>Dipankar</forenames></author></authors><title>Sharing of Nonlocality of a single member of an Entangled Pair Is Not
  Possible by More Than Two Unbiased Observers on the other wing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the recently posed question as to whether the nonlocality of a
single member of an entangled pair of spin $1/2$ particles can be shared among
multiple observers on the other wing who act sequentially and independently of
each other [1]. We first show that the optimality condition for the trade-off
between information gain and disturbance in the context of weak or non-ideal
measurements emerges naturally when one employs a one-parameter class of
positive operator valued measures (POVMs). Using this formalism we then prove
analytically that it is impossible to obtain violation of the
Clauser-Horne-Shimony-Holt (CHSH) inequality by more than two Bobs in one of
the two wings using unbiased input settings with an Alice in the other wing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08721</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Birtea</keyname><forenames>Petre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Com&#x103;nescu</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics under Geometric Dissipation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give sufficient conditions for asymptotic stabilization of equilibrium
points and periodic orbits of a dynamical system when we add a geometric
dissipation of gradient type. We also describe the domain of attraction in the
case of asymptotic stability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08739</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Information Theory and Statistical Mechanics Revisited</title><categories>math-ph cs.IT math.IT math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive Bose-Einstein statistics and Fermi-Dirac statistics by Principle of
Maximum Entropy applied to two families of entropy functions different from the
Boltzmann-Gibbs-Shannon entropy. These entropy functions are identified with
special cases of modified Naudts' $\phi$-entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08745</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Mason J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Huiwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burch</keyname><forenames>Kenneth S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magneto-Elastic Coupling in a potential ferromagnetic 2D Atomic Crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cr2Ge2Te6 has been of interest for decades, as it is one of only a few
naturally forming ferromagnetic semiconductors. Recently, this material has
been revisited due to its potential as a 2 dimensional semiconducting
ferromagnet and a substrate to induce anomalous quantum Hall states in
topological insulators. However, many relevant properties of Cr2Ge2Te6 still
remain poorly understood, especially the spin-phonon coupling crucial to
spintronic, multiferrioc, thermal conductivity, magnetic proximity and the
establishment of long range order on the nanoscale. We explore the interplay
between the lattice and magnetism through high resolution micro-Raman
scattering measurements over the temperature range from 10 K to 325 K. Strong
spin-phonon coupling effects are confirmed from multiple aspects: two low
energy modes splits in the ferromagnetic phase, magnetic quasielastic
scattering in paramagnetic phase, the phonon energies of three modes show clear
upturn below Tc, and the phonon linewidths change dramatically below Tc as
well. Our results provide the first demonstration of spin-phonon coupling in a
potential 2 dimensional atomic crystal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08747</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Damm</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dung</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vewinger</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weitz</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klaers</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Calorimetry of a Bose-Einstein condensed photon gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>14 pages, including 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 11340 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms11340</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phase transitions, as the condensation of a gas to a liquid, are often
revealed by a discontinuous behavior of thermodynamic quantities. For liquid
Helium, for example, a divergence of the specific heat signals the transition
from the normal fluid to the superfluid state. Apart from liquid helium,
determining the specific heat of a Bose gas has proven to be a challenging
task, for example for ultracold atomic Bose gases. Here we examine the
thermodynamic behavior of a trapped two-dimensional photon gas, a system that
allows us to spectroscopically determine the specific heat and the entropy of a
nearly ideal Bose gas from the classical high temperature to the Bose-condensed
quantum regime. The critical behavior at the phase transition is clearly
revealed by a cusp singularity of the specific heat. Regarded as a test of
quantum statistical mechanics, our results demonstrate a quantitative agreement
with its predictions at the microscopic level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08753</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rich</keyname><forenames>Sami Abou</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leroy</keyname><forenames>P</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nittler</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pireaux</keyname><forenames>Jean Jacques</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-density polyethylene films treated by an atmospheric Ar--O2
  post-discharge: functionalization, etching, degradation and partial recovery
  of the native wettability state</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Physics D: Applied Physics, IOP Publishing, 2014, 47
  (6), pp.065203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0022-3727/47/6/065203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To optimize the adhesion of layers presenting strong barrier properties on
low-density polyethylene (LDPE) surfaces, we investigated the influence of
argon and argon-oxygen atmospheric pressure post-discharges. This study was
performed using x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, atomic force microscopy,
optical emission spectroscopy (OES) and dynamic water contact angle (WCA)
measurements. After the plasma treatment, a slight increase in the roughness
was emphasized, more particularly for the samples treated in a post-discharge
supplied in oxygen. Measurements of the surface roughness and of the oxygen
surface concentration suggested the competition of two processes playing a role
on the surface hydrophilicity and occurring during the post-discharge
treatment: the etching and the activation of the surface. The etching rate was
estimated to about 2.7 nm.s-1 and 5.8 nm.s-1 for Ar and Ar-O2 post-discharges,
respectively. The mechanisms underlying this etching were investigated through
experiments, in which we discuss the influence of the O2 flow rate and the
distance (gap) separating the plasma torch from the LDPE surface located
downstream. O atoms and NO molecules (emitting in the UV range) detected by OES
seem to be good candidates to explain the etching process. An ageing study is
also presented to evidence the stability of the treated surfaces over 60 days.
After 60 days of storage, we showed that whatever the O2 flow rate, the treated
films registered a loss of their hydrophilic state since their WCA increased
towards a common threshold of 80{\textdegree}. This 'hydrophobic recovery'
effect was mostly attributed to the reorientation of induced polar chemical
groups into the bulk of the material. Indeed, the relative concentrations of
the carbonyl and carboxyl groups at the surface decreased with the storage time
and seemed to reach a plateau after 30 days.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08754</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rich</keyname><forenames>Sami Abou</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leroy</keyname><forenames>Perrine</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nittler</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pireaux</keyname><forenames>Jean-Jacques</forenames><affiliation>PMR</affiliation></author></authors><title>LDPE Surface Modifications Induced by Atmospheric Plasma Torches with
  Linear and Showerhead Configurations</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Processes and Polymers, Wiley-VCH Verlag, 2015, 12 (8),
  pp.771-785</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/ppap.201400097</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low density polyethylene (LDPE) surfaces have been plasma modified to improve
their nanostructural and wettability properties. These modifications can
significantly improve the deposition of subsequent layers such as films with
specific barrier properties. For this purpose, we compare the treatments
induced by two atmospheric plasma torches with different configurations
(showerhead vs. linear). The modifications of LDPE films in terms of chemical
surface composition and surface morphology are evidenced by X-ray photoelectron
spectro-scopy, water contact angles measurements, and atomic force microscopy.
A comparison between the two post-discharge treatments is achieved for several
torch-to-substrate distances (gaps), treatment times, and oxygen flow rates in
terms of etching rate, roughening rate, diffusion of oxygen into the
subsur-face and hydrophilicity. By correlating these results with the chemical
composition of the post-discharges, we identify and compare the 'species which
are responsible for the chemical surface functionalization, the surface
roughening, and etching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08755</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozkan</keyname><forenames>Alp</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Tiago</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Britun</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Snyders</keyname><forenames>Rony</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bogaerts</keyname><forenames>Annemie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>The influence of power and frequency on the filamentary behavior of a
  flowing DBD-application to the splitting of CO2</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology, IOP Publishing, 2016, 25
  (2)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0963-0252/25/2/025013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this experimental study, a flowing dielectric barrier discharge operating
at atmospheric pressure is used for the splitting of CO2 into O2 and CO. The
influence of the applied frequency and plasma power on the microdischarge
properties is investigated to understand their role on the CO2 conversion.
Electrical measurements are carried out to explain the conversion trends and to
characterize the microdischarges through their number, their lifetime, their
intensity and the induced electrical charge. Their influence on the gas and
electrode temperatures is also evidenced through optical emission spectroscopy
and infrared imaging. It is shown that, in our configuration, the conversion
depends mostly on the charge delivered in the plasma and not on the effective
plasma voltage when the applied power is modified. Similarly, at constant total
current, a better conversion is observed at low frequencies, where a less
filamentary discharge regime with a higher effective plasma voltage than that
at a higher frequency is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08792</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Kulsreshath</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schwaederle</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Overzet</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lefaucheux</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dussart</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Ignition and extinction phenomena in helium micro hollow cathode
  discharges</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics, American Institute of Physics, 2013,
  114 (24), pp.243303</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4858418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Micro hollow cathode discharges (MHCD) were produced using 250 m thick
dielectric layer of alumina sandwiched between two nickel electrodes of 8 m
thickness. A through cavity at the center of the chip was formed by laser
drilling technique. MHCD with a diameter of few hundreds of micrometers allowed
us to generate direct current discharges in helium at up to atmospheric
pressure. A slowly varying ramped voltage generator was used to study the
ignition and the extinction periods of the microdischarges. The analysis was
performed by using electrical characterisation of the V-I behaviour and the
measurement of He*(3S1) metastable atoms density by tunable diode laser
spectroscopy. At the ignition of the microdischarges, 2 s long current peak as
high as 24 mA was observed, sometimes followed by low amplitude damped
oscillations. At helium pressure above 400 Torr, an oscillatory behaviour of
the discharge current was observed just before the extinction of the
microdischarges. The same type of instability in the extinction period at high
pressure also appeared on the density of He*(3S1) metastable atoms, but delayed
by a few s relative to the current oscillations. Metastable atoms thus cannot
be at the origin of the generation of the observed instabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08794</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Overzet</keyname><forenames>Lawrence J.</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mandra</keyname><forenames>Monali</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goeckner</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dussart</keyname><forenames>Remi</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lefaucheux</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author></authors><title>RF impedance measurements of DC atmospheric micro-discharges</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal D, EDP Sciences, 2010, 60,
  pp.449-454</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2010-00274-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The available diagnostics for atmospheric micro-plasmas remain limited and
relatively complex to implement; so we present a radio-frequency technique for
diagnosing a key parameter here. The technique allows one to estimate the
dependencies of the electron density by measuring the RF-impedance of the
micro-plasma and analyzing it with an appropriate equivalent circuit. This
technique is inexpensive, can be used in real time and gives reasonable results
for argon and helium DC micro-plasmas in holes over a wide pressure range. The
electron density increases linearly with current in the expected range
consistent with normal glow discharge behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08795</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Collette</keyname><forenames>S</forenames><affiliation>UMons</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>UMons</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Viville</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames><affiliation>UMons</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Reactivity of water vapor in an atmospheric pressure DBD -Application to
  LDPE surfaces</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>ISPC-22, Jul 2015, Antwerp, Belgium. 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reactivity of water vapor introduced in an atmospheric dielectric barrier
discharge supplied in argon is investigated through optical emission
spectroscopy measurements. This discharge is also used for the treatment of
LDPE surfaces. Water contact angles measurements, XPS and AFM techniques are
used to study the grafting of oxygen functions on the LDPE surface and increase
its hydrophilicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08796</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Duluard</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of ambient air on the flowing afterglow of an atmospheric
  pressure Ar/O2 radiofrequency plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics, American Institute of Physics, 2013,
  113 (9), pp.093303</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4794324</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of ambient air on the flowing afterglow of an atmospheric
pressure Ar/O2 radiofrequency plasma has been investigated experimentally.
Spatially resolved mass spectrometry and laser induced fluorescence on OH
radicals were used to estimate the intrusion of air in between the plasma torch
and the substrate as a function of the torch-to-substrate separation distance.
No air is detected, within the limits of measurement uncertainties, for
separation distances smaller than 5 mm. For larger distances, the effect of
ambient air can no longer be neglected, and radial gradients in the
concentrations of species appear. The Ar 4p population, determined through
absolute optical emission spectroscopy, is seen to decrease with separation
distance, whereas a rise in emission from the N2(C--B) system is measured. The
observed decay in Ar 4p and N2(C) populations for separation distances greater
than 9mm is partly assigned to the increasing collisional quenching rate by N2
and O2 molecules from the entrained air. Absorption measurements also point to
the formation of ozone at concentrations from 10^14 to 10^15 cm-3, depending
both on the injected O2 flow rate and the torch-to-substrate separation
distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08798</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rich</keyname><forenames>Sami Abou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leroy</keyname><forenames>Perrine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehbe</keyname><forenames>Nimer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houssiau</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>In-depth diffusion of oxygen into LDPE exposed to an Ar--O2 atmospheric
  post-discharge: a complementary approach between AR-XPS and Tof-SIMS
  techniques</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Surface and Interface Analysis, Wiley-Blackwell, 2014, 46 (3),
  pp.164-174</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/sia.5403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The in-depth oxygen diffusion into a low density polyethylene film is
performed in the post-discharge of an atmospheric plasma torch, supplied in
argon as carrier gas and with or without oxygen as reactive gas. The chemical
and structural properties of the polymer surface and bulk are studied in terms
of plasma parameters (treatment time, power, and reactive gas flow rate). A
good correlation between XPS and Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy
analyses is demonstrated. The penetration depth of oxygen into the bulk of the
polymer is investigated by angle resolved-XPS and time-of-flight SIMS. It is
shown that, depending on the plasma conditions, oxygen could penetrate up to
20--40 nm into the low density polyethylene during the atmospheric plasma
treatment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08802</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dussart</keyname><forenames>Remi</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Overzet</keyname><forenames>Lawrence J.</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lefaucheux</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ranson</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. -B</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mandra</keyname><forenames>Monali</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goeckner</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>Nader</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct current parallel microdischarges in helium</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>ISPC-18, Aug 2007, Kyoto, Japan. 2007</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Parallel Micro Hollow Cathodes Discharges are characterised by electrical and
spectroscopic studies and by using an ICCD camera. V-I curves present a
hysteresis cycle between Townsend and normal glow regimes. For I d =4-10mA, gas
temperature ranges between 300-500{\textdegree}C. When the diameter of a hole
decreases, a more significant discharge voltage is needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08803</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>El-Mourad</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Vos</keyname><forenames>Caroline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrogen peroxide generated by an atmospheric He-O2-H2O flowing
  post-discharge: production mechanisms and absolute quantification</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>ISPC-22, Jul 2015, Antwerp, Belgium. 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An atmospheric plasma torch has been supplied with a gaseous mixture of
helium, water vapour and/or oxygen to study the production of reactive species
within its flowing post-discharge, in particular hydrogen peroxide. The
mechanisms responsible for the production of H2O2 have been investigated by
correlating measurements of mass spectrometry and absorption photospectrometry.
An absolute quantification of H2O2 has also been achieved and indicated that
for 5 mmol of water vapour injected in the He-H2O discharge, approximately 9.5
mol of H2O2 were produced in post-discharge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08807</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Wren</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Mass Ordering Studies with PINGU and IceCube/DeepCore</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Precision IceCube Next Generation Upgrade (PINGU) is a proposed extension
to the IceCube detector. The design of PINGU would augment the existing 86
strings with an additional 40 with the main goal of determining the neutrino
mass ordering (NMO). Preliminary studies of the NMO can start with
IceCube/DeepCore, a sub-array of more densely- packed strings in operation
since 2011. This detector has a neutrino energy threshold of roughly 10 GeV and
allows for high-statistics datasets of atmospheric neutrinos to be collected.
This data provides a unique opportunity to better understand the systematic
effects involved in making the NMO measurement by comparing the simulation
studies to real data. These proceedings will present the current status of
these studies in Monte Carlo simulations with projected DeepCore sensitivity
for the NMO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08811</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Overzet</keyname><forenames>Lawrence J.</forenames><affiliation>PSAL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dussart</keyname><forenames>Remi</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pitchford</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames><affiliation>CPAT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>N</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lefaucheux</keyname><forenames>P</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kulsreshath</keyname><forenames>M</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ranson</keyname><forenames>P</forenames><affiliation>GREMI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Experimental study and simulation of a micro-discharge with limited
  cathode area</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal D, EDP Sciences, 2010, 60,
  pp.565-574</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2010-00273-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report in this paper simulation results and experimental measurements to
characterize a micro-discharge generated in a single micro cavity device
operating in helium. By spatially limiting the cathode surface area using a
dielectric layer, we demonstrate the ability of the micro-discharge to work in
a steady-state abnormal glow regime. The physical properties of this regime are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08815</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandencasteele</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desbief</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazzaroni</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Etching Processes of Polytetrafluoroethylene Surfaces Exposed to He and
  He-O2 Atmospheric Post-discharges</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Langmuir, American Chemical Society, 2012, 18 (25), pp.9466-9474</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/la300822j</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A comparative study of polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) surfaces treated by the
post-discharge of He and He-O2 plasmas at atmospheric pressure is presented.
The characterization of treated PTFE surfaces and the species involved in the
surface modification are related. In pure He plasmas, no significant change of
the surface has been observed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS),
dynamic water contact angles (dWCA) and atomic force microscopy (AFM), in spite
of important mass losses recorded. According to these observations, a
layer-by-layer physical etching without any preferential orientation is
proposed, where the highly energetic helium metastables are the main species
responsible for the scission of --(CF2)n-- chains. In He--O 2 plasmas, as the
density of helium metastables decreases as a function of the oxygen flow rate,
the treatment leads to fewer species ejected from the PTFE surfaces (in
agreement with mass loss measurements and the detection of fluorinated species
onto aluminum foil). However, the dWCA and AFM measurements show an increase in
the hydrophobicity and the roughness of the surface. The observed alveolar
structures are assumed to be caused by an anisotropic etching where the oxygen
atoms etch mainly the amorphous phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08818</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandencasteele</keyname><forenames>N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical mechanisms inducing a dc current measured in the flowing
  post-discharge of an RF He-O2 plasma torch</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology, IOP Publishing, 2012, 21,
  045013 (10pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0963-0252/21/4/045013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The post-discharge of an RF plasma torch supplied with helium and oxygen
gases is characterized by mass spectrometry, optical emission spectroscopy and
electrical measurements. We have proved the existence of a dc current in the
post-discharge (1--20 A), attributed to the Penning ionization of atmospheric
nitrogen and oxygenated species. The mechanisms ruling this dc current are
investigated through experiments in which we discuss the influence of the O2
flow rate, the He flow rate and the distance separating the plasma torch from a
material surface located downstream.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08825</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Favre</keyname><forenames>Maroussia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sornette</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames></author></authors><title>Forms of social relationships in distinct cultural settings</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We contribute to the understanding of social relationships within cultural
contexts by proposing a connection between a social theory, relational models
theory (RMT: Fiske 1991, 1992) and a social and political one, cultural or
plural rationality theory (PRT: Douglas, 1982, Thompson et al., 1990). Drawing
examples from the literature of both theories, we argue that each relational
model of RMT may be implemented in ways compatible with each cultural bias of
PRT. A cultural bias restrains the range of congruent implementations of
relational models, but does not preclude any relational model altogether. This
stands in contrast to earlier reconciliation attempts between PRT and RMT.
Based on hypothetical one-to-one mappings, these attempts expect each cultural
setting to be significantly associated with some, but not all, relational
models. The framework we develop helps explain the findings of these previous
attempts and provides insights into empirical research by clarifying which
associations to expect between relationships and cultural contexts. We discuss
the theoretical basis of our framework, including the idea that RMT and PRT
apply to different levels of analysis: RMT's relational models are tied to
relationships between two actors and PRT's cultural biases to structures of
social networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08854</id><created>2016-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhirnov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>Aleksey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesterov</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karasik</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svelto</keyname><forenames>Cesare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pnev</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of laser frequency drift in phase-sensitive optical time-domain
  reflectometry fiber sensors</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.data-an physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work studies the influence of laser frequency drifts on operating
of phase-sensitive optical time-domain reflectometry ($\Phi$-OTDR) fiber
sensors. A mathematical model and numerical simulations are employed to
highlight the influence of frequency drifts of light sources on two
characteristic scales: large-time (minutes) and short-time (milliseconds)
frequency drifts. Numerical simulation results are compared with predictions
given by the fluctuation ratio coefficient (FRC), and they are in a qualitative
agreement. In addition to qualitative criteria for light sources given by the
FRC, quantitive requirements for optimal light sources for $\Phi$-OTDR sensors
are obtained. Numerical simulation results are verified by comparison with
experimental data for three significantly different types of light source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08892</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Unger</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Th&#xfc;rmer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aziz</keyname><forenames>E. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cederbaum</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muchov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slav&#xed;&#x10d;ek</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kryzhevoi</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>First Observation of Electron Transfer Mediated Decay in Aqueous
  Solutions: A Novel Probe of Ion Pairing</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to Nature Chemistry 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major goal of many spectroscopic techniques is to provide comprehensive
information on the local chemical environment. Electron transfer mediated decay
(ETMD) is a sensitive probe of the environment since it is actively involved in
this non-local radiationless decay process through electron and energy transfer
steps. We report the first experimental observation of ETMD in the liquid
phase. Using liquid-jet X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy we explore LiCl
aqueous solution, and detect low-energy electrons unambiguously emerging from
the ETMD processes of core-ionized Li+. We interpret the experimental results
with molecular dynamics and high-level ab initio calculations. By considering
various solvation-structure models we show that both water molecules and Cl-
anions can participate in ETMD, with each process having its characteristic
spectral fingerprint. Different ion associations lead to different spectral
shapes. The potential application of the unique sensitivity of the ETMD
spectroscopy to the local hydration structure and ion pairing is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08899</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Trodden</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical Aspects of Cosmic Acceleration</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures. Invited plenary talk at the Dark Side of the
  Universe conference, Kyoto, Japan, December 2015. To appear in the
  proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Efforts to understand and map the possible explanations for the late time
acceleration of the universe have led to a broad range of suggestions, ranging
from the cosmological constant and straightforward dark energy, to exotically
coupled models, to infrared modifications of General Relativity. If we are to
uncover which, if any, of these approaches might provide a serious answer to
the problem, it is crucial to understand the constraints that theoretical
consistency places on the models, and on the regimes in which they make
predictions. In this talk, delivered as an invited plenary lecture at the Dark
Side of the Universe conference in Kyoto, Japan, I briefly describe some modern
attempts to carry out this program and some of the more interesting ideas that
have emerged. As an example, I use the Galileon model, discussing how the
Vainshtein mechanism occurs, and how a number of these theoretical problems
arise around such backgrounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08930</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Raghoonundun</keyname><forenames>Ambrish M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Solutions for Compact Objects in General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>314 pages, PhD Thesis, defended on 12 April 2016. Separate chapters
  will be published subsequently as journal articles</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Seven new solutions to the interior static and spherically symmetric
Einstein's field equations (EFE) are found and investigated. These new
solutions are a generalisation of the quadratic density fall-off profile of the
Tolman VII solution. The generalisation involves the addition of anisotropic
pressures and electric charge to the density profile. Of these new solutions
three are found to obey all the necessary conditions of physical acceptability,
including linear stability under radial perturbations, and causality of the
speed of pressure waves inside the object. Additionally an equation of state
can be found for all the physically viable solutions. The generalised pulsation
equation for interior solutions to the EFE that include both electric charge
and pressure anisotropy is derived and used to determine the stability of the
solutions. However the pulsation equation found is general and can be used for
all new solutions that contain these ingredients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08931</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghimire</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thapa</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic Mott-Insulating State in Double Perovskites Gd2MgIrO6</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the electronic and magnetic properties of double perovskites
Gd2MgIrO6 by first-principles density functional theory (DFT). Based on the DFT
calculations, Gd2MgIrO6 is found to have a ferromagnetic (FM) ground state. The
material undergo half-metallic ferromagnets to Mott-Hubbard insulator
transition which happens due to strong correlation in Gd-4f and Ir-5d states.
Our results shows that the 5d electrons of Ir hybridize strongly with O-2p
states near the Fermi level giving rise to the insulating state of Gd2MgIrO6.
Our study suggests that the enhanced magnetic moment is a result of itinerant
exchange rather than the exchange interaction involving individual ions of Gd
and Ir atoms. The total magnetic moment calculated in the present studies is 15
{\mu}B per formula unit for Gd2MgIrO6.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08948</id><created>2016-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrovic</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ca$_3$Ir$_4$Sn$_{13}$: A weakly correlated nodeless superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 86, 024522 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.86.024522</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report detailed Seebeck coefficient, Hall resistivity as well as specific
heat measurement on Ca$_3$Ir$_4$Sn$_{13}$ single crystals. The Seebeck
coefficient exhibits a peak corresponding to the anomaly in resistivity at
$T^*$, and the carrier density is suppressed significantly below $T^*$. This
indicates a significant Fermi surface reconstruction and the opening of the
charge density wave gap at the supperlattice transition. The magnetic field
induced enhancement of the residual specific heat coefficient $\gamma(H)$
exhibits a nearly linear dependence on magnetic field, indicating a nodeless
gap. In the temperature range close to $T_c$ the Seebeck coefficient can be
described well by the diffusion model. The zero-temperature extrapolated
thermoelectric power is very small, implying large normalized Fermi
temperature. Consequently the ratio $\frac{T_c}{T_F}$ is very small. Our
results indicate that Ca$_3$Ir$_4$Sn$_{13}$ is a weakly correlated nodeless
superconductor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0307545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0307545</id><created>2003-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Drazer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auradou</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koplik</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hulin</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractal fronts in fractal fractures: large and small-scale structure</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Submitted to Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 92, 014501 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.92.014501</doi><abstract>  The evolution and spatial structure of displacement fronts in fractures with
self-affine rough walls are studied by numerical simulations. The fractures are
open and the two faces are identical but shifted along their mean plane, either
parallel or perpendicular to the flow. An initially flat front advected by the
flow is progressively distorted into a self-affine front with Hurst exponent
equal to that of the fracture walls. The lower cutoff of the self-affine regime
depends on the aperture and lateral shift, while the upper cutoff grows
linearly with the width of the front.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ph/0507187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ph/0507187</id><created>2005-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Okiharu</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>Nihon U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>RIKEN BNL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ichie</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Tokyo Inst. Tech.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Iida</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Tokyo Inst. Tech.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Tokyo Inst. Tech.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Tokyo Inst. Tech.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Suganuma</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Tokyo Inst. Tech.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>T. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tetraquark and Pentaquark Systems in Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 3 tables, 16 figures. Talk given at International Workshop
  on Quark Nuclear Physics 2005 (QNP05), Phoenix Park, Korea, 22-24, Feb., 2005</comments><journal-ref>J.Mod.Phys. 7 (2016) 774-789</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jmp.2016.78072</doi><abstract>  Motivated by the recent experimental discoveries of multi-quark candidates,
e.g., the $\Theta^+(1540)$, we study multi-quark systems in lattice QCD. First,
we perform accurate mass measurements of low-lying 5Q states with $J=1/2$ and
I=0 in both positive- and negative-parity channels in anisotropic lattice QCD.
The lowest positive-parity 5Q state is found to have a large mass of about
2.24GeV after the chiral extrapolation. To single out the compact 5Q state from
$NK$ scattering states, we develop a new method with the hybrid-boundary
condition (HBC), and find no evidence of the compact 5Q state below 1.75GeV in
the negative-parity channel. Second, we perform the first study of the
multi-quark potential in lattice QCD to clarify the inter-quark interaction in
multi-quark systems. The 5Q potential $V_{\rm 5Q}$ for the QQ-${\rm
\bar{Q}}$-QQ system is found to be well described by the ``OGE Coulomb plus
multi-Y Ansatz&quot;: the sum of the one-gluon-exchange (OGE) Coulomb term and the
multi-Y-type linear term based on the flux-tube picture. The 4Q potential
$V_{\rm 4Q}$ for the QQ-${\rm \bar{Q}\bar{Q}}$ system is also described by the
OGE Coulomb plus multi-Y Ansatz, when QQ and $\rm \bar Q \bar Q$ are well
separated. The 4Q system is described as a &quot;two-meson&quot; state with disconnected
flux tubes, when the nearest quark and antiquark pair is spatially close. We
observe a lattice-QCD evidence for the ``flip-flop'', i.e., the flux-tube
recombination between the connected 4Q state and the ``two-meson'' state. On
the confinement mechanism, the lattice QCD results indicate the flux-tube-type
linear confinement in multi-quark hadrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0407062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0407062</id><created>2004-07-08</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernando</keyname><forenames>Sharmanthie</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational perturbation and quasi-normal modes of charged black holes
  in Einstein-Born-Infeld gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages and 10 figures, references added, figures are replaced and
  few changes to text is done</comments><journal-ref>Gen.Rel.Grav. 37 (2005) 585-604</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-005-0044-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Born-Infeld electrodynamics has attracted considerable interest due to its
relation to strings and D-branes. In this paper the gravitational perturbations
of electrically charged black holes in Einstein-Born-Infeld gravity are
studied. Effective potentials for axial perturbations are derived and
discussed. The quasi normal modes for the gravitational perturbations are
computed using the WKB method. The modes are compared with those of the
Reissner-Nordstrom black hole. The relation of the quasi normal modes with the
non-linear parameter and the spherical index are also investigated. Comments on
stability of the black hole and on future directions are made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
