<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:42:45Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-11-27" from="2016-11-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0710.5684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0710.5684</id><created>2007-10-30</created><updated>2010-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fatkullin</keyname><forenames>Nail</forenames></author></authors><title>Why Does the Rouse Model Works at Least Satisfactorily at Polymer
  Molecular Masses M&lt;M_c ?</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author, an extended and improved
  version is: N.F.Fatkullin, T.V.Shakirov, N.A.Balakirev, Why Does the Rouse
  Model Fairly Describe the Dynamical Characteristics of Polymer Melts at
  Molecular Masses below Critical Mass? Polymer Science, Ser. A, 2010, V.52,
  No. 1, pp. 72-81</comments><abstract>  Generalization of the Rouse model without any use of the postulates
concerning the Gaussian distribution of the vector connecting the ends of
segments is advanced. In the initial (in general, nonlinear) Langevin
equations, self-averaging over continuous fragments of a macromolecule
naturally defines a linear term for the tagged chain, and this term differs
from the entropy term of the classical Rouse model only by the numerical
coefficient. According to the inertia-free approximation, the initial decay
rates of correlation functions for the normal modes are described by the Rouse
model independently of the character of fluctuations of the vector connecting
the ends of the Kuhn segment. This statement is valid for any moment if the
initial Langevin equations are treated in terms of the approximation of dynamic
self-consistency. Simulation of the Fraenkel chains by the method of Brownian
dynamics shows that decay of autocorrelation functions of shortwave normal
modes is fairly described by the linearized equations for a given model of a
chain and that the Rouse equation can be used for the longwave modes. The
results of this study make it possible to explain a marked difference between
the lengths of the Kuhn and Rouse segments that is estimated from static and
dynamic experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0909.1696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0909.1696</id><created>2009-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mazon</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames><affiliation>DRFC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Blum</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames><affiliation>JAD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boulbe</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;dric</forenames><affiliation>JAD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Faugeras</keyname><forenames>Blaise</forenames><affiliation>JAD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boboc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brix</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Vries</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharapov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabeo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-time identification of the current density profile in the JET
  Tokamak: method and validation</title><categories>math.NA physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd hal-00414481</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The real-time reconstruction of the plasma magnetic equilibrium in a Tokamak
is a key point to access high performance regimes. Indeed, the shape of the
plasma current density profile is a direct output of the reconstruction and has
a leading effect for reaching a steady-state high performance regime of
operation. In this paper we present the methodology followed to identify
numerically the plasma current density in a Tokamak and its equilibrium. In
order to meet the real-time requirements a C++ software has been developed
using the combination of a finite element method, a nonlinear fixed point
algorithm associated to a least square optimization procedure. The experimental
measurements that enable the identification are the magnetics on the vacuum
vessel, the interferometric and polarimetric measurements on several chords and
the motional Stark effect. Details are given about the validation of the
reconstruction on the JET tokamak, either by comparison with 'off-line'
equilibrium codes or real time software computing global quantities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.2151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.2151</id><created>2010-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Essafi</keyname><forenames>Wafa</forenames><affiliation>INRAP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Spiteri</keyname><forenames>Marie Noelle</forenames><affiliation>LLB</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Claudine</forenames><affiliation>LPMC, LPFO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bou&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames><affiliation>LLB</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hydrophobic Polyelectrolytes in Better Polar Solvent. Structure and
  Chain Conformation as seen by Saxs and Sans</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><proxy>ccsd hal-00446551</proxy><journal-ref>Macromolecules / J Macromolecules 42, (24) (2009) 9568?9580</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/ma9003874</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate in this paper the influence of solvent quality on the
structure of the semi-dilute solution of a hydrophobic polyelectrolyte,
partially sulfonated Poly-Styrene Sulfonate. Two solvents are used: (i) one
mixture of water and an organic solvent: THF, which is also slightly polar;
(ii) DMSO, a polar organic solvent. In case (i), it is shown by SAXS study that
the structure - namely the scattering from all chains, characterised by a
maximum (&quot;polyelectrolyte peak&quot;), of the aqueous hydrophobic polyelectrolyte
solutions (PSS) depends on the solvent quality through the added amount of
organic solvent THF. This dependence is more pronounced when the sulfonation
rate is low (more hydrophobic polyelectrolyte). It is proposed that when THF is
added, the chain conformation evolves from the pearl necklace shape already
reported in pure water, towards the conformation in pure water for fully
sulfonated PSS, which is string-like as also reported previously. On the
contrary, for a hydrophilic polyelectrolyte, AMAMPS, no evolution occurs with
added THF in the aqueous solution. In case (ii), it is shown directly by SANS
study that PSS can behave as a classical solvophilic polyelectrolyte when
dissolved in an organic polar solvent such as DMSO: the structure (total
scattering) as well as the form factor (single chain scattering measured by
SANS using the Zero Average Contrast method) of the PSS chains is independent
of the charge content in agreement with Manning condensation, and identical to
the one of a fully charged PSS chain in pure water, which has a classical
polyelectrolyte behaviour in the semi-dilute regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.4561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.4561</id><created>2010-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Varga</keyname><forenames>Tamas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Lindsay G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toby</keyname><forenames>Brian H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malliakas</keyname><forenames>Christos D.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-pressure synthesis, crystal and electronic structures of a new
  scandium tungstate, Sc0.67WO4</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>29 pages total, 1 table, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jssc.2010.04.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Negative thermal expansion (NTE) materials possess a low-density, open
structure which can respond to high pressure conditions, leading to new
compounds and/or different physical properties. Here we report that one such
NTE material -- white, insulating, orthorhombic Sc2W3O12 -- transforms into a
black compound when treated at 4 GPa and 1400 oC. The high pressure phase,
Sc0.67WO4, crystallizes in a defect-rich wolframite-type structure, a dense,
monoclinic structure (space group P2/c) containing 1-D chains of edge-sharing
WO6 octahedra. The chemical bonding of Sc0.67WO4 vis-a-vis the ambient pressure
Sc2W3O12 phase can be understood on the basis of the Sc defect structure.
Magnetic susceptibility, resistivity, thermoelectric power and IR spectroscopic
measurements reveal that Sc0.67WO4 is a paramagnet whose conductivity is that
of a metal in the presence of weak localization and electron-electron
interactions. Oxygen vacancies are suggested as a potential mechanism for
generating the carriers in this defective wolframite material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.5010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.5010</id><created>2010-01-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Duvert</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>LAOG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>LAOG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Malbet</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>LAOG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kern</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>LAOG</affiliation></author></authors><title>Phase closure nulling of HD 59717 with AMBER/VLTI . Detection of the
  close faint companion</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><proxy>ccsd insu-00450990</proxy><journal-ref>Astronomy and Astrophysics509:66, 2010</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/200811037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aims: The detection of close and faint companions is an essential step in
many astrophysical fields, including the search for planetary companions. A new
method called &quot;phase closure nulling&quot; has been proposed for the detection of
such faint and close companions based on interferometric observations when the
system visibility amplitude is close to zero due to the large diameter of the
primary star. We aim at demonstrating this method by analyzing observations
obtained on the spectroscopic binary HD 59717. Methods: Using the AMBER/VLTI
instrument in the K-band with ~1500 spectral resolution, we record the
spectrally dispersed closures phases of the SB1 binary HD 59717 with a
three-baseline combination adequate for applying phase closure methods. After a
careful data reduction, we fit the primary diameter, the binary flux ratio, and
the separation using the phase closure data. Results: We detect the 5-mag
fainter companion of HD 59717 at a distance of 4 stellar radii from the
primary. We determine the diameter of the primary, infer the secondary's
spectral type and determine the masses and sizes of the stars in the binary
system. This is one of the highest contrasts detected by interferometry between
a companion and its parent star. Based on observations collected at the
European Southern Observatory, Paranal, Chile, within the commissioning
programme 60.A-9054(A).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1002.0914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1002.0914</id><created>2010-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Fran&#xe7;ois</keyname><forenames>Marc Louis Maurice</forenames><affiliation>FAST, LMT</affiliation></author></authors><title>A plasticity model with yield surface distortion for non proportional
  loading</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd hal-00453149</proxy><journal-ref>International Journal of Plasticity 17, 5 (2001) 703?718</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0749-6419(00)00025-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to enhance the modeling of metallic materials behavior in non
proportional loadings, a modification of the classical elastic-plastic models
including distortion of the yield surface is proposed. The new yield criterion
uses the same norm as in the classical von Mises based criteria, and a
&quot;distorted stress&quot; Sd replacing the usual stress deviator S. The obtained yield
surface is then &quot;egg-shaped&quot; similar to those experimentally observed and
depends on only one new material parameter. The theory is built in such a way
as to recover the classical one for proportional loading. An identification
procedure is proposed to obtain the material parameters. Simulations and
experiments are compared for a 2024 T4 aluminum alloy for both proportional and
nonproportional tension-torsion loading paths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1002.2323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1002.2323</id><created>2010-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Canet</keyname><forenames>Elisabeth</forenames><affiliation>LGIT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fournier</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames><affiliation>IPGP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jault</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames><affiliation>LGIT</affiliation></author></authors><title>Forward and adjoint quasi-geostrophic models of the geomagnetic secular
  variation</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd hal-00455441</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Geophysical Research B: Solid Earth 114 (2009) B11101</journal-ref><doi>10.1029/2008JB006189</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a quasi-geostrophic model of core dynamics, which aims at
describing core processes on geomagnetic secular variation timescales. It
extends the formalism of Alfv\'en torsional oscillations by incorporating
non-zonal motions. Within this framework, the magnetohydrodynamics takes place
in the equatorial plane; it involves quadratic magnetic quantities, which are
averaged along the direction of rotation of the Earth. In addition, the
equatorial flow is projected on the core-mantle boundary. It interacts with the
magnetic field at the core surface, through the radial component of the
magnetic induction equation. That part of the model connects the dynamics and
the observed secular variation, with the radial component of the magnetic field
acting as a passive tracer. We resort to variational data assimilation to
construct formally the relationship between model predictions and observations.
Variational data assimilation seeks to minimize an objective function, by
computing its sensitivity to its control variables. The sensitivity is
efficiently calculated after integration of the adjoint model. We illustrate
that framework with twin experiments, performed first in the case of the
kinematic core flow inverse problem, and then in the case of Alfv\'en torsional
oscillations. In both cases, using the adjoint model allows us to retrieve core
state variables which, while taking part in the dynamics, are not directly
sampled at the core surface. We study the effect of several factors on the
solution (width of the assimilation time window, amount and quality of data),
and we discuss the potential of the model to deal with real geomagnetic
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1005.3435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1005.3435</id><created>2010-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Palacios-Laloy</keyname><forenames>Agustin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mallet</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertet</keyname><forenames>Patrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vion</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esteve</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental violation of a Bell's inequality in time with weak
  measurement</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>26 pages including 10 figures, preprint format</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 6, 442-447 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys1641</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The violation of J. Bell's inequality with two entangled and spatially
separated quantum two- level systems (TLS) is often considered as the most
prominent demonstration that nature does not obey ?local realism?. Under
different but related assumptions of &quot;macrorealism&quot;, plausible for macroscopic
systems, Leggett and Garg derived a similar inequality for a single degree of
freedom undergoing coherent oscillations and being measured at successive
times. Such a &quot;Bell's inequality in time&quot;, which should be violated by a
quantum TLS, is tested here. In this work, the TLS is a superconducting quantum
circuit whose Rabi oscillations are continuously driven while it is
continuously and weakly measured. The time correlations present at the detector
output agree with quantum-mechanical predictions and violate the inequality by
5 standard deviations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.4009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.4009</id><created>2010-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Cabrera-Trujillo</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montejano-Carrizales</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. L. Rodriguez-Loopez W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velazquez-Salazar</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jose-Yacaman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nucleation and Growth of Stellated Gold Clusters: Experimental Synthesis
  and Molecular Dynamics Study</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>11 figures, plus 1 as graphical abstract</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An experimental and theoretical study on the structure and energetics of
stellated gold clusters at several sizes is presented. Systematic molecular
dynamics simulations on Kepler-Poisont classified clusters are performed based
on cubo-octahedral and icosahedral cores, following present and previous
studies that suggest stellated clusters grew up from these seeds. For cluster
sizes up to 10802 atoms full atomistic molecular dynamics simulations at room
temperature have been carried out. Results show that stellated clusters in the
bigger size regime maintain their star-like shape at room temperature, and by
means of linear fitting of energy data to proper function models, it is
predicted that the two type of stellated structures might coexist at room
temperature for relatively large sizes, being these findings in good agreement
with experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.4367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.4367</id><created>2010-07-25</created><updated>2010-07-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yi-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Kai-Nan</forenames></author></authors><title>Invariance of the Hamilton-Jacobi tunneling method for black holes and
  FRW model</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, typos corrected, references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we revisit the topic of Hawking radiation as tunneling. We show
that the imaginary part of the action of the tunneling particle should be
reconstructed in a covariant way, as a line integral along the classical
forbidden trajectory of tunneling particles. As the quantum tunneling
phenomenon, the probability of tunneling is related to the imaginary part of
the action for the classical forbidden trajectory. We do the calculations for
massless and massive particles, in Schwarzschild coordinate and Painlev\'e
coordinate. The construction of particle action is invariant under coordinate
transformations, so this method of calculation black hole tunneling does not
have the so called &quot;factor 2 problem&quot;. As an application, we find that the
temperature of Hawking temperature of apparent horizon in a FRW universe is
$T=\frac{\kappa}{2\pi}$. Based on this result, we briefly discuss the unified
first law of apparent horizon in FRW universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1008.1288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1008.1288</id><created>2010-08-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jiuning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schiffli</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallabhaneni</keyname><forenames>Ajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Xiulin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yong P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tuning the thermal conductivity of graphene nanoribbons by edge
  passivation and isotope engineering: a molecular dynamics study</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.3491267</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using classical molecular dynamics simulation, we have studied the effect of
edge-passivation by hydrogen (H-passivation) and isotope mixture (with random
or supperlattice distributions) on the thermal conductivity of rectangular
graphene nanoribbons (GNRs) (of several nanometers in size). We found that the
thermal conductivity is considerably reduced by the edge H-passivation. We also
find that the isotope mixing can reduce the thermal conductivities, with the
supperlattice distribution giving rise to more reduction than the random
distribution. These results can be useful in nanoscale engineering of thermal
transport and heat management using GNRs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1008.2253</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1008.2253</id><created>2010-08-13</created><updated>2010-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piran</keyname><forenames>Tsvi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Revised Limit of the Lorentz Factors of GRBs with Two Emitting Regions</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>15 pages 4 figuers</comments><doi>10.1088/2041-8205/726/1/L2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fermi observations of GeV emission from GRBs have suggested that the Lorentz
factor of some GRBs is around a thousand or even higher. At the same time the
same Fermi observations have shown an extended GeV emission indicating that
this higher energy emission might be a part of the afterglow and it does not
come from the same region as the lower energy prompt emission. If this
interpretation is correct than we should reconsider the opacity limits on the
Loretnz factor of the emitting regions which are based on a one-zone model. We
describe here a two-zone model in which the GeV photons are emitted in a larger
radius than the MeV photons and we calculate the optical depth for pair
creation of a GeV photon passing the lower energy photons shell. We find that,
as expected, the new two-zone limits on the Lorentz factor are significantly
lower. The corresponding limits for the Fermi bursts are lower by a factor of
five compared to the one-zone model and it is possible that both the MeV and
GeV regions have relatively modest Lorentz factors (~200 - 400).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1009.2972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1009.2972</id><created>2010-09-15</created><updated>2010-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Arabindo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>Peter A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bock</keyname><forenames>James J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapin</keyname><forenames>Edward L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devlin</keyname><forenames>Mark J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dicker</keyname><forenames>Simon R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>France</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibb</keyname><forenames>Andrew G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffin</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gundersen</keyname><forenames>Joshua O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hargrave</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>David H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Jeff</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsden</keyname><forenames>Gaelen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Jorge L. Morales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Netterfield</keyname><forenames>Calvin B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noriega-Crespo</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olmi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patanchon</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rex</keyname><forenames>Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Douglas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semisch</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truch</keyname><forenames>Matthew D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Carole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Gregory S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viero</keyname><forenames>Marco P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebe</keyname><forenames>Donald V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Balloon-Borne Large Aperture Submillimeter Telescope (BLAST) 2005: A
  10 deg^2 Survey of Star Formation in Cygnus X</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>42 pages, 31 Figures, 6 tables</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/727/2/114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present Cygnus X in a new multi-wavelength perspective based on an
unbiased BLAST survey at 250, 350, and 500 micron, combined with rich datasets
for this well-studied region. Our primary goal is to investigate the early
stages of high mass star formation. We have detected 184 compact sources in
various stages of evolution across all three BLAST bands. From their
well-constrained spectral energy distributions, we obtain the physical
properties mass, surface density, bolometric luminosity, and dust temperature.
Some of the bright sources reaching 40 K contain well-known compact H II
regions. We relate these to other sources at earlier stages of evolution via
the energetics as deduced from their position in the luminosity-mass (L-M)
diagram. The BLAST spectral coverage, near the peak of the spectral energy
distribution of the dust, reveals fainter sources too cool (~ 10 K) to be seen
by earlier shorter-wavelength surveys like IRAS. We detect thermal emission
from infrared dark clouds and investigate the phenomenon of cold ``starless
cores&quot; more generally. Spitzer images of these cold sources often show stellar
nurseries, but these potential sites for massive star formation are ``starless&quot;
in the sense that to date there is no massive protostar in a vigorous accretion
phase. We discuss evolution in the context of the L-M diagram. Theory raises
some interesting possibilities: some cold massive compact sources might never
form a cluster containing massive stars; and clusters with massive stars might
not have an identifiable compact cold massive precursor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.0810</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.0810</id><created>2010-11-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Sedransk</keyname><forenames>Nell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cox</keyname><forenames>Lawrence H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nolan</keyname><forenames>Deborah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soper</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiegelman</keyname><forenames>Cliff</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Linda J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelner</keyname><forenames>Katrina L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moffitt</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakar</keyname><forenames>Ani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raddick</keyname><forenames>Jordan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ungvarsky</keyname><forenames>Edward J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>Richard W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apweiler</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author></authors><title>Make Research Data Public? -- Not Always so Simple: A Dialogue for
  Statisticians and Science Editors</title><categories>stat.ME cs.DL physics.data-an</categories><comments>Published in at http://dx.doi.org/10.1214/10-STS320 the Statistical
  Science (http://www.imstat.org/sts/) by the Institute of Mathematical
  Statistics (http://www.imstat.org)</comments><proxy>vtex</proxy><report-no>IMS-STS-STS320</report-no><journal-ref>Statistical Science 2010, Vol. 25, No. 1, 41-50</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/10-STS320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Putting data into the public domain is not the same thing as making those
data accessible for intelligent analysis. A distinguished group of editors and
experts who were already engaged in one way or another with the issues inherent
in making research data public came together with statisticians to initiate a
dialogue about policies and practicalities of requiring published research to
be accompanied by publication of the research data. This dialogue carried
beyond the broad issues of the advisability, the intellectual integrity, the
scientific exigencies to the relevance of these issues to statistics as a
discipline and the relevance of statistics, from inference to modeling to data
exploration, to science and social science policies on these issues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.6354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.6354</id><created>2011-09-28</created><updated>2012-07-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nicolaidis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Shortcuts in Spacetime</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>To appear in Mod. Phys. Lett. A 2012</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732312501271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theories with large extra dimensions may be tested using sterile neutrinos
living in the bulk. A bulk neutrino can mix with a flavor neutrino localized in
the brane leading to unconventional patterns of neutrino oscillations. A
resonance phenomenon, strong mixing between the flavor and the sterile
neutrino, allows to determine the radius of the large extra dimension. If our
brane is curved, then the sterile neutrino can take a shortcut through the
bulk, leading to an apparent superluminal neutrino speed. The amount of
&quot;superluminality&quot; is directly connected to parameters determining the shape of
the brane. On the experimental side, we suggest that a long baseline neutrino
beam from CERN to NESTOR neutrino telescope will help to clarify these
important issues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1202.1388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1202.1388</id><created>2012-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tetzlaff</keyname><forenames>Nina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Janos G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hohle</keyname><forenames>Markus M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neuhaeuser</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron stars from young nearby associations the origin of
  RXJ1605.3+3249</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>accepted for publication in PASA, special volume Astronomy with
  Radioactivities; 10 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables</comments><doi>10.1071/AS11057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many neutron stars (NSs) and runaway stars apparently come from the same
regions on the sky. This suggests that they share the same birth places, namely
associations and clusters of young massive stars. To identify NS birth places,
we attempt to and NS-runaway pairs that could be former companions that were
disrupted in a supernova (SN). The remains of recent (&lt;few Myr) nearby (&lt; 150
pc) SNe should still be identifiable by observing the emission of rare
radioisotopes such as 26Al and 60Fe that can also be used as additional
indicators to confirm a possible SN event. We investigated the origin of the
isolated NS RXJ1605.3+3249 and found that it was probably born ~100 pc far from
Earth 0.45 Myr ago in the extended Corona-Australis or Octans associations, or
in Sco OB4 ~1 kpc 3.5 Myr ago. A SN in Octans is supported by the
identification of one to two possible former companions the runaway stars HIP
68228 and HIP 89394, as well as the appearance of a feature in the gamma ray
emission from 26Al decay at the predicted SN place. Both, the progenitor masses
estimated by comparison with theoretical 26Al yields as well as derived from
the life time of the progenitor star, are found to be ~11MSun.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.6323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.6323</id><created>2012-06-27</created><updated>2014-08-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Debashis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandan</keyname><forenames>Sanket</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>Prasanta K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Local implementations of non-local quantum gates in linear entangled
  channel</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures and 7 tables</comments><journal-ref>JQIS 4 (02), 97 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jqis.2014.42010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we demonstrate n-party controlled unitary gate implementations
locally on arbitrary remote state through linear entangled channel where
control parties share entanglement with the adjacent control parties and only
one of them shares entanglement with the target party. In such a network, we
describe the protocol of simultaneous implementation of controlled-Hermitian
gate starting from three party scenario. We also explicate the implementation
of three party controlled-Unitary gate, a generalized form of Toffoli gate and
subsequently generalize the protocol for n-party using minimal cost.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.5857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.5857</id><created>2013-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barat</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasistatic Stick-slip in Dislocation Core and Frenkel-Kontorova Chain</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 87, 214107 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.87.214107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of atomistic simulations, we demonstrate that a dislocation core
exhibits intermittent quasistatic restructuring during incremental shear within
the same Peierls valley. This can be regarded as a stick-slip transition, which
is also reproduced for a one-dimensional Frenkel-Kontorova chain under rigid
boundary conditions. This occurs due to a discontinuous jump in an order
parameter of the system, which signifies the extent of region forbidden for the
presence of particles in the chain. The stick-slip phenomenon observed in the
dislocation core is also shown to be reflected after dimensionality reduction
of the multidimensional atomic coordinates, which provides a basis for
comparison with the simple one-dimensional chain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.5387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.5387</id><created>2013-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Martin-Cocher</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>John</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Patrick M.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Chih-Wen</forenames><affiliation>c</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei-Long</forenames><affiliation>d</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ming-Tang</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Raffin</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>Chin-Long</forenames><affiliation>e</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Paul T. P.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Symmes</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author></authors><title>ALMA Nutator Design and Preliminary Performance</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Published: 23 August 2012; 12 pages</comments><journal-ref>2012 SPIE Proceedings Vol. 8452, Millimeter, Submillimeter, and
  Far-Infrared Detectors and Instrumentation for Astronomy VI</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.925809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the past two years of collaboration between the different actors on
the ALMA nutator. Building on previous developments, the nutator has seen
changes in much of the design. A high-modulus carbon fiber structure has been
added on the back of the mirror in order to transfer the voice coils forces
with less deformation, thus reducing delay problems due to flexing. The
controller is now an off-the-shelf National Instrument NI-cRIO, and the
amplifier a class D servo drive from Advanced Motion Controls, with high peak
power able to drive the coils at 300 Volts DC. The stow mechanism has been
totally redesigned to improve on the repeatability and precision of the stow
position, which is also the reference for the 26 bits Heidenhain encoders. This
also improves on the accuracy of the stow position with wind loading. Finally,
the software, written largely with National Instrument's LabView, has been
developed. We will discuss these changes and the preliminary performances
achieved to date. Keywords: ALMA, nutator, class D, high-modulus carbon fiber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.6820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.6820</id><created>2013-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>OuYang</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is silicene stable in air? -- First principles study of oxygen
  adsorption and dissociation on silicene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The oxygen adsorption and dissociation on pristine silicene surface are
studied by use of first-principles in this letter. The oxygen adsorption and
dissociation on pristine silicene surface are studied by use of
first-principles in this letter. It is found that the pristine silicene is not
stable in air because the oxygen molecule can be easily adsorbed and
dissociated into two O atoms without overcoming any energy barrier on pristine
silicene surface. In addition, dissociated oxygen atoms are relatively
difficult to migrate on or desorbed from pristine silicene surface, leading to
poor mobility of oxygen atom. As a result, silicene would be changed into Si-O
compounds in air. The work will be helpful to reveal the detail of the
interaction between oxygen molecules and pristine silicene surface, especially
helpful to understand the stability of silicene in air.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05967</id><created>2016-01-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Scheuer</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwartz</keyname><forenames>Ilai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulze-S&#xfc;nninghausen</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carl</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retzker</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumiya</keyname><forenames>Hitoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isoya</keyname><forenames>Junichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luy</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plenio</keyname><forenames>Martin B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naydenov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jelezko</keyname><forenames>Fedor</forenames></author></authors><title>Optically induced dynamic nuclear spin polarisation in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>This is the revision submitted to NJP</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 013040 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/1/013040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensitivity of Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) depends strongly on
nuclear spin polarisation and, motivated by this observation, dynamical nuclear
spin polarisation has recently been applied to enhance MRI protocols
(Kurhanewicz, J., et al., Neoplasia 13, 81 (2011)). Nuclear spins associated
with the 13 C carbon isotope (nuclear spin I = 1/2) in diamond possess uniquely
long spin lattice relaxation times (Reynhardt, E.C. and G.L. High, Prog. in
Nuc. Mag. Res. Sp. 38, 37 (2011)) If they are present in diamond nanocrystals,
especially when strongly polarised, they form a promising contrast agent for
MRI. Current schemes for achieving nuclear polarisation, however, require
cryogenic temperatures. Here we demonstrate an efficient scheme that realises
optically induced 13 C nuclear spin hyperpolarisation in diamond at room
temperature and low ambient magnetic field. Optical pumping of a
Nitrogen-Vacancy (NV) centre creates a continuously renewable electron spin
polarisation which can be transferred to surrounding 13 C nuclear spins.
Importantly for future applications we also realise polarisation protocols that
are robust against an unknown misalignment between magnetic field and crystal
axis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01548</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gamel</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author></authors><title>Entangled Bloch Spheres: Bloch Matrix and Two Qubit State Space</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP physics.optics</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 062320 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.062320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We represent a two-qubit density matrix in the basis of Pauli matrix tensor
products, with the coefficients constituting a Bloch matrix, analogous to the
single qubit Bloch vector. We find the quantum state positivity requirements on
the Bloch matrix components, leading to three important inequalities, allowing
us to parametrize and visualize the two-qubit state space. Applying the
singular value decomposition naturally separates the degrees of freedom to
local and nonlocal, and simplifies the positivity inequalities. It also allows
us to geometrically represent a state as two entangled Bloch spheres with
superimposed correlation axes. It is shown that unitary transformations, local
or nonlocal, have simple interpretations as axis rotations or mixing of certain
degrees of freedom. The nonlocal unitary invariants of the state are then
derived in terms of local unitary invariants. The positive partial transpose
criterion for entanglement is generalized, and interpreted as a reflection, or
a change of a single sign. The formalism is used to characterize maximally
entangled states, and generalize two qubit isotropic and Werner states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
