<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:34:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-11-10" from="2016-11-10" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0806.4788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0806.4788</id><created>2008-06-30</created><updated>2008-11-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zeng-Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of Narrow-Band Polarization-Entangled Photon Pairs for Atomic
  Quantum Memories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 101, 190501 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.101.190501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental realization of a narrow-band polarization-entangled
photon source with a linewidth of 9.6 MHz through cavity-enhanced spontaneous
parametric down-conversion. This linewidth is comparable to the typical
linewidth of atomic ensemble based quantum memories. Single-mode output is
realized by setting a reasonable cavity length difference between different
polarizations, using of temperature controlled etalons and actively stabilizing
the cavity. The entangled property is characterized with quantum state
tomography, giving a fidelity of 94% between our state and a maximally
entangled state. The coherence length is directly measured to be 32 m through
two-photon interference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0809.4476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0809.4476</id><created>2008-09-25</created><updated>2008-10-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shafranjuk</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directional photoelectric current across the bilayer graphene junction</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Phys.: Cond. Matt. 20, 015301 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/21/1/015301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A directional photon-assisted resonant chiral tunneling through a bilayer
graphene barrier is considered. An external electromagnetic field applied to
the barrier switches the transparency $T$ in the longitudinal direction from
its steady state value T=0 to the ideal T=1 at no energy costs. The switch
happens because the a.c. field affects the phase correlation between the
electrons and holes inside the graphene barrier changing the whole angular
dependence of the chiral tunneling (directional photoelectric effect). The
suggested phenomena can be implemented in relevant experiments and in various
sub-millimeter and far-infrared optical electronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1009.0462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1009.0462</id><created>2010-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Poklonski</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Syaglo</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vyrko</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analog of the Auger effect in radiative decay of a trion in a quantum
  well</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Spectrosc., Vol.68, No.3 (2001) pp.371-376</journal-ref><doi>10.1023/A:1011961603382</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analyzed the energetics of decay of the X^- trion (exciton +
electron) on the assumption that the exciton and trion are independent
excitations of a single two-dimensional semiconducting quantum well. For the
first time, it has been shown that in filling a well with electrons from a
selective donor-doped matrix, the binding energy of the trion (of the electron
with the exciton) increases linearly with a shift of the Fermi level into the
depth of the c band. This agrees with the well-known experimental data on the
low-temperature radiative decay (photoluminescence) of trions in the
heterostructures ZnSe/Zn_0.89Mg_0.11S_0.18Se_0.82 and CdTe/Cd_0.7Mg_0.3Te.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.0772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.0772</id><created>2010-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Wei-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goebel</keyname><forenames>Alexander M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Han-Ning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagenknecht</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zeng-Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Teleportation-based realization of an optical quantum two-qubit
  entangling gate</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>PNAS 107, 20869-20874 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1005720107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, there has been heightened interest in quantum teleportation,
which allows for the transfer of unknown quantum states over arbitrary
distances. Quantum teleportation not only serves as an essential ingredient in
long-distance quantum communication, but also provides enabling technologies
for practical quantum computation. Of particular interest is the scheme
proposed by Gottesman and Chuang [Nature \textbf{402}, 390 (1999)], showing
that quantum gates can be implemented by teleporting qubits with the help of
some special entangled states. Therefore, the construction of a quantum
computer can be simply based on some multi-particle entangled states, Bell
state measurements and single-qubit operations. The feasibility of this scheme
relaxes experimental constraints on realizing universal quantum computation.
Using two different methods we demonstrate the smallest non-trivial module in
such a scheme---a teleportation-based quantum entangling gate for two different
photonic qubits. One uses a high-fidelity six-photon interferometer to realize
controlled-NOT gates and the other uses four-photon hyper-entanglement to
realize controlled-Phase gates. The results clearly demonstrate the working
principles and the entangling capability of the gates. Our experiment
represents an important step towards the realization of practical quantum
computers and could lead to many further applications in linear optics quantum
information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.4112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.4112</id><created>2012-08-20</created><updated>2013-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shafranjuk</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat to Electricity Conversion by a Graphene Stripe with Heavy Chiral
  Fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2014) 87: 99</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2014-40794-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A conversion of thermal energy into electricity is considered in the
electrically polarized graphene stripes with zigzag edges where the heavy
chiral fermion (HCF) states are formed. The stripes are characterized by a high
electric conductance Ge and by a significant Seebeck coefficient S. The
electric current in the stripes is induced due to a non-equilibrium thermal
injection of &quot;hot&quot; electrons. This thermoelectric generation process might be
utilized for building of thermoelectric generators with an exceptionally high
figure of merit Z{\delta}T \simeq 100 &gt;&gt; 1 and with an appreciable electric
power densities \sim 1 MW/cm2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1211.5930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1211.5930</id><created>2012-11-26</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cordero-Carri&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerd&#xe1;-Dur&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author></authors><title>Partially implicit Runge-Kutta methods for wave-like equations</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><comments>39 pages, 10 figures</comments><msc-class>35L60, 35L05, 83C35</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present a new class of Runge-Kutta (RK) methods for solving
systems of hyperbolic equations with a particular structure, generalization of
a wave-equation. The new methods are {\it partially implicit} in the sense that
a proper subset of the equations of the system contains some terms which are
treated implicitly. These methods can be viewed as a particular case of the
implicit-explicit (IMEX) RK methods for systems of equations with wave-like
structure. For these systems, the optimal methods with the new structure are
easier to derive than the IMEX ones, specially when aiming at higher-order (up
to fourth-order in this work). The methods are constructed considering the
classical strong-stability-preserving optimal explicit RK methods for the
purely explicit part. The resulting partially implicit RK methods do not
require any inversion of operators and hence their computational cost per
iteration is similar to those of explicit RK methods. We analyse the stability
and convergence properties and show their practical applicability in several
numerical examples. Our results show that, compared with explicit RK methods,
the new methods have better stability properties (larger steps are allowed) and
in general show smaller discretization error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.5975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.5975</id><created>2013-11-23</created><updated>2013-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaspar</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mungan</keyname><forenames>Muhittin</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact results for a toy model exhibiting dynamic criticality</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP math.PR</categories><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincar\'e 16 (2015) 2837-2879</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-014-0387-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we discuss an exactly solvable, one-dimensional, periodic toy
charge density wave model introduced in [D.C. Kaspar, M. Mungan, EPL {\bf 103},
46002 (2013)]. In particular, driving the system with a uniform force, we show
that the depinning threshold configuration is an explicit function of the
underlying disorder, as is the evolution from the negative threshold to the
positive threshold, the latter admitting a description in terms of record
sequences. This evolution is described by an avalanche algorithm, which
identifies a sequence of static configurations that are stable at successively
stronger forcing, and is useful both for analysis and simulation. We focus in
particular on the behavior of the polarization $P$, which is related to the
cumulative avalanche size, as a function of the threshold force minus the
current force $(F_{\mathrm{th}} - F)$, as this has been the focus of several
prior numerical and analytical studies of CDW systems. The results presented
are rigorous, with exceptions explicitly indicated, and show that the depinning
transition in this model is indeed a dynamic critical phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.1007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.1007</id><created>2013-12-03</created><updated>2014-09-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sodin</keyname><forenames>Sasha</forenames></author></authors><title>A limit theorem at the spectral edge for corners of time-dependent
  Wigner matrices</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>37 pages; v2: revised the presentation and fixed lapses; v3: added
  minor clarifications</comments><journal-ref>Int Math Res Notices (2015) 2015 (17): 7575-7607</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/imrn/rnu180</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the eigenvalues of principal submatrices of stochastically evolving
Wigner matrices, we construct and study the edge scaling limit: a random
decreasing sequence of continuous functions of two variables, which at every
point has the distribution of the Airy point process. The analysis is based on
the methods developed by Soshnikov to study the extreme eigenvalues of a single
Wigner matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.6629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.6629</id><created>2014-02-26</created><updated>2016-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fields</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Decompositional equivalence: A fundamental symmetry underlying quantum
  theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 3 figures; accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Axiomathes 26 (2016) 279-311</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10516-016-9289-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Decompositional equivalence is the principle that there is no preferred
decomposition of the universe into subsystems. It is shown here, by using
simple thought experiments, that quantum theory follows from decompositional
equivalence together with Landauer's principle. This demonstration raises
within physics a question previously left to psychology: how do human - or any
- observers agree about what constitutes a &quot;system of interest&quot;?
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.2862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.2862</id><created>2014-03-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sekizawa</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yabana</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent Hartree-Fock calculations for multi-nucleon transfer
  processes: Effects of particle evaporation on production cross sections</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, Talk given at VI International Conference
  FUSION14, Feb. 24-28, 2014, New Delhi, India</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conf. 86, 00043 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/20158600043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a microscopic calculation of multi-nucleon transfer reactions
employing the time-dependent Hartree-Fock (TDHF) theory. In our previous
publication [Phys. Rev. C 88, 014614 (2013)], we reported our analysis for the
multi-nucleon transfer processes for several systems. Here we discuss effects
of particle evaporation processes on the production cross sections. Since
particle evaporation processes may not be described adequately by the TDHF
calculations, we evaluate them using a statistical model. As an input of the
statistical model, excitation energies of the final fragments are necessary. We
evaluate them from the TDHF wave function after collisions, extending the
particle number projection technique. From the calculation, the particle
evaporation effects are found to improve descriptions of the production cross
sections. However, the production cross sections are still underestimated for
processes where a number of protons are transferred. Possible origins of the
discrepancy are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.7804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.7804</id><created>2014-07-29</created><updated>2015-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Disertori</keyname><forenames>Margherita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sodin</keyname><forenames>Sasha</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-classical analysis of non self-adjoint transfer matrices in
  statistical mechanics. I</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>28 pp, improved the presentation</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Henri Poincar\'e (2016) 17: 437</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-015-0397-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a way to study one-dimensional statistical mechanics models with
complex-valued action using transfer operators. The argument consists of two
steps. First, the contour of integration is deformed so that the associated
transfer operator is a perturbation of a normal one. Then the transfer operator
is studied using methods of semi-classical analysis.
  In this paper we concentrate on the second step, the main technical result
being a semi-classical estimate for powers of an integral operator which is
approximately normal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3312</id><created>2014-08-14</created><updated>2015-03-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gamayun</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezvershenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheianov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The fate of a gray soliton in a quenched Bose-Einstein condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP nlin.PS</categories><comments>4+epsilon pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A. 91 031605 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.91.031605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the destiny of a gray soliton in a repulsive one-dimensional
Bose-Einstein condensate undergoing a sudden quench of the non-linearity
parameter. The outcome of the quench is found to depend dramatically on the
ratio $\eta$ of the final and initial values of the speed of sound. For integer
$\eta$ the soliton splits into exactly $2\eta-1$ solitons. For non-integer
$\eta$ the soliton decays into multiple solitons and Bogoliubov modes. The case
of integer $\eta$ is analyzed in detail. The parameters of solitons in the
out-state are found explicitly. Our approach exploits the inverse scattering
method and can be easily used for the similar quenches in any classical
integrable system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.0996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.0996</id><created>2014-09-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiujuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective medium theory for anisotropic metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Paper draft. An updated formal version is under review</comments><doi>10.1038/srep07892</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an effective medium theory that can predict the effective
permittivity and permeability of a geometrically anisotropic two-dimensional
metamaterial composed with a rectangular array of elliptical cylinders. It is
possible to obtain a closed-form analytical solution for the anisotropic
effective medium parameters if the aspect ratio of the lattice and the
eccentricity of elliptical cylinder satisfy certain conditions. The derived
effective medium theory can recover the well-known Maxwell-Garnett results in
the quasi-static regime. More importantly, it is valid beyond the
long-wavelength limit, where the wavelength in the host medium is comparable to
the size of the lattice so that previous anisotropic effective medium theories
fail. The validity of the derived effective medium theory is verified by band
structure calculations. A real sample of a recent theoretically proposed
anisotropic medium with near-zero index to control flux is achieved from the
derived effective medium theory and control of electromagnetic waves in the
sample is clearly demonstrated. The accuracy of the theory is further
systematically studied as material and geometric parameter varies, and we find
the derived effective medium theory applies over a large range in the parameter
space. Such applicability greatly broadens the applicable realm of the
effective medium theory and opens many vistas in the design of structures with
desired anisotropic material characteristics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.8612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.8612</id><created>2014-09-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Sekizawa</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yabana</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong Orientation Dependence of Multinucleon Transfer Processes in
  $^{238}$U+$^{124}$Sn Reaction</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Poster given at 2nd Conference of Advances in
  Radioactive Isotope Science (ARIS2014), June 1-6, 2014, Tokyo, Japan</comments><journal-ref>JPS Conf. Proc. 6, 030084 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSCP.6.030084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate multinucleon transfer (MNT) processes in
$^{238}$U+$^{124}$Sn reaction at $E_\mathrm{lab}=5.7$ MeV/$A$ using the
time-dependent Hartree-Fock (TDHF) theory. For this reaction, measurements of
MNT processes have been reported, showing substantial MNT cross sections
accompanying more than ten protons. From the calculation, we find that the
amount of transferred nucleons depends much on the relative orientation between
the deformation axis of $^{238}$U and the relative vector connecting centers of
$^{238}$U and $^{124}$Sn nuclei. We find a formation of thick neck when the
$^{238}$U collides from its tip with $^{124}$Sn. However, the neck formation is
substantially suppressed when $^{238}$U collides from its side. We have found
that a large number of protons are transferred in the tip collision. This is
caused by the breaking of the neck and subsequent absorption of nucleons in the
neck region. We thus conclude that the measured MNT processes involving about
ten protons originate from the neck breaking dynamics in the tip collisions of
a deformed $^{238}$U nucleus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.3996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.3996</id><created>2014-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Shafranjuk</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantized magneto-thermoelectric transport in low-dimensional junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>EPL, 109, 68003 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/109/68003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantization of the magneto-thermoelectric transport is studied when an
external d.c. magnetic field is applied to the C/N-knot formed as crossing
between a narrow stripe of conducting atomic monolayer C on the one hand and
metal stripe N on the other hand. The temperature gradient in C is created by
injecting the non-equilibrium electrons, holes and phonons from the heater H
thereby directing them toward the C/N-knot. A non-linear coupling between
electron states of the C/N-knot counter electrodes causes splitting of the heat
flow into several fractions owing to the Lorentz force acting in the C/N-knot
vicinity, thereby inducing the magneto-thermoelectric current in N whereas the
phonons pass and propagate along C further ahead. The heat flow along C
generates a transversal electric current in N showing a series of maximums when
dimensions of the Landau orbits and the C/N-knot match each other. It allows
observing the interplay between the quantum Hall effect and the spatial
quantization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.0451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.0451</id><created>2014-12-01</created><updated>2015-02-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>A. M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The properties of XO-5b and WASP-82b redetermined using new
  high-precision transit photometry and global data analyses</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure, 4 tables. Accepted for publication in Acta
  Astronomica</comments><journal-ref>Acta Astron., 65, 117 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents new transit photometry from the Isaac Newton Telescope of
two transiting exoplanetary systems, XO-5 and WASP-82. In each case the new
transit light curve is more precise than any other of that system previously
published. The new data are analysed alongside previously-published photometry
and radial velocities, resulting in an improved orbital ephemeris and a refined
set of system parameters in each case. The observational baseline of XO-5 is
extended by very nearly four years, resulting in a determination of the orbital
period of XO-5b to a precision of just 50 ms. The mass and radius of XO-5b are
1.19$\pm$0.03 and 1.14$\pm$0.03 times those of Jupiter, respectively. The light
curve of WASP-82 is only the second published for this system. The planetary
mass is 1.25$\pm$0.05 $M_{\rm Jup}$, and the radius is 1.71$\pm$0.08 $M_{\rm
Jup}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04922</id><created>2015-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonsante</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seppi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>On Codazzi tensors on a hyperbolic surface and flat Lorentzian geometry</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc math.GT</categories><comments>49 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Mathematics Research Notices (2016) no.2, 343-417</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using global considerations, Mess proved that the moduli space of globally
hyperbolic flat Lorentzian structures on $S\times\mathbb{R}$ is the tangent
bundle of the Teichm\&quot;uller space of $S$, if $S$ is a closed surface. One of
the goals of this paper is to deepen this surprising occurrence and to make
explicit the relation between the Mess parameters and the embedding data of any
Cauchy surface. This relation is pointed out by using some specific properties
of Codazzi tensors on hyperbolic surfaces. As a by-product we get a new
Lorentzian proof of Goldman's celebrated result about the coincidence of the
Weil-Petersson symplectic form and the Goldman pairing.
  In the second part of the paper we use this machinery to get a classification
of globally hyperbolic flat space-times with particles of angles in $(0,2\pi)$
containing a uniformly convex Cauchy surface. The analogue of Mess' result is
achieved showing that the corresponding moduli space is the tangent bundle of
the Teichm\&quot;uller space of a punctured surface. To generalize the theory in the
case of particles, we deepen the study of Codazzi tensors on hyperbolic
surfaces with cone singularities, proving that the well-known decomposition of
a Codazzi tensor in a harmonic part and a trivial part can be generalized in
the context of hyperbolic metrics with cone singularities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07832</id><created>2015-02-27</created><updated>2016-11-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khodam-Mohammadi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karimkhani</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alaei</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauss Bonnet dark energy Chaplygin Gas Model</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures, Abstract and introduction of the text revised,
  slightly rearranged presentation, references added, Accepted for publication
  in EPJ Plus journal</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131:398</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16398-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The correspondence of the Gauss-Bonnet (GB) and its modification (MGB) models
of dark energy with the standard and generalized Chaplygin gas-scalar field
models (SCG and GCG) have been studied in a {\deg}at universe. The exact
solution of potentials and scalar fields, which describe the accelerated
expansion of the universe, are reconstructed. According to the evolutionary
behavior of the GB and MGB models, the same form of dynamics of scalar field
and potential for different SCG and GCG models are derived. By calculating the
squared sound speed of the MGB, GB model as well as the SCG, GCG, and
investigating the GB-Chaplygin gas from the viewpoint of linear perturbation
theory, we find that the best results which is consistent with the observation,
may be appeared by considering the MGB-GCG. Also we find out some bounds for
parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06605</id><created>2015-03-23</created><updated>2016-09-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Walk Search through Potential Barriers</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49, 484002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/48/484002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An ideal quantum walk transitions from one vertex to another with perfect
fidelity, but in physical systems, the particle may be hindered by potential
energy barriers. Then the particle has some amplitude of tunneling through the
barriers, and some amplitude of staying put. We investigate the algorithmic
consequence of such barriers for the quantum walk formulation of Grover's
algorithm. We prove that the failure amplitude must scale as $O(1/\sqrt{N})$
for search to retain its quantum $O(\sqrt{N})$ runtime; otherwise, it searches
in classical $O(N)$ time. Thus searching larger &quot;databases&quot; requires
increasingly reliable hop operations or error correction. This condition holds
for both discrete- and continuous-time quantum walks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.02271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.02271</id><created>2015-05-09</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Derezi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majewski</keyname><forenames>Przemys&#x142;aw</forenames></author></authors><title>From Conformal Group to Symmetries of Hypergeometric Type Equations</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.CA math.CV math.MP</categories><comments>comment by PM: the editing done by SIGMA deteriorates the quality of
  the paper which is very sad, please visit
  http://www.fuw.edu.pl/~derezins/sym-hyp-submitted.pdf for the submitted and
  reviewed version which looks as the authors intended; part of PM's doctoral
  thesis</comments><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 108, 69 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.108</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We show that properties of hypergeometric type equations become transparent
if they are derived from appropriate 2nd order partial differential equations
with constant coefficients. In particular, we deduce the symmetries of the
hypergeometric and Gegenbauer equation from conformal symmetries of the 4- and
3-dimensional Laplace equation. We also derive the symmetries of the confluent
and Hermite equation from the so-called Schr\&quot;odinger symmetries of the heat
equation in 2 and 1 dimension. Finally, we also describe how properties of the
${}_0F_1$ equation follow from the Helmholtz equation in 2 dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.02807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.02807</id><created>2015-05-11</created><updated>2015-05-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shih</keyname><forenames>Hong-Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Tsung-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldenfeld</keyname><forenames>Nigel</forenames></author></authors><title>Ecological collapse and the emergence of traveling waves at the onset of
  shear turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.CD q-bio.PE</categories><comments>5 pages and 3 figures + 2 pages of supplementary material and 1
  supplementary figure. v2: Minor typos corrected, brief discussion added about
  the derivation and role of effective theories in transitional turbulence</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics, 12, 245-248 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3548</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transition to turbulence exhibits remarkable spatio-temporal behavior
that continues to defy detailed understanding. Near the onset to turbulence in
pipes, transient turbulent regions decay either directly or, at higher Reynolds
numbers through splitting, with characteristic time-scales that exhibit a
super-exponential dependence on Reynolds number. Here we report numerical
simulations of transitional pipe flow, showing that a zonal flow emerges at
large scales, activated by anisotropic turbulent fluctuations; in turn, the
zonal flow suppresses the small-scale turbulence leading to stochastic
predator-prey dynamics. We show that this &quot;ecological&quot; model of transitional
turbulence reproduces the super-exponential lifetime statistics and
phenomenology of pipe flow experiments. Our work demonstrates that a fluid on
the edge of turbulence is mathematically analogous to an ecosystem on the edge
of extinction, and provides an unbroken link between the equations of fluid
dynamics and the directed percolation universality class.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01936</id><created>2015-08-08</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yaghjian</keyname><forenames>Arthur D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical power and energy relations for macroscopic dipolar continua
  derived from the microscopic Maxwell equations</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Progress in Electromagnetics Research B, Vol. 71, pp. 1-37, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Positive semi-definite expressions for the time-domain macroscopic energy
density in passive, spatially nondispersive, dipolar continua are derived from
the underlying microscopic Maxwell equations satisfied by classical models of
discrete bound dipolar molecules or inclusions of the material or metamaterial
continua. The microscopic derivation reveals two distinct positive
semi-definite macroscopic energy expressions, one that applies to diamagnetic
continua and another that applies to paramagnetic continua. The diamagnetic
dipoles are &quot;unconditionally passive&quot; in that their Amperian magnetic dipole
moments are zero in the absence of applied fields. The analysis of paramagnetic
continua, whose magnetization is caused by the alignment of randomly oriented
&quot;permanent&quot; Amperian magnetic dipole moments that dominate any induced
diamagnetic magnetization, is greatly simplified by first proving that the
microscopic power equations for rotating &quot;permanent&quot; Amperian magnetic dipoles
(which are shown to not satisfy unconditional passivity) reduce effectively to
the same power equations obeyed by rotating unconditionally passive
magnetic-charge magnetic dipoles. The difference between the macroscopic
paramagnetic and diamagnetic energy expressions is equal to a &quot;hidden energy&quot;
that parallels the hidden momentum often attributed to Amperian magnetic
dipoles. The microscopic derivation reveals that this hidden energy is drawn
from the reservoir of inductive energy in the initial paramagnetic microscopic
Amperian magnetic dipole moments. The macroscopic, positive semi-definite,
time-domain energy expressions are applied to lossless bianisotropic media to
determine the inequalities obeyed by the frequency-domain bianisotropic
constitutive parameters. Subtleties associated with the causality as well as
the group and energy-transport velocities for diamagnetic media are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04019</id><created>2015-08-17</created><updated>2015-10-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>Adonis Silva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Hari Prasad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vassen</keyname><forenames>Wim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knoop</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author></authors><title>Simple method for producing Bose-Einstein condensates of metastable
  helium using a single beam optical dipole trap</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>improved manuscript (accepted for publication in Applied Physics B)</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. B 121, 391 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-015-6243-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a simple scheme to reach Bose-Einstein condensation (BEC) of
metastable triplet helium atoms using a single beam optical dipole trap with
moderate power of less than 3 W. Our scheme is based on RF-induced evaporative
cooling in a quadrupole magnetic trap and transfer to a single beam optical
dipole trap that is located below the magnetic trap center. We transfer 1x10^6
atoms into the optical dipole trap, with an initial temperature of 14 \mu K,
and observe efficient forced evaporative cooling both in a hybrid trap, in
which the quadrupole magnetic trap operates just below the levitation gradient,
and in the pure optical dipole trap, reaching the onset of BEC with 2x10^5
atoms and a pure BEC of 5x10^4 atoms. Our work shows that a single beam hybrid
trap can be applied for a light atom, for which evaporative cooling in the
quadrupole magnetic trap is strongly limited by Majorana spin-flips, and the
very small levitation gradient limits the axial confinement in the hybrid trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05357</id><created>2015-09-17</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deriglazov</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>Walberto Guzm&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathisson-Papapetrou-Tulczyjew-Dixon (MPTD) equations in
  ultra-relativistic regime and gravimagnetic moment</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages, typos corrected, close to published version</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics D Vol. 26 (2017) 1750047
  (12 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021827181750047X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mathisson-Papapetrou-Tulczyjew-Dixon (MPTD) equations in the Lagrangian
formulation correspond to the minimal interaction of spin with gravity. Due to
the interaction, in the Lagrangian equations instead of the original metric $g$
emerges spin-dependent effective metric $G=g+h(S)$. So we need to decide, which
of them the MPTD particle sees as the space-time metric. We show that MPTD
equations, if considered with respect to original metric, have unsatisfactory
behavior: the acceleration in the direction of velocity grows up to infinity in
the ultra-relativistic limit. If considered with respect to $G$, the theory has
no this problem. But the metric now depends on spin, so there is no unique
space-time manifold for the Universe of spinning particles: each particle
probes his own three-dimensional geometry. This can be improved by adding a
non-minimal interaction of spin with gravity through gravimagnetic moment. The
modified MPTD equations with unit gravimagnetic moment have reasonable behavior
within the original metric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05729</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>MINERvA Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Wolcott</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altinok</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellantoni</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bercellie</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betancourt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bravar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budd</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carneiro</keyname><forenames>M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chvojka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Motta</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dytman</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberly</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felix</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fields</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fine</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gran</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higuera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiveni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleykamp</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kordosky</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maher</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caicedo</keyname><forenames>D. A. Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGivern</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGowan</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messerly</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mislivec</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morfin</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousseau</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muhlbeier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naples</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norrick</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osta</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdue</keyname><forenames>G. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakotondravohitra</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ransome</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rimal</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruterbories</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schellman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitz</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salinas</keyname><forenames>C. J. Solano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagg</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tice</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valencia</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wospakrik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zavala</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziemer</keyname><forenames>B. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of electron neutrino quasielastic and quasielastic-like
  scattering on hydrocarbon at $\langle E_{\nu} \rangle $ = 3.6 GeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>includes ancillary files with flux, measured cross sections, and
  covariance matrices (v9 includes tables of nu_e + antinu_e / nu_mu ratio and
  associated covariances)</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-15-399-ND</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 081802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.081802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first direct measurement of electron-neutrino quasielastic and
quasielastic-like scattering on hydrocarbon in the few-GeV region of incident
neutrino energy has been carried out using the MINERvA detector in the NuMI
beam at Fermilab. The flux-integrated differential cross sections in electron
production angle, electron energy and $Q^{2}$ are presented. The ratio of the
quasielastic, flux-integrated differential cross section in $Q^{2}$ for
$\nu_{e}$ with that of similarly-selected $\nu_{\mu}$-induced events from the
same exposure is used to probe assumptions that underpin conventional
treatments of charged-current $\nu_{e}$ interactions used by long-baseline
neutrino oscillation experiments. The data are found to be consistent with
lepton universality and are well-described by the predictions of the neutrino
event generator GENIE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02769</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>Zak</forenames></author></authors><title>The Clifford group forms a unitary 3-design</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information and Computation 16, 1379-1400 (2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unitary $k$-designs are finite ensembles of unitary matrices that approximate
the Haar distribution over unitary matrices. Several ensembles are known to be
2-designs, including the uniform distribution over the Clifford group, but no
family of ensembles was previously known to form a 3-design. We prove that the
Clifford group is a 3-design, showing that it is a better approximation to
Haar-random unitaries than previously expected. Our proof strategy works for
any distribution of unitaries satisfying a property we call Pauli 2-mixing and
proceeds without the use of heavy mathematical machinery. We also show that the
Clifford group does not form a 4-design, thus characterizing how well random
Clifford elements approximate Haar-random unitaries. Additionally, we show that
the generalized Clifford group for qudits is not a 3-design unless the
dimension of the qudit is a power of 2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05186</id><created>2015-10-17</created><updated>2016-10-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamada</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawana</keyname><forenames>Kiyoharu</forenames></author></authors><title>Reheating-era leptogenesis</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures; published version(v2)</comments><report-no>KUNS-2580</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.10.067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel leptogenesis scenario at the reheating era. Our setup is
minimal in the sense that, in addition to the standard model Lagrangian, we
only consider an inflaton and higher dimensional operators. The lepton number
asymmetry is produced not by the decay of a heavy particle, but by the
scattering between the standard model particles. After the decay of an
inflaton, the model is described within the standard model with higher
dimensional operators. The Sakharov's three conditions are satisfied by the
following way. The violation of the lepton number is realized by the
dimension-5 operator. The complex phase comes from the dimension-6 four lepton
operator. The universe is out of equilibrium before the reheating is completed.
It is found that the successful baryogenesis is realized for the wide range of
parameters, the inflaton mass and reheating temperature, depending on the
cutoff scale. Since we only rely on the effective Lagrangian, our scenario can
be applicable to all mechanisms to generate neutrino Majorana masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06197</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takano</keyname><forenames>Masanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wada</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Ichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Reciprocal Altruism-based Cooperation in a Social Network Game</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Published in New Generation Computing, Volume 34, Issue 3, p.
  257-272, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00354-016-0304-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cooperative behaviors are common in humans and are fundamental to our
society. Theoretical and experimental studies have modeled environments in
which the behaviors of humans, or agents, have been restricted to analyze their
social behavior. However, it is important that such studies are generalized to
less restrictive environments to understand human society. Social network games
(SNGs) provide a particularly powerful tool for the quantitative study of human
behavior. In SNGs, numerous players can behave more freely than in the
environments used in previous studies; moreover, their relationships include
apparent conflicts of interest and every action can be recorded. We focused on
reciprocal altruism, one of the mechanisms that generate cooperative behavior.
This study aims to investigate cooperative behavior based on reciprocal
altruism in a less restrictive environment. For this purpose, we analyzed the
social behavior underlying such cooperative behavior in an SNG. We focused on a
game scenario in which the relationship between the players was similar to that
in the Leader game. We defined cooperative behaviors by constructing a payoff
matrix in the scenario. The results showed that players maintained cooperative
behavior based on reciprocal altruism, and cooperators received more advantages
than noncooperators. We found that players constructed reciprocal relationships
based on two types of interactions, cooperative behavior and unproductive
communication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06468</id><created>2015-10-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Prado</keyname><forenames>Caio A G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cosentino</keyname><forenames>Mauro R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Munhoz</keyname><forenames>Marcelo G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noronha</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suaide</keyname><forenames>Alexandre A P</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy flavor electron $R_\text{AA}$ and $v_2$ in event-by-event
  relativistic hydrodynamics</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings for the XIII International Workshop on Hadron Physics,
  Angra dos Reis, Brazil, March 22-27, 2015; 6 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/706/5/052005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we investigate how event-by-event hydrodynamics fluctuations
affect the nuclear suppression factor and elliptic flow of heavy flavor mesons
and non-photonic electrons. We use a 2D+1 Lagrangian ideal hydrodynamic code on
an event-by-event basis in order to compute local temperature and flow
profiles. Using a strong coupling inspired energy loss parametrization on top
of the evolving space-time energy density distributions we are able to
propagate the heavy quarks inside the medium until the freeze-out temperature
is reached and a Pythia modeling of hadronization takes place. The resulting
D$^0$ and heavy-flavor electron yield is compared with recent experimental data
for $R_\text{AA}$ and $v_2$ from the STAR and Phenix collaborations. In
addition we present preditions for the higher order Fourier harmonic
coefficients $v_3(p_T)$ of heavy-flavor electrons at RHIC's $\sqrt{S_\text{NN}}
= 200$ GeV collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07988</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leonardi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alunni</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romeo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panella</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hunting for heavy composite Majorana neutrinos at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures, Minor comments and few references added. Version
  accepted by the European Physical Journal C (EPJC)</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016) no.11, 593</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4396-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the search for heavy Majorana neutrinos stemming from a
composite model scenario at the upcoming LHC Run II at a center of mass energy
of 13 TeV. While previous studies of the composite Majorana neutrino were
focussed on gauge interactions via magnetic type transition coupling between
ordinary and heavy fermions (with mass $m^*$) here we complement the composite
model with contact interactions at the energy scale $\Lambda$ and we find that
the production cross sections are dominated by such contact interactions by
roughly two/three orders of magnitude. This mechanism provides therefore very
interesting rates at the prospected luminosities. We study the same sign
di-lepton and di-jet signature ($pp \to \ell\ell jj$) and perform a fast
detector simulation based on Delphes. We compute 3$\sigma$ and 5$\sigma$
contour plots of the statistical significance in the parameter space
($\Lambda,m^*$). We find that the potentially excluded regions at $\sqrt{s}
=13$ TeV are quite larger than those excluded so far at Run I considering
searches with other signatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08051</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Harinder</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vyas</keyname><forenames>Manan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomsovic</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Gaussian wave packet dynamics: Integrable and Chaotic
  Systems</title><categories>quant-ph nlin.CD</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures, corrected a typo in Eqs. 29,32</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 012213 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.012213</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ultimate semiclassical wave packet propagation technique is a complex,
time-dependent WBK method known as generalized Gaussian wave packet dynamics
(GGWPD). It requires overcoming many technical difficulties in order to be
carried out fully in practice. In its place roughly twenty years ago,
linearized wave packet dynamics was generalized to methods that include sets of
off-center, real trajectories for both classically integrable and chaotic
dynamical systems that completely capture the dynamical transport. The
connections between those methods and GGWPD are developed in a way that enables
a far more practical implementation of GGWPD. The generally complex saddle
point trajectories at its foundation are found using a multi-dimensional,
Newton-Raphson root search method that begins with the set of off-center, real
trajectories. This is possible because there is a one-to-one correspondence.
The neighboring trajectories associated with each off-center, real trajectory
form a path that crosses a unique saddle; there are exceptions which are
straightforward to identify. The method is applied to the kicked rotor to
demonstrate the accuracy improvement as a function of $\hbar$ that comes with
using the saddle point trajectories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02115</id><created>2015-11-06</created><authors><author><keyname>del Pino</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feist</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Vidal</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures of Vibrational Strong Coupling in Raman Scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, 2015, 119 (52)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b11654</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Letter we analyze theoretically how the emergence of collective
strong coupling between vibrational excitations and confined cavity modes
affects Raman scattering processes. This work is motivated by recent
experiments [Shalabney et al., Angew. Chemie 54, 7971 (2015)], which reported
enhancements of up to three orders of magnitude in the Raman signal. By using
different models within linear response theory, we show that the total Raman
cross section is maintained constant when the system evolves from the
weak-coupling limit to the strong-coupling regime. A redistribution of the
Raman signal among the two polaritons is the main fingerprint of vibrational
strong coupling in the Raman spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08312</id><created>2015-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Yuge</keyname><forenames>Koretaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishimoto</keyname><forenames>Tetuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical study on density of microscopic states in configuration
  space via Random Matrix</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Trans. Mat. Res. Soc. Jpn. 41, 213 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In classical systems, our recent theoretical study provides new insight into
how spatial constraint on the system connects with macroscopic properties,
which lead to universal representation of equilibrium macroscopic physical
property and structure in disordered states. These important characteristics
rely on the fact that statistical interdependence for density of microscopic
states (DOMS) in configuration space appears numerically vanished at
thermodynamic limit for a wide class of spatial constraints, while such
behavior of the DOMS is not quantitatively well-understood so far. The present
study theoretically address this problem based on the Random Matrix with
Gaussian Orthogonal Ensemble, where corresponding statistical independence is
mathematically guaranteed. Using the generalized Ising model, we confirm that
lower-order moment of density of eigenstates (DOE) of covariance matrix of DOMS
shows asymptotic behavior to those for Random Matrix with increase of system
size. This result supports our developed theoretical approach, where
equilibrium macroscopic property in disordered states can be decomposed into
individual contribtion from each generalized coordinate with the sufficiently
high number of constituents in the given system, leading to representing
equilibrium macroscopic properties by a few special microscopic states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02035</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gamayun</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenyakin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Soliton splitting in quenched classical integrable systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.PS</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 335201</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/33/335201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We take a soliton solution of a classical non-linear integrable equation and
quench (suddenly change) its non-linearity parameter. For that we multiply the
amplitude or the width of a soliton by a numerical factor $\eta$ and take the
obtained profile as a new initial condition. We find the values of $\eta$ at
which the post-quench solution consists of only a finite number of solitons.
The parameters of these solitons are found explicitly. Our approach is based on
solving the direct scattering problem analytically. We demonstrate how it works
for Kortewig-de-Vries, sine-Gordon and non-linear Schr\&quot;odinger integrable
equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02085</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yadin</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Jiajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Girolami</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Mile</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedral</keyname><forenames>Vlatko</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum processes which do not use coherence</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, comments are welcome. Revised presentation and
  added Result 7. Close to published version (accepted for publication in
  Physical Review X)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 041028 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.041028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major signature of quantum mechanics beyond classical physics is coherence,
the existence of superposition states. The recently developed resource theory
of quantum coherence allows the formalisation of incoherent operations -- those
operations which cannot create coherence. We identify the set of operations
which additionally do not use coherence. These are such that coherence cannot
be exploited by a classical observer, who measures incoherent properties of the
system, to go beyond classical dynamics. We give a physical interpretation in
terms of interferometry and prove a dilation theorem, showing how these
operations can always be constructed by interacting the system in an incoherent
way with an ancilla. Such a physical justification is not known for the
incoherent operations, thus our results lead to a physically well-motivated
resource theory of coherence. Next, we investigate the implications for
coherence in multipartite systems. We show that quantum correlations can be
defined naturally with respect to a fixed basis, providing a link between
coherence and quantum discord. We demonstrate the interplay between these two
quantities under our studied operations, and suggest implications for the
theory of quantum discord by relating the studied operations to those which
cannot create discord.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09051</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Azovtsev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pertsev</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetization dynamics and spin pumping induced by standing elastic
  waves</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 17 figures, submitted to Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 184401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.184401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetization dynamics induced by standing elastic waves excited in a
thin ferromagnetic film is described with the aid of micromagnetic simulations
taking into account the magnetoelastic coupling between spins and lattice
strains. The simulations have been performed for the 2 nm thick Fe81Ga19 film
dynamically strained by longitudinal and transverse standing waves with various
frequencies, which span a wide range around the resonance frequency nu_res of
coherent magnetization precession in unstrained Fe81Ga19 film. It is found that
standing elastic waves give rise to complex local magnetization dynamics and
spatially inhomogeneous dynamic magnetic patterns. The spatio-temporal
distributions of the magnetization oscillations in standing elastic waves have
the form of standing spin waves with the same wavelength. Remarkably, the
amplitude of magnetization precession does not go to zero at the nodes of these
spin waves, which cannot be precisely described by simple analytical formulae.
In the steady-state regime, the magnetization oscillates with the frequency of
elastic wave, except for the case of longitudinal waves with frequencies well
below nu_res, where the magnetization precesses with a variable frequency
strongly exceeding the wave frequency. The precession amplitude at the
antinodes of standing spin waves strongly increases when the frequency of
elastic wave becomes close to nu_res. The results obtained for the
magnetization dynamics driven by elastic waves are used to calculate the spin
current pumped from the dynamically strained ferromagnet into adjacent
paramagnetic metal. Importantly, the transverse charge current created by the
spin current via the inverse spin Hall effect is high enough to be measured
experimentally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02203</id><created>2016-01-10</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nojiri</keyname><forenames>Shin'ichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Some solutions for one of the cosmological constant problems</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>LaTeX 9 pages, references are added, the version to appear in
  Mod.Phys.Lett.A</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732316502138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose several covariant models which may solve one of the problems in
the cosmological constant. One of the model can be regarded as an extension of
sequestering model. Other models could be regarded as extensions of the
covariant formulation of the unimodular gravity. The contributions to the
vacuum energy from the quantum corrections from the matters are absorbed into a
redefinition of a scalar field and the quantum corrections become irrelevant to
the dynamics. In a class of the extended unimodular gravity models, we also
consider models which are regarded as topological field theories. The models
can be extended and not only the vacuum energy but any quantum corrections to
the gravitational action could become irrelevant for the dynamics. We find,
however, that the BRS symmetry in the topological field theories is broken
spontaneously and therefore the models might not be consistent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02928</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Mengyao</forenames><affiliation>Beijing Normal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Biwei</forenames><affiliation>Beijing Normal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames><affiliation>Beijing Normal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jiaming</forenames><affiliation>Beijing Normal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames><affiliation>Beijing Normal University</affiliation><affiliation>University of Missouri</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Aigen</forenames><affiliation>University of Missouri</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Precise Determination of the Mid-Infrared Interstellar Extinction Law
  Based on the APOGEE Spectroscopic Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>The bandpass coverage of WISE in Fig.18 changed from photon-counting
  relative system response (RSR) to QE-based (response per photon) RSR</comments><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/224/2/23</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A precise measure of the mid-infrared interstellar extinction law is crucial
to the investigation of the properties of interstellar dust, especially of the
grains in the large size end. Based on the stellar parameters derived from the
SDSS-III/APOGEE spectroscopic survey, we select a large sample of G- and K-type
giants as the tracers of the Galactic mid-infrared extinction. We calculate the
intrinsic stellar color excesses from the stellar effective temperatures and
use them to determine the mid-infrared extinction for a given line of sight.
For the entire sky of the Milky Way surveyed by APOGEE, we derive the
extinction (relative to the K$_{\rm S}$ band at wavelength $\lambda=2.16\mu$m)
for the four WISE bands at 3.4, 4.6, 12 and 22$\mu$m, the four Spitzer/IRAC
bands at 3.6, 4.5, 5.8 and 8$\mu$m, the Spitzer/MIPS24 band at 23.7$\mu$m and
for the first time, the AKARI/S9W band at 8.23$\mu$m. Our results agree with
previous works in that the extinction curve is flat in the ~3--8$\mu$m
wavelength range and is generally consistent with the $R_V=5.5$ model curve
except our determination exceeds the model prediction in the WISE/W4 band.
Although some previous works found that the mid-IR extinction law appears to
vary with the extinction depth $A_{\rm{K_S}}$, no noticeable variation has been
found in this work. The uncertainties are analyzed in terms of the bootstrap
resampling method and Monte-Carlo simulation and are found to be rather small.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05977</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shahbazyan</keyname><forenames>Tigran V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Local density of states for nanoplasmonics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 207401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.207401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain the local density of states (LDOS) for any nanoplasmonic system in
the frequency range dominated by a localized surface plasmon. By including the
Ohmic losses in a consistent way, we show that the plasmon LDOS is proportional
to the local field intensity normalized by the absorbed power. We obtain
explicit formulas for the energy transfer (ET) between quantum emitters and
plasmons as well as between donors and acceptors situated near a plasmonic
structure. In the latter case, we find that the plasmon-assisted ET rate is
proportional to the LDOS product at the donor and acceptor positions, obtain,
in a general form, the plasmon ET enhancement factor, and establish the
transition onset between Forster-dominated and plasmon-dominated ET regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00537</id><created>2016-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Fengxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Zeyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Shijing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieslich</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Donald M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carpenter</keyname><forenames>Michael A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bristowe</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheetham</keyname><forenames>Anthony K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Synthesis, Structure and Electronic Properties of a Lead-Free Hybrid
  Inorganic-Organic Double Perovskite (MA)2KBiCl6 (MA = methylammonium)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1039/C6MH00053C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a search for Lead-free materials that could be used as alternatives to the
hybrid perovskites,(MA)PbX3, in photovoltaic applications, we have discovered a
hybrid double perovskite, (MA)2KBiCl6, which shows striking similarities to the
lead analogues. Spectroscopic measurements and nanoindentation studies are
combined with density functional calculations to reveal the properties of this
interesting system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00616</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dicko</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pages</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Firszt</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strzalkowski</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paszkowicz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maillard</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jobard</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-forward Raman selection rules of the phonon-polariton created by
  alloying in (Zn,Be)Se</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 120, 185702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4967315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Raman selection rules of the (ZnSe, BeSe) mixed phonon polariton created
by alloying in the three mode (1ZnSe, 2BeSe) ZnBeSe system, whose dramatic S
like dispersion covers the large frequency gap between the ZnSe and BeSe
spectral ranges, is studied in its wave vector dependence by near forward
scattering. Both the collapse regime away from the Brillouin zone centre and
the reinforcement regime near the Brillouin zone centre are addressed, using
appropriate laser lines and Be contents. We find that in both regimes the
considered phonon polariton, in fact a transverse mode with mixed mechanical
and electrical character, obeys the same nominal Raman selection rules as its
purely mechanical variant commonly observed in the backscattering geometry.
Besides, marked differences in the phonon polariton Raman lineshapes in the two
regimes give a hint about how the phonon polariton electrical field E develops
while descending the S like dispersion towards the Brillouin zone centre. In
the reinforcement regime E is large, leading to intramode on top of intermode
transfers of oscillator strength mediated by E between the two BeSe modes, that
both exhibit a fine structure on account of the alloy disorder. In contrast, in
the collapse regime E remains weak, as testified by the absence of intramode
transfer. The discussion is supported by contour modeling of the multi phonon
polariton Raman lineshapes in their wave vector dependence within the linear
dielectric approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01104</id><created>2016-04-04</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>In-Jee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sodin</keyname><forenames>Sasha</forenames></author></authors><title>A Limit Theorem for Stochastically Decaying Partitions at the Edge</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>39 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Random Matrices: Theory Appl. 05, 1650016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S2010326316500167</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the asymptotic behavior of the first, second, and so
on rows of stochastically decaying partitions. We establish that, with
appropriate scaling in time and length, the sequence of rows converges to the
Airy$_2$ line ensemble.
  This result was first established, in a more general setting, by Borodin and
Olshanski, who relied on the determinantal structure of the Poissonized
correlation functions. Our argument is based on a different, combinatorial
approach, developed by Okounkov. This approach may be useful in other problems
in which no determinantal structure is available, and also highlights the
similarity between random partitions and random matrices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05867</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05867</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arakawa</keyname><forenames>Naoya</forenames></author></authors><title>Vector chirality for effective total momentum $J_{\textrm{eff}}$ in a
  nonfrustrated Mott insulator: Effects of strong spin-orbit coupling and
  broken inversion symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 174416 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.174416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I propose the emergence of the spin-orbital-coupled vector chirality in a
non-frustrated Mott insulator with the strong spin-orbit coupling due to
$ab$-plane's inversion-symmetry (IS) breaking. I derive the superexchange
interactions for a $t_{2g}$-orbital Hubbard model on a square lattice with the
strong spin-orbit coupling and the IS-breaking-induced hopping integrals, and
explain the microscopic origins of the Dzyaloshinsky-Moriya (DM) -type and the
Kitaev-type interactions. Then, by adopting the mean-field approximation to a
minimal model including only the Heisenberg-type and the DM-type
nearest-neighbor interactions, I show that the IS breaking causes the
spin-orbital-coupled chirality as a result of stabilizing the screw state. I
also highlight the limit of the hard-pseudospin approximation in discussing the
stability of the screw states in the presence of both the DM-type and the
Kitaev-type interactions, and discuss its meaning. I finally discuss the
effects of tetragonal crystal field and $J_{\textrm{eff}}=\frac{3}{2}$ states,
and the application to the iridates near the $[001]$ surface of
Sr$_{2}$IrO$_{4}$ and the interface between Sr$_{2}$IrO$_{4}$ and
Sr$_{3}$Ir$_{2}$O$_{7}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07000</id><created>2016-04-24</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jourdan</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stoltz</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames><affiliation>MATHERIALS, CERMICS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Legoll</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames><affiliation>NAVIER, MATHERIALS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Monasse</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames><affiliation>CERMICS</affiliation></author></authors><title>An accurate scheme to solve cluster dynamics equations using a
  Fokker-Planck approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Computer Physics Communications, Elsevier, 2016, 207, pp.170</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2016.06.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a numerical method to accurately simulate particle size
distributions within the formalism of rate equation cluster dynamics. This
method is based on a discretization of the associated Fokker-Planck equation.
We show that particular care has to be taken to discretize the advection part
of the Fokker-Planck equation, in order to avoid distortions of the
distribution due to numerical diffusion. For this purpose we use the
Kurganov-Noelle-Petrova scheme coupled with the monotonicity-preserving
reconstruction MP5, which leads to very accurate results. The interest of the
method is highlighted on the case of loop coarsening in aluminum. We show that
the choice of the models to describe the energetics of loops does not
significantly change the normalized loop distribution, while the choice of the
models for the absorption coefficients seems to have a significant impact on
it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07287</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferizi</keyname><forenames>Uran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scherrer</keyname><forenames>Benoit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Torben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alipoor</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eufracio</keyname><forenames>Odin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fick</keyname><forenames>Rutger H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deriche</keyname><forenames>Rachid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loya-Olivas</keyname><forenames>Ana K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivera</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poot</keyname><forenames>Dirk H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez-Manzanares</keyname><forenames>Alonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marroquin</keyname><forenames>Jose L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rokem</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xf6;tter</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dougherty</keyname><forenames>Robert F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakaie</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wheeler-Kingshott</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warfield</keyname><forenames>Simon K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witzel</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wald</keyname><forenames>Lawrence L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raya</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Daniel C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion MRI microstructure models with in vivo human brain Connectom
  data: results from a multi-group comparison</title><categories>physics.med-ph q-bio.NC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A large number of mathematical models have been proposed to describe the
measured signal in diffusion-weighted (DW) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and
infer properties about the white matter microstructure. However, a head-to-head
comparison of DW-MRI models is critically missing in the field. To address this
deficiency, we organized the &quot;White Matter Modeling Challenge&quot; during the
International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI) 2015 conference. This
competition aimed at identifying the DW-MRI models that best predict unseen DW
data. in vivo DW-MRI data was acquired on the Connectom scanner at the
A.A.Martinos Center (Massachusetts General Hospital) using gradients strength
of up to 300 mT/m and a broad set of diffusion times. We focused on assessing
the DW signal prediction in two regions: the genu in the corpus callosum, where
the fibres are relatively straight and parallel, and the fornix, where the
configuration of fibres is more complex. The challenge participants had access
to three-quarters of the whole dataset, and their models were ranked on their
ability to predict the remaining unseen quarter of data. In this paper we
provide both an overview and a more in-depth description of each evaluated
model, report the challenge results, and infer trends about the model
characteristics that were associated with high model ranking. This work
provides a much needed benchmark for DW-MRI models. The acquired data and model
details for signal prediction evaluation are provided online to encourage a
larger scale assessment of diffusion models in the future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00603</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Olesen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A center vortex representaton of the classical SU(2) vacuum</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Some references are added and a more detailed discussion of the
  quantum case is given</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classical massless SU(2) field theory has an infinite number of gauge
equivalent representations of the vacuum. We show that among these there exists
a non-perturbative center vortex representation with some similarity to the
quantum vacuum of the same theory. This classical SU(2) vacuum consists of a
lattice of center vortex pairs combining to triviality. However, this
triviality can be broken by perturbations, for example by adding a mass term,
or by considering the electroweak theory where the Higgs field does the
breaking, or by quantum fluctuations like in QCD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02207</id><created>2016-05-07</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Sumit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manchon</keyname><forenames>Aurelien</forenames></author></authors><title>Signature of topological phases in Zitterbewegung</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>LaTex, 6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>SPIN 06, 1640004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S201032471640004X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the {\em Zitterbewegung} effect on an infinite two
dimensional sheet with honeycomb lattice. By tuning the perpendicular electric
field and the magnetization of the sheet, it can enter different topological
phases. We have shown that the phase and magnitude of Zitterbewegung effect,
i.e. the jittering motion of relativistic particles, correlates with the
various topological phases. The topological phase diagram can be reconstructed
by analyzing these features. Our findings are applicable to materials like
silicene, germanene, stanene etc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04679</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-06-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takabe</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hukushima</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>Typical Performance of Approximation Algorithms for NP-hard Problems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cs.DS</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures; typos are fixed</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 113401</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/11/113401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Typical performance of approximation algorithms is studied for randomized
minimum vertex cover problems. A wide class of random graph ensembles
characterized by an arbitrary degree distribution is discussed with some
theoretical frameworks. Here three approximation algorithms are examined; the
linear-programming relaxation, the loopy-belief propagation, and the
leaf-removal algorithm. The former two algorithms are analyzed using the
statistical-mechanical technique while the average-case analysis of the last
one is studied by the generating function method. These algorithms have a
threshold in the typical performance with increasing the average degree of the
random graph, below which they find true optimal solutions with high
probability. Our study reveals that there exist only three cases determined by
the order of the typical-performance thresholds. We provide some conditions for
classifying the graph ensembles and demonstrate explicitly examples for the
difference in the threshold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05347</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roscher</keyname><forenames>Dietrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strack</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual QED3 at &quot;NF = 1/2&quot; is an interacting CFT in the infrared</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures; v2 minor typos fixed</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 11 (2016) 017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the fate of weakly coupled dual QED3 in the infrared, that is, a
single two-component Dirac fermion coupled to an emergent U(1) gauge field, but
without Chern-Simons term. This theory has recently been proposed as a dual
description of 2D surfaces of certain topological insulators. Using the
renormalization group, we find that the interplay of gauge fluctuations with
generated interactions in the four-fermi sector stabilizes an interacting
conformal field theory (CFT) with finite four-fermi coupling in the infrared.
The emergence of this CFT is due to cancellations in the $\beta$-function of
the four-fermi coupling special to &quot;NF = 1/2&quot;. We also quantify how a possible
&quot;strong&quot; Dirac fermion duality between a free Dirac cone and dual QED3 would
constrain the universal constants of the topological current correlator of the
latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06119</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Halzen</keyname><forenames>Francis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheirandish</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>High Energy Neutrinos from Recent Blazar Flares</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/831/1/12</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy density of cosmic neutrinos measured by IceCube matches the one
observed by Fermi in extragalactic photons that predominantly originate in
blazars. This has inspired attempts to match Fermi sources with IceCube
neutrinos. A spatial association combined with a coincidence in time with a
flaring source may represent a smoking gun for the origin of the IceCube flux.
In June 2015, the Fermi Large Area Telescope observed an intense flare from
blazar 3C 279 that exceeded the steady flux of the source by a factor of forty
for the duration of a day. We show that IceCube is likely to observe neutrinos,
if indeed hadronic in origin, in data that are still blinded at this time. We
also discuss other opportunities for coincident observations that include a
recent flare from blazar 1ES 1959+650 that previously produced an intriguing
coincidence with AMANDA observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07453</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-11-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for hidden-charm baryonium signals in QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, 1 table. Accepted by Eur. Phys. J. C</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C76 (2016) no.11, 602</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4459-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an explicit QCD sum rule investigation to hidden-charm baryonium
states with the quark content $u\bar u d\bar d c\bar c$, spin $J=0/1/2/3$, and
of both positive and negative parities. We systematically construct the
relevant local hidden-charm baryonium interpolating currents, which can
actually couple to various structures, including hidden-charm baryonium states,
charmonium states plus two pions, and hidden-charm tetraquark states plus one
pion, etc. We do not know which structure these currents couple to at the
beginning, but after sum rule analyses we can obtain some information. We find
some of them can couple to hidden-charm baryonium states, using which we
evaluate the masses of the lowest-lying hidden-charm baryonium states with
quantum numbers $J^P=2^-/3^-/0^+/1^+/2^+$ to be around 5.0 GeV. We suggest to
search for hidden-charm baryonium states, especially the one of $J=3^-$, in the
$D$-wave $J/\psi \pi \pi$ and $P$-wave $J/\psi \rho$ and $J/\psi \omega$
channels in this energy region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00301</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Stenull</keyname><forenames>Olaf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kane</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubensky</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological phonons and Weyl lines in 3 dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 068001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.068001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological mechanics and phononics have recently emerged as an exciting
field of study. Here we introduce and study generalizations of the
three-dimensional pyrochlore lattice that have topologically protected edge
states and Weyl lines in their bulk phonon spectra, which lead to zero surface
modes that flip from one edge to the opposite as a function of surface
wavenumber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02625</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the Inelastic Proton-Proton Cross Section at $\sqrt{s} =
  13$ TeV with the ATLAS Detector at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>12 pages plus author list + cover pages (30 pages total), 3 figures,
  1 table. Revised version including an update of Figure 3. Published in Phys.
  Rev. Lett.. All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2015-05</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-140</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 182002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.182002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This Letter presents a measurement of the inelastic proton-proton cross
section using 60 $\mu$b$^{-1}$ of $pp$ collisions at a center-of-mass energy
$\sqrt{s}$ of $13$ TeV with the ATLAS detector at the LHC. Inelastic
interactions are selected using rings of plastic scintillators in the forward
region ($2.07&lt;|\eta|&lt;3.86$) of the detector. A cross section of $68.1\pm 1.4$
mb is measured in the fiducial region $\xi=M_X^2/s&gt;10^{-6}$, where $M_X$ is the
larger invariant mass of the two hadronic systems separated by the largest
rapidity gap in the event. In this $\xi$ range the scintillators are highly
efficient. For diffractive events this corresponds to cases where at least one
proton dissociates to a system with $M_X&gt;13$ GeV. The measured cross section is
compared with a range of theoretical predictions. When extrapolated to the full
phase space, a cross-section of $78.1 \pm 2.9$ mb is measured, consistent with
the inelastic cross section increasing with center-of-mass energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02836</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Odake</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author></authors><title>Recurrence Relations of the Multi-Indexed Orthogonal Polynomials IV :
  closure relations and creation/annihilation operators</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.CA math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>33 pages</comments><report-no>DPSU-16-2</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 57 (2016) 113503 (22pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4966985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the exactly solvable quantum mechanical systems whose
eigenfunctions are described by the multi-indexed orthogonal polynomials of
Laguerre, Jacobi, Wilson and Askey-Wilson types. Corresponding to the
recurrence relations with constant coefficients for the $M$-indexed orthogonal
polynomials, it is expected that the systems satisfy the generalized closure
relations. In fact we can verify this statement for small $M$ examples. The
generalized closure relation gives the exact Heisenberg operator solution of a
certain operator, from which the creation and annihilation operators of the
system are obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02916</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Zeyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Fengxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Shijing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieslich</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheetham</keyname><forenames>Anthony K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bristowe</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the properties of lead-free hybrid double perovskites using a
  combined computational-experimental approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1039/C6TA05817E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density functional theory screening of the hybrid double perovskites
(MA)2BIBiX6 (BI=K,Cu,Ag,Tl; X=Cl,Br,I) shows that systems with band gaps
similar to those of the MAPbX3 lead compounds can be expected for BI=Cu,Ag,Tl.
Motivated by these findings, (MA)2TlBiBr6, isoelectronic with MAPbBr3, was
synthesised and found to have a band gap of ~2.0eV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02944</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ze-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudo-time-reversal symmetry and topological edge states in
  two-dimensional acoustic crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1038/srep32752</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple two-dimensional acoustic crystal to realize topologically
protected edge states for acoustic waves. The acoustic crystal is composed of a
triangular array of core-shell cylinders embedded in a water host. By utilizing
the point group symmetry of two doubly degenerate eigenstates at the \Gamma
point, we can construct pseudo-time-reversal symmetry as well as pseudo-spin
states in this classical system. We develop an effective Hamiltonian model for
the associated dispersion bands around the Brillouin zone center, and find the
inherent link between the band inversion and the topological phase transition.
With numerical simulations, we unambiguously demonstrate the unidirectional
propagation of acoustic edge states along the interface between a topologically
nontrivial acoustic crystal and a trivial one, and the robustness of the edge
states against defects with sharp bends. Our work provides a new design
paradigm for manipulating and transporting acoustic waves in a topologically
protected manner. Technological applications and devices based on our design
are expected in various frequency ranges of interest, spanning from infrasound
to ultrasound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03823</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armendariz-Picon</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x15e;eng&#xf6;r</keyname><forenames>Gizem</forenames></author></authors><title>BRST Quantization of Cosmological Perturbations</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>50 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP11(2016)016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/11/016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  BRST quantization is an elegant and powerful method to quantize theories with
local symmetries. In this article we study the Hamiltonian BRST quantization of
cosmological perturbations in a universe dominated by a scalar field, along
with the closely related quantization method of Dirac. We describe how both
formalisms apply to the perturbations in a time-dependent background, and how
expectation values of gauge-invariant operators can be calculated in the in-in
formalism. Our analysis focuses mostly on the free theory. By appropriate
canonical transformations we simplify and diagonalize the free Hamiltonian.
BRST quantization in derivative gauges allows us to dramatically simplify the
structure of the propagators, whereas quantization in synchronous gauge, which
amounts to Dirac quantization, dispenses with the need to introduce ghosts and
preserves the locality of the gauge-fixed action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04961</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lapsien</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kogler</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haller</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>A new tagger for hadronically decaying heavy particles at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures; updated timing test with new HOTVR version
  improved for timing performance, updated efficiency comparison curves; this
  version matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76, 600 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4443-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new algorithm for the identification of boosted, hadronically decaying,
heavy particles at the LHC is presented. The algorithm is based on the known
procedure of jet clustering with variable distance parameter $R$ and adapts the
jet size to its transverse momentum $p_T$. Subjets are found using a mass jump
condition. The resulting algorithm - called Heavy Object Tagger with Variable
$R$ (HOTVR) - features little algorithmic complexity and combines jet
clustering, subjet finding and rejection of soft clusters in one sequence.
While the HOTVR algorithm can be used for the identification of any heavy
object decaying hadronically, e.g. W, Z, H, t, or possible new heavy
resonances, this paper targets specifically the tagging of boosted top quarks.
The studies presented here demonstrate a stable performance of the HOTVR
algorithm in a wide range of top quark $p_T$, from low $p_T$, where the decay
products can be resolved, to the region of boosted decays at high $p_T$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05823</id><created>2016-06-18</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Yajnavalkya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darewych</keyname><forenames>Jurij W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs particles interacting via a scalar Dark Matter field</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><journal-ref>Canadian Journal of Physics, 10.1139/cjp-2016-0467</journal-ref><doi>10.1139/cjp-2016-0467</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a system of two Higgs bound state, interacting via a real scalar
Dark Matter mediating field, without imposing $Z_2$ symmetry on the DM sector
of the postulated Lagrangian. The variational method in the Hamiltonian
formalism of QFT is used to derive relativistic wave equations for the
two-Higgs system, using a truncated Fock-space trial state. Approximate
solutions of the 2-body relativistic coupled integral equations are presented,
and conditions for the existence of Higgs bound states is examined in a broad
parameter space of DM mass and coupling constants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06027</id><created>2016-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Adabi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haseli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salimi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reducing the entropic uncertainty lower bound in the presence of quantum
  memory via local operation and classical communication</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages and 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 115 (2016) 60004</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/60004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The uncertainty principle sets lower bound on the uncertainties of two
incompatible observables measured on a particle. The uncertainty lower bound
can be reduced by considering a particle as a quantum memory entangled with the
measured particle. In this paper, we consider a tripartite scenario in which a
quantum state has been shared between Alice, Bob, and Charlie. The aim of Bob
and Charlie is to minimize Charlie's lower bound about Alice's measurement
outcomes. To this aim, they concentrate their correlation with Alice in
Charlie's side via a cooperative strategy based on local operations and
classical communication. We obtain lower bound for Charlie's uncertainty about
Alice's measurement outcomes after concentrating information and compare it
with the lower bound without concentrating information in some examples. We
also provide a physical interpretation of the entropic uncertainty lower bound
based on the dense coding capacity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06272</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiocchetta</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambassi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>Jamir</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal short-time dynamics: boundary functional renormalization group
  for a temperature quench</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 174301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.174301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method to calculate short-time non-equilibrium universal
exponents within the functional renormalization-group scheme. As an example, we
consider the classical critical dynamics of the relaxational model A after a
quench of the temperature of the system and calculate the initial slip exponent
which characterizes the non-equilibrium universal short-time behaviour of both
the order parameter and correlation functions. The value of this exponent is
found to be consistent with the result of a perturbative dimensional expansion
and of Monte Carlo simulations in three spatial dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04417</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04417</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fauseweh</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groitl</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolfs</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennant</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habicht</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uhrig</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent correlations in quantum magnets at finite temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 180404(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.180404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we investigate the time dependence of the gap mode of copper
nitrate at various temperatures. We combine state-of-the-art theoretical
calculations with high precision neutron resonance spin-echo measurements to
understand the anomalous decoherence effects found previously in this material.
It is shown that the time domain offers a complementary view on this
phenomenon, which allows us to directly compare experimental data and
theoretical predictions without the need of further intensive data analysis,
such as (de)convolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06117</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>Jasmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gagn&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Artigau</keyname><forenames>&#xc9;tienne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lafreni&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nadeau</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doyon</keyname><forenames>Ren&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malo</keyname><forenames>Lison</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albert</keyname><forenames>Lo&#xef;c</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simard</keyname><forenames>Corinne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gagliuffi</keyname><forenames>Daniella C. Bardalez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgasser</keyname><forenames>Adam J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Brown Dwarf Census from the SIMP Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>85 pages, 9 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/830/2/144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have conducted a near-infrared (NIR) proper motion survey, the Sondage
Infrarouge de Mouvement Propre, in order to discover field ultracool dwarfs
(UCD) in the solar neighborhood. The survey was conducted by imaging $\sim28\%$
of the sky with the Cam\'era PAnoramique Proche-InfraRouge both in the southern
hemisphere at the Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory 1.5 m telescope, and
in the northern hemisphere at the Observatoire du Mont-M\'egantic 1.6 m
telescope and comparing the source positions from these observations with the
Two Micron All-Sky Survey Point Source Catalog (2MASS PSC). Additional color
criteria were used to further discriminate unwanted astrophysical sources. We
present the results of an NIR spectroscopic follow-up of 169 M, L, and T
dwarfs. Among the sources discovered are 2 young field brown dwarfs, 6
unusually red M and L dwarfs, 25 unusually blue M and L dwarfs, 2 candidate
unresolved L+T binaries, and 24 peculiar UCDs. Additionally, we add 9 L/T
transition dwarfs (L6--T4.5) to the already known objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07552</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Peng-Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>An-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Guo-Zhu</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay of Coulomb interaction and disorder in a two-dimensional
  semi-Dirac fermion system</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 195114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.195114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It was recently found that Coulomb interaction can induce a series of
nontrivial spectral and transport properties in a two-dimensional anisotropic
Weyl semimetal. Different from graphehe that is basically an ordinary Fermi
liquid, the Coulomb interaction in this system makes the Fermi liquid
description invalid over a wide range of energy scales. We present a systematic
renormalization group analysis of the interplay of Coulomb interaction and
quenched disorder, and show that they have substantial mutual effects on each
other, which then leads to a variety of quantum phase transitions and non-Fermi
liquid behaviors. The low-energy physics of the system depends sensitively on
the effective strength of Coulomb interaction and disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03704</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Bhagya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xuereb</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dantan</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavity optomechanics with arrays of thick dielectric membranes</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 053812 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.053812</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optomechanical arrays made of structured flexible dielectrics are a promising
system for exploring quantum and many-body optomechanical phenomena. We
generalize investigations of the optomechanical properties of periodic arrays
of one-dimensional scatterers in optical resonators to the case of vibrating
membranes whose thickness is not necessarily small with respect to the optical
wavelength of interest. The array optical transmission spectrum and its
optomechanical coupling with a linear Fabry-Perot cavity field are investigated
both analytically and numerically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03851</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kerner</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Next-to-Leading Order Corrections to Higgs Boson Pair Production in
  Gluon Fusion</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the proceedings of 'Loops and Legs in Quantum Field
  Theory', 24-29 April 2016, Leipzig, Germany</comments><report-no>MPP-2016-258</report-no><journal-ref>PoS LL2016 (2016) 023</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a calculation of the next-to-leading order QCD corrections to the
production of Higgs boson pairs in gluon fusion keeping the full dependence on
the mass of the top quark. The virtual corrections, involving two-loop
integrals with up to four mass scales, have been calculated numerically and we
present an efficient algorithm to obtain accurate results of the virtual
amplitude using numerical integrations. Taking the top quark mass into account
we obtain significant differences compared to results obtained in the heavy top
limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03992</id><created>2016-08-13</created><updated>2016-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apostolovska</keyname><forenames>Gordana</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking radiation of Dirac monopoles from the global monopole black hole
  with quantum gravity effects</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure, to appear in Astrophysics and Space Science</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys Space Sci (2016) 361: 374</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2962-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the quantum tunneling of Dirac magnetic monopoles from
the global monopole black hole under quantum gravity effects. We start from the
modified Maxwell's equations and the Generalized Uncertainty Relation (GUP), to
recover the GUP corrected temperature for the global monopole black hole by
solving the modified Dirac equation via Hamilton-Jacobi method. Furthermore, we
also include the quantum corrections beyond the semiclassical approximation, in
particular, first we find the logarithmic corrections of GUP corrected entropy
and finally we calculate the GUP corrected specific heat capacity. It is argued
that the GUP effects may prevent a black hole from complete evaporation and
leave remnants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06360</id><created>2016-08-22</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Yizhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Decorated defect condensate, a window to unconventional quantum phase
  transitions in Weyl semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 195112(2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.195112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the unconventional quantum phase transitions in Weyl
semimetals. The emergent boson fields, coupling with the Weyl fermion
bilinears, contain a Wess-Zumino-Witten term or topological $\Theta$ term
inherited from the momentum space monopoles carried by Weyl points. Three types
of unconventional quantum critical points will be studied in order: (1) The
transition between two distinct symmetry breaking phases whose criticality is
beyond Landau's paradigm. (2) The transition between a symmetry breaking state
to a topological ordered state. (3) The transition between $3d$ topological
order phase to trivial disordered phase whose criticality could be traced back
to a $Z_2$ symmetry breaking transition in $4d$. The essence of these
unconventional critical points lies in the fact that the topological defect of
an order parameter carries either a nontrivial quantum number or a topological
term so the condensation of the defects would either break some symmetry or
give rise to a topological order phase with nontrivial braiding statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07447</id><created>2016-08-26</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haba</keyname><forenames>Naoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Yuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Naturalness and lepton number/flavor violation in inverse seesaw models</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures: version accepted for publication in JHEP</comments><report-no>SU-HET-06-2016</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1611 (2016) 003</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce three right-handed neutrinos and three sterile neutrinos, and
consider an inverse seesaw mechanism for neutrino mass generation. From
naturalness point of view, their Majorana masses should be small, while it
induces a large neutrino Yukawa coupling. Then, a neutrinoless double beta
decay rate can be enhanced, and a sizable Higgs mass correction is inevitable.
We find that the enhancement rate can be more than ten times compared with a
standard prediction from light neutrino contribution alone, and an analytic
form of heavy neutrino contributions to the Higgs mass correction. In addition,
we numerically analyze the model, and find almost all parameter space of the
model can be complementarily searched by future experiments of neutrinoless
double beta decay and $\mu \to e$ conversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00700</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2016-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bouhmadi-L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Mariam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Che-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards the Quantization of Eddington-inspired-Born-Infeld Theory</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>26 pages, 1 figure. Discussion expanded and further mathematical and
  physical details provided. Version accepted in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 11 (2016) 023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/11/023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum effects close to the classical big rip singularity within the
Eddington-inspired-Born-Infeld theory (EiBI) are investigated through quantum
geometrodynamics. It is the first time that this approach is applied to a
modified theory constructed upon Palatini formalism. The Wheeler-DeWitt (WDW)
equation is obtained and solved based on an alternative action proposed in
Ref.[1], under two different factor ordering choices. This action is
dynamically equivalent to the original EiBI action while it is free of square
root of the spacetime curvature. We consider a homogeneous, isotropic and
spatially flat universe, which is assumed to be dominated by a phantom perfect
fluid whose equation of state is a constant. We obtain exact solutions of the
WDW equation based on some specific conditions. In more general cases, we
propose a qualitative argument with the help of a Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin
(WKB) approximation to get further solutions. Besides, we also construct an
effective WDW equation by simply promoting the classical Friedmann equations.
We find that for all the approaches considered, the DeWitt condition hinting
singularity avoidance is satisfied. Therefore the big rip singularity can be
avoided through the quantum approach within the EiBI theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01479</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stratford</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>A Lightweight Approach to Performance Portability with targetDP</title><categories>cs.DC hep-lat</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, accepted to the International Journal of High
  Performance Computing Applications (IJHPCA), acceptance date 27th October
  2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Leading HPC systems achieve their status through use of highly parallel
devices such as NVIDIA GPUs or Intel Xeon Phi many-core CPUs. The concept of
performance portability across such architectures, as well as traditional CPUs,
is vital for the application programmer. In this paper we describe targetDP, a
lightweight abstraction layer which allows grid-based applications to target
data parallel hardware in a platform agnostic manner. We demonstrate the
effectiveness of our pragmatic approach by presenting performance results for a
complex fluid application (with which the model was co-designed), plus a
separate lattice QCD particle physics code. For each application, a single
source code base is seen to achieve portable performance, as assessed within
the context of the Roofline model. TargetDP can be combined with MPI to allow
use on systems containing multiple nodes: we demonstrate this through provision
of scaling results on traditional and GPU-accelerated large scale
supercomputers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03859</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yuge</keyname><forenames>Koretaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kojima</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taikei</keyname><forenames>Tetsuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Extension of Configurational Polyhedra to Finite Temperature Property</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Trans. Mat. Res. Soc. Jpn. 41, 363-366 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Configurational polyhedora (CP) is a hyperpolyhedra on multidimensional
configuration space, whose vertex (and edges) corresponds to upper or lower
limit value of correlation functions for all possible atomic configuration on
given lattice. In classical systems where physical property including internal
energy and elastic modulus can be a linear map for structures considered, it is
known that atomic configuration having highest (or lowerst) physical quantity
should always locate on one of the vertices at absolute zero temperature. The
present study extend the idea of CP to finite-temperature property (especially,
focusing on internal energy), and successfully provides demonstration of how
temperature dependence of internal energy in equilibrium state for alloys is
interpreted in terms of the density of states for non-interacting system along
specially selected direction on cofiguration space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04911</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Xueyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jinniu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>The quark mean field model with pion and gluon corrections</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures, 4 tables, accepted to Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 044308 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.044308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The properties of nuclear matter and finite nuclei are studied within the
quark mean field (QMF) model by taking the effects of pion and gluon into
account at the quark level. The nucleon is described as the combination of
three constituent quarks confined by a harmonic oscillator potential. To
satisfy the spirit of QCD theory, the contributions of pion and gluon on the
nucleon structure are treated in second-order perturbation theory. For the
nuclear many-body system, nucleons interact with each other by exchanging
mesons between quarks. With different constituent quark mass, $m_q$, we
determine three parameter sets about the coupling constants between mesons and
quarks, named as QMF-NK1, QMF-NK2, and QMF-NK3 by fitting the ground-state
properties of several closed-shell nuclei. It is found that all of the three
parameter sets can give satisfactory description on properties of nuclear
matter and finite nuclei, meanwhile they can also predict the larger neutron
star mass around $2.3M_\odot$ without the hyperon degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05028</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2016-10-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamada</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitano</keyname><forenames>Ryuichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Primordial Lepton Oscillations and Baryogenesis</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages; published version(v2)</comments><report-no>KEK-TH-1932, MAD-TH-16-06</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The baryon asymmetry of the Universe should have been produced after the
inflation era. We consider the possibility that the asymmetry is generated by
the flavor oscillations in the reheating process after inflation, so that the
baryon asymmetry is realized already at the beginning of the radiation
dominated era. In the seesaw model, we show that the propagators of the
left-handed leptons generically have flavor mixings in the thermal background,
that can generate flavor-dependent lepton asymmetry through the $CP$ violation
in the oscillation phenomena. The flavor dependent rates for the wash-out
process can leave the net asymmetry today.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05567</id><created>2016-09-18</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Subbarao</keyname><forenames>Kris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahajan</keyname><forenames>Sukhbir</forenames></author></authors><title>Is Feynman's Analysis of Electrostatic Screening Correct?</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper on electrostatic shielding, Chapman, Hewett and Trefethen
present arguments that the analysis of this effect by Feynman is incorrect.
Feynman analyzed shielding by a row of infinitesimally thin wires. They claim
that Feynman used the wrong boundary conditions invalidating his analysis. In
this paper we emphasize that Feynman's solution is a Green's function through
which behavior of the potential due to finite thickness wires of arbitrary
cross-section with appropriate boundary condition can be understood. This shows
that the main conclusions of Feynman's treatment are indeed correct. Analogy to
a parallel plate capacitor with one of the plates replaced by a row of wires
provides a more intuitive understanding of Feynman's argument. The case of a
finite number of wires arranged in a ring (not treated by Feynman), as a model
of Faraday cage, is different. The structure of the solution in radial
coordinates already suggests that one should not expect exponential behavior
and further analysis confirms this. There appear to be contradictory results in
the literature for its screening behavior in the presence of external charges
or fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00786</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Ryohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuge</keyname><forenames>Koretaka</forenames></author></authors><title>First-Principles Study on Preferential Energetics of Mg-based Ternary
  Alloys Revisited by Short-Range Order in Disordered Phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To investigate the formation of Mg-based long-period stacking ordered (LPSO)
structure, we systematically study the preference of the short-range order
(SRO) in metastable disordered phases of Mg-RE-Zn (RE = Y, La, Er, Ho, Dy, Tb)
and Mg-Gd-Al ternary alloy systems through first-principles calculation. RE-Zn
(RE = Y, Er, Ho, Dy, Tb) and Gd-Al pair clusters' probability showed the
tendency of increasing. In contrast, La-Zn pair clusters' probability is not
increasing, whose system dose not form LPSO structure. This preference of SRO
in disordered phases of Mg-based ternary alloys certainly indicates that
peculiar L12-type ordering in LPSO as well as possibility of LPSO formation
should have strong correlation with SRO tendency of energetically competitive
disordered phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04503</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tashima</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tame</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;zdemir</keyname><forenames>&#x15e;. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koashi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinfurter</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photonic multipartite entanglement conversion using nonlocal operations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, correction of reference list, add Journal ref.
  and DOI</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 052309 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.052309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple setup for the conversion of multipartite entangled states
in a quantum network with restricted access. The scheme uses nonlocal
operations to enable the preparation of states that are inequivalent under
local operations and classical communication, but most importantly does not
require full access to the states. It is based on a flexible linear optical
conversion gate that uses photons, which are ideally suited for distributed
quantum computation and quantum communication in extended networks. In order to
show the basic working principles of the gate, we focus on converting a
four-qubit entangled cluster state to other locally inequivalent four-qubit
states, such as the GHZ and symmetric Dicke state. We also show how the gate
can be incorporated into extended graph state networks, and can be used to
generate variable entanglement and quantum correlations without entanglement
but nonvanishing quantum discord.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05295</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Urich</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denton</keyname><forenames>Alan R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Swelling, Structure, and Phase Stability of Compressible Microgels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 9086 - 9094 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6sm02056a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microgels are soft colloidal particles that, when dispersed in a solvent,
swell and deswell in response to changes in environmental conditions, such as
temperature, concentration, and $p$H. Using Monte Carlo simulation, we model
bulk suspensions of microgels that interact via Hertzian elastic interparticle
forces and can expand or contract via trial moves that allow particles to
change size in accordance with the Flory-Rehner free energy of cross-linked
polymer gels. We monitor the influence of particle compressibility, size
fluctuations, and concentration on bulk structural and thermal properties by
computing particle swelling ratios, radial distribution functions, static
structure factors, osmotic pressures, and freezing densities. For microgels in
the nanoscale size range, particle compressibility and associated size
fluctuations suppress crystallization, shifting the freezing transition to a
higher density than for the hard-sphere fluid. As densities increase beyond
close packing, microgels progressively deswell, while their intrinsic size
distribution grows increasingly polydisperse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07581</id><created>2016-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Gofryk</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griveau</keyname><forenames>J-C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riseborough</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durakiewicz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric power as a probe of density of states in correlated
  actinide materials: the case of PuCoGa$_{5}$ superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B (October 24, 2016)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 195117 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.195117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of the thermoelectric power of the plutonium-based
unconventional superconductor PuCoGa$_{5}$. The data is interpreted within a
phenomenological model for the quasiparticle density of states of intermediate
valence systems and the results are compared with results obtained from
photoemission spectroscopy. The results are consistent with intermediate
valence nature of 5$f$-electrons, furthermore, we propose that measurements of
the Seebeck coefficient can be used as a probe of density of states in this
material, thereby providing a link between transport measurements and
photoemission in strongly correlated materials. We discuss these results and
their implications for the electronic structure determination of other strongly
correlated systems, especially actinide materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07860</id><created>2016-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ngek</keyname><forenames>Isaiah Ndifon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dikande</keyname><forenames>Alain M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moubissi</keyname><forenames>Alain Brice</forenames></author></authors><title>Matter-Wave Fields for Double-Slit Atom Interferometry: Variational
  Versus Exact Solitons</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>23 pages, 40 figures, Journal of the Physical Society of Japan (in
  print)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Physical Society of Japan 85, 124002, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.124002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major challenge in the theoretical modeling of double-slit interferometry
involving matter-wave fields is the appropriate waveform to be assigned to this
field. While all the studies carried out to date on this issue deal with
variational fields, experiments suggest that the optical field is generated by
splitting a single-hump Bose-Einstein condensate into two spatially and
temporally entangled pulses indicating the possibility of fully controlling the
subsequent motion of the two output pulses. To probe the consistency of
variational and exact soliton solutions to the field equation, we solve the
Gross-Pitaevskii equation with an optical potential barrier assumed to act as a
beam splitter, while including gravity. The exact solution is compared with the
two most common variational wavefunctions, namely, the Hermite-Gaussian and
super-sech modes. From numerical simulations, evidence is given of the exact
solution as being the most appropriate matter-wave structure that provides a
coherent description of the generation and spatio-temporal evolution of
matter-wave optical fields in a hypothetical implementation of double-slit atom
interferometry
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09636</id><created>2016-10-30</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fairlamb</keyname><forenames>John R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oudmaijer</keyname><forenames>Rene D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendigutia</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilee</keyname><forenames>John D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ancker</keyname><forenames>Mario E van den</forenames></author></authors><title>A spectroscopic survey of Herbig Ae/Be stars with X-Shooter II:
  Accretion diagnostic lines</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2643</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Herbig Ae/Be stars (HAeBes) allow an exploration of the properties of
Pre-Main Sequence(PMS) stars above the low-mass range ($&lt;2{\rm\thinspace
M_{\odot}}$) and those bordering the high-mass range ($&gt;8{\rm\thinspace
M_{\odot}}$). This paper is the second in a series exploring accretion in 91
HAeBes with Very Large Telescope/X-shooter spectra. Equivalent width
measurements are carried out on 32 different lines, spanning the UV to NIR, in
order to obtain their line luminosities. The line luminosities were compared to
accretion luminosities, which were determined directly from measurements of an
UV-excess. When detected, emission lines always demonstrate a correlation with
the accretion luminosity, regardless of detection frequency. The average
relationship between accretion luminosity and line luminosity is found to be
${\thinspace L_{\rm acc}}\propto{\thinspace L_{\rm line}}^{1.16 \pm 0.15}$.
This is in agreement with the findings in Classical T Tauri stars, although the
HAeBe relationship is generally steeper, particularly towards the Herbig Be
mass range. Since all observed lines display a correlation with the accretion
luminosity, all of them can be used as accretion tracers. This has increased
the number of accretion diagnostic lines in HAeBes tenfold. However, questions
still remain on the physical origin of each line, which may not be due to
accretion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01234</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lao</keyname><forenames>B. -Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohan</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>X. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Y. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. -L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parsec-scale jet properties of the gamma-ray quasar 3C 286</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, accept for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2887</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasar 3C~286 is one of two compact steep spectrum sources detected by
the {\it Fermi}/LAT. Here, we investigate the radio properties of the
parsec(pc)-scale jet and its (possible) association with the $\gamma$-ray
emission in 3C~286. The Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) images at
various frequencies reveal a one-sided core--jet structure extending to the
southwest at a projected distance of $\sim$1 kpc. The component at the jet base
showing an inverted spectrum is identified as the core, with a mean brightness
temperature of $2.8\times 10^{9}$~K. The jet bends at about 600 pc (in
projection) away from the core, from a position angle of $-135^\circ$ to
$-115^\circ$. Based on the available VLBI data, we inferred the proper motion
speed of the inner jet as $0.013 \pm 0.011$ mas yr$^{-1}$ ($\beta_{\rm app} =
0.6 \pm 0.5$), corresponding to a jet speed of about $0.5\,c$ at an inclination
angle of $48^\circ$ between the jet and the line of sight of the observer. The
brightness temperature, jet speed and Lorentz factor are much lower than those
of $\gamma$-ray-emitting blazars, implying that the pc-scale jet in 3C~286 is
mildly relativistic. Unlike blazars in which $\gamma$-ray emission is in
general thought to originate from the beamed innermost jet, the location and
mechanism of $\gamma$-ray emission in 3C~286 may be different as indicated by
the current radio data. Multi-band spectrum fitting may offer a complementary
diagnostic clue of the $\gamma$-ray production mechanism in this source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02243</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2016-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rohde</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeiler</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>On Riemann Solvers and Kinetic Relations for Isothermal Two-Phase Flows
  with Surface Tension</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a sharp-interface approach for the inviscid isothermal dynamics
of compressible two-phase flow, that accounts for phase transition and surface
tension effects. To fix the mass exchange and entropy dissipation rate across
the interface kinetic relations are frequently used. The complete
uni-directional dynamics can then be understood by solving generalized
two-phase Riemann problems. We present new well-posedness theorems for the
Riemann problem and corresponding computable Riemann solvers, that cover quite
general equations of state, metastable input data and curvature effects. The
new Riemann solver is used to validate different kinetic relations on
physically relevant problems including a comparison with experimental data.
Riemann solvers are building blocks for many numerical schemes that are used to
track interfaces in two-phase flow. It is shown that the new Riemann solver
enables reliable and efficient computations for physical situations that could
not be treated before.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02692</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>Abdel Nasser</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic and transport properties of QGP within PLSM approach</title><categories>nucl-th hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, talk given at Int. Conf. on High Energy Phys.
  (ICHEP 2016), Aug. 3-10, 2016, Chicago, USA</comments><report-no>ECTP-2016-18-18, WLCAPP-2016-18-18</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to study the response of the quantum chromodynamic matter to finite
electromagnetic fields, we utilize the Polyakov linear - sigma model (PLSM) in
mean-field approximation. Due to participants' momentum imbalance and
off-center relativistic motion of the spectators' electric charges, localized,
short-lived, huge electromagnetic fields are to be generated in the
relativistic heavy-ion collisions. We report on various electromagnetic and
transport properties of the new-state-of matter; the quark-gluon plasma (QGP)
within the QCD-like approach, PLSM. We find an excellent agreement between our
PLSM calculations and various recent lattice QCD simulations and notice that
the magnetization and the magnetic susceptibility and the relative permeability
obviously increase in the QGP phase. We predict that increasing the magnetic
field remarkable decreases the viscosity, especially in hadron phase. while in
QGP phase, the viscous properties seem not being affected with.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02693</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Diab</keyname><forenames>Abdel Magied</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ahmadov</keyname><forenames>Azar I.</forenames><affiliation>Baku State U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>Abdel Nasser</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dahab</keyname><forenames>Eiman Abou El</forenames><affiliation>WLCAPP, Cairo and MTI U., Cairo</affiliation></author></authors><title>SU($4$) Polyakov linear-sigma model at finite temperature and density</title><categories>nucl-th hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, talk given at Int. Conf. on High Energy Phys.
  (ICHEP 2016), Aug. 3-10, 2016, Chicago, USA</comments><report-no>ECTP-2016-20-20, WLCAPP-2016-20-20</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In mean-field approximation, the SU($4$) Polyakov linear - sigma model (PLSM)
is constructed in order to characterize the quark-hadron phase structure in a
wide range of temperatures and densities. The chiral condensates $\sigma_l$,
$\sigma_s$ and $\sigma_c$ for light, strange and charm quarks, respectively,
and the deconfinement order-parameters $\phi$ and $\phi^*$ shall be analyzed at
finite temperatures and densities. We conclude that the critical temperatures
corresponding to charm condensates are greater than that to strange and light
ones, respectively. Thus, the charm condensates are likely not affected by the
QCD phase transition. Furthermore, increasing the chemical potentials decreases
the corresponding critical temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02696</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sheka</keyname><forenames>Elena F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reduced Graphene Oxide and Its Natural Counterpart Shungite Carbon</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large variety of structure and chemical-composition of reduced graphene oxide
(RGO) is explained from a quantum-chemical standpoint. The related molecular
theory of graphene oxide, supported by large experience gained by the modern
graphene science, has led the foundation of the concept of a multi-stage
graphene oxide reduction. This microscopic approach has found a definite
confirmation when analyzing the available empirical data concerning both
synthetic and natural RGO products, the latter in view of shungite carbon,
suggesting the atomic-microscopic model for its structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02706</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>D. J. B.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Best</keyname><forenames>P. N.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Duncan</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hatch</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jarvis</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;ttgering</keyname><forenames>H. J. A.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stott</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cochrane</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Coppin</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dannerbauer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Geach</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hale</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hardcastle</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hatfield</keyname><forenames>P. W.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Houghton</keyname><forenames>R. C. W.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Maddox</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>McGee</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morabito</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nisbet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pandey-Pommier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Prandoni</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Saxena</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shimwell</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tarr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>van Bemmel</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>W. L.</forenames><affiliation>the WEAVE Consortium</affiliation></author></authors><title>The WEAVE-LOFAR Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, proceedings of the SF2A conference, Lyon, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In these proceedings we highlight the primary scientific goals and design of
the WEAVE-LOFAR survey, which will use the new WEAVE spectrograph on the 4.2m
William Herschel Telescope to provide the primary source of spectroscopic
information for the LOFAR Surveys Key Science Project. Beginning in 2018,
WEAVE-LOFAR will generate more than 10$^6$ R=5000 365-960 nm spectra of
low-frequency selected radio sources, across three tiers designed to
efficiently sample the redshift-luminosity plane, and produce a data set of
enormous legacy value. The radio frequency selection, combined with the high
multiplex and throughput of the WEAVE spectrograph, make obtaining redshifts in
this way very efficient, and we expect that the redshift success rate will
approach 100 per cent at $z &lt; 1$. This unprecedented spectroscopic sample -
which will be complemented by an integral field component - will be
transformational in key areas, including studying the star formation history of
the Universe, the role of accretion and AGN-driven feedback, properties of the
epoch of reionisation, cosmology, cluster haloes and relics, as well as the
nature of radio galaxies and protoclusters. Each topic will be addressed in
unprecedented detail, and with the most reliable source classifications and
redshift information in existence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02718</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Cridland</keyname><forenames>Alex J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pudritz</keyname><forenames>Ralph E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birnstiel</keyname><forenames>Tilman</forenames></author></authors><title>Radial Drift of Dust in Protoplanetary Disks: The Evolution of Ice lines
  and Dead zones</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>16 pages, 24 figures, submitted to MNRAS after one round of revisions</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a new model for the astrochemical structure of a viscously
evolving protoplanetary disk that couples an analytic description of the disk's
temperature and density profile, chemical evolution, and an evolving dust
distribution. We compute evolving radial distributions for a range of dust
grain sizes, which depend on coagulation, fragmentation and radial drift
processes. In particular we find that the water ice line plays an important
role in shaping the radial distribution of the maximum grain size because ice
coated grains are significantly less susceptible to fragmentation than their
dry counterparts. This in turn has important effects on disk ionization and
therefore on the location of dead zones. In comparison to a simple constant
gas-to-dust ratio model for the dust as an example, we find that the new model
predicts an outer dead zone edge that moves in by a factor of about 3 at 1 Myr
(to 5 AU) and by a factor of about 14 by 3 Myr (to 0.5 AU). We show that the
changing position of the dead zone and heat transition traps have important
implications for the formation and trapping of planets in protoplanetary disks.
Finally, we consider our results in light of recent ALMA observations of HL Tau
and TW Hya.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02725</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baghernejad</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Galiby</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manrique</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamill</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broekmann</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandlowski</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Three State NDI Switch: Integration of Pendant Redox Unit for
  Conductance Tuning</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We studied charge transport phenomena through a core substituted
naphthalenediimide (NDI) single-molecule junctions using the electrochemical
STM-based break junction technique in combination with DFT calculations. The
conductance switch among three well-defined states is acquired by
electrochemically controlling the redox state of the pendent diimide unit of
the molecule in ionic liquid, and the conductance difference is more than one
order of magnitude between di-anion states and neutral state. The potential
dependent charge transport characteristics of the NDI molecules are confirmed
by DFT calculations accounting for electrochemical double-layer effects on the
conductance of the NDI junctions. This work suggests that the integration of
redox unit in the pendent position with strong coupling to molecular backbone
can significantly tune the charge transport of the single-molecule device by
controlling different redox states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02735</id><created>2016-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Jannelli</keyname><forenames>Nicole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nastro</keyname><forenames>Rosa Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cigolotti</keyname><forenames>Viviana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minutillo</keyname><forenames>Mariagiovanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falcucci</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author></authors><title>Low pH, high salinity: too much for Microbial Fuel Cells?</title><categories>q-bio.OT physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 Figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.07.079</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Twelve single chambered, air-cathode Tubular Microbial Fuel Cells (TMFCs)
have been filled up with fruit and vegetable residues. The anodes were realized
by means of a carbon fiber brush, while the cathodes were realized through a
graphite-based porous ceramic disk with Nafion membranes (117 Dupont). The
performances in terms of polarization curves and power production were assessed
according to different operating conditions: percentage of solid substrate
water dilution, adoption of freshwater and a 35mg/L NaCl water solution and,
finally, the effect of an initial potentiostatic growth.
  All TMFCs operated at low pH (pH$=3.0 \pm 0.5$), as no pH amendment was
carried out. Despite the harsh environmental conditions, our TMFCs showed a
Power Density (PD) ranging from 20 to 55~mW/m$^2 \cdot$kg$_{\text{waste}}$ and
a maximum CD of 20~mA/m$^2 \cdot$kg$_{\text{waste}}$, referred to the cathodic
surface. COD removal after a $28-$day period was about $45 \%$.
  The remarkably low pH values as well as the fouling of Nafion membrane very
likely limited TMFC performances. However, a scale-up estimation of our
reactors provides interesting values in terms of power production, compared to
actual anaerobic digestion plants. These results encourage further studies to
characterize the graphite-based porous ceramic cathodes and to optimize the
global TMFC performances, as they may provide a valid and sustainable
alternative to anaerobic digestion technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02738</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Shan</forenames></author></authors><title>The Meaning of the Wave Function: In Search of the Ontology of Quantum
  Mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>199 pages, 8 figures. Draft of a forthcoming book. Endorsed by
  Stephen L. Adler, GianCarlo Ghirardi, Nicolas Gisin, Peter Holland, and Wayne
  Myrvold. To be published in March 2017 by Cambridge University Press
  (http://www.cambridge.org/catalogue/catalogue.asp?isbn=9781107124356)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The meaning of the wave function has been a hot topic of debate since the
early days of quantum mechanics. Recent years have witnessed a growing interest
in this long-standing question. Is the wave function ontic, directly
representing a state of reality, or epistemic, merely representing a state of
(incomplete) knowledge, or something else? If the wave function is not ontic,
then what, if any, is the underlying state of reality? If the wave function is
indeed ontic, then exactly what physical state does it represent? In this book,
I aim to make sense of the wave function in quantum mechanics and find the
ontological content of the theory. The book can be divided into three parts.
The first part addresses the question of the nature of the wave function
(Chapters 1-5). After giving a comprehensive and critical review of the
competing views of the wave function, I present a new argument for the ontic
view in terms of protective measurements. In addition, I also analyze the
origin of the wave function by deriving the free Schroedinger equation. The
second part analyzes the ontological meaning of the wave function (Chapters 6,
7). I propose a new ontological interpretation of the wave function in terms of
random discontinuous motion of particles, and give two main arguments
supporting this interpretation. The third part investigates whether the
suggested quantum ontology is complete in accounting for our definite
experience and whether it needs to be revised in the relativistic domain
(Chapters 8, 9).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02744</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Lordan</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>Micheal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manning</keyname><forenames>Mary</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amann</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Connell</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyons</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quinn</keyname><forenames>Aidan J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymmetric pentagonal metal meshes for flexible transparent electrodes
  and heaters</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metal meshes have emerged as an important class of flexible transparent
electrodes. We report on the characteristics of a new class of asymmetric
meshes, tiled using a recently-discovered family of pentagons. Micron-scale
meshes were fabricated on flexible polyethylene terephthalate substrates via
optical lithography, metal evaporation (Ti 10 nm, Pt 50 nm) and lift-off. Three
different designs were assessed, each with the same tessellation pattern and
linewidth (5 micron), but with different sizes of the fundamental pentagonal
unit. The designs corresponded to areal coverage of the metal patterns of 27%
(Design#1), 14% (Design#2) and 9% (Design#3), respectively. Good mechanical
stability was observed for both tensile strain and compressive strain. After
1,000 bending cycles, devices subjected to tensile strain showed fractional
resistance increases in the range 8% to 17% with the lowest changes observed
for Design#2. Devices subjected to compressive strain showed fractional
resistance increases in the range 0% to 7% with best results observed for
Design#1. The performance of the pentagonal metal mesh devices as visible
transparent heaters via Joule heating was also assessed. A saturation
temperature of 88 +/- 1 degrees C was achieved at low voltage (5 V) with a fast
response time (~ 20 s) and a high thermal resistance (168 +/- 6 degrees C
cm2/W). Finally, de-icing was successfully demonstrated (45 s at 5 V) for an
ice layer on a glass coupon placed on top of the PET substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02748</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Merritt</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Rivera</keyname><forenames>Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Weiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chenglin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Pengcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rezik</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Absence of long wavelength nematic fluctuations in LiFeAs</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, one figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigated long-wavelength nematic fluctuations in an Fe-based
superconductor LiFeAs near q=(0.05,0,0) by measuring temperature-dependent
renormalization of acoustic phonons through inelastic neutron scattering. We
found that the phonons have conventional behavior, as would be expected in the
absence of electronic nematic fluctuations. This observation implies that
either electron-phonon coupling is too weak to see any effect or that nematic
fluctuations are not present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02766</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xf8;rensen</keyname><forenames>L. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Integral- and Intermediate-Screened Coupled-Cluster Method</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>43 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the formulation and implementation of the integral- and
intermediate-screened coupled-cluster method (ISSCC). The IISCC method gives a
simple and rigorous integral and intermediate screening (IIS) of the
coupled-cluster method and will significantly reduces the scaling for all
orders of the CC hierarchy exactly like seen for the integral-screened
configuration-interaction method (ISCI). The rigorous IIS in the IISCC gives a
robust and adjustable error control which should allow for the possibility of
converging the energy without any loss of accuracy while retaining low or
linear scaling at the same time. The derivation of the IISCC is performed in a
similar fashion as in the ISCI where we show that the tensor contractions for
the nested commutators are separable up to an overall sign and that this
separability can lead to a rigorous IIS. In the nested commutators the
integrals are screened in the first tensor contraction and the intermediates
are screened in all successive tensor contractions. The rigorous IIS will lead
to linear scaling for all nested commutators for large systems in a similar way
as seen for the ISCI. The reduced scaling can in this way be obtained without
any range dependent parameter for the interaction, unlike other low scaling
methods and is therefore also suitable for charge separated systems. It is
expected that the IISCC, just like the ISCI, can use dramatically larger
orbital spaces combined with large CC expansions as compared with traditional
CC methods. Due to the size extensive nature of the CC method the IISCC should
not only be applicable to few electron systems but also to large molecular
system unlike the ISCI. The IISCC can here either be used as a stand alone
method or combined with other linear scaling approaches like the fragmentation
method or other methods which introduces a range dependent interaction
screening.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02769</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Wyatt</keyname><forenames>Bryant M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petz</keyname><forenames>Jonathan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumpter</keyname><forenames>William J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Ty R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Edward L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fain</keyname><forenames>Baylor G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutyra</keyname><forenames>Taylor J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cook</keyname><forenames>Scott A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hibbs</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goderya</keyname><forenames>Shaukat N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Creating an Isotopically Similar Earth-Moon System with Correct Angular
  Momentum from a Giant Impact</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><msc-class>85-04</msc-class><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The giant impact hypothesis is the dominant theory explaining the formation
of our Moon. However, its inability to produce an isotopically similar
Earth-Moon system with correct angular momentum has cast a shadow on its
validity. Computer-generated impacts have been successful in producing virtual
systems that possess many of the physical properties we observe. Yet,
addressing the isotopic similarities between the Earth and Moon coupled with
correct angular momentum has proven to be challenging. Equilibration and
evection resonance have been put forth as a means of reconciling the models.
However, both were rejected in a meeting at The Royal Society in London. The
main concern was that models were multi-staged and too complex. Here, we
present initial impact conditions that produce an Earth-Moon system whose
angular momentum and isotopic properties are correct. The model is
straightforward and the results are a natural consequence of the impact.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02814</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Menglin L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Li Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sha</keyname><forenames>Wei E. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrathin Complementary Metasurface for Orbital Angular Momentum
  Generation at Microwave Frequencies</title><categories>physics.class-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ANTENNAS AND PROPAGATION, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TAP.2016.2626722</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetic (EM) waves with helical wavefront carry orbital angular
momentum (OAM), which is associated with the azimuthal phase of the complex
electric field. OAM is a new degree of freedom in EM waves and is promising for
channel multiplexing in communication system. Although the OAM-carrying EM wave
attracts more and more attention, the method of OAM generation at microwave
frequencies still faces challenges, such as efficiency and simulation time. In
this work, by using the circuit theory and equivalence principle, we build two
simplified models, one for a single scatter and one for the whole metasurface
to predict their EM responses. Both of the models significantly simplify the
design procedure and reduce the simulation time. In this paper, we propose an
ultrathin complementary metasurface that converts a left-handed (right-handed)
circularly polarized plane wave without OAM to a right-handed (left-handed)
circularly polarized wave with OAM of arbitrary orders and a high transmission
efficiency can be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02820</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Soam</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maheswar</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Chang Won</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neha</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>B-G</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field structure of IC 63 and IC 59 associated to H II region -
  Sh 185</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2649</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bright-rimmed clouds (BRCs) are formed at the periphery of H$~$II regions as
the radiation from the central star interacts with dense gas. The ionization
and resulting compression of the clouds may lead to cloud disruption causing
secondary star formation depending on the stellar and gas parameters. Here we
use R-band polarimetry to probe the plane-of-the sky magnetic field in the two
near-by BRCs IC\,59 and IC\,63. Both nebulae are illuminated by $\gamma$ Cas
with the direction of ionizing radiation being orientated parallel or
perpendicular to the local magnetic field, allowing us to probe the importance
of magnetic field pressure in the evolution of BRCs. Because of the proximity
of the system ($\sim$200pc) we have acquired a substantial sample of over 500
polarization measurements for stars background to the nebulae. On large scales,
the magnetic field geometries of both clouds are anchored to the ambient
magnetic field. For IC 63, the magnetic field is aligned parallel to the
head-tail morphology of the main condensation, with convex morphology relative
to the direction of the ionizing radiation. We estimate the plane of the sky
magnetic field strength in IC\,63 to be $\sim90\mu$G. In IC\,59, the projected
magnetic field follows the M shape morphology of the cloud. Here, field lines
present a concave shape with respect to the direction of the ionizing radiation
from $\gamma$ Cas. Comparing our observations to published theoretical models
we find good general agreement, supporting the importance of magnetic fields in
BRC evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02825</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Terasaki</keyname><forenames>Kunihiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Tetra-Quark Interpretation of X(3872) and Z_c(3900) Revisited</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 0 figures</comments><report-no>YITP-16-123</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In relation to the newly observed bottom-strange X^{+,-}(5568) mesons, we
revisit our tetra-quark interpretation of X(3872) and Z_c(3900). It is
discussed that our assignment of X^{+,-}(5568) to charged components of
iso-triplet bottom partners of D_{s0}^+(2317) is compatible with the revised
version of our tetra-quark interpretation of X(3872) and Z_c(3900).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02829</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>Ray P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polsterer</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>WTF? Discovering the Unexpected in next-generation radio continuum
  surveys</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>For Publication in ADASS XXV processdings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most major discoveries in astronomy have come from unplanned discoveries made
by surveying the Universe in a new way, rather than by testing a hypothesis or
conducting an investigation with planned outcomes. Next generation radio
continuum surveys such as the Evolutionary Map of the Universe (EMU: the radio
continuum survey on the new Australian SKA Pathfinder telescope), will
significantly expand the volume of observational phase space, so we can be
reasonably confident that we will stumble across unexpected new phenomena or
new types of object. However, the complexity of the instrument and the large
data volumes mean that it may be non-trivial to identify them. On the other
hand, if we don't, then we may be missing out on the most exciting science
results from EMU. We have therefore started a project called &quot;WTF&quot;, which
explicitly aims to mine EMU data to discover unexpected science that is not
part of our primary science goals, using a variety of machine-learning
techniques and algorithms. Although targeted specifically at EMU, we expect
this approach will have broad applicability to astronomical survey data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02834</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Hai</keyname><forenames>Rihan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostylev</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical study of the stripline ferromagnetic resonance response of
  metallic ferromagnetic films based on an analytical model</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop an advanced analytical model for calculating the broadband
stripline ferromagnetic resonance (FMR) response for metallic ferromagnetic
films, taking into account the exchange interaction as well as the exchange
boundary conditions at the film surface. This approach leads to simple
analytical expressions in the Fourier space. As a result, a numerical code
which implements inverse Fourier transform of these equations is very quick.
This allows us to explore a wide space of parameters as numerical examples of
application of this theory. In particular, we investigate the joint effect of
microwave eddy current shielding and magnetisation pinning at the ferromagnetic
film surfaces on the shape of the stripline FMR response of the film.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02837</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Tulika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadanandan</keyname><forenames>Aswin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bajpai</keyname><forenames>Gaurav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>Saurabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amin</keyname><forenames>Ruhul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasir</keyname><forenames>Mohd.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Sunil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirage</keyname><forenames>Parasharam M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biring</keyname><forenames>Sajal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Somaditya</forenames></author></authors><title>Importance of strain reduction in improvement of optical transmission
  and conductance in Si4+ doped ZnO: a probable new moisture resistant
  Transparent Conductive Oxide</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Pages:9; Figures:8 Keywords: Si doped ZnO, transparent conductive
  oxide, humidity, conductivity, adsorption</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Si doped ZnO has been reported to be a better conductor than pure ZnO. It is
reported that carrier density increases and hence conductivity increases.
However, the effect on optical transmission is yet not clear until our recent
report [1]. Zn1-xSixO for x= 0, 0.013, 0.020 and 0.027 have been synthesized
using sol-gel method (a citric acid-glycerol route) followed by solid state
sintering. We found that there is a decrease in defect states due to Si doping.
The correlation of strain to the decrement in vacancy sites is discussed in
this report. In modern electronics and solar cell fabrication, transparent
conductive oxides (TCOs) are important components which conduct electrically
without absorbing visible light. Known TCOs are extremely costly and are
composed of non-abundant elements. Search for new ecofriendly, cheap and
sustainable TCOs has been a recent research of attraction. Keeping in mind that
most solar cells are exposed to natural conditions, the humidity tolerance
becomes a determining factor. We report that sensitivity to moisture decreases
drastically while the conductivity and optical transparency increases with
doping. The reduction of strain and improvement of transport properties results
in increased conductivity of Si doped ZnO pellets, tempting us to envisage this
material as a probable alternate TCO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02846</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Baer</keyname><forenames>Howard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berggren</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lehtinen</keyname><forenames>Suvi-Leena</forenames></author><author><keyname>List</keyname><forenames>Jenny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanabe</keyname><forenames>Tomohiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jacqueline</forenames></author></authors><title>Naturalness and light higgsinos: A powerful reason to build the ILC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5pages plus title page, proceedings ICHEP 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A core prediction of natural Supersymmetry is the existence of four light
higgsinos not too far above the mass of the $Z$ boson. The small mass
splittings amongst the higgsinos -- typically 5-20\,GeV -- imply very little
visible energy release from decays of heavier higgsinos. In particular, if
other SUSY particles are quite heavy, as can be the case in SUSY with
radiatively-driven naturalness, the higgsinos are extremely hard to detect at
hadron colliders. The clean environment of electron-positron colliders with
$\sqrt{s} &gt; 2m_{\mathrm{higgsino}}$, however, would allow for a decisive search
for the required light higgsinos. Thus, $e^+e^-$ colliders should either
discover or exclude natural SUSY. We present a detailed study of higgsino pair
production at the proposed International Linear $e^+e^-$ Collider which is
under consideration for construction in Japan. A variety of precision
measurements should allow for extraction of underlying parameters and provide a
window onto physics at the grand unified scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02847</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Foerster</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maci&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Ferran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Statuto</keyname><forenames>Nahuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finizio</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez-M&#xed;nguez</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lend&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>Sergi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Paulo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontcuberta</keyname><forenames>Josep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe0;ndez</keyname><forenames>Joan Manel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xe4;ui</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aballe</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author></authors><title>Simultaneous imaging of strain waves and induced magnetization dynamics
  at the nanometer scale</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16pages and 3 fig (plus 4 pages and 2 figs in supplemeantray). 3
  videos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Changes in strain can be used to modify electronic and magnetic properties in
crystal structures, to manipulate nanoparticles and cells, or to control
chemical reactions. The magneto-elastic (ME) effect--the change of magnetic
properties caused by the elastic deformation (strain) of a magnetic
material--has been proposed as an alternative approach to magnetic fields for
the low power control of magnetization states of nanoelements since it avoids
charge currents, which entail ohmic losses. Multiferroic heterostructures
\cite{Zheng2004} and nanocomposites have exploited this effect in search of
electric control of magnetic states, mostly in the static regime. Quantitative
studies combining strain and magnetization dynamics are needed for practical
applications and so far, a high resolution technique for this has been lacking.
Here, we have studied the effect of the dynamic strain accompanying a surface
acoustic wave on magnetic nanostructures. We have simultaneously imaged the
temporal evolution of both strain waves and magnetization dynamics of
nanostructures at the picosecond timescale. The newly developed experimental
technique, based on X-ray microscopy, is versatile and provides a pathway to
the study of strain-induced effects at the nanoscale. Our results provide
fundamental insight in the coupling between strain and magnetization in
nanostructures at the picosecond timescale, having implications in the design
of strain-controlled magnetostrictive nano-devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02849</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Bernardin</keyname><forenames>Cedric</forenames><affiliation>JAD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goncalves</keyname><forenames>Patricia</forenames><affiliation>IST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jara</keyname><forenames>Milton</forenames><affiliation>IMPA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Weakly harmonic oscillators perturbed by a conservative noise</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1402.1562</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a chain of weakly harmonic coupled oscillators perturbed by a
conservative noise. We show that by tuning accordingly the coupling constant
energy can diffuse like a Brownian motion or superdiffuse like a maximally
3/2-stable asymmetric L{\'e}vy process. For a critical value of the coupling,
the energy diffusion is described by a family of L{\'e}vy processes which
interpolates between these two processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02852</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Capello</keyname><forenames>Carolina</forenames><affiliation>ISMO, CLUPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames><affiliation>ISMO, CLUPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Broquier</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames><affiliation>ISMO, CLUPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dedonder-Lardeux</keyname><forenames>Claude</forenames><affiliation>PIIM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jouvet</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames><affiliation>PIIM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pino</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrogen bonds vs. $\pi$-stacking interactions in the
  p-aminophenol...p-cresol dimer: an experimental and theoretical study</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>PCCP : Physical chemistry chemical physics, Royal Society of
  Chemistry, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6cp06352g</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gas phase structure and excited state lifetime of the
p-aminophenol...p-cresol heterodimer have been investigated by REMPI and LIF
spectroscopy with nanosecond laser pulses and pump-probe experiments with
picosecond laser pulses as a model system to study the competition between p-p
and H-bonding interactions in aromatic dimers. The excitation is a broad and
unstructured band. The excitedstate of the heterodimer is long lived (2.5 +/-
0.5) ns with a very broad fluorescence spectrum red-shifted by 4000 cm^{-1}
with respect to the excitation spectrum. Calculations at the MP2/RI-CC2 and
DFT-oB97X-D levels indicate that hydrogen-bonded (HB) and p-stacked isomers are
almost isoenergetic in the ground state while in the excited state only the
p-stacked isomer exists. This suggests that the HB isomer cannot be excited due
to negligible Franck-Condon factors and therefore the excitation spectrum is
associated with the p-stacked isomer that reaches vibrationally excited states
in the S1 state upon vertical excitation. The excited state structure is an
exciplex responsible for the fluorescence of the complex. Finally,a comparison
was performed between the p-stacked structure observed for the
p-aminophenol...p-cresol heterodimer and the HB structure reported for the
(p-cresol)2 homodimer indicating that the differences are due to different
optical properties (oscillator strengths and Franck-Condon factors) of the
isomers of both dimers and not to the interactions involved in the ground state
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02856</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Sourabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopal</keyname><forenames>R K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Jit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parallel and series conduction model in Topological Insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Accepted in International Conference on the Physics of Semiconductors
  2016 (ICPS 2016 )</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the past few years there has been a surge in the material science
engineering in order to synthesize bulk insulating and surface metallic
Topological Insulating (TI) materials. This quest is not only theoretically
important but also promising from the novel application perspective. The
dependence of temperature on resistance (R-T) of a particular sample reveals a
plethora of information about the electronic properties especially in a unique
sample like TI where there are two components comprising of an insulating bulk
and metallic surface states. Depending on the amount of intrinsic doping during
the sample formation, the bulk can either couple or remain decoupled with the
surface. The former leads to a metallic R-T profile whereas the latter is
captured by an insulating R-T behavior. These two behaviors can be represented
by series and parallel resistor models respectively. In this work we study the
R-T behavior in the framework of resistor models capturing the essential
features of our sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02858</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>S. -W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwong</keyname><forenames>D. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase stabilization of Kerr frequency comb internally without nonlinear
  optical interferometry</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical frequency comb (OFC) technology has been the cornerstone for
scientific breakthroughs such as precision frequency metrology, redefinition of
time, extreme light-matter interaction, and attosecond sciences. While the
current mode-locked laser-based OFC has had great success in extending the
scientific frontier, its use in real-world applications beyond the laboratory
setting remains an unsolved challenge. Microresonator-based OFCs, or Kerr
frequency comb, have recently emerged as a candidate solution to the challenge
because of their preferable size, weight, and power consumption (SWaP). On the
other hand, the current phase stabilization technology requires either external
optical references or power-demanding nonlinear processes, overturning the SWaP
benefit of Kerr frequency combs. Introducing a new concept in phase control,
here we report an internally phase stabilized Kerr frequency comb without the
need of any optical references or nonlinear processes. We describe the comb
generation analytically with the theory of cavity induced modulation
instability, and demonstrate for the first time that the optical frequency can
be stabilized by control of two internally accessible parameters: an intrinsic
comb offset and the comb spacing. Both parameters are phase locked to microwave
references, with 55 mrad and 20 mrad residual phase noises, and the resulting
comb-to-comb frequency uncertainty is 0.08 Hz or less. Out-of-loop measurements
confirm good coherence and stability across the comb, with measured optical
frequency fractional instabilities of 5x10^-11/sqrt(t). The new phase
stabilization method preserves the Kerr frequency comb's key advantages and
potential for chip-scale electronic and photonic integration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02865</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kravets</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomonay</keyname><forenames>Olena V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polishchuk</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tykhonenko-Polishchuk</keyname><forenames>Yu. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polek</keyname><forenames>T. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tovstolytkin</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korenivski</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of nanostructure layout on spin pumping phenomena in
  antiferromagnet/ nonmagnetic metal/ ferromagnet multilayered stacks</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Submitted as a conference paper to 2016 MMM Conference, to appear in
  AIP Advances</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we focus on magnetic relaxation in Mn$_{80}$Ir$_{20}$(12 nm)/
Cu(6 nm)/ Py($d_\mathrm{F}$) antiferromagnet/Cu/ferromagnet (AFM/Cu/FM)
multilayers with different thickness of the ferromagnetic permalloy layer. An
effective FM-AFM interaction mediated via the conduction electrons in the
nonmagnetic Cu spacer -- the spin-pumping effect -- is detected as an increase
in the linewidth of the ferromagnetic resonance (FMR) spectra and a shift of
the resonant magnetic field. We further find experimentally that the
spin-pumping-induced contribution to the linewidth is inversely proportional to
the thickness of the Py layer. We show that this thickness dependence likely
originates from the dissipative dynamics of the free and localized spins in the
AFM layer. The results obtained could be used for tailoring the dissipative
properties of spintronic devices incorporating antiferromagnetic layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02866</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Yuge</keyname><forenames>Koretaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyazono</keyname><forenames>Hisashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Ryohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taikei</keyname><forenames>Tetsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhito</forenames></author></authors><title>First-principles Study on Formation of LPSO Structures for Ternary
  Alloys Revisited from Short-range Order</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the formation of long-period stacking ordered (LPSO) structure
for Mg-Y-Zn ternary alloys based on the short-range order (SRO) tendency of
energetically competitive disordered phases. We find that unisotropic SRO
tendencies for structures with stacking faults cannot be simply interpreted by
arithmetic average of SRO for constituent fcc and hcp stackings, indicating
that the SRO should be significantly affected by periodically-introduced
stacking faults. We also find that SRO for neighboring Y-Zn pair, which should
have positive sign to form specific L12 type cluster found in LPSO, is strongly
affected by the distance between stacking faults: e.g., five atomic layer
distance does not prefer in-plane Y-Zn pair, while seven atomic layer distance
prefer both in- and inter-plane Y-Zn pair. These facts strongly indicate that
ordering tendency for the Mg-Y-Zn alloy is significantly dominated by the
stacking faults as well as their periodicity. We also systematically
investigate correlation between SRO for other Mg-RE-Zn (RE = La, Tb, Dy, Ho,
Er) alloys and the physical property of RE elements. We find that while SRO for
RE-Zn pair does not show effective correlation with atomic radius, it has
strong quadratic correlation with atomic radius considering unisotoropy along
in- and inter-plane directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02873</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>R</keyname><forenames>Varsha</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute Of Space Science and Technology, Trivandrum, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute Of Space Science and Technology, Trivandrum, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tej</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute Of Space Science and Technology, Trivandrum, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vig</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute Of Space Science and Technology, Trivandrum, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames><affiliation>National Centre for Radio Astrophysics</affiliation><affiliation>Tata Institute of Fundamental Research</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ojha</keyname><forenames>D. K.</forenames><affiliation>Tata Institute of Fundamental Research</affiliation></author></authors><title>Radio and infrared study of the star forming region IRAS 20286+4105</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A multi-wavelength investigation of the star forming complex IRAS 20286+4105,
located in the Cygnus-X region, is presented here. Near-infrared K-band data is
used to revisit the cluster / stellar group identified in previous studies. The
radio continuum observations, at 610 and 1280 MHz show the presence of a HII
region possibly powered by a star of spectral type B0 - B0.5. The cometary
morphology of the ionized region is explained by invoking the bow-shock model
where the likely association with a nearby supernova remnant is also explored.
A compact radio knot with non-thermal spectral index is detected towards the
centre of the cloud. Mid-infrared data from the Spitzer Legacy Survey of the
Cygnus-X region show the presence of six Class I YSOs inside the cloud. Thermal
dust emission in this complex is modelled using Herschel far-infrared data to
generate dust temperature and column density maps. Herschel images also show
the presence of two clumps in this region, the masses of which are estimated to
be {\sim} 175 M{\sun} and 30 M{\sun}. The mass-radius relation and the surface
density of the clumps do not qualify them as massive star forming sites. An
overall picture of a runaway star ionizing the cloud and a triggered population
of intermediate-mass, Class I sources located toward the cloud centre emerges
from this multiwavelength study. Variation in the dust emissivity spectral
index is shown to exist in this region and is seen to have an inverse relation
with the dust temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02884</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mai</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plasser</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquetand</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lischka</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Leticia</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbational treatment of spin-orbit coupling for generally applicable
  high-level multi-reference methods</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 141, 074105 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4892060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An efficient perturbational treatment of spin-orbit coupling within the
framework of high-level multi-reference techniques has been implemented in the
most recent version of the COLUMBUS quantum chemistry package, extending the
existing fully variational two-component (2c) multi-reference configuration
interaction singles and doubles (MRCISD) method. The proposed scheme follows
related implementations of quasi-degenerate perturbation theory (QDPT) model
space techniques. Our model space is built either from uncontracted,
large-scale scalar relativistic MRCISD wavefunctions or based on the
scalar-relativistic solutions of the linear-response-theory-based
multi-configurational averaged quadratic coupled cluster method (LRT-MRAQCC).
The latter approach allows for a consistent, approximatively size-consistent
and size-extensive treatment of spin-orbit coupling. The approach is described
in detail and compared to a number of related techniques. The inherent accuracy
of the QDPT approach is validated by comparing cuts of the potential energy
surfaces of acrolein and its S, Se, and Te analoga with the corresponding data
obtained from matching fully variational spin-orbit MRCISD calculations. The
conceptual availability of approximate analytic gradients with respect to
geometrical displacements is an attractive feature of the 2c-QDPT-MRCISD and
2c-QDPT-LRT-MRAQCC methods for structure optimization and ab inito molecular
dynamics simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02893</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kadenko</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plujko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bondar</keyname><forenames>Borys</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbachenko</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leshchenko</keyname><forenames>Borys</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solodovnyk</keyname><forenames>Kateryna</forenames></author></authors><title>Gamma-rays from $^{nat}$Sn and $^{nat}$C induced by fast neutrons</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, article submitted to Nuclear Physics and Atomic
  Energy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The cross-sections of prompt gamma-ray production from $^{nat}$Sn and
$^{nat}$C elements induced by 14.1-MeV neutrons were measured. The
time-of-flight technique was used for n-gamma discrimination. The experimental
results were compared with theoretical calculations performed by Empire 3.2 and
Talys 1.6 codes using different models for photon strength function and nuclear
level density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02896</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Cha</keyname><forenames>Minryeong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Juyeon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong Woon</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden Criticality of Counterion Condensation Near a Charged Cylinder</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the condensation transition of counterions on a charged cylinder via
Monte Carlo simulations. Varying the cylinder radius systematically in relation
to the system size, we find that all counterions are bound to the cylinder and
the heat capacity shows a drop at a finite Manning parameter. A finite-size
scaling analysis is carried out to confirm the criticality of the complete
condensation transition, yielding the same critical exponents with the Manning
transition. We show that the existence of the complete condensation is
essential to explain how the condensation nature alters from continuous to
discontinuous transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02898</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mutailamov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murtazaev</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Short-Time Dynamics of the Three-Dimensional Fully Frustrated Ising
  Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 table, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, 2015, vol. 102, No. 1, pp. 51-54</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364015130111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The critical relaxation from the low-temperature ordered state of the
three-dimensional fully frustrated Ising model on a simple cubic lattice has
been studied using the short time dynamics method. Particles with the periodic
boundary conditions containing N = 262144 spins have been studied. Calculations
have been performed by the standard Metropolis Monte Carlo algorithm. The
static critical exponents of the magnetization and correlation radius have been
obtained. The dynamic critical exponent of the model under study has been
calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02921</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Tseng</keyname><forenames>Yi-Chin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>High Spatio-Temporal-Resolution Detection of Chlorophyll Fluorescence
  Dynamics from a Single Chloroplast with Confocal Imaging Fluorometer</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Chlorophyll fluorescence (CF) is a key indicator to study plant physiology or
photosynthesis efficiency. Conventionally, CF is characterized by fluorometers,
which only allows ensemble measurement through wide-field detection. For
imaging fluorometers, the typical spatial and temporal resolutions are on the
order of millimeter and second, far from enough to study cellular/sub-cellular
CF dynamics. In addition, due to the lack of optical sectioning capability,
conventional imaging fluorometers cannot identify CF from a single cell or even
a single chloroplast. Here we demonstrated a novel fluorometer based on
confocal imaging, that not only provides high contrast images, but also allows
CF measurement with spatiotemporal resolution as high as micrometer and
millisecond. CF transient (the Kautsky curve) from a single chloroplast is
successfully obtained, with both the temporal dynamics and the intensity
dependences corresponding well to the ensemble measurement from conventional
studies. The significance of confocal imaging fluorometer is to identify the
variation among individual chloroplasts, e.g. the half-life period of the slow
decay in the Kautsky curve, that is not possible to analyze with wide-field
techniques. A linear relationship is found between excitation Intensity and the
temporal positions of peaks/valleys in the Kautsky curve. In addition, an
interesting 6-order increase in excitation intensity is found between
wide-field and confocal fluorometers, whose pixel integration time and optical
sectioning may account for this substantial difference. Confocal imaging
fluorometers provide micrometer and millisecond CF characterization, opening up
unprecedented possibilities toward detailed spatiotemporal analysis of CF
transients and its propagation dynamics, as well as photosynthesis efficiency
analysis, on the scale of organelles, in a living plant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02928</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Bate</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loren-Aguilar</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author></authors><title>On the dynamics of dust during protostellar collapse</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. Animations
  available at: http://www.astro.ex.ac.uk/people/mbate/Animations/</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2853</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of dust and gas can be quite different from each other when the
dust is poorly coupled to the gas. In protoplanetary discs, it is well known
that this decoupling of the dust and gas can lead to diverse spatial structures
and dust-to-gas ratios. In this paper, we study the dynamics of dust and gas
during the earlier phase of protostellar collapse, before a protoplanetary disc
is formed. We find that for dust grains with sizes &lt; 10 micron, the dust is
well coupled during the collapse of a rotating, pre-stellar core and there is
little variation of the dust-to-gas ratio during the collapse. However, if
larger grains are present, they may have trajectories that are very different
from the gas during the collapse, leading to mid-plane settling and/or
oscillations of the dust grains through the mid-plane. This may produce
variations in the dust-to-gas ratio and very different distributions of large
and small dust grains at the very earliest stages of star formation, if large
grains are present in pre-stellar cores.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02930</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Aarts</keyname><forenames>Gert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seiler</keyname><forenames>Erhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sexty</keyname><forenames>Denes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stamatescu</keyname><forenames>Ion-Olimpiu</forenames></author></authors><title>On complex Langevin dynamics and zeroes of the measure I: Formal proof
  and simple models</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, talk presented at the 34th International Symposium on
  Lattice Field Theory, 24-30 July 2016, University of Southampton, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the complex Langevin approach to lattice simulations at nonzero density,
zeroes of the fermion determinant lead to a meromorphic drift and hence a need
to revisit the theoretical derivation. We discuss how poles in the drift affect
the formal justification of the approach and then explore the various potential
issues in simple models, in a manner that is applicable to heavy dense and full
QCD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02931</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Aarts</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seiler</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sexty</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stamatescu</keyname><forenames>I. -O.</forenames></author></authors><title>On complex Langevin dynamics and zeroes of the measure II: Fermionic
  determinant</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, talk presented at the 34rd International
  Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016,
  Southampton, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lattice QCD at non-vanishing chemical potential is studied using the complex
Langevin equation (CLE). One of the conditions for the correctness of the
results of the CLE is that the zeroes of the measure coming from the fermionic
determinant are outside of the distribution of the configurations, or at least
in a region where support for the distribution is very much suppressed. We
investigate this issue for Heavy Dense QCD (HDQCD) and full QCD at high
temperatures. In HDQCD it is found that the configurations move closest to the
zeroes of the measure around the critical chemical potential of the onset
transition, where the sign problem is diminished, but results remain largely
unaffected. In full QCD at high temperatures the investigation of the spectrum
of the Dirac operator yields a similar observation: the results are unaffected
by the issue of the poles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02933</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Shin-Shan</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the CMS Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Search for Dark Matter in pp Collisions with CMS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings for the 38th International Conference on High Energy
  Physics (Chicago, USA), 6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Searches in CMS for dark matter in final states with invisible particles
recoiling against jets, top, W, Z, photon, and Higgs are presented. Various
topologies are explored, covering several specific dark-matter production
modes. The summary in a simplified-model framework of various searches for
direct dark matter production with the CMS detector is discussed, highlighting
sensitivities of the analyses under various assumptions of DM production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02948</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itahashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujioka</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayyad</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benlliure</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brinkmann</keyname><forenames>K. -T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geissel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gellanki</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haettner</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harakeh</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayano</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higashi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirenzaki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hornung</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Igarashi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeno</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jido</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantar-Nayestanaki</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanungo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kn&#xf6;bel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurz</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metag</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukha</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagae</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagahiro</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pietri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prochazka</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappold</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiter</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheidenberger</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sitar</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strmen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szarka</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takechi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanihata</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weick</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widmann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winfield</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamakami</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of excitation spectra in the ${}^{12}$C$(p,d)$ reaction near
  the $\eta'$ emission threshold</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 117, 202501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.202501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Excitation spectra of $^{11}$C were measured in the $^{12}$C$(p,d)$ reaction
near the $\eta'$ emission threshold. A proton beam extracted from the
synchrotron SIS-18 at GSI with an incident energy of 2.5 GeV impinged on a
carbon target. The momenta of deuterons emitted at 0 degrees were precisely
measured with the fragment separator FRS operated as a spectrometer. In
contrast to theoretical predictions on the possible existence of deeply bound
$\eta'$ mesic states in carbon nuclei, no distinct structures were observed
associated with the formation of bound states. The spectra were analyzed to set
stringent constraints on the formation cross section and on the hitherto
barely-known $\eta'$-nucleus interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02957</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilin</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karavaev</keyname><forenames>Yury L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments on the paper &quot;Terminal retrograde turn of rolling rings&quot;</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mir Abbas Jalali et al. [Phys. Rev. E 92, 032913(2015)] explained the
retrograde turn of rings by aerodynamic phenomena due to the presence of a
central hole in the ring as opposed to a disk. The results of our experiments
suggest that the drag torque is not the main reason for the retrograde turn of
the rings, and the results of theoretical research have shown that such a
motion is possible for both the ring and the disk in the case of rolling
without slipping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02963</id><created>2016-11-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruglov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Corrections to Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om black hole solution due to
  exponential nonlinear electrodynamics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures, to appear in Europhys. Letters</comments><journal-ref>Europhys. Letters, Vol. 115 (2016), 60006</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/60006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An exponential model of nonlinear electrodynamics coupled with the
gravitational field is analyzed. It was shown that weak, dominant, and strong
energy conditions are satisfied. We obtain corrections to Coulomb's law at
$r\rightarrow\infty$. It was demonstrated that electric-magnetic duality
between ${\cal F}$ and ${\cal P}$ frames is violated. The asymptotic black hole
solution at $r\rightarrow \infty$ is found that contains corrections to the
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om solution. The electromagnetic mass of the black hole is
calculated, expressed through the parameter $\beta$ of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02974</id><created>2016-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Rozgacheva</keyname><forenames>I. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agapov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On a problem of dark matter: A centrally symmetric distribution of a
  pseudoscalar field in the general relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A precise solution of the general relativity equations for centrally
symmetric distribution of a pseudoscalar field with U(1) symmetry is presented.
It is found that energy density of the field is restricted in the symmetry
center and falls with radial distance at a much slower rate than in numerical
simulations of dark matter haloes. This result can solve the cusp problem for
galaxies and the problem of rotation curves for galaxy exteriors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03018</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Weingartner</keyname><forenames>Nicholas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pueblo</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Flavio S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelton</keyname><forenames>K. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nussinov</keyname><forenames>Zohar</forenames></author></authors><title>A phase space approach to supercooled liquids and a universal collapse
  of their viscosity</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Front. Mater. 3:50 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3389/fmats.2016.00050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A broad fundamental understanding of the mechanisms underlying the
phenomenology of supercooled liquids has remained elusive, despite decades of
intense exploration. When supercooled beneath its characteristic melting
temperature, a liquid sees a sharp rise in its viscosity over a narrow
temperature range, eventually becoming frozen on laboratory timescales.
Explaining this immense increase in viscosity is one of the principle goals of
condensed matter physicists. To that end, numerous theoretical frameworks have
been proposed which explain and reproduce the temperature dependence of the
viscosity of supercooled liquids. Each of these frameworks appears only
applicable to specific classes of glassformers and each possess a number of
variable parameters. Here we describe a classical framework for explaining the
dynamical behavior of supercooled liquids based on statistical mechanical
considerations, and possessing only a single variable parameter. This parameter
varies weakly from liquid to liquid. Furthermore, as predicted by this new
classical theory and its earlier quantum counterpart, we find with the aid of a
small dimensionless constant that varies in size from $\sim 0.05-0.12$, a
universal (16 decade) collapse of the viscosity data as a function of
temperature. The collapse appears in all known types of glass forming
supercooled liquids (silicates, metallic alloys, organic systems, chalcogenide,
sugars, and water).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03030</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Neilson</keyname><forenames>Hilding R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Percy</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Horace A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Period Changes and Evolution in Pulsating Variable Stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>To be published in the Journal of the American Association of
  Variable Star Observers</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review ways in which observations of the changing periods of pulsating
variable stars can be used to detect and directly measure their evolution. We
briefly describe the two main techniques of analysis -- (O-C) analysis and
wavelet analysis -- and results for pulsating variable star types which are
reasonably periodic: type I and II Cepheids, RR Lyrae stars, beta Cephei stars,
and Mira stars. We comment briefly on delta Scuti stars and pulsating white
dwarfs. For some of these variable star types, observations agree approximately
with the predictions of evolutionary models, but there still exist significant
areas of disagreement that challenge future models of stellar evolution. There
may be a need, for instance, to include processes such as rotation, mass loss,
and magnetic fields. There may also be non-evolutionary processes which are
contributing to the period changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03032</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Sandeman</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The mechanocaloric potential of spin crossover compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, no figures. Published version in APL Materials is fully open
  access (DOI and journal reference given below)</comments><journal-ref>APL Materials 4, 111102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4967282</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a first evaluation of the potential for spin crossover (SCO)
compounds to be considered as a new class of giant mechanocaloric effect
material. From literature data on the variation of the spin crossover
temperature with pressure, we estimate the maximum available adiabatic
temperature change for several compounds and the relatively low pressures that
may be required to observe these effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03033</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Xiuyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rachh</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinerberger</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Diffusion Geometry of Graph Laplacians and Applications</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study directed, weighted graphs $G=(V,E)$ and consider the (not
necessarily symmetric) averaging operator $$ (\mathcal{L}u)(i) = -\sum_{j
\sim_{} i}{p_{ij} (u(j) - u(i))},$$ where $p_{ij}$ are normalized edge weights.
Given a vertex $i \in V$, we define the diffusion distance to a set $B \subset
V$ as the smallest number of steps $d_{B}(i) \in \mathbb{N}$ required for half
of all random walks started in $i$ and moving randomly with respect to the
weights $p_{ij}$ to visit $B$ within $d_{B}(i)$ steps. Our main result is that
the eigenfunctions interact nicely with this notion of distance. In particular,
if $u$ satisfies $\mathcal{L}u = \lambda u$ on $V$ and $$ B = \left\{ i \in V:
- \varepsilon \leq u(i) \leq \varepsilon \right\} \neq \emptyset,$$ then, for
all $i \in V$, $$ d_{B}(i) \log{\left( \frac{1}{|1-\lambda|} \right) } \geq
\log{\left( \frac{ |u(i)| }{\|u\|_{L^{\infty}}} \right)} -
\log{\left(\frac{1}{2} + \varepsilon\right)}.$$ $d_B(i)$ is a remarkably good
approximation of $|u|$ in the sense of having very high correlation. The result
implies that the classical one-dimensional spectral embedding preserves
particular aspects of geometry in the presence of clustered data. We also give
a continuous variant of the result which has a connection to the hot spots
conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03040</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevirkovets</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandrasekhar</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafranjuk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transduction between electrical energy and the heat in a carbon nanotube
  using a voltage-controlled doping</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>27 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High electric conductivity ~100 MegaSiemens/m and Seebeck coefficient &gt;200
mkV/K of carbon nanotubes (CNT) make them attractive for a variety of
applications. Unfortunately, a high thermal conductivity ~ 3000 W/(m*K) due to
the phonon transport limits their capability for transforming energy between
the heat and electricity. Here we show that increasing the charge carrier
concentrations not only leads to an increase of both electric conductivity and
Seebeck coeffcient, but also causes a substantial suppression of the thermal
conductivity due to intensifying the phonon-electron collisions. A strong
transduction effect corresponding to an effective electron temperature change
~115 K was observed in a CNT device, where the local gate electrodes have
controlled the charge doping in the opposite ends. Transduction between the
heat and the energy of the electron subsystem corresponds to an impressive
figure of merit cold ZT ~ 6 and the transduced power density P ~ 80kW/cm2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03048</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharjee</keyname><forenames>Somendra M.</forenames></author></authors><title>What is dimension?</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Introductory lectures given in the SERC School on &quot;Topology and
  condensed matter physics&quot; held in Kolkata, Nov-Dec 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This chapter explores the notion of &quot;dimension&quot; of a set. Various power laws
by which an Euclidean space can be characterized are used to define dimensions,
which then explore different aspects of the set. Also discussed are the
generalization to multifractals, and discrete and continuous scale invariance
with the emergence of complex dimensions. The idea of renormalization group
flow equations can be introduced in this framework, to show how the power laws
determined by dimensional analysis (engineering dimensions) get modified by
extra anomalous dimensions. As an example of the RG flow equation, the scaling
of conductance by disorder in the context of localization is used. A few
technicalities, including the connection between entropy and fractal dimension,
can be found in the appendices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03055</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Bobrov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitov</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozhkov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Remote monitoring of weak aftershock activity with waveform cross
  correlation: the case of the DPRK September 9, 2016 underground test</title><categories>physics.soc-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The method of waveform cross correlation (WCC) allows remote monitoring of
weak seismic activity induced by underground tests. This type of monitoring is
considered as a principal task of on-site inspection under the Comprehensive
nuclear-test-ban treaty. On September 11, 2016, a seismic event with body wave
magnitude 2.1 was found in automatic processing near the epicenter of the
underground explosion conducted by the DPRK on September 9, 2016. This event
occurred approximately two days after the test. Using the WCC method, two array
stations of the International Monitoring System (IMS), USRK and KSRS, detected
Pn-wave arrivals, which were associated with a unique event. Standard automatic
processing at the International Data Centre (IDC) did not create an event
hypothesis, but in the following interactive processing based on WCC
detections, an IDC analyst was able to create a two-station event . Location
and other characteristics of this small seismic source indicate that it is
likely an aftershock of the preceding explosion. Building on the success of
automatic detection and phase association, we carried out an extended analysis,
which included later phases and closest non-IMS stations. The final cross
correlation solution uses four stations, including MDJ (China) and SEHB
(Republic of Korea), with the epicenter approximately 2 km to north-west from
the epicenter of the Sept. 9 test. We also located the aftershock epicenter by
standard IDC program LocSAT using the arrival times obtained by cross
correlation. The distance between the DPRK and LocSAT aftershock epicenters is
25.5 km, i.e. by an order of magnitude larger than that obtained by the WCC
relative location method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03072</id><created>2016-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>Fergus</forenames></author></authors><title>Apocalypse Now? Reviving the Doomsday Argument</title><categories>stat.OT physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Whether the fate of our species can be forecast from its past has been the
topic of considerable controversy. One refutation of the so-called Doomsday
Argument is based on the premise that we are more likely to exist in a universe
containing a greater number of observers. Here we present a Bayesian
reformulation of the Doomsday Argument which is immune to this effect. By
marginalising over the spatial configuration of observers, we find that any
preference for a larger total number of observers has no impact on the inferred
local number. Our results remain unchanged when we adopt either the
Self-Indexing Assumption (SIA) or the Self-Sampling Assumption (SSA).
Furthermore the median value of our posterior distribution is found to be in
agreement with the frequentist forecast. Humanity's prognosis for the coming
century is well approximated by a global catastrophic risk of 0.2% per year.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03074</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Holstein</keyname><forenames>Barry R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical On-shell Calculation of Higher Order Scattering: Massless
  Particles</title><categories>hep-ph gr-qc hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>38 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1610.07957</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that the use of on-shell methods involving calculation of the
discontinuity across the t-channel cut associated with the exchange of a pair
of massless particles can be used to evaluate loop contributions to the
electromagnetic and gravitational scattering of both massive and massless
particles. In the gravitational case the use of factorization permits a
straightforward and algebraic calculation of higher order scattering results,
which were obtained previously by considerably more arduous Feynman diagram
techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0211063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0211063</id><created>2002-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Sixia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zeng-Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong-De</forenames></author></authors><title>Classifying N-qubit Entanglement via Bell's Inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>PRL 90, 080401 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.90.080401</doi><abstract>  All the states of N qubits can be classified into N-1 entanglement classes
from 2-entangled to N-entangled (fully entangled) states. Each class of
entangled states is characterized by an entanglement index that depends on the
partition of N. The larger the entanglement index of an state, the more
entangled or the less separable is the state in the sense that a larger maximal
violation of Bell's inequality is attainable for this class of state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0502085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0502085</id><created>2005-02-14</created><updated>2005-09-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zukowski</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zeng-Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>All-Versus-Nothing Violation of Local Realism by Two-Photon,
  Four-Dimensional Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures; typo errors corrected and some references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 95, 240406 (2005)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.95.240406</doi><abstract>  We develop and exploit a source of two-photon four-dimensional entanglement
to report the first two-particle all-versus-nothing test of local realism with
a linear optics setup, but without resorting to a non-contextuality ssumption.
Our experimental results are in well agreement with quantum mechanics while in
extreme contradiction with local realism. Potential applications of our
experiment are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
