<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:23:36Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-10-17" from="2016-10-17" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.5424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.5424</id><created>2011-08-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Alagic</keyname><forenames>Gorjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bering</keyname><forenames>Edgar A.</forenames><suffix>IV</suffix></author></authors><title>Quantum Algorithms for Invariants of Triangulated Manifolds</title><categories>quant-ph math.GT</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information &amp; Computation; Vol. 12 Issue 9-10, pp. 843-863
  (2012)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the apparent advantages of quantum computers over their classical
counterparts is their ability to efficiently contract tensor networks. In this
article, we study some implications of this fact in the case of topological
tensor networks. The graph underlying these networks is given by the
triangulation of a manifold, and the structure of the tensors ensures that the
overall tensor is independent of the choice of internal triangulation. This
leads to quantum algorithms for additively approximating certain invariants of
triangulated manifolds. We discuss the details of this construction in two
specific cases. In the first case, we consider triangulated surfaces, where the
triangle tensor is defined by the multiplication operator of a finite group;
the resulting invariant has a simple closed-form expression involving the
dimensions of the irreducible representations of the group and the Euler
characteristic of the surface. In the second case, we consider triangulated
3-manifolds, where the tetrahedral tensor is defined by the so-called Fibonacci
anyon model; the resulting invariant is the well-known Turaev-Viro invariant of
3-manifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.0836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.0836</id><created>2013-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Jordan</keyname><forenames>Stephen P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong equivalence of reversible circuits is coNP-complete</title><categories>cs.CC quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><report-no>Quantum Information and Computation 14(15/16):1302-1307, 2014</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well-known that deciding equivalence of logic circuits is a
coNP-complete problem. As a corollary, the problem of deciding weak equivalence
of reversible circuits, i.e. ignoring the ancilla bits, is also coNP-complete.
The complexity of deciding strong equivalence, including the ancilla bits, is
less obvious and may depend on gate set. Here we use Barrington's theorem to
show that deciding strong equivalence of reversible circuits built from the
Fredkin gate is coNP-complete. This implies coNP-completeness of deciding
strong equivalence for other commonly used universal reversible gate sets,
including any gate set that includes the Toffoli or Fredkin gate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.1720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.1720</id><created>2014-12-04</created><updated>2014-12-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Loh</keyname><forenames>Huanqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Shiqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hablutzel</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maslennikov</keyname><forenames>Gleb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsukevich</keyname><forenames>Dzmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Zeeman-Splitting-Assisted Quantum Logic Spectroscopy of Trapped Ions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 90, 061402(R) (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.90.061402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a quantum logic scheme to detect atomic and molecular ions in
different states of angular momentum based on their magnetic $g$-factors. The
state-dependent magnetic $g$-factors mean that electronic, rotational or
hyperfine states may be distinguished by their Zeeman splittings in a given
magnetic field. Driving motional sidebands of a chosen Zeeman splitting enables
reading out the corresponding state of angular momentum with an auxillary logic
ion. As a proof-of-principle demonstration, we show that we can detect the
ground electronic state of a ${^{174}}$Yb$^+$ ion using ${^{171}}$Yb$^+$ as the
logic ion. Further, we can distinguish between the ${^{174}}$Yb$^+$ ion being
in its ground electronic state versus the metastable ${^{2}}D_{3/2}$ state. We
discuss the suitability of this scheme for the detection of rotational states
in molecular ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.07820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.07820</id><created>2015-01-30</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berman</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onnheim</keyname><forenames>Magnus</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of chaos, Wasserstein gradient flows and toric
  Kahler-Einstein metrics</title><categories>math-ph math.DG math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>v1: 37 pages. v2: 47 pages. Improved exposition and added
  applications to particle approximations for singular pair interactions in 1D-
  v3: 39 pages. Complex geometric motivations included. The applications to
  singular pair interactions have been moved to the companion paper
  &quot;Propagation of chaos for a class of first order models with singular mean
  field interactions&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by a probabilistic approach to Kahler-Einstein metrics we consider
a general non-equilibrium statistical mechanics model in Euclidean space
consisting of the stochastic gradient flow of a given (possibly singular)
quasi-convex N-particle interaction energy. We show that a deterministic
&quot;macroscopic&quot; evolution equation emerges in the large N-limit of many
particles. This is a strengthening of previous results which required a uniform
two-sided bound on the Hessian of the interaction energy. The proof uses the
theory of weak gradient flows on the Wasserstein space. Applied to the setting
of permanental point processes at &quot;negative temperature&quot; the corresponding
limiting evolution equation yields a drift-diffusion equation, coupled to the
Monge-Ampere operator, whose static solutions correspond to toric
Kahler-Einstein metrics. This drift-diffusion equation is the gradient flow on
the Wasserstein space of probability measures of the K-energy functional in
Kahler geometry and it can be seen as a fully non-linear version of various
extensively studied dissipative evolution equations and conservations laws,
including the Keller-Segel equation and Burger's equation. We also obtain a
real probabilistic (and tropical) analog of the complex geometric
Yau-Tian-Donaldson conjecture in this setting. In a companion paper
applications to singular pair interactions are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02890</id><created>2015-02-10</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dujardin</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbina</keyname><forenames>Juan Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlagheck</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Describing many-body bosonic waveguide scattering with the truncated
  Wigner method</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annalen der Physik 527, 629 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201500113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider quasi-stationary scattering of interacting bosonic matter waves
in one-dimensional waveguides, as they arise in guided atom lasers. We show how
the truncated Wigner (tW) method, which corresponds to the semiclassical
description of the bosonic many-body system on the level of the diagonal
approximation, can be utilized in order to describe such many-body bosonic
scattering processes. Special emphasis is put on the discretization of space at
the exact quantum level, in order to properly implement the semiclassical
approximation and the tW method, as well as on the discussion of the results to
be obtained in the continuous limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06182</id><created>2015-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Zi-Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Field Equations in the Complex Quaternion Spaces</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1503.06098</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics, Vol.2014, 450262, 6 pages, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2014/450262</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper aims to adopt the complex quaternion and octonion to formulate the
field equations for electromagnetic and gravitational fields. Applying the
octonionic representation enables one single definition to combine some physics
contents of two fields, which were considered to be independent of each other
in the past. J. C. Maxwell applied simultaneously the vector terminology and
the quaternion analysis to depict the electromagnetic theory. This method
edified the paper to introduce the quaternion and octonion spaces into the
field theory, in order to describe the physical feature of electromagnetic and
gravitational fields, while their coordinates are able to be the complex
number. The octonion space can be separated into two subspaces, the quaternion
space and the S-quaternion space. In the quaternion space, it is able to infer
the field potential, field strength, field source, field equations, and so
forth, in the gravitational field. In the S-quaternion space, it is able to
deduce the field potential, field strength, field source, and so forth, in the
electromagnetic field. The results reveal that the quaternion space is
appropriate to describe the gravitational features; meanwhile the S-quaternion
space is proper to depict the electromagnetic features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01638</id><created>2015-05-07</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anvari</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohmann</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tabar</keyname><forenames>M. Reza Rahimi</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xe4;chter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milan</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinemann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peinke</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppressing the non-Gaussian statistics of Renewable Power from Wind and
  Solar</title><categories>physics.soc-ph nlin.AO physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn because a new version of the paper has
  been written and submitted as article arXiv:1606.03426</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The power from wind and solar exhibits a nonlinear flickering variability,
which typically occurs at time scales of a few seconds. We show that
high-frequency monitoring of such renewable powers enables us to detect a
transition, controlled by the field size, where the output power qualitatively
changes its behaviour from a flickering type to a diffusive stochastic
behaviour. We find that the intermittency and strong non-Gaussian behavior in
cumulative power of the total field, even for a country-wide installation still
survives for both renewable sources. To overcome the short time intermittency,
we introduce a time-delayed feedback method for power output of wind farm and
solar field that can change further the underlying stochastic process and
suppress their strong non- gaussian fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04179</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kleinmann</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabello</keyname><forenames>Adan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum correlations are stronger than all nonsignaling correlations
  produced by n-outcome measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 150401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.150401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that, for any n, there are m-outcome quantum correlations, with m&gt;n,
which are stronger than any nonsignaling correlation produced from selecting
among n-outcome measurements. As a consequence, for any n, there are m-outcome
quantum measurements that cannot be constructed by selecting locally from the
set of n-outcome measurements. This is a property of the set of measurements in
quantum theory that is not mandatory for general probabilistic theories. We
also show that this prediction can be tested through high-precision Bell-type
experiments and identify past experiments providing evidence that some of these
strong correlations exist in nature. Finally, we provide a modified version of
quantum theory restricted to having at most n-outcome quantum measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06877</id><created>2015-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Rittmeyer</keyname><forenames>Simon P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juaristi</keyname><forenames>J. I&#xf1;aki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic friction-based vibrational lifetimes of molecular adsorbates:
  Beyond the independent atom approximation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages including 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 046102 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.046102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assess the accuracy of vibrational damping rates of diatomic adsorbates on
metal surfaces as calculated within the local-density friction approximation
(LDFA). An atoms-in-molecules (AIM) type charge partitioning scheme accounts
for intra-molecular contributions and overcomes the systematic underestimation
of the non-adiabatic losses obtained within the prevalent independent atom
approximation. The quantitative agreement obtained with theoretical and
experimental benchmark data suggests the LDFA-AIM as an efficient and reliable
approach to account for electronic dissipation in ab initio molecular dynamics
simulations of surface chemical reactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00312</id><created>2015-07-01</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Elouard</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auff&#xe8;ves</keyname><forenames>Alexia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clusel</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic thermodynamics in the quantum regime</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>This manuscript corresponds to a work started with Dr. Maxime Clusel,
  who sadly passed away on October 2015. Since then, the manuscript has been
  completed. Please find new version at : arXiv:1607.02404</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article sets up a formalism to describe stochastic thermodynamics for
driven out-of-equilibrium open quantum systems. A stochastic Schr\&quot;odinger
equation allows to construct quantum trajectories describing the dynamics of
the system state vector in presence of an eventually monitored environment.
Thermodynamic quantities are defined at the single quantum trajectory level,
independently of any energy measurement, at any time of the protocol. We
thereby identify coherent contributions, without classical counterparts,
leading to quantum fluctuations of thermodynamic quantities. This formalism
eventually leads to central fluctuation theorems for entropy, extending in the
quantum regime results obtained in classical stochastic thermodynamics. The
thermal imprint of coherences on a simple implementation of Jarzynski equality
is investigated, opening avenues for a thermodynamic approach to decoherence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02393</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02393</id><created>2015-08-10</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvati</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchiorri</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>New constraints on primordial gravitational waves from Planck 2015</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure, matching the version published on PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B760 (2016) 823-825</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the new precise measurements of Cosmic Microwave Background
(CMB) temperature and polarization anisotropies made by the Planck satellite
significantly improves previous constraints on the cosmic gravitational waves
background (CGWB) at frequencies $f&gt;10^{-15}$ Hz. On scales smaller than the
horizon at the time of decoupling, primordial gravitational waves contribute to
the total radiation content of the Universe. Considering adiabatic
perturbations, CGWB affects temperature and polarization CMB power spectra and
matter power spectrum in a manner identical to relativistic particles.
Considering the latest Planck results we constrain the CGWB energy density to
$\Omega_{\rm gw} h^2 &lt;1.7\times 10^{-6} $ at 95\% CL. Combining CMB power
spectra with lensing, BAO and primordial Deuterium abundance observations, we
obtain $\Omega_{\rm gw} h^2 &lt;1.2\times 10^{-6} $ at 95\% CL, improving previous
Planck bounds by a factor 3 and the recent direct upper limit from the LIGO and
VIRGO experiments a factor 2. A combined analysis of future satellite missions
as COrE and EUCLID could improve current bound by more than an order of
magnitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06131</id><created>2015-08-25</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Negash</keyname><forenames>Hluf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhatnagar</keyname><forenames>Shashank</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopy of ground and excited states of pseudoscalar and vector
  charmonium and bottomonium</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 5 figure, 6 tables</comments><journal-ref>Intl. J. Mod. Phys. E25, 1650059 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218301316500592</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we calculate the mass spectrum, weak decay constants, two photon
decay widths, and two gluon decay widths of ground (1S), and radially excited
(2S,3S,...) states of pseudoscalar charmoniuum and bottomonium such as
$\eta_{c}$ and $\eta_{b}$, as well as the mass spectrum and leptonic decay
constants of ground state (1S), excited (2S,1D,3S,2D,4S,and 3D) states of
vector charmonium and bottomonium such as $J/\psi$, and $\Upsilon$, using the
formulation of Bethe-Salpeter equation under covariant Instantaneous Ansatz
(CIA). Our results are in good agreement with data (where ever available) and
other models. In this framework, from the beginning, we employ a $4\times 4$
representation for two-body ($q\overline{q}$) BS amplitude for calculating both
the mass spectra as well as the transition amplitudes. However, the price we
have to pay is to solve a coupled set of equations for both pseudoscalar and
vector quarkonia, which we have explicitly shown get decoupled in the
heavy-quark approximation, leading to mass spectral equation with analytical
solutions for both masses, as well as eigenfunctions for all the above states,
in an approximate harmonic oscillator basis. Further, in the present framework
of BSE, the hadron-quark vertex function (and the full 4D BS wave function) for
pseudoscalar and vector quarkonia used for calculation of various processes,
accommodates all the Dirac structures from their complete set in a natural
manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04891</id><created>2015-10-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lo</keyname><forenames>Hoi-Kwong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Charles Ci Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siopsis</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chitambar</keyname><forenames>Eric A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pooser</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Philip G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grice</keyname><forenames>Warren</forenames></author></authors><title>Free-space reconfigurable quantum key distribution network</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to IEEE The International Conference on Space Optical
  Systems and Applications (ICSOS) 2015</comments><doi>10.1109/ICSOS.2015.7425063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a free-space reconfigurable quantum key distribution (QKD) network
to secure communication among mobile users. Depends on the trustworthiness of
the network relay, the users can implement either the highly secure
measurement-device-independent QKD, or the highly efficient decoy state BB84
QKD. Based on the same quantum infrastructure, we also propose a loss tolerant
quantum position verification scheme, which could allow the QKD users to
initiate the QKD process without relying on pre-shared key.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07770</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Kallol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Aninda</forenames></author></authors><title>On critical exponents without Feynman diagrams</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>27 pages, 1 figure, Comments added. Typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>IOP Publishing Ltd. Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and
  Theoretical, Volume 49, Number 44 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/44/445401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to achieve a better analytic handle on the modern conformal
bootstrap program, we re-examine and extend the pioneering 1974 work of
Polyakov's, which was based on consistency between the operator product
expansion and unitarity. As in the bootstrap approach, this method does not
depend on evaluating Feynman diagrams. We show how this approach can be used to
compute the anomalous dimensions of certain operators in the $O(n)$ model at
the Wilson-Fisher fixed point in $4-\epsilon$ dimensions up to $O(\epsilon^2)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00636</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Rishabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sidharth</keyname><forenames>Burra G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corda</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>The Jeans theorem and the &quot;Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkov equation&quot; in an
  exact wave solution of R^2 gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Comments: 15 pages, the results of arXiv:1105.0147 have been
  partially reviewed. Final version matching the one published in the Adv. High
  En. Phys. Special Issue &quot;Classical and Quantum Gravity and Its Applications&quot;
  Edited by S. Hossein Hendi and others</comments><journal-ref>Adv. High. En. Phys. 2601741 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/2601741</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Corda, Mosquera Cuesta and Lorduy Gomez have shown that spherically symmetric
stationary states can be used as a model for galaxies in the framework of the
linearized R^2 gravity. Those states could represent a partial solution to the
Dark Matter Problem. Here we discuss an improvement of this work. In fact, as
the star density is a functional of the invariants of the associated Vlasov
equation, we show that any of these invariants is in its turn a functional of
the local energy and the angular momentum. As a consequence, the star density
depends only on these two integrals of the Vlasov system. This result is known
as the &quot;Jeans theorem&quot;. In addition, we find an analogous of the historical
Tolman- Oppenheimer-Volkov equation for the system considered in this paper.
For the sake of completeness, in the final Section of the paper we consider two
additional models which argue that Dark Matter could not be an essential
element.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01971</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Isabela A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Alexandre M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bromley</keyname><forenames>Thomas R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cianciaruso</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marx</keyname><forenames>Raimund</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarthour</keyname><forenames>Roberto S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Rosario Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glaser</keyname><forenames>Steffen J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>deAzevedo</keyname><forenames>Eduardo R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares-Pinto</keyname><forenames>Diogo O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of time-invariant coherence in a room temperature quantum
  simulator</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall nucl-ex physics.data-an</categories><comments>5+4 pages, 3 figures; close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 160402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.160402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to live in coherent superpositions is a signature trait of
quantum systems and constitutes an irreplaceable resource for quantum-enhanced
technologies. However, decoherence effects usually destroy quantum
superpositions. It has been recently predicted that, in a composite quantum
system exposed to dephasing noise, quantum coherence in a transversal reference
basis can stay protected for indefinite time. This can occur for a class of
quantum states independently of the measure used to quantify coherence, and
requires no control on the system during the dynamics. Here, such an invariant
coherence phenomenon is observed experimentally in two different setups based
on nuclear magnetic resonance at room temperature, realising an effective
quantum simulator of two- and four-qubit spin systems. Our study further
reveals a novel interplay between coherence and various forms of correlations,
and highlights the natural resilience of quantum effects in complex systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03436</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Volkoff</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Uwe R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Amplification of the quantum superposition macroscopicity of a flux
  qubit by a magnetized Bose gas</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 042320 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.042320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate a measure of superposition macroscopicity $\mathcal{M}$ for a
superposition of screening current states in a superconducting flux qubit
(SFQ), by relating $\mathcal{M}$ to the action of an instanton trajectory
connecting the potential wells of the flux qubit. When a magnetized
Bose-Einstein condensed (BEC) gas containing $N_{B}\sim \mathcal{O}(10^6)$
atoms is brought into a $\mathcal{O}(1)$ $\mu\text{m}$ proximity of the flux
qubit in an experimentally realistic geometry, we demonstrate the appearance of
a two- to five-fold amplification of $\mathcal{M}$ over the bare value without
the BEC, by calculating the instantion trajectory action from the
microscopically derived effective flux Lagrangian of a hybrid quantum system
composed of the flux qubit and a spin-$F$ atomic Bose gas. Exploiting the
connection between $\mathcal M$ and the maximal metrological usefulness of a
multimode superposition state, we show that amplification of $\mathcal{M}$ in
the ground state of the hybrid system is equivalent to a decrease in the
quantum Cram\'{e}r-Rao bound for estimation of an externally applied flux. Our
result therefore demonstrates the increased usefulness of the BEC--SFQ hybrid
system as a sensor of ultraweak magnetic fields below the standard quantum
limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04647</id><created>2015-11-14</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ponder</keyname><forenames>Kara A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood-Vasey</keyname><forenames>W. Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zentner</keyname><forenames>Andrew R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Incorporating Astrophysical Systematics into a Generalized Likelihood
  for Cosmology with Type Ia Supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures, 3 tables. Updated to include acknowledgements</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 825, Issue 1, article id. 35, 13
  pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/1/35</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Traditional cosmological inference using Type Ia supernovae (SNeIa) have used
stretch- and color-corrected fits of SN Ia light curves and assumed a resulting
fiducial mean and symmetric intrinsic dispersion for the resulting relative
luminosity. As systematics become the main contributors to the error budget, it
has become imperative to expand supernova cosmology analyses to include a more
general likelihood to model systematics to remove biases with losses in
precision. To illustrate an example likelihood analysis, we use a simple model
of two populations with a relative luminosity shift, independent intrinsic
dispersions, and linear redshift evolution of the relative fraction of each
population. Treating observationally viable two-population mock data using a
one-population model results in an inferred dark energy equation of state
parameter $w$ that is biased by roughly 2 times its statistical error for a
sample of N $ \gtrsim$ 2500 SNeIa. Modeling the two-population data with a
two-population model removes this bias at a cost of an approximately $\sim20\%$
increase in the statistical constraint on $w$. These significant biases can be
realized even if the support for two underlying SNeIa populations, in the form
of model selection criteria, is inconclusive. With the current
observationally-estimated difference in the two proposed populations, a sample
of N $ \gtrsim$ 10,000 SNeIa is necessary to yield conclusive evidence of two
populations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06800</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fong</keyname><forenames>Heather</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Prayush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Harald P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyle</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hemberger</keyname><forenames>Daniel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kidder</keyname><forenames>Lawrence E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheel</keyname><forenames>Mark A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szilagyi</keyname><forenames>Bela</forenames></author></authors><title>On the accuracy and precision of numerical waveforms: Effect of waveform
  extraction methodology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav. 33 (2016) no.16, 165001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/16/165001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new set of 95 numerical relativity simulations of non-precessing
binary black holes (BBHs). The simulations sample comprehensively both
black-hole spins up to spin magnitude of 0.9, and cover mass ratios 1 to 3. The
simulations cover on average 24 inspiral orbits, plus merger and ringdown, with
low initial orbital eccentricities $e&lt;10^{-4}$. A subset of the simulations
extends the coverage of non-spinning BBHs up to mass ratio $q=10$.
Gravitational waveforms at asymptotic infinity are computed with two
independent techniques, extrapolation, and Cauchy characteristic extraction. An
error analysis based on noise-weighted inner products is performed. We find
that numerical truncation error, error due to gravitational wave extraction,
and errors due to the finite length of the numerical waveforms are of similar
magnitude, with gravitational wave extraction errors somewhat dominating at
noise-weighted mismatches of $\sim 3\times 10^{-4}$. This set of waveforms will
serve to validate and improve aligned-spin waveform models for gravitational
wave science.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07890</id><created>2015-12-24</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cruz</keyname><forenames>W. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maluf</keyname><forenames>R. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dantas</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>C. A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiresonance modes in sine-Gordon brane models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages. 12 figures. Version to appear in Annals of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 375 (2016) 49-64</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.09.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the localization of the vector gauge field in two
five-dimensional braneworlds generated by scalar fields coupled to gravity. The
sine-Gordon like potentials are employed to produce different thick brane
setups. A zero mode localized is obtained, and we show the existence of
reverberations with the wave solutions indicating a quasi-localized massive
mode. More interesting results are achieved when we propose a double
sine-Gordon potential to the scalar field. The resulting thick brane shows a
more detailed topology with the presence of an internal structure composed by
two kinks. The massive spectrum of the gauge field is revalued on this scenario
revealing the existence of various resonant modes. Furthermore, we compute the
corrections to Coulomb law coming from these massive KK vector modes in these
thick scenarios, where is concluded that the dilaton parameter regulates these
corrections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00069</id><created>2016-01-01</created><updated>2016-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Komacek</keyname><forenames>Thaddeus D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Showman</keyname><forenames>Adam P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atmospheric Circulation of Hot Jupiters: Dayside-Nightside Temperature
  Differences</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>24 pages, 14 figures, Accepted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 821, 16 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/821/1/16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The full-phase infrared light curves of low-eccentricity hot Jupiters show a
trend of increasing dayside-to-nightside brightness temperature difference with
increasing equilibrium temperature. Here we present a three-dimensional model
that explains this relationship, in order to shed insight on the processes that
control heat redistribution in tidally-locked planetary atmospheres. This
three-dimensional model combines predictive analytic theory for the atmospheric
circulation and dayside-nightside temperature differences over a range of
equilibrium temperature, atmospheric composition, and potential frictional drag
strengths with numerical solutions of the circulation that verify this analytic
theory. This analytic theory shows that the longitudinal propagation of waves
mediates dayside-nightside temperature differences in hot Jupiter atmospheres,
analogous to the wave adjustment mechanism that regulates the thermal structure
in Earth's tropics. These waves can be damped in hot Jupiter atmospheres by
either radiative cooling or potential frictional drag. This frictional drag
would likely be caused by Lorentz forces in a partially ionized atmosphere
threaded by a background magnetic field, and would increase in strength with
increasing temperature. Additionally, the amplitude of radiative heating and
cooling increases with increasing temperature, and hence both radiative
heating/cooling and frictional drag damp waves more efficiently with increasing
equilibrium temperature. Radiative heating and cooling play the largest role in
controlling dayside-nightside temperature temperature differences in both our
analytic theory and numerical simulations, with frictional drag only important
if it is stronger than the Coriolis force. As a result, dayside-nightside
temperature differences in hot Jupiter atmospheres increase with increasing
stellar irradiation and decrease with increasing pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01245</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Yanjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zu</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zheyu</forenames></author></authors><title>Revealing the spin optics of conics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ellipse and hyperbola are two well-known curves in mathematics with numerous
applications in various fields, but their properties and inherent differences
in spin optics are less understood. Here, we investigate the peculiar optical
spin properties of the two curves and establish a connection between their foci
and the spin states of incident light. We show that the optical spin Hall
effect is the intrinsic optical spin property of ellipse, where photons with
different spin states can be exactly separated to each of its two foci. While a
hyperbola exhibits optical spin-selective effect, where only photons with one
particular spin state can be accumulated at its foci. These properties are then
experimentally demonstrated in near field by arranging nanoslits in conic
shape. Based on the spin properties of the curves, we design spin-based
plasmonic devices with various functionalities. Our results reveal the
intrinsic optical spin properties behind conic curves and provide a route for
designing spin-based plasmonic device.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04826</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>Michael S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinberg</keyname><forenames>Martin D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katz</keyname><forenames>Neal</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter Trapping by Stellar Bars: The Shadow Bar</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures. MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the complex interactions between the stellar disc and the
dark-matter halo during bar formation and evolution using N-body simulations
with fine temporal resolution and optimally chosen spatial resolution. We find
that the forming stellar bar traps dark matter in the vicinity of the stellar
bar into bar-supporting orbits. We call this feature the shadow bar. The shadow
bar modifies both the location and magnitude of the angular momentum transfer
between the disc and dark matter halo and adds 10 per cent to the mass of the
stellar bar over 4 Gyr. The shadow bar is potentially observable by its density
and velocity signature in spheroid stars and by direct dark matter detection
experiments. Numerical tests demonstrate that the shadow bar can diminish the
rate of angular momentum transport from the bar to the dark matter halo by more
than a factor of three over the rate predicted by dynamical friction with an
untrapped dark halo, and thus provides a possible physical explanation for the
observed prevalence of fast bars in nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07699</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hahn</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paranjape</keyname><forenames>Aseem</forenames></author></authors><title>General relativistic 'screening' in cosmological simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, minor changes to match version accepted by PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 083511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.083511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the issue of interpreting the results of large volume cosmological
simulations in the context of large scale general relativistic effects. We look
for simple modifications to the nonlinear evolution of the gravitational
potential $\psi$ that lead on large scales to the correct, fully relativistic
description of density perturbations in the Newtonian gauge. We note that the
relativistic constraint equation for $\psi$ can be cast as a diffusion
equation, with a diffusion length scale determined by the expansion of the
Universe. Exploiting the weak time evolution of $\psi$ in all regimes of
interest, this equation can be further accurately approximated as a Helmholtz
equation, with an effective relativistic 'screening' scale $\ell$ related to
the Hubble radius. We demonstrate that it is thus possible to carry out N-body
simulations in the Newtonian gauge by replacing Poisson's equation with this
Helmholtz equation, involving a trivial change in the Green's function kernel.
Our results also motivate a simple, approximate (but very accurate) gauge
transformation - $\delta_{\rm N}(\mathbf{k}) \approx \delta_{\rm
sim}(\mathbf{k})\times (k^2+\ell^{-2})/k^2$ - to convert the density field
$\delta_{\rm sim}$ of standard collisionless N-body simulations (initialised in
the comoving synchronous gauge) into the Newtonian gauge density $\delta_{\rm
N}$ at arbitrary times. A similar conversion can also be written in terms of
particle positions. Our results can be interpreted in terms of a Jeans
stability criterion induced by the expansion of the Universe. The appearance of
the screening scale $\ell$ in the evolution of $\psi$, in particular, leads to
a natural resolution of the 'Jeans swindle' in the presence of super-horizon
modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08140</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boughezal</keyname><forenames>Radja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaohui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petriello</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of the Z-boson plus jet process at NNLO</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables; published version. arXiv admin note:
  text overlap with arXiv:1602.06965</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 074015 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.074015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed phenomenological study of Z-boson production in
association with a jet through next-to-next-to-leading order (NNLO) in
perturbative QCD. Fiducial cross sections and differential distributions for
both 8 TeV and 13 TeV LHC collisions are presented. We study the impact of
different parton distribution functions (PDFs) on predictions for the Z+jet
process. Upon inclusion of the NNLO corrections, the residual scale uncertainty
is reduced such that both the total rate and the transverse momentum
distributions can be used to discriminate between various PDF sets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08822</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08822</id><created>2016-02-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Wendong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Rui-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Peizhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sofo</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy Dirac fermions in a graphene/topological insulator hetero-junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>2 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 3 (2016) 034006</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The low energy physics of both graphene and surface states of
three-dimensional topological insulators is described by gapless Dirac fermions
with linear dispersion. In this work, we predict the emergence of a &quot;heavy&quot;
Dirac fermion in a graphene/topological insulator hetero-junction, where the
linear term almost vanishes and the corresponding energy dispersion becomes
highly non-linear. By combining {\it ab initio} calculations and an effective
low-energy model, we show explicitly how strong hybridization between Dirac
fermions in graphene and the surface states of topological insulators can
reduce the Fermi velocity of Dirac fermions. Due to the negligible linear term,
interaction effects will be greatly enhanced and can drive &quot;heavy&quot; Dirac
fermion states into the half quantum Hall state with non-zero Hall conductance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00635</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jingshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>Thibault</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral shift and dephasing of electromagnetically induced transparency
  in an interacting Rydberg gas</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043806 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform spectroscopic measurements of electromagnetically induced
transparency (EIT) in a strongly interacting Rydberg gas, and observe a
significant spectral shift of the transparency from the single-atom EIT
resonance as well as a spectral dephasing of the same order. We characterize
the shift and dephasing as a function of atomic density, probe Rabi frequency,
and principal quantum number of Rydberg states, and demonstrate that the
observed spectral shift and dephasing are reduced if the size of a Gaussian
atomic cloud is increased. We simulate our experiment with a semi-analytical
model, which gives results in good agreement with our experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00886</id><created>2016-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Florio</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forte</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirtori</keyname><forenames>Emanuela</forenames></author></authors><title>Forecasting the Socio-Economic Impact of the Large Hadron Collider: a
  Cost-Benefit Analysis to 2025 and Beyond</title><categories>physics.soc-ph hep-ex hep-ph physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 7 figures; extended version of arXiv:1507.05638; to be
  submitted to the journal &quot;Technological Forecasting and Social Change&quot;</comments><report-no>TIF-UNIMI-2016-01</report-no><journal-ref>Techn. For. and Soc. Change 112 (2016) 38</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.techfore.2016.03.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we develop a cost-benefit analysis of a major research
infrastructure, the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the highest-energy accelerator
in the world, currently operating at CERN. We show that the evaluation of
benefits can be made quantitative by estimating their welfare effects on
different types of agents. Four classes of direct benefits are identified,
according to the main social groups involved: (a) scientists; (b) students and
young researchers; (c) firms in the procurement chain and other organizations;
(d) the general public, including onsite and website visitors and other media
users. These benefits are respectively related to the knowledge output of
scientists; human capital formation; technological spillovers; and direct
cultural effects for the general public. Welfare effects for taxpayers can also
be estimated by the contingent valuation of the willingness to pay for a pure
public good for which there is no specific direct use (i.e., as non-use value).
Using a Monte Carlo approach, we estimate the conditional probability
distribution of costs and benefits for the LHC from 1993 until its planned
decommissioning in 2025, assuming a range of values for some critical
stochastic variables. We conservatively estimate that there is around a 90\%
probability that benefits exceed costs, with an expected net present value of
about 2.9 billion euro, not considering the unpredictable applications of
scientific discovery.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03250</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-06-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shi-Yuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Large production rate of new $B^0_s \pi^{\pm}$ and $D^{\pm}_s \pi^{\pm}$
  states in high energy multi-production process</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>SDU-TH/2016001</report-no><journal-ref>Published in Phys.Rev. D94 (2016) no.1, 014023</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.014023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production rate of the X(5568) observed by D0 collabotation is quite
large and can not be understood by various general hadronization mechanism. We
propose an inclusive resonance production formulation to calculate the cross
section and extract the value of the effective wave function at origin. Based
on these results we suspect X($D_s \pi^{\pm}$) can be copiously produced and
observable at high enenrgy scatterings (the relative production ratio to D_s is
larger than 10 %).
  In the updated version the discussions on cluster model and FI are added.
Both cases can not give large rate.
  Then we show that pion in X(5568) decay can only gain a very small momentum.
In the pseudo-rapidity region [2,5], large part of the signal pions will be
dismissed by the detector since the transverse mometum is too small and/or
total momentum too small. If further requirement on pion tranverse mometum
larger than 1GeV/c added, almost all signal pions are rejected. But for the
charm partner, this problem does not exist since the charm partner can give a
larger boost factor. A 3D distribution of signal pions are added
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06294</id><created>2016-03-20</created><updated>2016-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schmittberger</keyname><forenames>Bonnie L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauthier</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous emergence of free-space optical and atomic patterns</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, updated version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 103021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/10/103021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spontaneous formation of patterns in dynamical systems is a rich
phenomenon that transcends scientific boundaries. Here, we report our
observation of coupled optical-atomic pattern formation, which results in the
creation of self-organized, multimode structures in free-space laser-driven
cold atoms. We show that this process gives rise to spontaneous
three-dimensional Sisyphus cooling even at very low light intensities and the
emergence of self-organized atomic structures on both sub- and super-wavelength
scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07257</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Di Muro</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buldyrev</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanley</keyname><forenames>H. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braunstein</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cascading failures in interdependent networks with finite functional
  components</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 042304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.042304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a cascading failure model of two interdependent networks in which
functional nodes belong to components of size greater than or equal to $s$. We
find theoretically and via simulation that in complex networks with random
dependency links the transition is first-order for $s\geq 3$ and second-order
for $s=2$. We find for two square lattices with a distance constraint $r$ in
the dependency links that increasing $r$ moves the system from a regime without
a phase transition to one with a second-order transition. As $r$ continues to
increase the system collapses in a first-order transition. Each regime is
associated with a different structure of domain formation of functional nodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07266</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Elouard</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marti</keyname><forenames>David Herrera</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clusel</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auff&#xe8;ves</keyname><forenames>Alexia</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic thermodynamics in the quantum regime: From quantum
  measurement to quantum trajectories</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>This article has been withdrawn by the authors to be replaced by a
  new version available at: arXiv:1607.02404</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article sets up a new formalism to investigate stochastic thermodynamics
of out-of-equilibrium quantum systems, where stochasticity primarily comes from
quantum measurement. In the absence of any bath, we define a purely quantum
component to heat exchange, that corresponds to energy fluctuations induced by
measurement back-action. By providing a central position to quantum
measurement, our formalism bridges the gap between quantum optics and quantum
thermodynamics: Thermal signatures of measurement induced irreversibility are
identified in a simple implementation of Jarzynski equality, while quantum
thermodynamics sheds new light on textbook paradoxical trajectories in quantum
optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08751</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08751</id><created>2016-03-29</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Augustin</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Niklaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dittmeier</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grzesik</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerich</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Qinhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Lennart</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiehn</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlinskiy</keyname><forenames>Alexandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aeschbacher</keyname><forenames>Frank Meier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peri&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrevoort</keyname><forenames>Ann-Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;ning</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shrestha</keyname><forenames>Shruti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruch</keyname><forenames>Dorothea vom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wauters</keyname><forenames>Frederik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedner</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>The MuPix System-on-Chip for the Mu3e Experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with final version accepted by the publisher</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.06.095</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mu3e is a novel experiment searching for charged lepton flavor violation in
the rare decay $\mu^+ \rightarrow e^+e^-e^+$. Decay vertex position, decay time
and particle momenta have to be precisely measured in order to reject both
accidental and physics background. A silicon pixel tracker based on $50\,\mu$m
thin high voltage monolithic active pixel sensors (HV-MAPS) in a 1 T solenoidal
magnetic field provides precise vertex and momentum information. The MuPix chip
combines pixel sensor cells with integrated analog electronics and a periphery
with a complete digital readout. The MuPix7 is the first HV-MAPS prototype
implementing all functionalities of the final sensor including a readout state
machine and high speed serialization with 1.25 Gbit/s data output, allowing for
a streaming readout in parallel to the data taking. The observed efficiency of
the MuPix7 chip including the full readout system is $\geq99\%$ in a high rate
test beam.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09257</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>K. Rama Koteswara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suter</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of hyperfine interaction between an NV electron spin
  and a first-shell 13C nuclear spin in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 060101(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.060101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Nitrogen-Vacancy (NV) center in diamond has attractive properties for a
number of quantum technologies that rely on the spin angular momentum of the
electron and the nuclei adjacent to the center. The nucleus with the strongest
interaction is the $^{13}$C nuclear spin of the first shell. Using this degree
of freedom effectively hinges on precise data on the hyperfine interaction
between the electronic and the nuclear spin. Here, we present detailed
experimental data on this interaction, together with an analysis that yields
all parameters of the hyperfine tensor, as well as its orientation with respect
to the atomic structure of the center.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04905</id><created>2016-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Bronnikov</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Sung-Won</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skvortsova</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Birkhoff theorem and string clouds</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>9 two-column pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33, 195006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/19/195006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider spherically symmetric space-times in GR under the unconventional
assumptions that the spherical radius $r$ is either a constant or has a null
gradient in the $(t,x)$ subspace orthogonal to the symmetry spheres (i.e.,
$(\partial r)^2 = 0$). It is shown that solutions to the Einstein equations
with $r = \rm const$ contain an extra (fourth) spatial or temporal Killing
vector and thus satisfy the Birkhoff theorem under an additional physically
motivated condition that the lateral pressure is functionally related to the
energy density. This leads to solutions that directly generalize the
Bertotti-Robinson, Nariai and Plebanski-Hacyan solutions. Under similar
conditions, solutions with $(\partial r)^2 = 0$ but $r\ne\rm const$, supported
by an anisotropic fluid, contain a null Killing vector, which again indicates a
Birkhoff-like behavior of the system. Similar space-times supported by pure
radiation (in particular, a massless radiative scalar field) contain a null
Killing vector without additional assumptions, which leads to one more
extension of the Birkhoff theorem. Exact radial wave solutions have been found
(i) with an anisotropic fluid and (ii) with a gas of radially directed cosmic
strings (or a &quot;string cloud&quot;) combined with pure radiation. Furthermore, it is
shown that a perfect fluid with isotropic pressure and a massive or
self-interacting scalar field cannot be sources of gravitational fields with a
null but nonzero gradient of $r$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00931</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Dubertrand</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billy</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;ry-Odelin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Georgeot</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemari&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Routes towards the experimental observation of the large fluctuations
  due to chaos assisted tunneling effects with cold atoms</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>20 pages, 26 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043621 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043621</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the presence of a complex classical dynamics associated with a mixed phase
space, a quantum wave function can tunnel between two stable islands through
the chaotic sea, an effect that has no classical counterpart. This phenomenon,
referred to as chaos assisted tunneling, is characterized by large fluctuations
of the tunneling rate when a parameter is varied. To date the full extent of
this effect as well as the associated statistical distribution have never been
observed in a quantum system. Here we analyze the possibility of characterizing
these effects accurately in a cold atom experiment. Using realistic values of
the parameters of an experimental setup, we examine through analytical
estimates and extensive numerical simulations a specific system that can be
implemented with cold atoms, the atomic modulated pendulum. We assess the
efficiency of three possible routes to observe in detail chaos assisted
tunneling properties. Our main conclusion is that due to the fragility of the
symmetry between positive and negative momenta as a function of quasimomentum,
it is very challenging to use tunneling between classical islands centered on
fixed points with opposite momentum. We show that it is more promising to use
islands symmetric in position space, and characterize the regime where it could
be done. The proposed experiment could be realized with current
state-of-the-art technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02108</id><created>2016-05-06</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martone</keyname><forenames>Giovanni I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Chunlei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stringari</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical-lattice-assisted magnetic phase transition in a
  spin-orbit-coupled Bose-Einstein condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Revised version, published in PRA</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043629 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043629</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of a periodic potential generated by a
one-dimensional optical lattice on the magnetic properties of an $S=1/2$
spin-orbit-coupled Bose gas. By increasing the lattice strength one can achieve
a magnetic phase transition between a polarized and an unpolarized Bloch wave
phase, characterized by a significant enhancement of the contrast of the
density fringes. If the wave vector of the periodic potential is chosen close
to the roton momentum, the transition could take place at very small lattice
intensities, revealing the strong enhancement of the response of the system to
a weak density perturbation. By solving the Gross-Pitaevskii equation in the
presence of a three-dimensional trapping potential, we shed light on the
possibility of observing the magnetic phase transition in currently available
experimental conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04928</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-09-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gauthier</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenton</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parry</keyname><forenames>N. McKay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baker</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubinsztein-Dunlop</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neely</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct imaging of a digital-micromirror device for configurable
  microscopic optical potentials</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><journal-ref>Published in Optica Vol. 3, Issue 10, pp. 1136-1143 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.001136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Programable spatial light modulators (SLMs) have significantly advanced the
configurable optical trapping of particles. Typically, these devices are
utilized in the Fourier plane of an optical system, but direct imaging of an
amplitude pattern can potentially result in increased simplicity and
computational speed. Here we demonstrate high-resolution direct imaging of a
digital micromirror device (DMD) at high numerical apertures (NA), which we
apply to the optical trapping of a Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC). We utilise a
(1200 x 1920) pixel DMD and commercially available 0.45 NA microscope
objectives, finding that atoms confined in a hybrid optical/magnetic or
all-optical potential can be patterned using repulsive blue-detuned (532 nm)
light with 630(10) nm full-width at half-maximum (FWHM) resolution, within 5%
of the diffraction limit. The result is near arbitrary control of the density
the BEC without the need for expensive custom optics. We also introduce the
technique of time-averaged DMD potentials, demonstrating the ability to produce
multiple grayscale levels with minimal heating of the atomic cloud, by
utilising the high switching speed (20 kHz maximum) of the DMD. These
techniques will enable the realization and control of diverse optical
potentials for superfluid dynamics and atomtronics applications with quantum
gases. The performance of this system in a direct imaging configuration has
wider application for optical trapping at non-trivial NAs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05718</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guadagnoli</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reboud</keyname><forenames>Meril</forenames></author></authors><title>More Lepton Flavor Violating Observables for LHCb's Run 2</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures. v4: some typos corrected. Such corrections are
  not implemented in the journal version</comments><report-no>LAPTH-023/16</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The R_K measurement by LHCb suggests non-standard lepton non-universality
(LNU) to occur in b -&gt; s l+ l- transitions, with effects in muons rather than
electrons. A number of other measurements of b -&gt; s l+ l- transitions by LHCb
and B-factories display disagreement with the SM predictions and, remarkably,
these discrepancies are consistent in magnitude and sign with the R_K effect.
Non-standard LNU suggests non-standard lepton flavor violation (LFV) as well,
for example in B -&gt; K l l' and B_s -&gt; l l'. There are good reasons to expect
that the new effects may be larger for generations closer to the third one. In
this case, the B_s -&gt; mu e decay may be the most difficult to reach
experimentally. We propose and study in detail the radiative counterpart of
this decay, namely B_s -&gt; mu e gamma, whereby the chiral-suppression factor is
replaced by a factor of order alpha/pi. A measurement of this mode would be
sensitive to the same physics as the purely leptonic LFV decay and, depending
on experimental efficiencies, it may be more accessible. A realistic
expectation is a factor of two improvement in statistics for either of the
B_{d,s} modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05790</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sakakihara</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Primordial fluctuations from inflation in dRGT bimetric theory of
  gravity</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, 1 figure, minor changes to follow the published version</comments><report-no>KUNS-2627, RESCEU-21/16</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 1609 (2016) 09, 033</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/09/033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate primordial gravitational waves and curvature perturbations in
de Rham-Gabadadze-Tolley (dRGT) bimetric gravity. We evaluate the power-spectra
in the leading order in slow roll. Taking into account the decay of massive
graviton, we find that the action up to the second order reduces to the
Einstein theory with a non-minimally coupled scalar field, which is simplified
to a minimally coupled model by conformal transformation. We also find that the
tensor to scalar ratio for large field inflation with power law potential is
larger than the general relativity counterpart for any choice of parameters in
dRGT bimetric gravity. In addition, we confirm that the usual consistency
relation holds and we have a steeper spectrum for gravitational waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07245</id><created>2016-05-23</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Villar</keyname><forenames>V. Ashley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>Edo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chornock</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margutti</keyname><forenames>Raffaella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laskar</keyname><forenames>Tanmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>Peter K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czekala</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunnan</keyname><forenames>Ragnhild</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Mark T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Intermediate Luminosity Optical Transient SN 2010da: The Progenitor,
  Eruption and Aftermath of a Peculiar Supergiant High-mass X-ray Binary</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>published; updated citations and other minor edits</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 830, 11 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/830/1/11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present optical spectroscopy, ultraviolet to infrared imaging and X-ray
observations of the intermediate luminosity optical transient (ILOT) SN 2010da
in NGC 300 (d=1.86 Mpc) spanning from -6 to +6 years relative to the time of
outburst in 2010. Based on the light curve and multi-epoch SEDs of SN 2010da,
we conclude that the progenitor of SN 2010da is a ~10-12 Msol yellow supergiant
possibly transitioning into a blue loop phase. During outburst, SN 2010da had a
peak absolute magnitude of M&lt;-10.4 mag, dimmer than other ILOTs and supernova
impostors. We detect multi-component hydrogen Balmer, Paschen, and Ca II
emission lines in our high-resolution spectra, which indicate a dusty and
complex circumstellar environment. Since the 2010 eruption, the star has
brightened by a factor of ~5 and remains highly variable in the optical.
Furthermore, we detect SN 2010da in archival Swift and Chandra observations as
an ultraluminous X-ray source (L~6x10^{39} erg/s). We additionally attribute He
II 4686 Angstrom and coronal Fe emission lines in addition to a steady X-ray
luminosity of ~10^{37} erg/s to the presence of a compact companion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09532</id><created>2016-05-31</created><authors><author><keyname>de Avellar</keyname><forenames>Marcio G B</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe9;ndez</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altamirano</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanna</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Guobao</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase lags of quasi-periodic oscillations across source states in the
  low-mass X-ray binary 4U 1636-53</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While there are many dynamical mechanisms and models that try to explain the
origin and phenomenology of the quasi-periodic oscillations (QPOs) seen in the
X-ray light curves of low-mass X-ray binaries, few of them address how the
radiative processes occurring in these extreme environments give rise to the
rich set of variability features actually observed in these light curves. A
step towards this end comes from the study of the energy and frequency
dependence of the phase lags of these QPOs. Here we used a methodology that
allowed us to study, for the first time, the dependence of the phase lags of
all QPOs in the range of 1 Hz to 1300 Hz detected in the low-mass X-ray binary
4U 1636-53 upon energy and frequency as the source changes its states as it
moves through the colour-colour diagram. Our results suggest that within the
context of models of up-scattering Comptonization, the phase lags dependencies
upon frequency and energy can be used to extract size scales and physical
conditions of the medium that produces the lags.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00188</id><created>2016-06-01</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Lianyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Shi-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xia-Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly correlated Fermi superfluid near an orbital Feshbach resonance:
  Stability, equation of state and Leggett mode</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043624 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study the superfluid phase of a strongly correlated
$^{173}$Yb Fermi gas near its orbital Feshbach resonance, by developing a
quantitative pair-fluctuation theory within a two-band model. We examine the
density excitation spectrum of the system and determine a stability phase
diagram. We find that the $^{173}$Yb Fermi gas is intrinsically metastable and
has a peculiar equation of state, due to the small but positive singlet
scattering length. The massive Leggett mode, arising from the fluctuation of
the relative phase of two order parameters, is severely damped. We discuss the
parameter space where an undamped Leggett mode may exist.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00688</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00688</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tianjun</forenames></author></authors><title>U-duality transformation of membrane on $T^{n}$ revisited</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages; v2: 20 pages, reference corrected, extended discussion in
  section 5, journal version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1608 (2016) 138</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem with the U-duality transformation of membrane on $T^{n}$ is
recently addressed in [arXiv:1509.02915 [hep-th]]. We will consider the
U-duality transformation rule of membrane on $T^{n}\times R$. It turns out that
winding modes on $T^{n}$ should be taken into account, since the duality
transformation may bring the membrane configuration without winding modes into
the one with winding modes. With the winding modes added, the membrane
worldvolume theory in lightcone gauge is equivalent to the $n+1$ dimensional
super-Yang-Mills (SYM) theory in $\tilde{T}^{n}$, which has $SL(2,Z)\times
SL(3,Z)$ and $SL(5,Z)$ symmetries for $n=3$ and $n=4$, respectively. The
$SL(2,Z)\times SL(3,Z)$ transformation can be realized classically, making the
on-shell field configurations transformed into each other. However, the
$SL(5,Z)$ symmetry may only be realized at the quantum level, since the
classical $5d$ SYM field configurations cannot form the representation of
$SL(5,Z)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02972</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-09-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guruciaga</keyname><forenames>Pamela C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarzia</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreyra</keyname><forenames>M. Victoria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cugliandolo</keyname><forenames>Leticia F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigera</keyname><forenames>Santiago A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borzi</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Field-tuned order by disorder in Ising frustrated magnets with
  antiferromagnetic interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures + supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 167203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.167203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the appearance of thermal order by disorder in Ising
pyrochlores with staggered antiferromagnetic order frustrated by an applied
magnetic field. We use a mean-field cluster variational method, a
low-temperature expansion and Monte Carlo simulations to characterise the
order-by-disorder transition. By direct evaluation of the density of states we
quantitatively show how a symmetry-broken state is selected by thermal
excitations. We discuss the relevance of our results to experiments in $2d$ and
$3d$ samples, and evaluate how anomalous finite-size effects could be exploited
to detect this phenomenon experimentally in two-dimensional artificial systems,
or in antiferromagnetic all-in--all-out pyrochlores like Nd$_2$Hf$_2$O$_7$ or
Nd$_2$Zr$_2$O$_7$, for the first time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03338</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>St-Jean</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc9;thier-Majcher</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andr&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;gis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Francoeur</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Fidelity and Ultrafast Initialization of a Hole Spin Bound to a Te
  Isoelectronic Center in ZnS</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 1 supplemental information section</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 167401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.167401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the optical initialization of a hole-spin qubit bound to an
isoelectronic center (IC) formed by a pair of Te impurities in ZnSe, an
impurity/host system providing high optical homogeneity, large electric dipole
moments, and long coherence times. The initialization scheme is based on the
spin-preserving tunneling of a resonantly excited donor-bound exciton to a
positively charged Te IC, thus forming a positive trion. The radiative decay of
the trion within less than 50 ps leaves a heavy hole in a well-defined
polarization-controlled spin state. The initialization fidelity exceeds 98:5 %
for an initialization time of less than 150 ps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04256</id><created>2016-06-14</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fujioka</keyname><forenames>Yukari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frantti</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouleau</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puretzky</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Harry M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nickel-cobalt-titanate thin films - new sustainable magnetic oxides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Results were given in the oral presentation on January 26, 2016 in
  the Energy, Materials and Nanotechnology (EMN) conference held in Hong Kong,
  China</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single phase nickel-cobalt-titanate thin films with a formula A1+2xTi1-xO3,
where A is Ni2+,Co2+ and -0.25&lt;x&lt;1, were grown by pulsed laser deposition on
sapphire substrates. There is a large window in which both Ni/Co ratio and x
can be chosen independently. In the prototype ilmenite and corundum structures
one third of the octahedra are vacant. The reported structure is obtained by
filling vacant (x&gt;0) or emptying filled (x&lt;0) octahedra. When x = 1 all
octahedra are filled. Two factors controlling the magnetism and crystal
distortion are identified. First is a direct overlap between the adjacent
cation d-orbitals resulting in a bond formation and magnetic interactions
between the cations. This is most clearly revealed as a crystal distortion in
the x approximately 0 compositions with approximately equal amounts of Ni and
Co: the distortion of the x approximately 0 compound is a function of Ni/Co
ratio. The second factor is x, which controls the cation shift towards a vacant
octahedron. The displacement decreases and the symmetry increases with
decreasing Ti content as was revealed by x-ray diffraction and Raman
spectroscopy. When all octahedra are filled the cations prefer octahedron
center positions. Also the number density of cations has increased by a factor
of 50 percent when compared to the ilmenite structure. The number density
ratios of Ni/Co cations between x=1 and x=0 compounds is 3. The Raman and x-ray
diffraction data collected on samples with x = 1 or close to 1 are interpreted
in terms of P63/mmc space group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07013</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armata</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasile</keyname><forenames>Ruggero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barcellona</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buhmann</keyname><forenames>Stefan Yoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzuto</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passante</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Casimir-Polder force between an excited atom and a conducting
  wall</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 042511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.042511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the dynamical atom-surface Casimir-Polder force in the
non-equilibrium configuration of an atom near a perfectly conducting wall,
initially prepared in an excited state with the field in its vacuum state. We
evaluate the time-dependent Casimir-Polder force on the atom, and find that it
shows an oscillatory behavior from attractive to repulsive both in time and in
space. We also investigate the asymptotic behavior in time of the dynamical
force and of related local field quantities, showing that the static value of
the force, as obtained by a time-independent approach, is recovered for times
much larger than the timescale of the atomic self-dressing, but smaller than
the atomic decay time. We then discuss the evolution of global quantities such
as atomic and field energies, and their asymptotic behavior. We also compare
our results for the dynamical force on the excited atom with analogous results
recently obtained for an initially bare ground-state atom. We show that new
relevant features are obtained in the case of an initially excited atom, for
example much larger values of the dynamical force with respect to the static
one, allowing for an easier way to single-out and observe the dynamical
Casimir-Polder effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07177</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coley</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregoris</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Woei Chet</forenames></author></authors><title>On the first $G_1$ stiff fluid spike solution in General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 1 figure. Figure updated. Minor changes to match published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 215010</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/21/215010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the Geroch transformation we obtain the first example of an exact stiff
fluid spike solution to the Einstein field equations in a closed form
exhibiting a spacelike $G_1$ group of symmetries (i.e., with a single
isometry). This new solution is of Petrov type I and exhibits a spike crossing
which persists to the past, which allows us to better understand spike
crossings in the context of structure formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07413</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Di Matteo</keyname><forenames>Olivia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosca</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Parallelizing quantum circuit synthesis</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, Vol 1 (1) 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/1/1/015003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum circuit synthesis is the process in which an arbitrary unitary
operation is decomposed into a sequence of gates from a universal set,
typically one which a quantum computer can implement both efficiently and
fault-tolerantly. As physical implementations of quantum computers improve, the
need is growing for tools which can effectively synthesize components of the
circuits and algorithms they will run. Existing algorithms for exact,
multi-qubit circuit synthesis scale exponentially in the number of qubits and
circuit depth, leaving synthesis intractable for circuits on more than a
handful of qubits. Even modest improvements in circuit synthesis procedures may
lead to significant advances, pushing forward the boundaries of not only the
size of solvable circuit synthesis problems, but also in what can be realized
physically as a result of having more efficient circuits.
  We present a method for quantum circuit synthesis using deterministic walks.
Also termed pseudorandom walks, these are walks in which once a starting point
is chosen, its path is completely determined. We apply our method to construct
a parallel framework for circuit synthesis, and implement one such version
performing optimal $T$-count synthesis over the Clifford+$T$ gate set. We use
our software to present examples where parallelization offers a significant
speedup on the runtime, as well as directly confirm that the 4-qubit 1-bit full
adder has optimal $T$-count 7 and $T$-depth 3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08295</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Gangopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sunandan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Abhijit</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on rainbow gravity functions from black hole thermodynamics</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages Latex, comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Euro.Phys.Lett. 115 (2016) 50005</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/50005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we investigate the thermodynamic properties of black holes in
the framework of rainbow gravity. By considering rainbow functions in the
metric of Schwarzschild and Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m black holes, remnant and
critical masses are found to exist. Demanding the universality of logarithmic
corrections to the semi-classical area law for the entropy leads to
constraining the form of the rainbow functions. The mass output and the
radiation rate for these constrained form of rainbow functions have been
computed for different values of the rainbow parameter $\eta$ and have striking
similarity to those derived from the generalized uncertainty principle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08715</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rajasekaran</keyname><forenames>G</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Chennai &amp; Chennai Mathematical Institute</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Story of the Neutrino</title><categories>physics.pop-ph hep-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 2 Figures, a few typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is an elementary review of the history and physics of neutrinos. The
story of the discovery of neutrino mass through neutrino oscillations is
described in some detail. Experiments on solar neutrinos and atmospheric
neutrinos played an important part. Recent advances are summarized and future
developments are indicated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02521</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Metz</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vossen</keyname><forenames>Anselm</forenames></author></authors><title>Parton Fragmentation Functions</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>103 pages, 31 figures, discussion and references added, accepted for
  publication in Progress in Particle and Nuclear Physics</comments><journal-ref>Progress in Particle and Nuclear Physics (2016) pp. 136-202</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ppnp.2016.08.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The field of fragmentation functions of light quarks and gluons is reviewed.
In addition to integrated fragmentation functions, attention is paid to the
dependence of fragmentation functions on transverse momenta and on polarization
degrees of freedom. Higher-twist and di-hadron fragmentation functions are
considered as well. Moreover, the review covers both theoretical and
experimental developments in single-inclusive hadron production in
electron-positron annihilation, deep-inelastic lepton-nucleon scattering, and
proton-proton collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03145</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Ashley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beutler</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chuang</keyname><forenames>Chia-Hsun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pellejero-Ibanez</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>Hee-Jong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vargas-Magana</keyname><forenames>Mariana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuesta</keyname><forenames>Antonio J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Percival</keyname><forenames>Will J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burden</keyname><forenames>Angela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>Ariel G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grieb</keyname><forenames>Jan Niklas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reid</keyname><forenames>Beth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brownstein</keyname><forenames>Joel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>Kyle S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenstein</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Shirley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitaura</keyname><forenames>Francisco-Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nichol</keyname><forenames>Robert C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olmstead</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prada</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Torres</keyname><forenames>Sergio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salazar-Albornoz</keyname><forenames>Salvador</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Donald P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tinker</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tojeiro</keyname><forenames>Rita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuting</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Gong-bo</forenames></author></authors><title>The clustering of galaxies in the completed SDSS-III Baryon Oscillation
  Spectroscopic Survey: Observational systematics and baryon acoustic
  oscillations in the correlation function</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Matches version accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2372</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) scale measurements determined
from the clustering of 1.2 million massive galaxies with redshifts 0.2 &lt; z &lt;
0.75 distributed over 9300 square degrees, as quantified by their
redshift-space correlation function. In order to facilitate these measurements,
we define, describe, and motivate the selection function for galaxies in the
final data release (DR12) of the SDSS III Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic
Survey (BOSS). This includes the observational footprint, masks for image
quality and Galactic extinction, and weights to account for density
relationships intrinsic to the imaging and spectroscopic portions of the
survey. We simulate the observed systematic trends in mock galaxy samples and
demonstrate that they impart no bias on baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) scale
measurements and have a minor impact on the recovered statistical uncertainty.
We measure transverse and radial BAO distance measurements in 0.2 &lt; z &lt; 0.5,
0.5 &lt; z &lt; 0.75, and (overlapping) 0.4 &lt; z &lt; 0.6 redshift bins. In each redshift
bin, we obtain a precision that is 2.7 per cent or better on the radial
distance and 1.6 per cent or better on the transverse distance. The combination
of the redshift bins represents 1.8 per cent precision on the radial distance
and 1.1 per cent precision on the transverse distance. This paper is part of a
set that analyses the final galaxy clustering dataset from BOSS. The
measurements and likelihoods presented here are combined with others in Alam et
al. (2016) to produce the final cosmological constraints from BOSS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04150</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Flavio S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nussinov</keyname><forenames>Zohar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Jeroen van den</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson currents induced by the Witten effect</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure. Published version (PRL editor's suggestion)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 167002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.167002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reveal the existence of a new type of topological Josephson effect
involving type II superconductors and three-dimensional topological insulators
as tunnel junctions. We predict that vortex lines induce a variant of the
Witten effect that is the consequence of the axion electromagnetic response of
the topological insulator: at the interface of the junction each flux quantum
attains a fractional electrical charge of e/4. As a consequence, if an external
magnetic field is applied perpendicular to the junction, the Witten effect
induces an AC Josephson effect in absence of any external voltage. We derive a
number of further experimental consequences and propose potential setups where
these {quantized, flux induced, Witten} effects may be observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05630</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Aqeel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlietstra</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostovoy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Wees</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palstra</keyname><forenames>T. T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical detection of spiral spin structures in Pt|Cu_2OSeO_3
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 134418 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.134418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction between the itinerant spins in metals and localized spins in
magnetic insulators thus far has only been explored in collinear spin systems,
such as garnets. Here, we report the spin-Hall magnetoresistance (SMR)
sensitive to the surface magnetization of the spin-spiral material, Cu_2OSeO_3.
We experimentally demonstrate that the angular dependence of the SMR changes
drastically at the transition between the helical spiral and the conical spiral
phases. Furthermore, the sign and magnitude of the SMR in the conical spiral
state are controlled by the cone angle. We show that this complex behaviour can
be qualitatively explained within the SMR theory initially developed for
collinear magnets. In addition, we studied the spin Seebeck effect (SSE), which
is sensitive to the bulk magnetization. It originates from the conversion of
thermally excited low-energy spin waves in the magnet, known as magnons, into
the spin current in the adjacent metal contact (Pt). The SSE displays
unconventional behavior where not only the magnitude but also the phase of the
SSE vary with the applied magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06775</id><created>2016-06-11</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhitong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Xiaoqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gjika</keyname><forenames>Eda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keidar</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of cold atmospheric plasma generated in deionized water in cell
  cancer therapy</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1605.05345</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cold atmospheric plasma (CAP) was shown to affect cells not only directly,
but also indirectly by means of plasma pre-treated solution. This study
investigated a new application of CAP generated in deionized (DI) water for the
cancer therapy. In our experiments, the CAP solution was generated in DI water
using helium as carrier gas. We report on the effects of this plasma solution
in breast (MDA-MD-231) and gastric (NCI-N87) cancer cells. The results revealed
that apoptosis efficiency was dependent on the plasma exposure time and on the
levels of reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (ROS and RNS). The plasma
solution that resulted from 30-minute treatment of DI water had the most
significant effect in the rate of apoptosis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06856</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Loheac</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbour</keyname><forenames>Andi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komanicky</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Chenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collini</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruffino</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yihua</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Hoydoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierce</keyname><forenames>Michael S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction of Molecular Oxygen with Hexagonally Reconstructed Au (001)
  Surface</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 10 figures, submitted J. Phys. Chem. C</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, Vol 120, 23001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b07020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kinetics of molecular oxygen / Au (001) surface interaction has been studied
at high temperature and near atmospheric pressures of O2 gas with in situ x-ray
scattering measurements. We find that the hexagonal reconstruction (hex) of Au
(001) surface lifts to (1x1) in the presence of O2 gas, indicating that the
(1x1) is more favored when some oxygen atoms present on the surface. The
measured lifting rate constant vs. temperature is found to be highest at
intermediate temperature exhibiting a 'volcano'-type behavior. At low
temperature, the hex-to-(1x1) activation barrier (Eact = 1.3(3) eV) limits the
lifting. At high temperature, oxygen adsorption energy (Eads = 1.6(2) eV)
limits the lifting. The (1x1)-to-hex activation barrier (Ehex = 0.41(14) eV) is
also obtained from hex recovery kinetics. The pressure-temperature (PT) surface
phase diagram obtained in this study shows three regions: hex at low P and T,
(1x1) at high P and T, and coexistence of the hex and (1x1) at the intermediate
P and T.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07690</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saliba</keyname><forenames>Mirna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosgra</keyname><forenames>Jeroen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>David</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>Aaron D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Ulrich H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thibault</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Resolution Hard X-ray Holography by Unconfined Atomic Layer
  Deposited Phase-Shifting 3D References</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate high-resolution non-iterative holographic coherent diffraction
imaging with hard X-rays using a novel phase-shifting reference, fabricated by
atomic layer deposition to produce nanosharp 3D structure. The method surpasses
the limitations associated with absorbing substrates predominantly employed in
soft X-ray holography using extended, customized and point-source references.
The unconfined experimental setup relaxes the technical constraints, allows
effective data correction, and enables independent sample translation and
rotation for data averaging and tomography. Applicable to single-shot
measurements, phase and amplitude reconstructions of samples are retrieved with
single-pixel resolution and differential contrast by simple non-iterative
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08817</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2016-09-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cruz-Martinez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehrmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glover</keyname><forenames>E. W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaquier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>NNLO QCD corrections to Higgs boson production at large transverse
  momentum</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>28 pages, 13 figures</comments><report-no>IPPP/16/73, ZU-TH 29/16, FR-PHENO-2016-014</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1610 (2016) 066</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2016)066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the second-order QCD corrections to the production of a Higgs boson
recoiling against a parton with finite transverse momentum, working in the
effective field theory in which the top quark contributions are integrated out.
To account for quark mass effects, we supplement the effective field theory
result by the full quark mass dependence at leading order. Our calculation is
fully differential in the final state kinematics and includes the decay of the
Higgs boson to a photon pair. It allows one to make next-to-next-to- leading
order (NNLO)-accurate theory predictions for Higgs-plus-jet final states and
for the transverse momentum distribution of the Higgs boson, accounting for the
experimental definition of the fiducial cross sections. The NNLO QCD
corrections are found to be moderate and positive, they lead to a substantial
reduction of the theory uncertainty on the predictions. We compare our results
to 8 TeV LHC data from ATLAS and CMS. While the shape of the data is
well-described for both experiments, we agree on the normalization only for
CMS. By normalizing data and theory to the inclusive fiducial cross section for
Higgs production, good agreement is found for both experiments, however at the
expense of an increased theory uncertainty. We make predictions for Higgs
production observables at the 13 TeV LHC, which are in good agreement with
recent ATLAS data. At this energy, the leading order mass corrections to the
effective field theory prediction become significant at large transverse
momenta, and we discuss the resulting uncertainties on the predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06238</id><created>2016-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Palittapongarnpim</keyname><forenames>Pantita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wittek</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanders</keyname><forenames>Barry C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-shot Adaptive Measurement for Quantum-enhanced Metrology</title><categories>quant-ph stat.ML</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, paper accepted for Quantum Communications and
  Quantum Imaging XIV conference at SPIE Optics + Photonics 2016</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9980, Quantum Communications and Quantum Imaging XIV,
  (2016) 99800H (11pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2237355</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum-enhanced metrology aims to estimate an unknown parameter such that
the precision scales better than the shot-noise bound. Single-shot adaptive
quantum-enhanced metrology (AQEM) is a promising approach that uses feedback to
tweak the quantum process according to previous measurement outcomes.
Techniques and formalism for the adaptive case are quite different from the
usual non-adaptive quantum metrology approach due to the causal relationship
between measurements and outcomes. We construct a formal framework for AQEM by
modeling the procedure as a decision-making process, and we derive the
imprecision and the Cram\'{e}r-Rao lower bound with explicit dependence on the
feedback policy. We also explain the reinforcement learning approach for
generating quantum control policies, which is adopted due to the optimal policy
being non-trivial to devise. Applying a learning algorithm based on
differential evolution enables us to attain imprecision for adaptive
interferometric phase estimation, which turns out to be SQL when non-entangled
particles are used in the scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06946</id><created>2016-08-24</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Sridip</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantized Brans Dicke Theory: Phase Transition and Strong Coupling
  (Large $\omega$) Limit &amp; General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>v1: 5 Pages and a lonely line ; 1 figure; v2: 5.7 Pages, a note
  added, ref. added; emphasized cross-disciplinary interest v3: published
  version, graph mended</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 084023 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.084023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Friedmann-Robertson-Walker (FRW) geometry with flat spatial
section in quantized (Wheeler deWitt quantization) Brans Dicke (BD) theory
reveals a rich phase structure owing to anomalous breaking of a classical
symmetry, which maps the scale factor $a\mapsto\lambda a$ for some constant
$\lambda$. In the weak coupling ($\omega$) limit, the theory goes from a
symmetry preserving phase to a broken phase. The existence of phase boundary is
an obstruction to another classical symmetry [arXiv:gr-qc/9902083] (which
relates two BD theory with different coupling) admitted by BD theory with scale
invariant matter content i.e $T^{\mu}{}_{\mu}=0$. Classically, this prohibits
the BD theory to reduce to General Relativity (GR) for scale invariant matter
content. We show that strong coupling limit of BD and GR both preserves the
symmetry involving scale factor. We also show that with a scale invariant
matter content (radiation i.e $P=\frac{1}{3}\rho$), the quantized BD theory
does reduce to GR as $\omega\rightarrow\infty$, which is in sharp contrast to
classical behavior. This is a first known illustration of a scenario, where
quantized BD theory provides example of anomalous symmetry breaking and
resulting binary phase structure. We make a conjecture regarding strong
coupling limit of BD theory in generic scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08249</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lisandrini</keyname><forenames>Franco T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lobos</keyname><forenames>Alejandro M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobry</keyname><forenames>Ariel O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gazza</keyname><forenames>Claudio J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological quantum phase transition in strongly correlated Kondo
  insulators in 1D</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Papers in Physics 8, 080005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.4279/PIP.080005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate, by means of a field-theory analysis combined with the
density-matrix renormalization group (DMRG) method, a theoretical model for a
strongly correlated quantum system in one dimension realizing a
topologically-ordered Haldane phase ground state. The model consists of a
spin-1/2 Heisenberg chain coupled to a tight-binding chain via two competing
Kondo exchange couplings of different type: a &quot;s-wave&quot; Kondo coupling
($J^s_{K}$), and a less common &quot;p-wave&quot; ($J^p_{K}$) Kondo coupling. While the
first coupling is the standard Kondo interaction studied in many
condensed-matter systems, the latter has been recently introduced by Alexandrov
and Coleman [Phys. Rev. B 90, 115147 (2014)] as a possible mechanism leading to
a topological Kondo-insulating ground state in one dimension. As a result of
this competition, a topological quantum phase transition (TQPT) occurs in the
system for a critical value of the ratio $J^s_{K}/J^p_{K}$, separating a
(Haldane-type) topological phase from a topologically trivial ground state
where the system can be essentially described as a product of local singlets.
We study and characterize the TQPT by means for the magnetization profile, the
entanglement entropy and the full entanglement spectrum of the ground state.
Our results might be relevant to understand how topologically-ordered phases of
fermions emerge in strongly interacting quantum systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02363</id><created>2016-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>D. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guissart</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ormaza</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bachellier</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bengone</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limot</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kondo resonance of a Co atom exchange coupled to a ferromagnetic tip</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 16, 6298 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b02617</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kondo effect of a Co atom on Cu(100) was investigated with a
low-temperature scanning tunneling microscope using a monoatomically sharp
nickel tip. Upon a tip-Co contact, the differential conductance spectra exhibit
a spin-split asymmetric Kondo resonance. The computed ab initio value of the
exchange coupling is too small to suppress the Kondo effect, but sufficiently
large to produce the splitting observed. A quantitative analysis of the line
shape using the numerical renormalization group technique indicates that the
junction spin polarization is weak.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04476</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Glinka</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on 'Unraveling Photoinduced Spin Dynamics in the Topological
  Insulator Bi2Se3'</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 169701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.169701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Comment on a recent paper published in Physical Review Letters by M. C. Wang,
S. Qiao, Z. Jiang, S. N. Luo, and J. Qi [Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 036601 (2016),
arXiv:1511.02994v2].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09139</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babyak</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>T. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>All-optical spin switching: A new frontier in femtomagnetism -- A short
  review and a simple theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Invited short review article, 33 pages. Another related paper on AOS
  can be found arXiv:1609.05855 Add a new reference and also revised a few
  sentences in the paper</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters B Vol. 30, No. 21 (2016) 1630005 (33 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217984916300052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using an ultrafast laser pulse to manipulate the spin degree of freedom has
broad technological appeal. It allows one to control the spin dynamics on a
femtosecond time scale. The discipline, commonly called femtomagnetism, started
with the pioneering experiment by Beaurepaire and coworkers in 1996, who showed
subpicosecond demagnetization occurs in magnetic Ni thin films. This finding
has motivated extensive research worldwide. All-optical helicity-dependent spin
switching (AOS) represents a new frontier in femtomagnetism, where a single
ultrafast laser pulse can permanently switch spin without any assistance from a
magnetic field. This review summarizes some of the crucial aspects of this new
discipline: key experimental findings, leading mechanisms, controversial
issues, and possible future directions. The emphasis is on our latest
investigation. We first develop the all-optical spin switching rule that
determines how the switchability depends on the light helicity. This rule
allows one to understand microscopically how the spin is reversed and why the
circularly polarized light appears more powerful than the linearly polarized
light. Then we invoke our latest spin-orbit coupled harmonic oscillator model
to simulate single spin reversal. We consider both cw excitation and pulsed
laser excitation. The results are in a good agreement with the experimental
result. We then extend the code to include the exchange interaction among
different spin sites. We show where the &quot;inverse Faraday field&quot; comes from and
how the laser affects the spin reversal nonlinearly. Our hope is that this
review will motivate new experimental and theoretical investigations and
discussions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00612</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Samyobrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopal</keyname><forenames>A V</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>S Dutta</forenames></author></authors><title>Transverse spin with coupled plasmons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study theoretically the transverse spin associated with the eigenmodes of
a thin metal film embedded in a dielectric. We show that the transverse spin
has a direct dependence on the nature and strength of the coupling leading to
two distinct branches for the long- and short- range modes. We show that the
short-range mode exhibits larger extraordinary spin because of its more
'structured' nature due to higher decay in propagation. In contrast to some of
the earlier studies, calculations are performed retaining the full lossy
character of the metal. In the limit of vanishing losses we present analytical
results for the extraordinary spin for both the coupled modes. The results can
have direct implications for enhancing the elusive transverse spin exploiting
the coupled plasmon structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01055</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2016-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>C. de la Fuente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>R. de la Fuente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mialle</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Homing in for New Year: impact parameters and pre-impact orbital
  evolution of meteoroid 2014 AA</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>41 pages, 26 figures, 11 tables, abstract abridged and resolution of
  some figures reduced due to size limitations, revised to match version
  published in Astrophysics and Space Science</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and Space Science, vol. 361, p. 358 (33 pp.).
  November 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2945-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On 2008 October 7, small asteroid 2008 TC3 turned itself into the parent body
of the first meteor ever to be predicted before entering the Earth's
atmosphere. Over five years later, the 2014 AA event became the second instance
of such an occurrence. The uncertainties associated with the pre-impact orbit
of 2008 TC3 are relatively small because thousands of observations were made
during the hours preceding the actual meteor airburst. In sharp contrast, 2014
AA was only observed seven times before impact and consequently its trajectory
is somewhat uncertain. Here, we present a recalculation of the impact
parameters -location and timing- of this meteor based on infrasound recordings.
The new values and their uncertainties together with Monte Carlo and N-body
techniques, are applied to obtain an independent determination of the
pre-impact orbit of 2014 AA. Our orbital solution is used to investigate the
possible presence of known near-Earth objects (NEOs) moving in similar orbits.
Prior to impact, 2014 AA was subjected to a web of overlapping secular
resonances and it followed a path similar to those of 2011 GJ3, 2011 JV10, 2012
DJ54, and 2013 NJ4. NEOs in this transient group have their orbits controlled
by close encounters with the Earth-Moon system at perihelion and Mars at
aphelion, perhaps constituting a dynamical family. Extensive comparison with
other studies is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02959</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bartling</keyname><forenames>S&#xf6;nke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kachelrie&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray tomographic intervention guidance: Towards real-time 4D imaging</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Implementation of real-time, continuous, and three-dimensional imaging (4D
intervention guidance) would be a quantum leap for minimally-invasive medicine.
It allows guidance during interventions by assessing the spatial position of
instruments continuously in respect to their surroundings. Recent research
showed that it is feasible using X-ray and novel tomographic reconstruction
approaches. Radiation dose stays within reasonable limits. This article
provides abstractions and background information together with an outlook on
these prospects. There are explanations of how situational awareness during
interventions is generated today and how they will be in future. The
differences between fluoroscopically and CT-guided interventions are eluted to
within the context of these developments. The exploration of uncharted terrain
between these current methods is worth pursuing. Necessary image quality of 4D
intervention guidance varies relevantly from that of standard computed
tomography. Means to analyze the risk-benefit ratio of 4D intervention guidance
are provided and arguments for gantry-based setups vs C-arm based setups are
given. Due to the lack of moving organs, neuro-interventions might be the first
field in which 4D intervention guidance might become available, however,
registration and fusion algorithms might make it applicable in complex
whole-body interventions such as aortic valve replacement soon thereafter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03507</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gottesman</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum fault tolerance in small experiments</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages including supplementary material. v2 has footnotes and some
  typos fixed, extra references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I discuss a variety of issues relating to near-future experiments
demonstrating fault-tolerant quantum computation. I describe a family of
fault-tolerant quantum circuits that can be performed with 5 qubits arranged on
a ring with nearest-neighbor interactions. I also present a criterion whereby
we can say that an experiment has succeeded in demonstrating fault tolerance.
Finally, I discuss the possibility of using future fault-tolerant experiments
to answer important questions about the interaction of fault-tolerant protocols
with real experimental errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03672</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2016-10-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tinivella</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>A review of Cosmic-ray electrons and fermi-LAT</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>207 pages This work is an adaptation of my PhD thesis &quot;Preliminary
  study on the Cosmic-Ray Electron spectrum measurement using a new event-level
  analysis of Fermi-LAT&quot;, defended on 1, December 2014</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The study of Galactic Cosmic-ray electrons (CREs) saw important developments
in recent years, with the assumption of positron production only in interaction
of hadronic Cosmic-rays with interstellar matter challenged by new measurements
of CRE spectrum and related quantities. Indeed, all recent experiments seem to
confirm an hardening in the positrons, a feature that is totally in contrast
with the all-secondaries hypothesis, even if significant disagreements are
present about the CRE spectral behavior and the possible presence of spectral
features. Together with insufficient precision of current measurements, these
disagreements prevent the identification of the primary positron source, with
models involving Dark matter or astrophysical sources like Super Nova Remnants
and Pulsar Wind Nebula all able to explain current data.
  The fermi-LAT contribution to the CRE study was fundamental, with the 2009
measurement of the positron + electron spectrum extended to the 7 MeV - 1TeV
range with a statistics already exceeding previous results by many order of
magnitude; since then, the last statistic has largely increased, while the LAT
event reconstruction was significantly improved.
  In this article the reader will find an extensive and historical review of
the CRE science, a summary of the history of gamma astronomy before fermi, an
accurate description of the LAT and of its data analysis, a review of the
present knowledge about CRE spectrum and on the theories that try to explain
it, and finally a description of the changes and improvements introduced in the
LAT event reconstruction process at the beginning of 2015.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03780</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kluska</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>R. Garcia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benisty</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The innermost astronomical unit of protoplanetary disks</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>SPIE Astronomical Telescopes + Instrumentation 2016 in Edinburgh,
  Scotland, 8 pages, 2 figures</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2234439</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Circumstellar disks around young stars are the birthsites of planets. It is
thus fundamental to study the disks in which they form, their structure and the
physical conditions therein. The first astronomical unit is of great interest
because this is where the terrestrial-planets form and the angular momentum is
controled via massloss through winds/jets. With its milli-arcsecond resolution,
optical interferometry is the only technic able to spatially resolve the first
few astronomical units of the disk. In this review, we will present a broad
overview of studies of young stellar objects with interferometry, and discuss
prospects for the future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03974</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abens</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katkov</keyname><forenames>V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osipov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Isotopic Effect of Tunneling States in NbTi-H/D</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>PhysRevB.82.174204 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.82.174204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermal conductivity, heat capacity and heat release of NbTi, NbTi-H and
NbTi-D were measured at low temperatures. All three systems reveal low
temperature anomalies typical for structural glasses. It is shown that above a
concentration of 2\% H or D the tunneling states of the NbTi matrix disappear.
Therefore, for higher concentration it is a good system to proof how the change
of the mass of tunneling atoms influences the low temperature anomalies. For
the heat capacity we found the expected isotopic effect. However, the anomalous
isotopic effect observed for the heat release data cannot be explained within
the standard tunneling model. A surprising result is that tunneling systems
with very high barrier heights, even the systems with the maximum barrier
height, influence remarkable the heat capacity and the heat release data at low
temperatures. As a possible origin, we consider large-scale fluctuations in
thermal expansion which could generate anomalous two-level systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04225</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Tapas</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical approximate bound state solution of Schr\&quot;odinger equation in
  $D$-dimensions with a new mixed class of potential for arbitrary $\ell$-state
  via asymptotic iteration method</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 Pages, 57 References, No figure and table, Chinese Journal of
  Physics (2016)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cjph.2016.10.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The bound state solutions of the $D$-dimensional Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation for
new mixed class of potential, $V(r)=\frac{V_1}{r^2}+\frac{V_2e^{-\alpha
r}}{r}+V_3coth\alpha r+V_4\,,$ are studied within the framework of the Pekeris
approximation for any arbitrary $\ell$-state. Asymptotic iteration method (AIM)
is used for the work. The energy spectrum are obtained as well as their
corresponding normalized eigenfunctions are derived in terms of generalized
hypergeometric functions $\,_{2}F_{1}(a,b,c;z)$. It is shown that using the
Pekeris approximation, present potential model is very much capable of deriving
other well known potentials quite easily and corresponding solutions are in
excellent agreement with the previous work carried out in literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04241</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yachini</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bahabad</keyname><forenames>Alon</forenames></author></authors><title>Envelope time reversal of optical pulses following frequency conversion
  with accelerating quasi-phase-matching</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>ACS Photonics, in press</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown theoretically that the use of accelerating spatiotemporal
quasi-phase-matching (QPM) modulation patterns in media with parametric optical
interactions makes it possible to generate a time-reversed replica of the pump
pulse envelope in a frequency converted signal. The conversion is dependent on
the group-velocity mismatch between the fundamental and up-converted harmonics,
and controlled by the acceleration rate (chirp) of the QPM phase pattern.
Analytical results are corroborated by numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04254</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lan</keyname><forenames>Ganhui</forenames></author></authors><title>Overcrowding drives the unjamming transition of gap-free monolayers</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.CB</categories><comments>29 pages, 7 figures, submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Collective cell motility plays central roles in various biological phenomena
such as inflammatory response, wound healing, cancer metastasis and
embryogenesis. These are biological demonstrations of the unjamming transition.
However, contradictory to the typical density-driven jamming processes in
particulate assemblies, cellular systems often get unjammed in highly packed,
sometimes overcrowding tissue environments. In this work, we report that
overcrowding can unjam gap-free monolayers through increasing isotropic
compression. The transition boundary is determined by the isotropic compression
and the cell-cell adhesion. We explicitly construct the free energy landscape
for the T1 topological transition during monolayer rearrangement, and find that
it evolves from single-barrier shape to double-barrier shape upon completion of
the unjamming process. Our analyses reveal that the overcrowding and adhesion
induced unjamming transition reflects the mechanical yielding of the highly
deformable monolayer, which differs from those caused by loosing up a packed
particulate assembly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04262</id><created>2016-09-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciccariello</keyname><forenames>Salvino</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering intensity limit value at very small angles</title><categories>physics.class-ph physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of the limit of a sample scattering intensity, as the
scattering vector approaches zero, requires and is ensured by the property that
the mean value of the scattering density fluctuation over volume $V$
asymptotically behaves, at large $V$s, as $\nu V^{-1/2}$, $\nu$ being an
appropriate constant. Then, the limit of the normalized scattering intensity is
equal to $\nu^2$. The implications of this result are also analyzed in the case
of samples made up of two homogeneous phases.16 pages, 3 figures
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04274</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Weiyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hierarchical Clustering Given Confidence Intervals of Metric Distances</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper considers metric spaces where distances between a pair of nodes
are represented by distance intervals. The goal is to study methods for the
determination of hierarchical clusters, i.e., a family of nested partitions
indexed by a resolution parameter, induced from the given distance intervals of
the metric spaces. Our construction of hierarchical clustering methods is based
on defining admissible methods to be those methods that abide to the axioms of
value - nodes in a metric space with two nodes are clustered together at the
convex combination of the distance bounds between them - and transformation -
when both distance bounds are reduced, the output may become more clustered but
not less. Two admissible methods are constructed and are shown to provide
universal upper and lower bounds in the space of admissible methods. Practical
implications are explored by clustering moving points via snapshots and by
clustering networks representing brain structural connectivity using the lower
and upper bounds of the network distance. The proposed clustering methods
succeed in identifying underlying clustering structures via the maximum and
minimum distances in all snapshots, as well as in differentiating brain
connectivity networks of patients from those of healthy controls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04321</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Spencer R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayakumar</keyname><forenames>Anupriya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blinov</keyname><forenames>Boris B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortson</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Upper Bound on the Strongly Forbidden $6S_{1/2} \leftrightarrow
  5D_{3/2}$ Magnetic Dipole Transition Moment in {Ba}$^{+}$</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results from our first-generation experiment to measure the
magnetic-dipole transition moment (M1) between the $6S_{1/2}$ and $5D_{3/2}$
manifolds in Ba$^{+}$. Knowledge of M1 is crucial for the proposed
parity-nonconservation experiment in the ion \cite{Fortson93}, where M1 will be
a leading source of systematic error. To date, no measurement of M1 has been
made in Ba$^{+}$, and moreover, the sensitivity of the moment to
electron-electron correlations has confounded accurate theoretical predictions.
A precise measurement may help to resolve the theoretical discrepancies while
providing essential information for planning a future PNC measurement in
Ba$^{+}$. We demonstrate our technique for measuring M1 - including a method
for calibrating for stress-induced birefringence introduced by the scientific
apparatus - and place an upper bound of $\mathrm{M1} &lt; 93 \pm 39 \times 10^{-5}
\mu_{B}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04324</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Yen-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odom</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames></author></authors><title>High extinction amplitude modulation in ultrashort pulse shaping</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explored the issues related to the resolution and the modulation
extinction when filtering the spectrum of a UV femtosecond laser with a
standard ultrashort pulse shaper. We have learned that a higher pulse shaping
resolution often requires a larger working beam size or a higher density
grating for greater dispersion. However, these approaches also introduce more
optical errors and degrade the extinction. In this work, we examined specifics
of each component to determine the best configuration of our spectral filtering
setup. As a proof-of-concept demonstration, we utilized elements available as
standard products and achieved 100 GHz filtering resolution with high
extinction at the UV-A wavelength, which is superb in this wavelength range.
The high extinction spectral filtering is especially important while modifying
a broadband laser for the optical control of molecule's internal state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04327</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Berman</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;nnheim</keyname><forenames>Magnus</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of chaos for a class of first order models with singular
  mean field interactions</title><categories>math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>This paper supersedes and generalizes Section 4 in the first and
  second versions of arXiv:1501.07820</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical systems of N particles in \R^{D} interacting by a singular pair
potential of mean field type are considered. The systems are assumed to be of
gradient type and the existence of a macroscopic limit in the many particle
limit is established for a large class of singular interaction potentials in
the stochastic as well as the deterministic settings. The main assumption on
the potentials is an appropriate notion of quasi-convexity. When D=1 the
convergence result is sharp when applied to strongly singular repulsive
interactions and for a general dimension D the result applies to attractive
interactions with Lipschitz singular interaction potentials, leading to
stochastic particle solutions to the corresponding macroscopic aggregation
equations. The proof uses the theory of gradient flows in Wasserstein spaces of
Ambrosio-Gigli-Savaree.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04332</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kudlis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropy of a Cubic Ferromagnet at Criticality</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 tables, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 042107 (8 pages), 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.042107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Critical fluctuations change the effective anisotropy of cubic ferromagnet
near the Curie point. If the crystal undergoes phase transition into
orthorhombic phase and the initial anisotropy is not too strong, reduced
anisotropy of nonlinear susceptibility acquires at $T_c$ the universal value
$\delta_4^* = {{2v^*} \over {3(u^* + v^*)}}$ where $u^*$ and $v^*$ --
coordinates of the cubic fixed point on the flow diagram of renormalization
group equations. In the paper, the critical value of the reduced anisotropy is
estimated within the pseudo-$\epsilon$ expansion approach. The six-loop
pseudo-$\epsilon$ expansions for $u^*$, $v^*$, and $\delta_4^*$ are derived for
the arbitrary spin dimensionality $n$. For cubic crystals ($n = 3$)
higher-order coefficients of the pseudo-$\epsilon$ expansions obtained turn out
to be so small that use of simple Pad\'e approximants yields reliable numerical
results. Pad\'e resummation of the pseudo-$\epsilon$ series for $u^*$, $v^*$,
and $\delta_4^*$ leads to the estimate $\delta_4^* = 0.079 \pm 0.006$
indicating that detection of the anisotropic critical behavior of cubic
ferromagnets in physical and computer experiments is certainly possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04333</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sakaguchi</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Masashige</forenames></author></authors><title>Edge Magnon Excitation in Spin Dimer Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 104707 (2016) [15 Pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.104707</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic excitation in a spin dimer system on a bilayer honeycomb lattice is
investigated in the presence of a zigzag edge, where disordered and ordered
phases can be controlled by a quantum phase transition. In analogy with the
case of graphene with a zigzag edge, a flat edge magnon mode appears in the
disordered phase. In an ordered phase, a finite magnetic moment generates a
mean-field potential to the magnon. Since the potential is nonuniform on the
edge and bulk sites, it affects the excitation, and the dispersion of the edge
mode deviates from the flat shape. We investigate how the edge magnon mode
evolves when the phase changes through the quantum phase transition and discuss
the similarities to ordered spin systems on a monolayer honeycomb lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04335</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Baile</forenames></author></authors><title>Invisibility Dips of Near-Field Energy Transport in a Spoof Plasmonic
  Metadimer</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures in Advanced Functional Materials 2016</comments><doi>10.1002/adfm.201602233</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Invisibility dips, minima in scattering spectrum associated with asymmetric
Fano-like line-shapes, have been predicted with transformation optics in
studying strong coupling between two plasmonic nanoparticles. This feature of
strongly coupled plasmonic nanoparticles holds promise for sensor cloaking. It
requires an extremely narrow gap between the two nanoparticles, though,
preventing its experimental observation at optical frequencies. Here, the
concept of spoof surface plasmons is utilized to facilitate the strong coupling
between two spoof-localized-surface-plasmon (SLSP) resonators. Instead of
observing in far field, the near-field energy transport is probed through the
two SLSP resonators. By virtue of enhanced coupling between the two resonators
stacked vertically, a spectral transmission dip with asymmetric Fano-like
line-shape, similar to the far-field invisibility dips predicted by
transformation optics, is observed. The underlying mode interference mechanism
is further demonstrated by directly imaging the field maps of interfered waves
that are tightly localized around the resonators. These near-field invisibility
dips may find use in near-field sensing, on-chip switching, filters and logical
operation elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04337</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Saade</keyname><forenames>Alaa</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral Inference Methods on Sparse Graphs: Theory and Applications</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cs.IT cs.LG math.IT</categories><comments>PhD dissertation</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In an era of unprecedented deluge of (mostly unstructured) data, graphs are
proving more and more useful, across the sciences, as a flexible abstraction to
capture complex relationships between complex objects. One of the main
challenges arising in the study of such networks is the inference of
macroscopic, large-scale properties affecting a large number of objects, based
solely on the microscopic interactions between their elementary constituents.
Statistical physics, precisely created to recover the macroscopic laws of
thermodynamics from an idealized model of interacting particles, provides
significant insight to tackle such complex networks.
  In this dissertation, we use methods derived from the statistical physics of
disordered systems to design and study new algorithms for inference on graphs.
Our focus is on spectral methods, based on certain eigenvectors of carefully
chosen matrices, and sparse graphs, containing only a small amount of
information. We develop an original theory of spectral inference based on a
relaxation of various mean-field free energy optimizations. Our approach is
therefore fully probabilistic, and contrasts with more traditional motivations
based on the optimization of a cost function. We illustrate the efficiency of
our approach on various problems, including community detection, randomized
similarity-based clustering, and matrix completion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04338</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Suss</keyname><forenames>Matthew E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conforti</keyname><forenames>Kameron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilson</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buie</keyname><forenames>Cullen R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazant</keyname><forenames>Martin Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Membraneless flow battery leveraging flow-through heterogeneous porous
  media for improved power density and reduced crossover</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A key factor preventing the market penetration of renewable, intermittent
energy sources, such as solar, wind and wave, is the lack of cost-effective
energy storage options to counteract intermittency. Here, we propose and
demonstrate a novel flow battery architecture that replaces traditional
ion-exchange membranes with less expensive heterogeneous flow-through porous
media. We present an experimentally-validated model which demonstrates that our
architecture promises reduced crossover of reactive species compared to typical
membraneless systems employing co-laminar flows in open channels. In addition,
our prototype battery exhibits significantly improved power density (0.925
W/cm2) and maximum current density (3 A/cm2) compared to previous membraneless
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04348</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Xiangang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shining</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthetic Weyl points in generalized parameter space and their
  topological properties</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weyl fermions1 do not appear in nature as elementary particles, but they are
now found to exist as nodal points in the band structure of electronic and
classical wave crystals. Novel phenomena such as Fermi arcs and chiral anomaly
have fueled the interest of these topological points which are frequently
perceived as monopoles in momentum space. Here, we demonstrate that generalized
Weyl points can exist in a parameter space and we report the first observation
of such nodal points in one-dimensional photonic crystals in the optical range.
The reflection phase inside the band gap of a truncated photonic crystal
exhibits vortexes in the parameter space where the Weyl points are defined and
they share the same topological charges as the Weyl points. These vortexes
guarantee the existence of interface states, the trajectory of which can be
understood as &quot;Fermi arcs&quot; emerging from the Weyl nodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04351</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hisano</keyname><forenames>Ryohei</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-supervised Graph Embedding Approach to Dynamic Link Prediction</title><categories>stat.ML cs.LG cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple discrete time semi-supervised graph embedding approach to
link prediction in dynamic networks. The learned embedding reflects information
from both the temporal and cross-sectional network structures, which is
performed by defining the loss function as a weighted sum of the supervised
loss from past dynamics and the unsupervised loss of predicting the
neighborhood context in the current network. Our model is also capable of
learning different embeddings for both formation and dissolution dynamics.
These key aspects contributes to the predictive performance of our model and we
provide experiments with three real--world dynamic networks showing that our
method is comparable to state of the art methods in link formation prediction
and outperforms state of the art baseline methods in link dissolution
prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04352</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04352</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ditr&#xf3;i</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xe1;rk&#xe1;nyi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tak&#xe1;cs</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hermanne</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Activation cross sections of proton induced nuclear reactions on gold up
  to 65 MeV</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Applied Radiation and Isotopes 113(2016)96</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.apradiso.2016.04.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Activation cross sections of proton induced reactions on gold for production
of $^{197m,197g,195m,195g, 193m,193g,192}$Hg,
$^{196m,196g(cum),195g(cum),194,191(cum)}$Au, $^{191(cum)}$Pt and $^{192}$Ir
were measured up to 65 MeV proton energy, some of them for the first time. The
new data are in acceptably good agreement with the recently published earlier
experimental data in the overlapping energy region. The experimental data are
compared with the predictions of the TALYS 1.6 (results in TENDL-2015 on-line
library) and EMPIRE 3.2 code.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04359</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hee Jung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Sang-Kyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Hee Su</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental demonstration of high-dimensional photonic spatial
  entanglement between multi-core optical fibers</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fiber transport of multi-dimensional photonic qudits promises high
information capacity per photon without space restriction. This work
experimentally demonstrates transmission of spatial qudits through multi-core
optical fibers and measurement of the entanglement between two fibers with
quantum state analyzers, each composed of a spatial light modulator and a
single-mode fiber. Quantum state tomography reconstructs the four-dimension
entangled state that verifies the non-locality through concurrences in
two-dimensional subspaces and a high-dimensional Bell-type CGLMP inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04361</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yamasaki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tachibana</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higashino</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshimi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakagawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakatani</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamagami</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aratani</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirilmaz</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sing</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claessen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirakawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunoki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naitoh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takase</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuno</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takagi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiyama</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saitoh</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional electronic structures and the metal-insulator
  transition in Ruddlesden-Popper iridates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 115103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, we systematically investigate 3D momentum($\hbar k$)-resolved
electronic structures of Ruddlesden-Popper-type iridium oxides
Sr$_{n+1}$Ir$_n$O$_{3n+1}$ using soft-x-ray (SX) angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy (ARPES). Our results provide direct evidence of an
insulator-to-metal transition that occurs upon increasing the dimensionality of
the IrO$_2$-plane structure. This transition occurs when the spin-orbit-coupled
$j_{\rm eff}$=1/2 band changes its behavior in the dispersion relation and
moves across the Fermi energy. In addition, an emerging band along the
$\Gamma$(0,0,0)-R($\pi$,$\pi$,$\pi$) direction is found to play a crucial role
in the metallic characteristics of SrIrO$_3$. By scanning the photon energy
over 350 eV, we reveal the 3D Fermi surface in SrIrO$_3$ and $k_z$-dependent
oscillations of photoelectron intensity in Sr$_3$Ir$_2$O$_7$. In contrast to
previously reported results obtained using low-energy photons, folded bands
derived from lattice distortions and/or magnetic ordering make significantly
weak (but finite) contributions to the $k$-resolved photoemission spectrum. At
the first glance, this leads to the ambiguous result that the observed
$k$-space topology is consistent with the unfolded Brillouin zone (BZ) picture
derived from a non-realistic simple square or cubic Ir lattice. Through careful
analysis, we determine that a superposition of the folded and unfolded band
structures has been observed in the ARPES spectra obtained using photons in
both ultraviolet and SX regions. To corroborate the physics deduced using
low-energy ARPES studies, we propose to utilize SX-ARPES as a powerful
complementary technique, as this method surveys more than one whole BZ and
provides a panoramic view of electronic structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04379</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Grigorescu</keyname><forenames>Sabina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baerhausen</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Jeong Eun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hahn</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Tungsten doping of Ta3N5-Nanotubes for Band Gap Narrowing and Enhanced
  Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting Efficiency</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochemistry Communications, Volume 51, February 2015, Pages
  85 to 88</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elecom.2014.12.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ordered W-doped Ta2O5 nanotube arrays were grown by self-organizing
electrochemical anodization of TaW alloys with different tungsten
concentrations and by a suitable high temperature ammonia treatment, fully
converted to W:Ta3N5 tubular structures. A main effect found is that W doping
can decrease the band gap from 2 eV (bare Ta3N5) down to 1.75 eV. Ta3N5
nanotubes grown on 0.5 at% W alloy and modified with (CoOH)x as co-catalyst
show ~33% higher photocurrents in photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting
than pure Ta3N5.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04389</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kozhuharov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raggi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valente</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Projects on Dark Photon Search</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, Invited talk at Vulcano 2016 workshop &quot;Frontier
  Objects in Astrophysics and Particle Physics&quot;, to appear in Frascati Physics
  Series Vol. 64 (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the great success of the Standard Model of particle physics the
nature of Dark Matter still remains unclear. Recently, the idea of the
existence of a hidden sector coupling only weakly with the ordinary matter was
revitalized and gained popularity. A simple mediator between the hidden and the
visible sector could be a vector particle of a new gauge interaction, the so
called dark photon. Numerous of activities were initiated to probe its
parameter space. The present results and the foreseen experiments aimed to
search for dark photons in few directions are reviewed and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04404</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Morin</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desreumaux</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caussin</keyname><forenames>Jean-Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartolo</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author></authors><title>Distortion and destruction of colloidal flocks in disordered
  environments</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Final version published in Nature Physics</comments><doi>10.1038/nphys3903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How do flocks, herds and swarms proceed through disordered environments? This
question is not only crucial to animal groups in the wild, but also to
virtually all applications of collective robotics, and active materials
composed of synthetic motile units. In stark contrast, appart from very rare
exceptions, our physical understanding of flocking has been hitherto limited to
homogeneous media. Here we explain how collective motion survives to
geometrical disorder. To do so, we combine experiments on motile colloids
cruising through random microfabricated obstacles, and analytical theory. We
explain how disorder and bending elasticity compete to channel the flow of
polar flocks along sparse river networks akin those found beyond plastic
depinning in driven condensed matter. Further increasing disorder, we
demonstrate that collective motion is suppressed in the form of a first-order
phase transition generic to all polar active materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04427</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steffen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caffau</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonifacio</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludwig</keyname><forenames>H. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freytag</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced methods for computing spectra from CO5BOLD models using
  Linfor3D. Molecular bands in metal-poor stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>To be published as a proceeding of the 2016 CO5BOLD workshop in
  Memorie della SAIt Supplementi. 8 pages. 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular features such as the G-band, CN-band and NH-band are important
diagnostics for measuring a star's carbon and nitrogen abundances, especially
in metal-poor stars where atomic lines are no longer visible in stellar
spectra. Unlike atomic transitions, molecular features tend to form in bands,
which cover large wavelength regions in a spectrum. While it is a trivial
matter to compute carbon and nitrogen molecular bands under the assumption of
1D, it is extremely time consuming in 3D. In this contribution to the 2016
CO5BOLD workshop we review the improvements made to the 3D spectral synthesis
code Linfor3D, and discuss the new challenges found when computing molecular
features in 3D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04432</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grauer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized description of intermittency in turbulence via stochastic
  methods</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures, submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a generalized picture of intermittency in turbulence that is based
on the theory of stochastic processes. To this end, we rely on the
experimentally and numerically verified finding by R.~Friedrich and J.~Peinke
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 78, 863 (1997)] that allows for an interpretation of the
turbulent energy cascade as a Markov process of the velocity increments in
scale. It is explicitly shown that all known phenomenological models of
turbulence can be reproduced by the Kramers-Moyal expansion of the velocity
increment probability density function that is associated to a Markov process.
We compare the different sets of Kramers-Moyal coefficients of each
phenomenology and deduce that an accurate description of intermittency should
take into account an infinite number of coefficients. This is demonstrated in
more detail for the case of Burgers turbulence that exhibits the strongest
intermittency effects. Moreover, the influence of nonlocality on the
Kramers-Moyal coefficients is investigated by direct numerical simulations of a
generalized Burgers equation. Depending on the balance between nonlinearity and
nonlocality, we encounter different intermittency behaviour that ranges from
self-similarity (purely nonlocal case) to intermittent behaviour (intermediate
case that agrees with Yakhot's mean field theory [Phys. Rev. E 63 026307
(2001)]) to shock-like behaviour (purely nonlinear Burgers case).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04435</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolognesi</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental status of neutrino scattering</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings of NuFact2015</comments><report-no>C15-08-10.2</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After highlighting the importance of neutrino cross section modeling for
neutrino oscillation measurements, the most recent neutrino cross section
measurements are presented. New preliminary results are available from T2K for
the measurement of charged current interactions on carbon without pions in the
final state, single pion production in water, coherent pion production in
carbon and charged current inclusive interactions in carbon as a function of
neutrino energy. Few other results already published by the MINERvA and T2K
collaborations are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04436</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Mai</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquetand</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Leticia</forenames></author></authors><title>The DNA Nucleobase Thymine in Motion - Intersystem Crossing Simulated
  with Surface Hopping</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.10.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report ab initio excited-state dynamics simulations on isolated thymine to
investigate the mechanism of intersystem crossing, based on CASSCF potential
energy surfaces and the \textsc{Sharc} surface hopping method. We show that
even though $S_2 \rightarrow S_1$ internal conversion is not described
accurately with CASSCF, intersystem crossing can be correctly simulated.
Intersystem crossing in thymine occurs from the $S_1$ ($^1n\pi^*$) minimum, via
a nearby crossing with $T_2$ ($^3\pi\pi^*$). The system further relaxes via
ultrafast internal conversion in the triplet manifold to the $T_1$
($^3\pi\pi^*$) state. The simulations reveal that, once the system is trapped
in the $^1n\pi^*$ minimum, intersystem crossing might proceed with a time
constant of 1~ps. Furthermore, the change of the system's electronic state is
accompanied respectively by elongation/shortening of specific bonds, which
could thus be used as indicators to identify which state is populated in the
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04437</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Nhat Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altomare</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>JeongEun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient Photocatalytic H2 Evolution: Controlled Dewetting-Dealloying
  to Fabricate Site-Selective High-activity Nanoporous Au Particles on Highly
  Ordered TiO2 Nanotube Arrays</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Advanced Materials, Volume 27, Issue 20, May 27, 2015, Pages 3208
  to 3215</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adma.201500742</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Overlaid self-ordering processes: we form anodic self-organized TiO2
nanostumps and exploit them for self-ordering dewetting of Au-Ag sputtered
films. This forms ordered particle configurations at tube top (crown position)
or bottom (ground position). By dealloying we then form, from minimal amount of
noble metal, porous Au nanoparticles that when in crown position allow for a
drastically improved photocatalytic H2 production compared with nanoparticles
produced by conventional dewetting processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04444</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Jel&#xed;nek</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro-Tirado</keyname><forenames>Alberto J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunniffe</keyname><forenames>Ronan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorosabel</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>V&#xed;tek</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kub&#xe1;nek</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postigo</keyname><forenames>Antonio de Ugarte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guziy</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tello</keyname><forenames>Juan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe1;ta</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>Rub&#xe9;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oates</keyname><forenames>Samantha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>Soomin</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;trobl</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo-Carri&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Sebasti&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanguino</keyname><forenames>Tom&#xe1;s Mateo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabaza</keyname><forenames>Ovidio</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>Dolores</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretero</keyname><forenames>Benito A. de la Morena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudec</keyname><forenames>Ren&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reglero</keyname><forenames>V&#xed;ctor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabau-Graziati</keyname><forenames>Lola</forenames></author></authors><title>A decade of GRB follow-up by BOOTES in Spain (2003-2013)</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><journal-ref>Advances in Astronomy, Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID 1928465</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/1928465</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article covers ten years of GRB follow-ups by the Spanish BOOTES
stations: 71 follow-ups providing 23 detections. Follow-ups by BOOTES-1B from
2005 to 2008 were given in the previous article, and are here reviewed,
updated, and include additional detection data points as the former article
merely stated their existence. The all-sky cameras CASSANDRA have not yet
detected any GRB optical afterglows, but limits are reported where available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04447</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gracey</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>beta-functions in higher dimensional field theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, proceedings of Loops and Legs 2016</comments><report-no>LTH 1105</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review recent activity in the construction of the renormalization group
functions for O(N) scalar and gauge theories in six and higher dimensions. The
theories lie in their respective universality classes at the Wilson-Fisher
fixed point. The critical exponents at this fixed point in the various
dimensions are all in agreement with the known exponents determined in the
large Nexpansion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04456</id><created>2016-09-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of a Kaluza-Klein type Theory from One Dimension</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>51 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe how a physical theory incorporating the properties of fields
deriving from extra-dimensional structures over a four-dimensional spacetime
manifold can in principle be obtained through the analysis of a simple initial
structure consisting of the one dimension of time alone, as represented by the
real line. The simplicity of this starting point leads to symmetries of
multi-dimensional forms of time, from which a geometrical structure can be
derived which is similar to the framework employed in non-Abelian Kaluza-Klein
theories. This leads to a relationship between the external and internal
curvature on the spacetime manifold unified through the underlying constraint
of the one dimension of time for the theory presented here. We also describe
how the symmetry breaking structure is compatible with the Coleman-Mandula
theorem for the subsequent quantisation of the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04457</id><created>2016-09-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Sadun</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>What's wrong with the Platonic ideal of space and time?</title><categories>physics.pop-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>82C03, 8206</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a chapter for an upcoming book, &quot;Space, Time, and the Limits of Human
Understanding&quot;, edited by Shyam Wuppuluri and Giancarlo Ghirardi. I first
present the classical picture of flat space and ever-flowing time, as generally
accepted until about 1900, discuss the challenges posed by modern physics and
the adjustments required by special relativity, general relativity and quantum
mechanics, and finally consider (and reject) a recent hypothesis that
space-time is essentially discrete. Ultimately, none of the simple answers to
&quot;what is space-time?&quot; stand up to reality. We have more work ahead of us!
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04464</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xfc;tz</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnea</keyname><forenames>Tomer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gisin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental weak measurement of two non-commuting observables</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fact that not all quantum observables are jointly measurable is one of
the major differences between quantum and classical theory. In the former,
non-commuting observables can only be simultaneously measured with limited
precision. We report on an experimental implementation of such a simultaneous
measurement of two non-commuting observables based on the framework of weak von
Neumann measurements. We use a photonic setup where the polarisation degree of
freedom acts as the system and the two components of the transversal position
correspond to the pointers of the measurement apparatuses. In addition, the
theory shows that these weak measurements demonstrate a counter-intuitive
non-monotonicity: weaker measurements can potentially reveal more information
than stronger ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04466</id><created>2016-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Miao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadri</keyname><forenames>Usama</forenames></author></authors><title>Wavemaker theories for acoustic-gravity waves over a finite depth</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Acoustic-gravity waves (hereafter AGWs) in ocean have received much interest
recently, mainly with respect to early detection of tsunamis as they travel at
near the speed of sound in water which makes them ideal candidates for early
detection of tsunamis. While the generation mechanisms of AGWs have been
studied from the perspective of vertical oscillations of seafloor and triad
wave-wave interaction, in the current study we are interested in their
generation by wave-structure interaction with possible implication to the
energy sector. Here, we develop two wavemaker theories to analyze different
wave modes generated by impermeable (the classic Havelock's theory) and porous
(porous wavemaker theory) plates in weakly compressible fluids. Slight
modification has been made to the porous theory so that, unlike the previous
theory, the new solution depends on the geometry of the plate. The expressions
for three different types of plates (piston, flap, delta-function) are
introduced. Analytical solutions are also derived for the potential amplitude
of the gravity, acoustic-gravity, evanescent waves, as well as the surface
elevation, velocity distribution, and pressure for AGWs. Both theories reduce
to previous results for incompressible flow when the compressibility is
neglected. We also show numerical examples for AGWs generated in a wave flume
as well as in deep ocean. Our current study sets the theoretical background
towards remote sensing by AGWs, for optimized deep ocean wave-power harnessing,
among others.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04480</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Buballa</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>What can we learn from NJL-type models about dense matter?</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages; contribution to the proceedings of the Mini-Workshop
  &quot;Quarks, Hadrons, Matter&quot;, Bled, Slovenia, July 3-10, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The merits and limitations of the Nambu--Jona-Lasinio model as a model for
strong interactions at nonzero density are critically discussed. We present
several examples, demonstrating that, while in general the results should not
be trusted quantitatively, the NJL model is a powerful theoretical tool for
getting new insights and ideas about the QCD phase diagram and the dense-matter
equation of state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04487</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Swain</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamizhavel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Sanjeev K.</forenames></author></authors><title>DC Magnetization study of Ni$_{1-x}$Rh$_x$ nanoalloy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ni$_{1-x}$Rh$_x$ bulk alloys exhibit a ferromagnetic to paramagnetic quantum
phase transition (QPT) at the critical concentration $x_c \sim$ 0.37. A spin
glass phase arises below the Ferromagnetism by controlling the short range
interaction between Ni and Rh atoms. we have synthesized nanoalloys of two
different concentrations with two different reaction times by chemical reflux
method. From the dc magnetization measurements, existence of ferromagnetism and
spin glass phase in these nanoalloys is confirmed. A step like feature in both
ZFC and FC curve at certain temperature indicates the existence of the spin
glass phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04489</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Pepin</keyname><forenames>Mateo</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Stops from extra dimensions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures. To appear in the proceedings of the 28th
  Rencontres de Blois on Particle Physics and Cosmology, May 29 - June 03,
  2016. Based on arXiv:1608.06470</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In supersymmetric models the mass of the stops can be considered as the
naturalness measure of the theory. Roughly, the lighter the stops are, the more
natural the theory is. Both, the absence of supersymmetric signals at
experiment and the measurement of the Higgs mass, put scenarios with light
stops under increasing tension. I will present a supersymmetry breaking
mechanism of the Scherk-Schwarz type that, by introducing extra $SU(2)_L$
triplets in the Higgs sector, is able to generate the correct Higgs mass while
keeping stops light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04501</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Riemann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Koenigs Wusterhausen</affiliation></author></authors><title>S-matrix approach to the Z resonance</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, Proceedings of 39th International Conference of Theoretical
  Physics: Matter to the Deepest, Recent Developments in Physics of Fundamental
  Interactions, 13-18 September 2015, Ustron, Poland; presented also at the
  FCC-ee meeting, February 2015, Pisa; at CALC, July 2015, JINR, Dubna; at
  HEPKIT, October 2015, KIT, Karlsruhe. Note added on 14 October 2016</comments><report-no>KW 15-001</report-no><journal-ref>Acta Phys. Polon. B46 (2015) no.11, 2235</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolB.46.2235</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The proposed $e^+e^-$-collider FCC-ee aims at an unprecedented accuracy for
$e^+e^-$ collisions into fermion pairs at the $Z$ peak, based on about
$10^{13}$ events. The S-matrix approach to the $Z$ boson line shape allows the
model-independent quantitative description of the reaction $e^+e^- \to {\bar
f}f$ around the $Z$ peak in terms of few parameters, among them the mass $M_Z$
and width $\Gamma_Z$ of the $Z$-boson. While weak and strong corrections remain
&quot;black&quot;, a careful theoretical description of the photonic interactions is
mandatory. I introduce the method and describe applications and the analysis
tool SMATASY/ZFITTER.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04502</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Miranda</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penedones</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harth</keyname><forenames>Anne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louisy</keyname><forenames>Maite</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neoricic</keyname><forenames>Lana</forenames></author><author><keyname>L'Huillier</keyname><forenames>Anne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Cord L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized projection retrieval of dispersion scans for ultrashort
  pulse characterization</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a retrieval algorithm based on generalized projections for
ultrashort pulse characterization using dispersion scan (d-scan). The new
algorithm is tested on several simulated cases and in two different
experimental cases in the few-cycle regime. The proposed algorithm is much
faster and leads to a drastic reduction of retrieval times, but performs less
robust in the retrieval of noisy d-scan traces compared to the standard
algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04511</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Imgon</forenames></author><author><keyname>So</keyname><forenames>Seulgi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokhtar</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alshehri</keyname><forenames>Abdelmohsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Thabaiti</keyname><forenames>Shaeel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-walled TiO2 Nanotubes: Enhanced Carrier-transport Properties by
  TiCl4-Treatment</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Chemistry - A European Journal, Volume 21, Issue 25, pages
  9204-9208, June 15, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/chem.201500730</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work we report significant enhancement of the
photoelectrochemical properties of self-organized TiO2 nanotubes by a combined
de-coring of classic nanotubes followed by an appropiate TiCl4-treatment. We
show that, except for the expected particle decoration, a key effect of the
TiCl4 treatment is that the electron transport characteristics in TiO2
nanotubes can be drastically improved, e.g. we observe an enhancement of up to
70 % in electron transport times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04517</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Riboni</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Nhat Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>So</keyname><forenames>Seulgi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Aligned metal oxide nanotube arrays: key-aspects of anodic TiO2 nanotube
  formation and properties</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>from Nanoscale Horiz., 2016, Advance Article</comments><doi>10.1039/C6NH00054A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Over the past ten years, self-aligned TiO2 nanotubes have attracted
tremendous scientific and technological interest due to their anticipated
impact on energy conversion, environment remediation and biocompatibility. In
the present manuscript, we review fundamental principles that govern the
self-organized initiation of anodic TiO2 nanotubes. We start with the
fundamental question: Why is self-organization taking place? We illustrate the
inherent key mechanistic aspects that lead to tube growth in various different
morphologies, such as rippled-walled tubes, smooth tubes, stacks and
bamboo-type tubes, and importantly the formation of double-walled TiO2
nanotubes versus single-walled tubes, and the drastic difference in their
physical and chemical properties. We show how both double- and single-walled
tube layers can be detached from the metallic substrate and exploited for the
preparation of robust self-standing membranes. Finally, we show how by
selecting the right growth approach to TiO2 nanotubes specific functional
features can be significantly improved, e.g., an enhanced electron mobility,
intrinsic doping, or crystallization into pure anatase at extremely high
temperatures can be achieved. This in turn can be exploited in constructing
high performance devices based on anodic TiO2 in a wide range of applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04524</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fani</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naderi</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum dynamics of an optomechanical system in the presence of photonic
  Bose-Einstein condensate</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study theoretically the optomechanical interaction of an
almost pure condensate of photons with an oscillating mechanical membrane in a
micro-cavity. We show that in the Bogoliubov approximation, due to the large
number of photons in the condensate phase, there is a linear strong effective
coupling between the Bogoliubov mode of the photonic Bose-Einstein condensate
(BEC) and the mechanical motion of the membrane which depends on the nonlinear
photon-photon scattering potential. This coupling leads to the cooling of the
mechanical motion, the normal mode splitting (NMS), the squeezing of the output
field and the entanglement between the excited mode of the cavity and the
mechanical mode. We show that, in one hand, the nonlinearity of the photon gas
increases the degree of the squeezing of the output field of the micro-cavity
and the efficiency of the cooling process at high temperatures. In the other
hand, it reduces NMS in the displacement spectrum of the oscillating membrane
and the degree of the optomechanical entanglement. In addition, the temperature
of the photonic BEC can be used to control the above-mentioned phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04525</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Geyer</keyname><forenames>Yvonne</forenames></author></authors><title>Ambitwistor Strings: Worldsheet Approaches to perturbative Quantum Field
  Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>205 pages, D.Phil thesis, references accounted for until 02/16
  (submission date)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tree-level scattering amplitudes in massless theories not only exhibit a
simplicity entirely unexpected from Feynman diagrams, but also an underlying
structure remarkably reminiscent of worldsheet theory correlators. These
features can be explained by ambitwistor strings - two-dimensional chiral
conformal field theories in an auxiliary target space, the complexified phase
space of null geodesics. The aim of this thesis is to explore the ambitwistor
string approach to understand these structures in amplitudes, and thereby
provide a new angle on quantum field theories. The first part of the thesis
provides a user-friendly introduction to ambitwistor strings, as well as a
condensed overview over the literature and some novel results. Emphasising the
study of tree-level amplitudes, we then explore the wide-ranging impact of
ambitwistor strings for an extensive family of massless theories, and discuss
the duality between asymptotic symmetries and the low energy behaviour of a
theory from the point of view of the worldsheet CFT. The second part of this
thesis focusses on proving a conjectured ambitwistor string formula for loop
amplitudes, and extending the formalism to more general theories. Remarkably,
residue theorems reduce the computationally challenging ambitwistor
higher-genus expressions to simple formulae on nodal Riemann spheres. This idea
is developed into a widely applicable framework for loop integrands, that is
shown to be applicable to both supersymmetric and non-supersymmetric theories.
In the case of supergravity, this provides strong evidence for the validity of
the ambitwistor string at loop level, and explicit proofs are given for
non-supersymmetric theories. This leads to a proposal for an all-loop integrand
for gravity and Yang-Mills.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04537</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Mohammadpour</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moradi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cha</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>So</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kahnt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guldi</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altomare</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced Performance of Dye-Sensitized Solar Cells based on TiO2
  Nanotube Membranes using Optimized Annealing Profile</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Chem. Commun., 2015,51, 1631-1634</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C4CC08266D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use free-standing TiO2 nanotube membranes that are transferred onto FTO
slides in front-side illuminated dye-sensitized solar cells (DSSCs). We
investigate the key parameters for solar cell arrangement of self-ordered
anodic TiO2 nanotube layers on the FTO substrate and namely the influence of
the annealing procedure on the DSSC light conversion efficiency. The results
show that using an optimal temperature annealing profile can significantly
enhance the DSSC efficiency (in our case 9.8 %), as it leads to a markedly
lower density of trapping states in the tube oxide, and thus to strongly
improved electron transport properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04539</id><created>2016-02-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kudryashov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinelshchikov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extended models of nonlinear waves in liquid with gas bubbles</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Non-Linear Mechanics, 63, 31-38 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijnonlinmec.2014.03.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we generalize the models for nonlinear waves in a gas--liquid
mixture taking into account an interphase heat transfer, a surface tension and
a weak liquid compressibility simultaneously at the derivation of the equations
for nonlinear waves. We also take into consideration high order terms with
respect to the small parameter. Two new nonlinear differential equations are
derived for long weakly nonlinear waves in a liquid with gas bubbles by the
reductive perturbation method considering both high order terms with respect to
the small parameter and the above mentioned physical properties. One of these
equations is the perturbation of the Burgers equation and corresponds to main
influence of dissipation on nonlinear waves propagation. The other equation is
the perturbation of the Burgers--Korteweg--de Vries equation and corresponds to
main influence of dispersion on nonlinear waves propagation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04564</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Freivogel</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleban</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacua Morghulis</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We conjecture that all vacua in string theory decay. More precisely,
non-supersymmetric vacua in string theory are at most metastable and eventually
decay, while supersymmetric vacua are only marginally stable. All de Sitter
vacua with small cosmological constant are metastable to decay via a process
that occurs on scales small compared to the horizon size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04570</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Haupt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>A Quantum Mechanical Bound for Space-Energy Cost with Respect to the Von
  Neumann Entropy</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis discusses the possibility of uncertainty relations for space and
energy given a state of fixed entropy. In particular, it discusses the results
in the paper of Dam/Nguyen. There, the authors propose a lower bound for the
mixed cost in energy and space required for physically storing information in a
quantum mechanical system. We first critically examine the justifications for
the bound given in the paper.This is done from a mathematical point of view, in
contrast to the more physically motivated original paper.Then we give two
examples that illustrate the limitations of this inequality. We also present
numerical results to find an alternative energy-space bound in the finite
dimensional version of this problem. They indicate a slightly different version
of the inequality. In the end we describe a promising ansatz to find a lower
energy-space bound that depends on the amount stored information. Unfortunately
that did not result in a satisfactory result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04593</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Aaron S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kronfeld</keyname><forenames>Andreas S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ruizi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simone</keyname><forenames>James N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of the Nucleon Axial Form Factor Using Staggered Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-CONF-16-451-T</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nucleon axial form factor is a dominant contribution to errors in
neutrino oscillation studies. Lattice QCD calculations can help control theory
errors by providing first-principles information on nucleon form factors. In
these proceedings, we present preliminary results on a blinded calculation of
$g_A$ and the axial form factor using HISQ staggered baryons with 2+1+1 flavors
of sea quarks. Calculations are done using physical light quark masses and are
absolutely normalized. We discuss fitting form factor data with the
model-independent $z$ expansion parametrization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:gr-qc/0409082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>gr-qc/0409082</id><created>2004-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wainwright</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological models from a dynamical systems perspective</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This paper is based on a talk given at the Miami Waves Conference in
  January 2004</comments><journal-ref>J.Hyperbol.Diff.Equat. 2 (2005) 437-470</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219891605000531</doi><abstract>  It is useful to study the space of all cosmological models from a dynamical
systems perspective, that is, by formulating the Einstein field equations as a
dynamical system using appropriately normalized variables. We will discuss
various aspects of this work, the choices of normalization factor, multiple
representations of models, the past attractor, nonlinear dynamics in
close-to-Friedmann-Lemaitre models, Weyl curvature dominance, and numerical
simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:gr-qc/0511139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-17</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>gr-qc/0511139</id><created>2005-11-25</created><updated>2006-02-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Woei Chet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uggla</keyname><forenames>Claes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wainwright</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic silence-breaking singularities</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>25 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav. 23 (2006) 2607-2630</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/23/7/023</doi><abstract>  We discuss three complementary aspects of scalar curvature singularities:
asymptotic causal properties, asymptotic Ricci and Weyl curvature, and
asymptotic spatial properties. We divide scalar curvature singularities into
two classes: so-called asymptotically silent singularities and non-generic
singularities that break asymptotic silence. The emphasis in this paper is on
the latter class which have not been previously discussed. We illustrate the
above aspects and concepts by describing the singularities of a number of
representative explicit perfect fluid solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
