<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:22:22Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-10-14" from="2016-10-14" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.0408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.0408</id><created>2014-07-01</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cacciari</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salam</keyname><forenames>Gavin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soyez</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author></authors><title>SoftKiller, a particle-level pileup removal method</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 16 figures (2 appendices with further checks added)</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-TH/2014-116</report-no><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3267-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Existing widely-used pileup removal approaches correct the momenta of
individual jets. In this article we introduce an event-level, particle-based
pileup correction procedure, SoftKiller. It removes the softest particles in an
event, up to a transverse momentum threshold that is determined dynamically on
an event-by-event basis. In simulations, this simple procedure appears to be
reasonably robust and brings superior jet resolution performance compared to
existing jet-based approaches. It is also nearly two orders of magnitude faster
than methods based on jet areas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.2570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.2570</id><created>2014-07-09</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maximoff</keyname><forenames>Sergey N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of charge transfer in catalytic hydrogen oxidation over platinum</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Charge transfer plays the central role in chemisorption and chemical
reactions at metal surfaces. The Somorjai group in Nano. Lett. {\bf 9}, 3930
(2009) has reported a chemicurrent, a flux of charge carriers in response to
$\mathrm{H_2}$ oxidation by $\mathrm{O_2}$ into $\mathrm{H_2O}$ over a platinum
surface. The nature of the chemicurrent has been debated in the literature;
explanations both extrinsic and intrinsic to the reaction mechanism have been
offered. This article suggests a picture behind the chemicurrent experiments,
which is intrinsic to the mechanism of hydrogen oxidation in a high temperature
regime. Surface reaction intermediates, $&quot;\mathrm{O^-}&quot;$, $&quot;\mathrm{H^-}&quot;$,
$&quot;\mathrm{OH^-}&quot;$, are negatively charged while the product, $\mathrm{H_2O}$,
and reactants, $\mathrm{H_2}$ and $\mathrm{O_2}$, are neutral. Hence, charge
transfers between the metal and reacting species are inevitable. After
electrons are transferred from the metal to the interface in dissociative
oxygen and hydrogen adsorption, translationally excited electrons in the metal
arise in part as a result of decay of negatively charged transition states in
reaction steps connecting surface species of different charges,
$&quot;\mathrm{O^-+H^-}&quot; \rightleftarrows &quot;\mathrm{2 e+OH^-}&quot;$ and
$&quot;\mathrm{OH^-+H^-}&quot;\rightleftarrows &quot;\mathrm{2 e+H_2O}&quot;$. These transition
states are the lowest energy configurations possible for changing the charge of
the negatively charged surface intermediates. In particular, the transition
state for $&quot;\mathrm{O^-+H^-}&quot; \rightleftarrows \mathrm{&quot;2 e+OH^-&quot;}$ limits the
reaction rate. These processes may contribute to the chemicurrent. This picture
should also apply to other catalytic chemical reactions on metal surfaces that
proceed through formation of charged surface intermediates and their consequent
discharge into the metal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7275</id><created>2014-09-25</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrer-i-Cancho</keyname><forenames>Ramon</forenames></author></authors><title>The meaning-frequency law in Zipfian optimization models of
  communication</title><categories>cs.CL physics.data-an physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Glottometrics 35, 28-37 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to Zipf's meaning-frequency law, words that are more frequent tend
to have more meanings. Here it is shown that a linear dependency between the
frequency of a form and its number of meanings is found in a family of models
of Zipf's law for word frequencies. This is evidence for a weak version of the
meaning-frequency law. Interestingly, that weak law (a) is not an inevitable of
property of the assumptions of the family and (b) is found at least in the
narrow regime where those models exhibit Zipf's law for word frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02784</id><created>2015-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Peloso</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unal</keyname><forenames>Caner</forenames></author></authors><title>Trajectories with suppressed tensor-to-scalar ratio in Aligned Natural
  Inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><report-no>UMN--TH--3429/15</report-no><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/06/040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Aligned Natural Inflation, an alignment between different potential terms
produces an inflaton excursion greater than the axion scales in the potential.
We show that, starting from a general potential of two axions with two aligned
potential terms, the effective theory for the resulting light direction is
characterized by four parameters: an effective potential scale, an effective
axion constant, and two extra parameters (related to ratios of the axion scales
and the potential scales in the $2-$field theory). For all choices of these
extra parameters, the model can support inflation along valleys (in the
$2-$field space) that end in minima of the potential. This leads to a
phenomenology similar to that of single field Natural Inflation. For a
significant range of the extra two parameters, the model possesses also higher
altitude inflationary trajectories passing through saddle points of the
$2-$field potential, and disconnected from any minimum. These plateaus end when
the heavier direction becomes unstable, and therefore all of inflation takes
place close to the saddle point, where - due to the higher altitude - the
potential is flatter (smaller $\epsilon$ parameter). As a consequence, a
tensor-to-scalar ratio $r = {\rm O } \left( 10^{-4} - 10^{-2} \right)$ can be
easily achieved in the allowed $n_s$ region, well within the latest $1 \sigma$
CMB contours.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04673</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2015-08-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lan</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>A theory of 2+1D fermionic topological orders and fermionic/bosonic
  topological orders with symmetries</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>23 pages, 8 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155113 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose that, up to invertible topological orders, 2+1D fermionic
topological orders without symmetry and 2+1D fermionic/bosonic topological
orders with symmetry $G$ are classified by non-degenerate unitary braided
fusion categories (UBFC) over a symmetric fusion category (SFC); the SFC
describes a fermionic product state without symmetry or a fermionic/bosonic
product state with symmetry $G$, and the UBFC has a modular extension. We
developed a simplified theory of non-degenerate UBFC over a SFC based on the
fusion coefficients $N^{ij}_k$ and spins $s_i$. This allows us to obtain a list
that contains all 2+1D fermionic topological orders (without symmetry). We find
explicit realizations for all the fermionic topological orders in the table.
For example, we find that, up to invertible
$p+\hspace{1pt}\mathrm{i}\hspace{1pt} p$ fermionic topological orders, there
are only four fermionic topological orders with one non-trivial topological
excitation: (1) the $K={\scriptsize \begin{pmatrix} -1&amp;0\\0&amp;2\end{pmatrix}}$
fractional quantum Hall state, (2) a Fibonacci bosonic topological order
$2^B_{14/5}$ stacking with a fermionic product state, (3) the time-reversal
conjugate of the previous one, (4) a primitive fermionic topological order that
has a chiral central charge $c=\frac14$, whose only topological excitation has
a non-abelian statistics with a spin $s=\frac14$ and a quantum dimension
$d=1+\sqrt{2}$. We also proposed a categorical way to classify 2+1D invertible
fermionic topological orders using modular extensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02118</id><created>2015-08-09</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prasetyo</keyname><forenames>Ilham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramadhan</keyname><forenames>Handhika S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity of a noncanonical global monopole: conical topology and
  compactification</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Erratum added</comments><journal-ref>Gen.Rel.Grav. 48 (2016) no.1, 10</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-015-1998-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain solutions of Einstein's equations describing gravitational field
outside a noncanonical global monopole with cosmological constant. In
particular, we consider two models of k-monopoles: the Dirac-Born-Infeld (DBI)
and the power-law types, and study their corresponding exterior gravitational
fields. For each model we found two types of solutions. The first of which are
global k-monopole black hole with conical global topology. These are
generalizations of the Barriola-Vilenkin solution of global monopole. The
appearance of noncanonical kinetic terms does not modify the critical
symmetry-breaking scale, $\eta_{crit}$, but it does affect the corresponding
horizon(s). The second type of solution is compactification, whose topology is
a product of two $2$-dimensional spaces with constant curvatures; ${\mathcal
Y}_4\rightarrow {\mathcal Z}_2\times S^2$, with ${\mathcal Y}, {\mathcal Z}$
can be de Sitter, Minkowski, or Anti-de Sitter, and $S^2$ is the $2$-sphere. We
investigate all possible compactifications and show that the nonlinearity of
kinetic terms opens up new channels which are otherwise non-existent. For
$\Lambda=0$ four-dimensional geometry, we conjecture that these
compactification channels are their (possible) non-static super-critical
states, right before they undergo topological inflation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00696</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2015-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hauschild</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heidrich-Meisner</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author></authors><title>Sudden expansion and domain-wall melting of strongly interacting bosons
  in two-dimensional optical lattices and on multileg ladders</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>16 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 053629 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.053629</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically investigate the expansion of clouds of hard-core bosons in the
two-dimensional square lattice using a matrix-product-state based method. This
nonequilibrium set-up is induced by quenching the trapping potential to zero
and our work is specifically motivated by a recent experiment with interacting
bosons in an optical lattice [Ronzheimer et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 110, 205301
(2013)]. As the anisotropy of the amplitudes $J_x$ and $J_y$ for hopping in
different spatial directions is varied from the one- to the two-dimensional
case, we observe a crossover from a fast ballistic expansion in the
one-dimensional limit $J_x \gg J_y$ to much slower dynamics in the isotropic
two-dimensional limit $J_x=J_y$. We further study the dynamics on multi-leg
ladders and long cylinders. For these geometries we compare the expansion of a
cloud to the melting of a domain wall, which helps us to identify several
different regimes of the expansion as a function of time. By studying the
dependence of expansion velocities on both the anisotropy $J_y/J_x$ and the
number of legs, we observe that the expansion on two-leg ladders, while similar
to the two-dimensional case, is slower than on wider ladders. We provide a
qualitative explanation for this observation based on an analysis of the rung
spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02844</id><created>2015-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Khaydukov</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kravtsov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Progliado</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ustinov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikitenko</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aksenov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keimer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Peculiarities of neutron waveguides with thin Gd layer</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 746 (2016) 012064</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/746/1/012064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Peculiarities of the formation of a neutron enhanced standing wave in the
structure with a thin highly absorbing layer of gadolinium are considered in
the article. An analogue of the poisoning effect well known in reactor physics
was found. The effect is stronger for the Nb/Gd/Nb system. Despite of this
effect, for a Nb/Gd bilayer and a Nb/Gd/Nb trilayer placed between Al2O3
substrate and Cu layer, it is shown theoretically and experimentally that one
order of magnitude enhancement of neutron density is possible in the vicinity
of the Gd layer. This enhancement makes it possible to study domain formation
in the Gd layer under transition of the Nb layer(s) into the superconducting
state (cryptoferromagnetic phase).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04423</id><created>2015-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Holtzman</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Segre</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Wettability stabilizes fluid invasion into porous media via nonlocal,
  cooperative pore filling</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.soft nlin.PS physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>In review, Physics Review Letters</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 164501 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.164501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the impact of the wetting properties on the immiscible displacement
of a viscous fluid in disordered porous media. We present a novel pore-scale
model that captures wettability and dynamic effects, including the
spatiotemporal nonlocality associated with interface readjustments. Our
simulations show that increasing the wettability of the invading fluid (the
contact angle) promotes cooperative pore filling that stabilizes the invasion,
and that this effect is suppressed as the flow rate increases, due to viscous
instabilities. We use scaling analysis to derive two dimensionless numbers that
predict the mode of displacement. By elucidating the underlying mechanisms, we
explain classical yet intriguing experimental observations. These insights
could be used to improve technologies such as hydraulic fracturing, CO$_{2}$
geo-sequestration, and microfluidics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04678</id><created>2015-09-15</created><updated>2015-12-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of bond valence method in the non-isovalent semiconductor
  alloy (GaN)$_{1-x}$(ZnO)$_x$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Modelling Simul. Mater. Sci. Eng. 24 (2016) 075014</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0965-0393/24/7/075014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper studies the bond valence method (BVM) and its application in the
non-isovalent semiconductor alloy (GaN)$_{\rm{1-x}}$(ZnO)$_{\rm{x}}$.
Particular attention is paid to the role of short-range order (SRO). A physical
interpretation based on atomic orbital interaction is proposed and examined by
density-functional theory (DFT) calculations. Combining BVM with Monte-Carlo
simulations and a DFT-based cluster expansion model, bond-length distributions
and bond-angle variations are predicted. The correlation between bond valence
and bond stiffness is also revealed. Finally the concept of bond valence is
extended into the modelling of an atomistic potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00280</id><created>2015-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Sitenko</keyname><forenames>Yurii A</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-adjointness and the Casimir effect with confined quantized spinor
  matter</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages; based on talks at the International Conferences: ISQS-23,
  22-27 June 2015, Prague, Czech Republic, p-ADICS.2015, 07-12 September 2015,
  Belgrade, Republic of Serbia, and BGL-9, 27-30 October 2015, Minsk, Republic
  of Belarus; submitted to J. Phys. Conf. Series</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Series 670, 012048 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/670/1/012048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generalization of the MIT bag boundary condition for spinor matter is
proposed basing on the requirement that the Dirac hamiltonian operator be
self-adjoint. An influence of a background magnetic field on the vacuum of
charged spinor matter confined between two parallel material plates is studied.
Employing the most general set of boundary conditions at the plates in the case
of the uniform magnetic field directed orthogonally to the plates, we find the
pressure from the vacuum onto the plates. In physically plausible situations,
the Casimir effect is shown to be repulsive, independently of a choice of
boundary conditions and of a distance between the plates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00645</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deriglazov</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>Walberto Guzm&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-relativistic spinning particle and a rotating body in external
  fields</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, close to published version. arXiv admin note: text overlap
  with arXiv:1509.04926</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, vol. 2016, Article ID 1376016, 27
  pages, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/1376016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the vector model of spinning particle to analyze the influence of
spin-field coupling on the particle's trajectory in ultra-relativistic regime.
The Lagrangian with minimal spin-gravity interaction yields the equations
equivalent to the Mathisson-Papapetrou-Tulczyjew-Dixon (MPTD) equations of a
rotating body. We show that they have unsatisfactory behavior in the
ultra-relativistic limit. In particular, three-dimensional acceleration of the
particle increases with velocity and becomes infinite in the ultra-relativistic
limit. The reason is that in the equation for trajectory emerges the term which
can be thought as an effective metric generated by the minimal spin-gravity
coupling. Therefore we examine the non-minimal interaction through the
gravimagnetic moment $\kappa$, and show that the theory with $\kappa=1$ is free
of the problems detected in MPTD-equations. Hence the non-minimally interacting
theory seem more promising candidate for description of a relativistic rotating
body in general relativity.
  The Lagrangian for the particle in an arbitrary electromagnetic field in
Minkowski space leads to generalized Frenkel and Bargmann-Michel-Telegdi
equations. The particle with magnetic moment in electromagnetic field and the
particle with gravimagnetic moment in gravitational field have very similar
structure of equations of motion. In particular, the spin-electromagnetic
coupling also produces an effective metric for the particle with anomalous
magnetic moment. If we use the usual special-relativity notions for time and
distance, then the critical speed, which the particle cannot exceed during its
evolution in electromagnetic field, is different from the speed of light. This
can be corrected assuming that the three-dimensional geometry should be defined
with respect to the effective metric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04456</id><created>2015-11-13</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanaliloo</keyname><forenames>Behzad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lake</keyname><forenames>David P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>Tamiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadden</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barclay</keyname><forenames>Paul E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-crystal diamond low-dissipation cavity optomechanics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optica 3, 963-970 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.000963</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-crystal diamond cavity optomechanical devices are a promising example
of a hybrid quantum system: by coupling mechanical resonances to both light and
electron spins, they can enable new ways for photons to control solid state
qubits. However, realizing cavity optomechanical devices from high quality
diamond chips has been an outstanding challenge. Here we demonstrate
single-crystal diamond cavity optomechanical devices that can enable
photon-phonon-spin coupling. Cavity optomechanical coupling to $2\,\text{GHz}$
frequency ($f_\text{m}$) mechanical resonances is observed. In room temperature
ambient conditions, these resonances have a record combination of low
dissipation (mechanical quality factor, $Q_\text{m} &gt; 9000$) and high
frequency, with $Q_\text{m}\cdot f_\text{m} \sim 1.9\times10^{13}$ sufficient
for room temperature single phonon coherence. The system exhibits high optical
quality factor ($Q_\text{o} &gt; 10^4$) resonances at infrared and visible
wavelengths, is nearly sideband resolved, and exhibits optomechanical
cooperativity $C\sim 3$. The devices' potential for optomechanical control of
diamond electron spins is demonstrated through radiation pressure excitation of
mechanical self-oscillations whose 31 pm amplitude is predicted to provide 0.6
MHz coupling rates to diamond nitrogen vacancy center ground state transitions
(6 Hz / phonon), and $\sim10^5$ stronger coupling rates to excited state
transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05841</id><created>2015-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Alavi</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazemian</keyname><forenames>F S</forenames></author></authors><title>Photonic dark matter portal revisited</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, contribution to the TAUP 2015, International
  Conference on Topics in Astroparticle and Underground Physics, 7-11 September
  2015, Torino, Italy</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 718 (2016) no.4, 042002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/718/4/042002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our previous paper [1], we studied a model of dark matter (DM) in which
the hidden sector interacts with standard model particles via a hidden photonic
portal (HP). We investigated the effects of this new interaction on the
hydrogen atom and obtained an upper bound for the coupling of the model. In
this work, we study the effects of HP on two interesting exotic atoms namely
muonium and positronium. We obtain a tighter upper limit on the coupling. We
also calculate the change (shift) in the Aharonov-Bohm phase due to HP and find
that the phase shift is negligibly small (for DM particles mass in the GeV
range). Recently a 3.5 keV X ray line signal observed in the spectrum of 73
galaxy clusters, reported by the XXM-Newton X ray observatory. Since in HP
model the DM particles can decay directly into photons, so we finally calculate
the value of the coupling constant f using the condition Delta E=3.5 keV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06254</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>Eros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkard</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author></authors><title>A Tight Binding Approach to Strain and Curvature in Monolayer
  Transition-Metal Dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures, revised version v2</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155416 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a model of the electronic properties of monolayer transition-metal
dichalcogenides based on a tight binding approach which includes the effects of
strain and curvature of the crystal lattice. Mechanical deformations of the
lattice offer a powerful route for tuning the electronic structure of the
transition-metal dichalcogenides, as changes to bond lengths lead directly to
corrections in the electronic Hamiltonian while curvature of the crystal
lattice mixes the orbital structure of the electronic Bloch bands. We first
present an effective low energy Hamiltonian describing the electronic
properties near the K point in the Brillouin zone, then present the corrections
to this Hamiltonian due to arbitrary mechanical deformations and curvature in a
way which treats both effects on an equal footing. This analysis finds that
local area variations of the lattice allow for tuning of the band gap and
effective masses, while the application of uniaxial strain decreases the
magnitude of the direct band gap at the K point. Additionally, strain induced
bond length modifications create a fictitious gauge field with a coupling
strength that is smaller than that seen in related materials like graphene. We
also find that curvature of the lattice leads to the appearance of both an
effective in-plane magnetic field which couples to spin degrees of freedom and
a Rashba-like spin-orbit coupling due to broken mirror inversion symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09008</id><created>2015-11-29</created><updated>2016-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kov&#xe1;cs</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Bellido</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic troublemakers: the Cold Spot, the Eridanus Supervoid, and the
  Great Walls</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures. Accepted by MNRAS in this form</comments><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-15-132</report-no><journal-ref>Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 462 (2016) no.2, 1882-1893</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1752</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The alignment of the CMB Cold Spot and the Eridanus supervoid suggests a
physical connection between these two relatively rare objects. We use galaxy
cata\-logues with photometric (2MPZ) and spectroscopic (6dF) redshift
measurements, supplemented by low-redshift compilations of cosmic voids, in
order to improve the 3D mapping of the matter density in the Eridanus
constellation. We find evidence for a supervoid with a significant elongation
in the line-of-sight, effectively spanning the total redshift range $z&lt;0.3$.
Our tomographic imaging reveals important substructure in the Eridanus
supervoid, with a potential interpretation of a long, fully connected system of
voids. We improve the analysis by extending the line-of-sight measurements into
the antipodal direction that interestingly crosses the Northern Local Supervoid
at the lowest redshifts. Then it intersects very rich superclusters like
Hercules and Corona Borealis, in the region of the Coma and Sloan Great Walls,
as a possible compensation for the large-scale matter deficit of Eridanus. We
find that large-scale structure measurements are consistent with a central
matter underdensity $\delta_0 \approx -0.25$, projected transverse radius
$r_{0}^{\perp}\approx 195$ Mpc/h with an extra deepening in the centre, and
line-of-sight radius $r_{0}^{\parallel}\approx500$ Mpc/h, i.e. an ellipsoidal
supervoid. The expected integrated Sachs-Wolfe imprint of such an elongated
supervoid is at the $\Delta T_{\rm ISW} \approx -40 \mu K$ level, thus
inappropriate to accounting for the Cold Spot pattern in the CMB.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06116</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Ricardo Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganc</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nore&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sloth</keyname><forenames>Martin S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the validity of the perturbative description of axions during
  inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>V2: 18 pages, 6 figures. Small correction in the numerical one-loop
  result, conclusions otherwise unchanged</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/04/039 10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/E01</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Axions play a central role in many realizations of large field models of
inflation and in recent alternative mechanisms for generating primordial tensor
modes in small field models. If these axions couple to gauge fields, the
coupling produces a tachyonic instability that leads to an exponential
enhancement of the gauge fields, which in turn can decay into observable scalar
or tensor curvature perturbations. Thus, a fully self-consistent treatment of
axions during inflation is important, and in this work we discuss the
perturbative constraints on axions coupled to gauge fields. We show how the
recent proposal of generating tensor modes through these alternative mechanisms
is in tension with perturbation theory in the in-in formalism. Interestingly,
we point out that the constraints are parametrically weaker than one would
estimate based on naive power counting of propagators of the gauge field. In
the case of non-Abelian gauge fields, we derive new constraints on the size of
the gauge coupling, which apply also in certain models of natural large field
inflation, such as alignment mechanisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09011</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-02-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuautle</keyname><forenames>Eleazar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paic</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects produced by multi-parton interactions and color reconnection in
  small systems</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, Proceedings of XXV International Conference on
  Ultrarelativistic Nucleus-Nucleus Collisions, Kobe, Japan. Minor changes in
  the text were implemented</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. A956 (2016) 749-752</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.02.031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multi-parton interactions and color reconnection can produce QGP-like effects
in small systems, specifically, radial flow-like patterns. For pp collisions
simulated with Pythia 8.212, in this work we investigate their effects on
different observables like event multiplicity, event shapes and transverse
momentum distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04564</id><created>2016-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Partouche</keyname><forenames>Herve</forenames></author></authors><title>Large volume supersymmetry breaking without decompactification problem</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages. Based on a talk given at &quot;Lie theory and its applications
  in physics (LT-11), Varna, Bulgaria, 15 - 21 June 2015</comments><report-no>CPHT-PC002.012016</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider heterotic string backgrounds in four-dimensional Minkowski space,
where N=1 supersymmetry is spontaneously broken at a low scale m_{3/2} by a
stringy Scherk-Schwarz mechanism. We review how the effective gauge couplings
at 1-loop may evade the &quot;decompactification problem&quot;, namely the
proportionality of the gauge threshold corrections, with the large volume of
the compact space involved in the supersymmetry breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06149</id><created>2016-01-21</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Altmann</keyname><forenames>Yoann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Ximing</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>Aongus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buller</keyname><forenames>Gerald S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLaughlin</keyname><forenames>Steve</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust Bayesian target detection algorithm for depth imaging from sparse
  single-photon data</title><categories>physics.ins-det stat.AP</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1507.02511</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a new Bayesian model and associated algorithm for depth
and intensity profiling using full waveforms from time-correlated single-photon
counting (TCSPC) measurements in the limit of very low photon counts (i.e.,
typically less than 20 photons per pixel). The model represents each Lidar
waveform as an unknown constant background level, which is combined in the
presence of a target, to a known impulse response weighted by the target
intensity and finally corrupted by Poisson noise. The joint target detection
and depth imaging problem is expressed as a pixel-wise model selection and
estimation problem which is solved using Bayesian inference. Prior knowledge
about the problem is embedded in a hierarchical model that describes the
dependence structure between the model parameters while accounting for their
constraints. In particular, Markov random fields (MRFs) are used to model the
joint distribution of the background levels and of the target presence labels,
which are both expected to exhibit significant spatial correlations. An
adaptive Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithm including reversible-jump updates
is then proposed to compute the Bayesian estimates of interest. This algorithm
is equipped with a stochastic optimization adaptation mechanism that
automatically adjusts the parameters of the MRFs by maximum marginal likelihood
estimation. Finally, the benefits of the proposed methodology are demonstrated
through a series of experiments using real data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03687</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03687</id><created>2016-02-11</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Majumder</keyname><forenames>Gourab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>Arti</forenames></author></authors><title>Drude weight in hard core Boson systems: possibility of a finite
  temperature ideal conductor</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B \bf{94}, 134508 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.134508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the Drude weight in the superfluid (SF) and the supersolid (SS)
phases of hard core boson (HCB) model using stochastic series expansion (SSE).
We demonstrate from our numerical calculations that the normal phase of HCBs in
two dimensions can be an ideal conductor with dissipationless transport. In two
dimensions, when the ground state is a SF, the superfluid stiffness drops to
zero with a Kosterlitz-Thouless type transition at $T_{KT}$. The Drude weight,
though is equal to the stiffness below $T_{KT}$, surprisingly stays finite even
for temperatures above $T_{KT}$ indicating the non-dissipative transport in the
normal state of this system. In contrast to this in a three dimensional SF
phase, where the superfluid stiffness goes to zero continuously with a second
order phase transition at $T_c$, Drude weight also goes to zero at $T_c$ as
expected. We also calculated the Drude weight in a 2D SS phase, where the
charge density wave (CDW) order coexists with superfluidity. For the SS phase
we studied, superfluidity is lost via Kosterlitz-Thouless transition at
$T_{KT}$ and the transition temperature for the CDW order is larger than
$T_{KT}$. In striped SS phase where the CDW order breaks the rotational
symmetry of the lattice, for $T &gt; T_{KT}$, the system behaves like an ideal
conductor along one of the lattice direction while along the other direction it
behaves like an insulator. In contrast to this, in star-SS phase, Drude weight
along both the lattice directions goes to zero along with the superfluid
stiffness and for $T &gt; T_{KT}$ we have a finite temperature phase of a CDW
insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03752</id><created>2016-02-11</created><updated>2016-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liarte</keyname><forenames>Danilo B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Transtrum</keyname><forenames>Mark K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sethna</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ginzburg-Landau theory of the superheating field anisotropy of layered
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94 144504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.144504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effects of material anisotropy on the superheating field
of layered superconductors. We provide an intuitive argument both for the
existence of a superheating field, and its dependence on anisotropy, for
$\kappa = \lambda / \xi$ (the ratio of magnetic to superconducting healing
lengths) both large and small. On the one hand, the combination of our
estimates with published results using a two-gap model for MgB${}_2$ suggests
high anisotropy of the superheating field near zero temperature. On the other
hand, within Ginzburg-Landau theory for a single gap, we see that the
superheating field shows significant anisotropy only when the crystal
anisotropy is large and the Ginzburg-Landau parameter $\kappa$ is small. We
then conclude that only small anisotropies in the superheating field are
expected for typical unconventional superconductors near the critical
temperature. Using a generalized form of Ginzburg Landau theory, we do a
quantitative calculation for the anisotropic superheating field by mapping the
problem to the isotropic case, and present a phase diagram in terms of
anisotropy and $\kappa$, showing type I, type II, or mixed behavior (within
Ginzburg-Landau theory), and regions where each asymptotic solution is
expected. We estimate anisotropies for a number of different materials, and
discuss the importance of these results for radio-frequency cavities for
particle accelerators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04141</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-08-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Behrmann</keyname><forenames>Malte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lichtenstein</keyname><forenames>Alexander I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsnelson</keyname><forenames>Mikhail I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lechermann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Versatile Approach to the Spin Dynamics in Correlated Electron Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, revised version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 165120 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.165120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time-dependent spin phenomena in condensed matter are most often either
described in the weakly correlated limit of metallic Stoner/Slater-like
magnetism via band theory or in the strongly correlated limit of
Heisenberg-like interacting spins in an insulator. However many experimental
studies, e.g. of (de)magnetization processes, focus on itinerant local-moment
materials such as transition metals and various of their compounds. We here
present a general theoretical framework that is capable of addressing
correlated spin dynamics, also in the presence of a vanishing charge gap. A
real-space implementation of the time-dependent rotational-invariant slave
boson methodology allows to treat non-equilibrium spins numerically fast and
efficiently beyond linear response as well as beyond the band-theoretical or
Heisenberg limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07763</id><created>2016-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yingrui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yagan</keyname><forenames>Osman</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing the robustness of electrical power systems against cascading
  failures</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><comments>18 pages including 2 pages of supplementary file, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 27625 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep27625</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrical power systems are one of the most important infrastructures that
support our society. However, their vulnerabilities have raised great concern
recently due to several large-scale blackouts around the world. In this paper,
we investigate the robustness of power systems against cascading failures
initiated by a random attack. This is done under a simple yet useful model
based on global and equal redistribution of load upon failures. We provide a
complete understanding of system robustness by i) deriving an expression for
the final system size as a function of the size of initial attacks; ii)
deriving the critical attack size after which system breaks down completely;
iii) showing that complete system breakdown takes place through a first-order
(i.e., discontinuous) transition in terms of the attack size; and iv)
establishing the optimal load-capacity distribution that maximizes robustness.
In particular, we show that robustness is maximized when the difference between
the capacity and initial load is the same for all lines; i.e., when all lines
have the same redundant space regardless of their initial load. This is in
contrast with the intuitive and commonly used setting where capacity of a line
is a fixed factor of its initial load.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08182</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shaowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elahi</keyname><forenames>Mirza M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habib</keyname><forenames>K. M. Masum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Yuanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hone</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Avik W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dean</keyname><forenames>Cory R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron optics with ballistic graphene junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1126/science.aaf5481</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrons transmitted across a ballistic semiconductor junction undergo
refraction, analogous to light rays across an optical boundary. A pn junction
theoretically provides the equivalent of a negative index medium, enabling
novel electron optics such as negative refraction and perfect (Veselago)
lensing. In graphene, the linear dispersion and zero-gap bandstructure admit
highly transparent pn junctions by simple electrostatic gating, which cannot be
achieved in conventional semiconductors. Moreover ballistic transport over
micron length scales at ambient temperature has been realized, providing an
ideal platform to realize a new generation of device based on electron lensing.
Robust demonstration of these effects, however, has not been forthcoming. Here
we employ transverse magnetic focusing to probe propagation across an
electrostatically defined graphene junction. We find perfect agreement with the
predicted Snells law for electrons, including observation of both positive and
negative refraction. Resonant transmission across the pn junction provides a
direct measurement of the angle dependent transmission coefficient, and we
demonstrate good agreement with theory. Comparing experimental data with
simulation reveals the crucial role played by the effective junction width,
providing guidance for future device design. Our results pave the way for
realizing novel electron optics based on graphene pn junctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08686</id><created>2016-02-28</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Haitang</forenames></author></authors><title>Free-fall Frame Black Hole in Gravity's Rainbow</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures, Journal version. arXiv admin note: substantial
  text overlap with arXiv:1507.03768</comments><report-no>CTP-SCU/2016002</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064068 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Doubly special relativity (DSR) is an effective model for encoding quantum
gravity in flat spacetime. To incorporate DSR into general relativity, one
could use &quot;Gravity's rainbow&quot;, where the spacetime background felt by a test
particle would depend on its energy. In this scenario, one could rewrite the
rainbow metric $g_{\mu\nu}\left( E\right) $ in terms of some orthonormal frame
fields and use the modified equivalence principle to determine the energy
dependence of $g_{\mu\nu}\left( E\right) $. Obviously, the form of
$g_{\mu\nu}\left( E\right) $ depends on the choice of the orthonormal frame.
For a static black hole, there are two natural orthonormal frames, the static
one hovering above it and freely falling one along geodesics. The cases with
the static orthonormal frame have been extensively studied by many authors. The
aim of this paper is to investigate properties of rainbow black holes in the
scenario with the free-fall orthonormal frame. We first derive the metric of
rainbow black holes and their Hawking temperatures in this free-fall scenario.
Then, the thermodynamics of a rainbow Schwarzschild black hole is studied.
Finally, we use the brick wall model to compute the thermal entropy of a
massless scalar field near the horizon of a Schwarzschild rainbow black hole in
this free-fall scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00638</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Kazuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minomo</keyname><forenames>Kosho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogata</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating the alpha-clustering on the surface of $^{120}$Sn via
  ($p$,$p\alpha$) reaction and the validity of the factorization approximation</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 044604 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.044604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $^{120}$Sn($p$,$p\alpha$)$^{116}$Cd reaction at 392 MeV is investigated
with the distorted wave impulse approximation (DWIA) framework. We show that
this reaction is very peripheral mainly because of the strong absorption of
$\alpha$ by the reaction residue $^{116}$Cd, and the $\alpha$-clustering on the
nuclear surface can be probed clearly. We investigate also the validity of the
so-called factorization approximation that has frequently been used so far. It
is shown that the kinematics of $\alpha$ in the nuclear interior region is
significantly affected by the distortion of $^{116}$Cd, but it has no effect on
the reaction observables because of the strong absorption in that region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01260</id><created>2016-03-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Menyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallbank</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fal'ko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldhaber-Gordon</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Ballistic miniband conduction in a graphene superlattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Science 30 Sep 2016: Vol. 353, pp. 1526-1529</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aaf1095</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rational design of artificial lattices yields effects unavailable in simple
solids, and vertical superlattices of multilayer semiconductors are already
used in optical sensors and emitters. Manufacturing lateral superlattices
remains a much bigger challenge, with new opportunities offered by the use of
moire patterns in van der Waals heterostructures of graphene and hexagonal
crystals such as boron nitride (h-BN). Experiments to date have elucidated the
novel electronic structure of highly aligned graphene/h-BN heterostructures,
where miniband edges and saddle points in the electronic dispersion can be
reached by electrostatic gating. Here we investigate the dynamics of electrons
in moire minibands by transverse electron focusing, a measurement of ballistic
transport between adjacent local contacts in a magnetic field. At low
temperatures, we observe caustics of skipping orbits extending over hundreds of
superlattice periods, reversals of the cyclotron revolution for successive
minibands, and breakdown of cyclotron motion near van Hove singularities. At
high temperatures, we study the suppression of electron focusing by inelastic
scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02411</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Irie</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todt</keyname><forenames>Clemens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumada</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Yuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugiyama</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akazaki</keyname><forenames>Tatsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muraki</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>Andreev reflection and bound state formation in a ballistic
  two-dimensional electron gas probed by a quantum point contact</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155305 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study coherent transport and bound-state formation of Bogoliubov
quasiparticles in a high-mobility In$_{0.75}%$Ga$_{0.25}$As two-dimensional
electron gas (2DEG) coupled to a superconducting Nb electrode by means of a
quantum point contact (QPC) as a tunable single-mode probe. Below the
superconducting critical temperature of Nb, the QPC shows a single-channel
conductance greater than the conductance quantum $2e^{2}/h$ at zero bias, which
indicates the presence of Andreev-reflected quasiparticles, time-reversed
states of the injected electron, returning back through the QPC. The marked
sensitivity of the conductance enhancement to voltage bias and perpendicular
magnetic field suggests a mechanism analogous to reflectionless tunneling--a
hallmark of phase-coherent transport, with the boundary of the 2DEG cavity
playing the role of scatters. When the QPC transmission is reduced to the
tunneling regime, the differential conductance vs bias voltage probes the
single-particle density of states in the proximity area. Measured conductance
spectra show a double peak within the superconducting gap of Nb, demonstrating
the formation of Andreev bound states in the 2DEG. Both of these results,
obtained in the open and closed geometries, underpin the coherent nature of
quasiparticles, i.e., phase-coherent Andreev reflection at the InGaAs/Nb
interface and coherent propagation in the ballistic 2DEG.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03394</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Hegde</keyname><forenames>Suraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishveshwara</keyname><forenames>Smitha</forenames></author></authors><title>Majorana wavefunction oscillations, fermion parity switches, and
  disorder in Kitaev chains</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>21 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115166 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115166</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the decay and oscillations of Majorana fermion wavefunctions and
ground state (GS) fermion parity in one-dimensional topological superconducting
lattice systems. Using a Majorana transfer matrix method, we find that Majorana
wavefunction properties are encoded in the associated Lyapunov exponent, which
in turn is the sum of two independent components: a `superconducting component'
which characterizes the gap induced decay, and the `normal component', which
determines the oscillations and response to chemical potential configurations.
The topological phase transition separating phases with and without Majorana
end modes is seen to be a cancellation of these two components. We show that
Majorana wavefunction oscillations are completely determined by an underlying
non-superconducting tight-binding model and are solely responsible for GS
fermion parity switches in finite-sized systems. These observations enable us
to analytically chart out wavefunction oscillations, the resultant GS parity
configuration as a function of parameter space in uniform wires, and special
parity switch points where degenerate zero energy Majorana modes are restored
in spite of finite size effects. For disordered wires, we find that band
oscillations are completely washed out leading to a second localization length
for the Majorana mode and the remnant oscillations are randomized as per
Anderson localization physics in normal systems. Our transfer matrix method
further allows us to i) reproduce known results on the scaling of mid-gap
Majorana states and demonstrate the origin of its log-normal distribution, ii)
identify contrasting behavior of disorder-dependent GS parity switches for the
cases of even versus odd number of lattice sites, and iii) chart out the GS
parity configuration and associated parity switch points as a function of
disorder strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03579</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Apollaro</keyname><forenames>Tony J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palma</keyname><forenames>G. Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>Jamir</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement entropy in a periodically driven quantum Ising chain</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 134304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.134304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically study the dynamics of entanglement entropy, induced by an
oscillating time periodic driving of the transverse field, h(t), of a
one-dimensional quantum Ising chain. We consider several realizations of h(t),
and we find a number of results in analogy with entanglement entropy dynamics
induced by a sudden quantum quench. After short-time relaxation, the dynamics
of entanglement entropy synchronises with h(t), displaying an oscillatory
behaviour at the frequency of the driving. Synchronisation in the dynamics of
entanglement entropy, is spoiled by the appearance of quasi-revivals which fade
out in the thermodynamic limit, and which we interpret using a quasi-particle
picture adapted to periodic drivings. Taking the time-average of the
entanglement entropy in the synchronised regime, we find that it obeys a volume
law scaling with the subsystem's size. Such result is reminiscent of a thermal
state or of a Generalised Gibbs ensemble of a quenched Ising chain, although
the system does not heat up towards infinite temperature as a consequence of
the integrability of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03883</id><created>2016-03-12</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sheikhahmadi</keyname><forenames>Haidar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saridakis</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aghamohammadi</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saaidi</keyname><forenames>Khaled</forenames></author></authors><title>Hamilton-Jacobi formalism for inflation with non-minimal derivative
  coupling</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures, version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1610 (2016) no.10, 021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In inflation with nonminimal derivative coupling there is not a conformal
transformation to the Einstein frame where calculations are straightforward,
and thus in order to extract inflationary observables one needs to perform a
detailed and lengthy perturbation investigation. In this work we bypass this
problem by performing a Hamilton-Jacobi analysis, namely rewriting the
cosmological equations considering the scalar field to be the time variable. We
apply the method to two specific models, namely the power-law and the
exponential cases, and for each model we calculate various observables such as
the tensor-to-scalar ratio, and the spectral index and its running. We compare
them with 2013 and 2015 Planck data, and we show that they are in a very good
agreement with observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06858</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2016-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sinitsyn</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pershin</keyname><forenames>Y. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Theory of Spin Noise Spectroscopy: A Review</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Reports on Progress in Physics 79, 106501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/79/10/106501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct measurements of spin fluctuations are becoming the mainstream approach
for studies of complex condensed matter, molecular, nuclear, and atomic
systems. This review covers recent progress in the field of optical Spin Noise
Spectroscopy (SNS) with an additional goal to establish an introduction into
its theoretical foundations. Various theoretical techniques that have been
recently used to interpret results of SNS measurements are explained alongside
with examples of their applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07208</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Macke</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames><affiliation>PhLAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>S&#xe9;gard</keyname><forenames>Bernard</forenames><affiliation>PhLAM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Gain-assisted superluminal light propagation through a
  Bose-Einstein condensate cavity system&quot;</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal D, EDP Sciences, 2016, 70, pp.193</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2016-70210-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent theoretical article [Eur. Phys. J. D 70, 1 (2016)], Kazemi et al.
claim to have demonstrated superluminal light transmission in an optomechanical
system where a Bose-Einstein condensate serves as the mechanical oscillator. In
fact the superluminal propagation is only inferred from the existence of a
minimum of transmission of the system at the probe frequency. This condition is
not sufficient and we show that, in all the cases where superluminal
propagation is claimed by Kazemi et al., the propagation is in reality
subluminal. Moreover, we point out that the system under consideration is not
minimum-phase-shift. The Kramers-Kronig relations then only fix a lower limit
to the group delay and we show that these two quantities have sometimes
opposite signs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01010</id><created>2016-04-04</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rexin</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathey</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnus expansion approach to parametric oscillator systems in a thermal
  bath</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Contribution to special issue of Zeitschrift fuer Naturforschung A, &quot;
  Emergence in driven solid-state and cold-atom systems.&quot;</comments><doi>10.1515/zna-2016-0135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a Magnus formalism for periodically driven systems which provides
an expansion both in the driving term and the inverse driving frequency,
applicable to isolated and dissipative systems. We derive explicit formulas for
a driving term with a cosine dependence on time, up to fourth order. We apply
these to the steady state of a classical parametric oscillator coupled to a
thermal bath, which we solve numerically for comparison. Beyond dynamical
stabilization at second order, we find that the higher orders further
renormalize the oscillator frequency, and additionally create a weakly
renormalized effective temperature. The renormalized oscillator frequency is
quantitatively accurate almost up to the parametric instability, as we confirm
numerically. Additionally, a cut-off dependent term is generated, which
indicates the break-down of the hierarchy of time scales of the system, as a
precursor to the instability. Finally, we apply this formalism to a
parametrically driven chain, as an example for the control of the dispersion of
a many-body system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02413</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blomer</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgain</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radziwi&#x142;&#x142;</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudnick</keyname><forenames>Zeev</forenames></author></authors><title>Small gaps in the spectrum of the rectangular billiard</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.NT math.PR</categories><comments>minor changes</comments><msc-class>35P20, 11E16</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the size of the minimal gap between the first N eigenvalues of the
Laplacian on a rectangular billiard having irrational squared aspect ratio
$\alpha$, in comparison to the corresponding quantity for a Poissonian
sequence. If $\alpha$ is a quadratic irrationality of certain type, such as the
square root of a rational number, we show that the minimal gap is roughly of
size 1/N, which is essentially consistent with Poisson statistics. We also give
related results for a set of $\alpha$'s of full measure. However, on a fine
scale we show that Poisson statistics is violated for all $\alpha$. The proofs
use a variety of ideas of an arithmetical nature, involving Diophantine
approximation, the theory of continued fractions, and results in analytic
number theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02499</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Odashima</keyname><forenames>Mariana M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prado</keyname><forenames>Beatriz G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vernek</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pedagogical introduction to equilibrium Green's functions: condensed
  matter examples with numerical implementations</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>24 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Bras. Ens. Fis., 39, e1303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1590/1806-9126-RBEF-2016-0087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Green's function method has applications in several fields in Physics,
from classical differential equations to quantum many-body problems. In the
quantum context, Green's functions are correlation functions, from which it is
possible to extract information from the system under study, such as the
density of states, relaxation times and response functions. Despite its power
and versatility, it is known as a laborious and sometimes cumbersome method.
Here we introduce the equilibrium Green's functions and the equation-of-motion
technique, exemplifying the method in discrete lattices of non-interacting
electrons. We start with simple models, such as the two-site molecule, the
infinite and semi-infinite one-dimensional chains, and the two-dimensional
ladder. Numerical implementations are developed via the recursive Green's
function, implemented in Julia, an open-source, efficient and easy-to-learn
scientific language. We also present a new variation of the surface recursive
Green's function method, which can be of interest when simulating
simultaneously the properties of surface and bulk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05080</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Friedmann</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schemmel</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruebl</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartel</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hock</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>Karlheinz</forenames></author></authors><title>Demonstrating Hybrid Learning in a Flexible Neuromorphic Hardware System</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.dis-nn cs.NE</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from a new approach to learning and plasticity in
neuromorphic hardware systems: to enable flexibility in implementable learning
mechanisms while keeping high efficiency associated with neuromorphic
implementations, we combine a general-purpose processor with full-custom analog
elements.
  This processor is operating in parallel with a fully parallel neuromorphic
system consisting of an array of synapses connected to analog, continuous time
neuron circuits. Novel analog correlation sensor circuits process spike events
for each synapse in parallel and in real-time.
  The processor uses this pre-processing to compute new weights possibly using
additional information following its program.
  Therefore, learning rules can be defined in software giving a large degree of
flexibility.
  Synapses realize correlation detection geared towards Spike-Timing Dependent
Plasticity (STDP) as central computational primitive in the analog domain.
  Operating at a speed-up factor of 1000 compared to biological time-scale, we
measure time-constants from tens to hundreds of micro-seconds.
  We analyze variability across multiple chips and demonstrate learning using a
multiplicative STDP rule.
  We conclude, that the presented approach will enable flexible and efficient
learning as a platform for neuroscientific research and technological
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08582</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bash</keyname><forenames>Boulat A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandrasekaran</keyname><forenames>Nivedita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Saikat</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Key Distribution Using Multiple Gaussian Focused Beams</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The secret key rate attained by a free-space QKD system in the {\em
near-field} propagation regime (relevant for $1$-$10$ km range using $\approx
7$ cm radii transmit and receive apertures and $1.55~\mu$m transmission center
wavelenght) can benefit from the use of multiple spatial modes. A suite of
theoretical research in recent years have suggested the use of
orbital-angular-momentum (OAM) bearing spatial modes of light to obtain this
improvement in rate. We show that most of the aforesaid rate improvement in the
near field afforded by spatial-mode multiplexing can be realized by a
simple-to-build overlapping Gaussian beam array (OGBA) and a pixelated detector
array. With the current state-of-the-art in OAM-mode-sorting efficiencies, the
key-rate performance of our OGBA architecture could come very close to, if not
exceed, that of a system employing OAM modes, but at a fraction of the cost.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00213</id><created>2016-05-01</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Enkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Lixin</forenames></author></authors><title>Distinguish three time-dependent dark energy models using statefinder
  pairs with error bars and Bayesian evidence</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, two completely different approaches, statefinder with error
bars and Bayesian evidence, are used to distinguish and judge three
time-dependent dark energy models. The parameters constrain for the three dark
energy models are given using the current cosmic observational data sets :
$Planck$ 2015, SNIa, BAO and OHD. Using the statefinder pairs with error bars,
we find that the error region of the dark energy model, whose equation of state
parameter is given by $w(a) = w_0+w_3\frac{1-a}{a^2+(1-a)^2}$, is relativity
compact than the other two models during the all the evolving history.
Meanwhile, the Bayesian evidence also provide that this model is significantly
better than the other two models and the other two models are inconclusive.
Then, there are reasons for believing that this model is a preferential
candidate in dark energy investigation rather than the other two.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00875</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaur</keyname><forenames>Harneet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Sandeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Nidhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Jorg J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>O. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Ved Varun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Ritu</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Area Fabrication of Semiconducting Phosphorene by Langmuir
  Blodgett Assembly</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures in main paper, 7 supporting figures</comments><doi>10.1038/srep34095</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although a considerable number of solvent based methodologies have been
developed for exfoliating black phosphorus, so far there are no reports on
controlled organization of these exfoliated nanosheets on substrates. Here, for
the first time to the best of our knowledge, a mixture of
N-Methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP) and deoxygenated water is employed as a subphase
in Langmuir Blodgett (LB) trough for assembling the nanosheets followed by
their deposition on substrates and studied its field effect transistor (FET)
characteristics. Electron microscopy reveals the presence of densely aligned,
crystalline, ultra-thin sheets of pristine phosphorene having lateral
dimensions larger than hundred of microns. Furthermore, these assembled
nanosheets retain their electronic properties and show a high current
modulation of 10^4 at room temperature in FET devices. The proposed technique
provides semiconducting phosphorene thin films that are amenable for large area
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01667</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Molinari</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruppuso</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natoli</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on parity violation from ACTpol and forecasts for
  forthcoming CMB experiments</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures Version matching the published version</comments><journal-ref>Physics of the Dark Universe, Volume 14, December 2016, Pages
  65-72</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the ACTpol published cosmic microwave background (CMB) polarization
data to constrain cosmological birefringence, a tracer of parity violation
beyond the standard model of particle physics. To this purpose, we employ all
the polarized ACTpol spectra, including the cross-correlations between
temperature anisotropy and B mode polarization (TB) and between E mode and B
mode (EB), which are most sensitive to the effect. We build specific, so-called
D-estimators for birefringence and assess their performances and error budgets
by using realistic Monte Carlo simulations based on the experimental
characteristics provided by the ACTpol collaboration. We determine the optimal
multipole range for our analysis to be $250 &lt; \ell &lt; 3025$ over which we find a
null result for the uniform birefringence angle $\alpha = 0.29^\circ \pm
0.28^\circ$ (stat.) $\pm 0.5^\circ$ (syst.), the latter uncertainty being the
estimate published by the ACTpol team on their global systematic error budget.
We show that this result holds consistently when other multipole ranges are
considered. Finally, we forecast the capability of several forthcoming ground
based, balloon and space borne CMB experiments to constrain the birefringence
angle, showing, e.g., that the proposed post-Planck COrE satellite mission
could in principle constrain $\alpha$ at a level of 10 arcsec, provided that
all systematics are under control. Under the same circumstances, we find the
COrE constraints to be at least 2 or 3 times better than what could ideally be
achieved by the other experiments considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01906</id><created>2016-05-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Berngardt</keyname><forenames>O. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutelev</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potekhin</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>SuperDARN scalar radar equations</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.space-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 5 figures, Submitted to Radio Science</comments><doi>10.1002/2016RS006081</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quadratic scalar radar equations are obtained for SuperDARN radars that
are suitable for the analysis and interpretation of experimental data. The
paper is based on a unified approach to the obtaining radar equations for the
monostatic and bistatic sounding with use of hamiltonian optics and ray
representation of scalar Green's function and without taking into account the
polarization effects. The radar equation obtained is the sum of several terms
corresponding to the propagation and scattering over the different kinds of
trajectories, depending on their smoothness and the possibility of reflection
from the ionosphere. It is shown that the monostatic sounding in the media with
significant refraction, unlike the case of refraction-free media, should be
analyzed as a combination of monostatic and bistatic scattering. This leads to
strong dependence of scattering amplitude on background ionospheric density due
to focusing mechanism and appearance of new (bistatic) areas of effective
scattering with significant distortion of the scattered signal spectrum.
Selective properties of the scattering also have been demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04623</id><created>2016-05-15</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Daming</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison between Fermion Bag Approach and Complex Langevin Dynamics
  for Massive Thirring Model at Finite Density in 0 + 1 Dimensions</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the massive Thirring model at finite density in 0+1 dimension.
The fermion bag approach, Langevin dynamics and complex Langevin dynamics are
adopted to attack the sign problem for this model. Compared with the complex
Langevin dynamics, both fermion bag approach and Langvin dynamics avoid the
sign problem. The fermion density and chiral condensate, which are obtained by
these numerical methods, are compared with the exact results. The advantages of
the fermion bag approach over the other numerical methods are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05737</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Serbyn</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michailidis</keyname><forenames>Alexios A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abanin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Power-Law Entanglement Spectrum in Many-Body Localized Phases</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>v1: 5 pages, 4 figures; v2: extended bibliography, fixed typos,
  extended supplementary material, close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 160601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.160601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The entanglement spectrum of the reduced density matrix contains information
beyond the von Neumann entropy and provides unique insights into exotic orders
or critical behavior of quantum systems. Here, we show that strongly disordered
systems in the many-body localized phase have power-law entanglement spectra,
arising from the presence of extensively many local integrals of motion. The
power-law entanglement spectrum distinguishes many-body localized systems from
ergodic systems, as well as from ground states of gapped integrable models or
free systems in the vicinity of scale-invariant critical points. We confirm our
results using large-scale exact diagonalization. In addition, we develop a
matrix-product state algorithm which allows us to access the eigenstates of
large systems close to the localization transition, and discuss general
implications of our results for variational studies of highly excited
eigenstates in many-body localized systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07350</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-10-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Zehua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jieci</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Jiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dragan</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting the Curvature of de Sitter Universe with Two Entangled Atoms</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17pages, no figures. Accepted in Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 35222 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep35222</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Casimir-Polder interaction arises from the vacuum fluctuations of quantum
field that depend on spacetime curvature and thus is spacetime-dependent. Here
we show how to use the resonance Casimir-Polder interaction (RCPI) between two
entangled atoms to detect spacetime curvature. We find that the RCPI of two
static entangled atoms in the de Sitter-invariant vacuum depends on the de
Sitter spacetime curvature relevant to the temperature felt by the static
observer. It is characterized by a $1/L^2$ power law decay when beyond a
characteristic length scale associated to the breakdown of a local inertial
description of the two-atom system. However, the RCPI of the same setup
embedded in a thermal bath in the Minkowski universe is temperature-independent
and is always characterized by a $1/L$ power law decay. Therefore, although a
single static atom in the de Sitter-invariant vacuum responds as if it were
bathed in thermal radiation in a Minkowski universe, using the distinct
difference between RCPI of two entangled atoms one can in principle distinguish
these two universes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00607</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Perez-Reche</keyname><forenames>Francisco J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triguero</keyname><forenames>Carles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanzotto</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truskinovsky</keyname><forenames>Lev</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of scale-free intermittency in structural first-order phase
  transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages, 22 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 144102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.144102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A salient feature of cyclically driven first-order phase transformations in
crystals is their scale-free avalanche dynamics. This behavior has been linked
to the presence of a classical critical point but the mechanism leading to
criticality without extrinsic tuning remains unexplained. Here we show that the
source of scaling in such systems is an annealed disorder associated with
transformation-induced slip which co-evolves with the phase transformation,
thus ensuring the crossing of a critical manifold. Our conclusions are based on
a model where annealed disorder emerges in the form of a random field induced
by the phase transition. Such disorder exhibits super-transient chaotic
behavior under thermal loading, obeys a heavy-tailed distribution and exhibits
long-range spatial correlations. We show that the universality class is
affected by the long-range character of elastic interactions. In contrast, it
is not influenced by the heavy-tailed distribution and spatial correlations of
disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01388</id><created>2016-06-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>Jacopo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tengattini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tchernij</keyname><forenames>Sviatoslav Ditalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>Alfio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traina</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degiovanni</keyname><forenames>Ivo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreva</keyname><forenames>Ekaterina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brida</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grilj</keyname><forenames>Veljko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skukan</keyname><forenames>Natko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jak&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Milko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Creation and characterization of He-related color centers in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Luminescence 179 (2016) 59-63</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jlumin.2016.06.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diamond is a promising material for the development of emerging applications
in quantum optics, quantum information and quantum sensing. The fabrication and
characterization of novel luminescent defects with suitable opto-physical
properties is therefore of primary importance for further advances in these
research fields. In this work we report on the investigation in the formation
of photoluminescent (PL) defects upon MeV He implantation in diamond. Such
color centers, previously reported only in electroluminescence and
cathodoluminescence regime, exhibited two sharp emission lines at 536.5 nm and
560.5 nm, without significant phonon sidebands. A strong correlation between
the PL intensities of the above-mentioned emission lines and the He
implantation fluence was found in the 10^15-10^17 cm^{-2} fluence range. The PL
emission features were not detected in control samples, i.e. samples that were
either unirradiated or irradiated with different ion species (H, C). Moreover,
the PL emission lines disappeared in samples that were He-implanted above the
graphitization threshold. Therefore, the PL features are attributed to
optically active defects in the diamond matrix associated with He impurities.
The intensity of the 536.5 nm and 560.5 nm emission lines was investigated as a
function of the annealing temperature of the diamond substrate. The emission
was observed upon annealing at temperatures higher than 500{\deg}C, at the
expenses of the concurrently decreasing neutral-vacancy-related GR1 emission
intensity. Therefore, our findings indicate that the luminescence originates
from the formation of a stable lattice defect. Finally, the emission was
investigated under different laser excitations wavelengths (i.e. 532 nm and 405
nm) with the purpose of gaining a preliminary insight about the position of the
related levels in the energy gap of diamond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01464</id><created>2016-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Liheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Guoan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Kaikai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suo</keyname><forenames>Jinli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Changhuei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Qionghai</forenames></author></authors><title>Motion-corrected Fourier ptychography</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1364/BOE.7.004543</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fourier ptychography (FP) is a recently proposed computational imaging
technique for high space-bandwidth product imaging. In real setups such as
endoscope and transmission electron microscope, the common sample motion
largely degrades the FP reconstruction and limits its practicability. In this
paper, we propose a novel FP reconstruction method to efficiently correct for
unknown sample motion. Specifically, we adaptively update the sample's Fourier
spectrum from low spatial-frequency regions towards high spatial-frequency
ones, with an additional motion recovery and phase-offset compensation
procedure for each sub-spectrum. Benefiting from the phase retrieval redundancy
theory, the required large overlap between adjacent sub-spectra offers an
accurate guide for successful motion recovery. Experimental results on both
simulated data and real captured data show that the proposed method can correct
for unknown sample motion with its standard deviation being up to 10% of the
field-of-view scale. We have released our source code for non-commercial use,
and it may find wide applications in related FP platforms such as endoscopy and
transmission electron microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04120</id><created>2016-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>McQuinn</keyname><forenames>Kristen. B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skillman</keyname><forenames>Evan D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolphin</keyname><forenames>Andrew E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Danielle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennicutt</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>The Distance to M51</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 826, 21 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/21</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Great investments of observing time have been dedicated to the study of
nearby spiral galaxies with diverse goals ranging from understanding the star
formation process to characterizing their dark matter distributions. Accurate
distances are fundamental to interpreting observations of these galaxies, yet
many of the best studied nearby galaxies have distances based on methods with
relatively large uncertainties. We have started a program to derive accurate
distances to these galaxies. Here we measure the distance to M51 - the
Whirlpool galaxy - from newly obtained Hubble Space Telescope optical imaging
using the tip of the red giant branch method. We measure the distance modulus
to be 8.58+/-0.10 Mpc (statistical), corresponding to a distance modulus of
29.67+/-0.02 mag. Our distance is an improvement over previous results as we
use a well-calibrated, stable distance indicator, precision photometry in a
optimally selected field of view, and a Bayesian Maximum Likelihood technique
that reduces measurement uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05665</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Atay</keyname><forenames>Fatihcan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banisch</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cessac</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olbrich</keyname><forenames>Eckehard</forenames></author></authors><title>Perspectives on Multi-Level Dynamics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph math-ph math.MP nlin.AO quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Discontinuity, Nonlinearity, and Complexity, 5(3) 313--339 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.5890/DNC.2016.09.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As Physics did in previous centuries, there is currently a common dream of
extracting generic laws of nature in economics, sociology, neuroscience, by
focalising the description of phenomena to a minimal set of variables and
parameters, linked together by causal equations of evolution whose structure
may reveal hidden principles. This requires a huge reduction of dimensionality
(number of degrees of freedom) and a change in the level of description. Beyond
the mere necessity of developing accurate techniques affording this reduction,
there is the question of the correspondence between the initial system and the
reduced one. In this paper, we offer a perspective towards a common framework
for discussing and understanding multi-level systems exhibiting structures at
various spatial and temporal levels. We propose a common foundation and
illustrate it with examples from different fields. We also point out the
difficulties in constructing such a general setting and its limitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05671</id><created>2016-06-17</created><updated>2016-09-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rauscher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cescutti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>A. St. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heger</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainties in the production of $p$ nuclei in massive stars obtained
  from Monte Carlo variations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures; v2: slightly revised, typos amended, accepted
  for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 463 (2016) 4153</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2266</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nuclear uncertainties in the production of $p$ nuclei in massive stars have
been quantified in a Monte Carlo procedure. Bespoke temperature-dependent
uncertainties were assigned to different types of reactions involving nuclei
from Fe to Bi. Their simultaneous impact was studied in postprocessing
explosive trajectories for three different stellar models. It was found that
the grid of mass zones in the model of a 25 $M_\odot$ star, which is widely
used for investigations of $p$ nucleosynthesis, is too crude to properly
resolve the detailed temperature changes required for describing the production
of $p$ nuclei. Using models with finer grids for 15 $M_\odot$ and 25 $M_\odot$
stars with initial solar metallicity, it was found that most of the production
uncertainties introduced by nuclear reaction uncertainties are smaller than a
factor of two. Since a large number of rates were varied at the same time in
the Monte Carlo procedure, possible cancellation effects of several
uncertainties could be taken into account. Key rates were identified for each
$p$ nucleus, which provide the dominant contribution to the production
uncertainty. These key rates were found by examining correlations between rate
variations and resulting abundance changes. This method is superior to studying
flow patterns, especially when the flows are complex, and to individual,
sequential variation of a few rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06463</id><created>2016-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Balz</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lake</keyname><forenames>Bella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuther</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luetkens</keyname><forenames>Hubertus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nemann</keyname><forenames>Rico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmannsd&#xf6;rfer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Yogesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>A. T. M. Nazmul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wheeler</keyname><forenames>Elisa M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Rivera</keyname><forenames>Jose A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guidi</keyname><forenames>Tatiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simeoni</keyname><forenames>Giovanna G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baines</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryll</keyname><forenames>Hanjo</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical realization of a quantum spin liquid based on a novel
  frustration mechanism</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Modified version accepted in Nature Physics</comments><journal-ref>Nature Phys. 12, 942-949 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike conventional magnets where the magnetic moments are partially or
completely static in the ground state, in a quantum spin liquid they remain in
collective motion down to the lowest temperatures. The importance of this state
is that it is coherent and highly entangled without breaking local symmetries.
Such phenomena is usually sought in simple lattices where antiferromagnetic
interactions and/or anisotropies that favor specific alignments of the magnetic
moments are &quot;frustrated&quot; by lattice geometries incompatible with such order
e.g. triangular structures. Despite an extensive search among such compounds,
experimental realizations remain very few. Here we describe the investigation
of a novel, unexplored magnetic system consisting of strong ferromagnetic and
weaker antiferromagnetic isotropic interactions as realized by the compound
Ca$_{10}$Cr$_7$O$_{28}$. Despite its exotic structure we show both
experimentally and theoretically that it displays all the features expected of
a quantum spin liquid including coherent spin dynamics in the ground state and
the complete absence of static magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09434</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ohtani</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gubler</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative-parity nucleon excited state in nuclear matter</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 045203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.045203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spectral functions of the nucleon and its negative parity excited state in
nuclear matter are studied using QCD sum rules and the maximum entropy method
(MEM). It is found that in-medium modifications of the spectral functions are
attributed mainly to density dependencies of the $\langle \bar{q}q \rangle $
and $\langle q^{\dagger}q \rangle $ condensates. The MEM reproduces the
lowest-energy peaks of both the positive and negative parity nucleon states at
finite density up to $\rho \sim \rho_N$ (normal nuclear matter density). As the
density grows, the residue of the nucleon ground state decreases gradually
while the residue of the lowest negative parity excited state increases
slightly. On the other hand, the positions of the peaks, which correspond to
the total energies of these states, are almost density independent for both
parity states. The density dependencies of the effective masses and vector
self-energies are also extracted by assuming the mean-field green functions for
the peak states. We find that, as the density increases, the nucleon effective
mass decreases while the vector self-energy increases. The density dependence
of these quantities for the negative parity state on the other hand turns out
to be relatively weak.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09502</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dupont</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capponi</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laflorencie</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature dependence of the NMR relaxation rate 1/T_1 for quantum spin
  chains</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 144409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.144409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results of numerical simulations performed on one-dimensional spin
chains in order to extract the so-called relaxation rate $1/T_1$ accessible
through NMR experiments. Building on numerical tensor network methods using the
Matrix Product States (MPS) formalism, we can follow the non-trivial crossover
occurring in critical chains between the high-temperature diffusive classical
regime and the low-temperature response described by the Tomonaga-Luttinger
liquid (TLL) theory, for which analytical expressions are known. In order to
compare analytics and numerics, we focus on a generic spin-$1/2$ XXZ chain
which is a paradigm of gapless TLL, as well as a more realistic spin-$1$
anisotropic chain, modelling the DTN material, which can be either in a trivial
gapped phase or in a TLL regime induced by an external magnetic field. Thus, by
monitoring the finite temperature crossover, we provide quantitative limits on
the range of validity of TLL theory, that will be useful when interpreting
experiments on quasi one-dimensional materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00125</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kerbikov</keyname><forenames>B. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukashov</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluctuation sound absorption in quark matter</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 32 (2016) 1650179</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501790</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the sound absorption in quark matter due to the interaction of
the sound wave with the precritical fluctuations of the diquark-pair field
above $T_c$. The soft collective mode of the pair field is derived using the
time dependent Ginzburg-Landau functional with random Langevin forces. The
strong absorption near the phase transition line may be viewed as a
manifestation of the Mandelshtam-Leontovich slow relaxation time theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00568</id><created>2016-07-02</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Balram</keyname><forenames>Ajit C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting composite fermions: Nature of the 4/5, 5/7, 6/7, and 6/17
  fractional quantum Hall states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures, changed title, minor changes in text, published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 165303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.165303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical studies by W\'ojs, Yi and Quinn have suggested that an
unconventional fractional quantum Hall effect is plausible at filling factors
$\nu=$ 1/3 and 1/5, provided the interparticle interaction has an unusual form
for which the energy of two fermions in the relative angular momentum three
channel dominates. The interaction between composite fermions in the second
$\Lambda$ level (composite fermion analog of the electronic Landau level)
satisfies this property, and recent studies have supported unconventional
fractional quantum Hall effect of composite fermions at $\nu^*=$ 4/3 and 5/3,
which manifests as fractional quantum Hall effect of electrons at $\nu=$ 4/11,
4/13, 5/13, and 5/17. I investigate in this article the nature of the
fractional quantum Hall states at $\nu=$ 4/5, 5/7, 6/17, and 6/7, which
correspond to composite fermions at $\nu^*=$ 4/3, 5/3 and 6/5, and find that
all these fractional quantum Hall states are conventional. The underlying
reason is that the interaction between composite fermions depends substantially
on both the number and the direction of the vortices attached to the electrons.
I also study in detail the states with different spin polarizations at 6/17 and
6/7 and predict the critical Zeeman energies for the spin phase transitions
between them. I calculate the excitation gaps at 4/5, 5/7, 6/7, and 6/17 and
compare them against recent experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03118</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oltean</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonetti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spallicci</keyname><forenames>Alessandro D. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sopuerta</keyname><forenames>Carlos F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy theorems in classical mechanics, general relativity, and the
  gravitational two-body problem</title><categories>gr-qc cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>39 pages, 3 figures; v2: version to appear in Phys. Rev. D,
  references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064049 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In classical Hamiltonian theories, entropy may be understood either as a
statistical property of canonical systems, or as a mechanical property, that
is, as a monotonic function of the phase space along trajectories. In classical
mechanics, there are theorems which have been proposed for proving the
non-existence of entropy in the latter sense. We explicate, clarify and extend
the proofs of these theorems to some standard matter (scalar and
electromagnetic) field theories in curved spacetime, and then we show why these
proofs fail in general relativity; due to properties of the gravitational
Hamiltonian and phase space measures, the second law of thermodynamics holds.
As a concrete application, we focus on the consequences of these results for
the gravitational two-body problem, and in particular, we prove the
non-compactness of the phase space of perturbed Schwarzschild-Droste
spacetimes. We thus identify the lack of recurring orbits in phase space as a
distinct sign of dissipation and hence entropy production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03726</id><created>2016-07-13</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pellegrino</keyname><forenames>Francesco M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torre</keyname><forenames>Iacopo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geim</keyname><forenames>Andre K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron hydrodynamics dilemma: whirlpools or no whirlpools</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155414 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In highly viscous electron systems such as, for example, high quality
graphene above liquid nitrogen temperature, a linear response to applied
electric current becomes essentially nonlocal, which can give rise to a number
of new and counterintuitive phenomena including negative nonlocal resistance
and current whirlpools. It has also been shown that, although both effects
originate from high electron viscosity, a negative voltage drop does not
principally require current backflow. In this work, we study the role of
geometry on viscous flow and show that confinement effects and relative
positions of injector and collector contacts play a pivotal role in the
occurrence of whirlpools. Certain geometries may exhibit backflow at
arbitrarily small values of the electron viscosity, whereas others require a
specific threshold value for whirlpools to emerge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03941</id><created>2016-07-13</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>Tanya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vamivakas</keyname><forenames>A. Nick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberly</keyname><forenames>Joseph H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence Constraints and the Last Hidden Optical Coherence</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Accepted by Physical Review Letters</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 153901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.153901</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We have discovered a new domain of optical coherence, and show that it is the
third and last member of a previously unreported fundamental triad of
coherences. These are unified by our derivation of a parallel triad of
coherence constraints that take the form of complementarity relations. We have
been able to enter this new coherence domain experimentally and we describe the
novel tomographic approach devised for that purpose.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06731</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Lytel</keyname><forenames>Rick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mossman</keyname><forenames>Sean M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzyk</keyname><forenames>Mark G.</forenames></author></authors><title>General solution to nonlinear optical quantum graphs using
  Dalgarno-Lewis summation techniques</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 33(12), E14-E23 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.33.000E14</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop an algorithm to apply the Dalgarno-Lewis (DL) perturbation theory
to quantum graphs with multiple, connected edges. We use it to calculate the
nonlinear optical hyperpolarizability tensors for graphs and show that it
replicates the sum over states computations, but executes ten to fifty times
faster. DL requires only knowledge of the ground state of the graph,
eliminating the requirement to determine all possible degeneracies of a complex
network. The algorithm is general and may be applied to any quantum graph.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01424</id><created>2016-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Mowbray</keyname><forenames>Duncan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paz</keyname><forenames>Alejandro P&#xe9;rez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz-Soria</keyname><forenames>Georgina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauer</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacovig</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalmiglio</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizzit</keyname><forenames>Silvano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldoni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pichler</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ayala</keyname><forenames>Paola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author></authors><title>Disentangling Vacancy Oxidation on Metallicity-Sorted Carbon Nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><report-no>YACHAY-PUB-16-03-PN</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, 2016, 120 (32), pp 18316-18322</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b06163</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pristine single-walled carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs) are rather inert to O$_2$
and N$_2$, which for low doses chemisorb only on defect sites or vacancies of
the SWCNTs at the ppm level. However, very low doping has a major effect on the
electronic properties and conductivity of the SWCNTs. Already at low O$_2$
doses (80 L), the X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) O 1s signal becomes
saturated, indicating nearly all the SWCNT's vacancies have been oxidized. As a
result, probing vacancy oxidation on SWCNTs via XPS yields spectra with rather
low signal-to-noise ratios, even for metallicity-sorted SWCNTs. We show that,
even under these conditions, the first principles density functional theory
calculated Kohn-Sham O 1s binding energies may be used to assign the XPS O 1s
spectra for oxidized vacancies on SWCNTs into its individual components. This
allows one to determine the specific functional groups or bonding environments
measured. We find the XPS O 1s signal is mostly due to three O-containing
functional groups on SWCNT vacancies: epoxy (C$_2$$&gt;$O), carbonyl
(C$_2$$&gt;$C$=$O), and ketene (C$=$C$=$O), as ordered by abundance. Upon
oxidation of nearly all the SWCNT's vacancies, the central peak's intensity for
the metallic SWCNT sample is 60\% greater than for the semiconducting SWCNT
sample. This suggests a greater abundance of O-containing defect structures on
the metallic SWCNT sample. For both metallic and semiconducting SWCNTs, we find
O$_2$ does not contribute to the measured XPS O~1s spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02491</id><created>2016-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Carrillo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gracia-Linares</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzm&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parameter estimates in binary black hole collisions using neural
  networks</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 9 eps figures</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Rel. Grav. 48, 141 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2136-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an algorithm based on artificial neural networks (ANNs), that
estimates the mass ratio in a binary black hole collision out of given
Gravitational Wave (GW) strains. In this analysis, the ANN is trained with a
sample of GW signals generated with numerical simulations. The effectiveness of
the algorithm is evaluated with GWs generated also with simulations for given
mass ratios unknown to the ANN. We measure the accuracy of the algorithm in the
interpolation and extrapolation regimes. We present the results for noise free
signals and signals contaminated with Gaussian noise, in order to foresee the
dependence of the method accuracy in terms of the signal to noise ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03149</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2016-09-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Wynn C. G.</forenames><affiliation>Univ of Southampton</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames><affiliation>Univ of Southampton</affiliation></author></authors><title>Ejector and propeller spin-down: How might a superluminous supernova
  millisecond magnetar become the 6.67 hr pulsar in RCW103</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures; accepted for publication in MNRAS Letters; v2,
  minor edits and references added</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. R. Astron. Soc. Lett. 464, L65-L69 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw186</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The X-ray source 1E 161348-5055 in the supernova remnant RCW 103 recently
exhibited X-ray activity typical of magnetars, i.e. neutron stars with magnetic
fields &gt; 10^14-10^15 G. However, 1E 161348-5055 has an observed period of 6.67
hr, in contrast to magnetars which have a spin period of seconds. Here we
describe a simple model which can explain the spin evolution of 1E 161348-5055,
as well as other magnetars, from an initial period of milliseconds that would
be required for dynamo generation of magnetar-strength magnetic fields. We
propose that the key difference between 1E 161348-5055 and other magnetars is
the persistence of a remnant disk of small total mass. This disk caused 1E
161348-5055 to undergo ejector and propeller phases in its life, during which
strong torques caused a rapid increase of its spin period. By matching its
observed spin period and ~1-3 kyr age, we find that 1E 161348-5055 has the
(slightly) highest magnetic field of all known magnetars, with B~5x10^15 G, and
that its disk had a mass of ~10^24 g, comparable to that of the asteroid Ceres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05854</id><created>2016-08-20</created><updated>2016-09-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Thomas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prunet</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drissen</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal fitting of gaussian-apodized or under-resolved emission lines in
  Fourier Transform spectra providing new insights on the velocity structure of
  NGC 6720</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An analysis of the kinematics of NGC 6720 is performed on the commissioning
data obtained with SITELLE, the Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope's new imaging
Fourier transform spectrometer. In order to measure carefully the small
broadening effect of a shell expansion on an unresolved emission line, we have
determined a computationally robust implementation of the convolution of a
Gaussian with a sinc instrumental line shape which avoids arithmetic overflows.
This model can be used to measure line broadening of typically a few km/s even
at low spectral resolution (R less than 5000). We have also designed the
corresponding set of Gaussian apodizing functions that are now used by ORBS,
the SITELLE's reduction pipeline. We have implemented this model in ORCS, a
fitting engine for SITELLE's data, and used it to derive the [SII] density map
of the central part of the nebula. The study of the broadening of the [NII]
lines shows that the Main Ring and the Central Lobe are two different shells
with different expansion velocities. We have also derived deep and spatially
resolved velocity maps of the Halo in [NII] and Halpha and found that the
brightest bubbles are originating from two bipolar structures with a velocity
difference of more than 35 km/s lying at the poles of a possibly unique Halo
shell expanding at a velocity of more than 15 km/s.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00043</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deriglazov</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pupasov-Maksimov</keyname><forenames>Andrey M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic corrections to the algebra of position variables and
  spin-orbital interaction</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages, typos corrected, presentation improved</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 761 (2016) 207-212</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of vector model of spin, we discuss the problem of a
covariant formalism \cite{Pomeranskii1998} concerning the discrepancy between
relativistic and Pauli Hamiltonians. We show how the spin-induced non
commutativity of a position accounts the discrepancy on the classical level,
without appeal to the Dirac equation and Foldy-Wouthuysen transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00397</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sela</keyname><forenames>Orr</forenames></author></authors><title>Late-time decay of coupled electromagnetic and gravitational
  perturbations outside an extremal charged black hole</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages. Corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 084006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.084006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we employ the results of a previous paper on the late-time
decay of scalar-field perturbations of an extreme Reissner-Nordstrom black
hole, in order to find the late-time decay of coupled electromagnetic and
gravitational perturbations of this black hole. We explicitly write the
late-time tails of Moncrief's gauge invariant variables and of the
perturbations of the metric tensor and the electromagnetic field tensor in the
Regge-Wheeler gauge. We discuss some of the consequences of the results and
relations to previous works.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01478</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolcini</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iotti</keyname><forenames>Rita Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montorsi</keyname><forenames>Arianna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Fausto</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoexcitation of electron wave packets in quantum spin Hall edge
  states: effects of chiral anomaly from a localised electric pulse</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 165412 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.165412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that, when a spatially localised electric pulse is applied at the
edge of a quantum spin Hall system, electron wavepackets of the helical states
can be photoexcited by purely intra-branch electrical transitions, without
invoking the bulk states or the magnetic Zeeman coupling. In particular, as
long as the electric pulse remains applied, the photoexcited densities lose
their character of right- and left-movers, whereas after the ending of the
pulse they propagate in opposite directions without dispersion, i.e.
maintaining their space profile unaltered. Notably we find that, while the
momentum distribution of the photoexcited wave packets depends on the
temperature $T$ and the chemical potential $\mu$ of the initial equilibrium
state and displays a non-linear behavior on the amplitude of the applied pulse,
in the mesoscopic regime the space profile of the wave packets is independent
of $T$ and $\mu$. Instead, it depends purely on the applied electric pulse, in
a linear manner, as a signature of the chiral anomaly characterising massless
Dirac electrons. We also discuss how the photoexcited wave packets can be
tailored with the electric pulse parameters, for both low and finite
frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04729</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Pin</forenames></author></authors><title>Momentum dissipation and holographic transport without self-duality</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>33 pages, 14 figures, typo corrected, references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We implement the momentum dissipation introduced by spatial linear axionic
fields in a holographic model without self-duality, broke by Weyl tensor
coupling to Maxwell field, and study its response. It is found that for the
positive Weyl coupling parameter $\gamma&gt;0$, the momentum dissipation
characterized by parameter $\hat{\alpha}$ drives the boundary conformal field
theory (CFT), in which the conductivity exhibits a peak at low frequency, into
the incoherent metallic phase with a dip, which is away from CFT due to the
introduction of axionic fields. While for $\gamma&lt;0$, an oppositive scenario is
found. Our present model provides a possible route toward the problem that
which sign of $\gamma$ is the correct description of the CFT of boson Hubbard
model. In addition, we also investigate the DC conductivity, diffusion constant
and susceptibility. We find that for each of these observables there is a
specific value of $\hat{\alpha}$, for which these observables are independent
of $\gamma$. Finally, the electromagnetic (EM) duality is also studied and we
find that there is also a specific value of $\hat{\alpha}$, for which the
particle-vortex duality related by the change of the sign of $\gamma$ in the
boundary theory holds better than for other values of $\hat{\alpha}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04733</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Elkafrawy</keyname><forenames>Tamer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanis</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warczak</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-photon emission associated with double electron capture in F9+ +
  C collisions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to Phys. Rev. A</comments><msc-class>81V45</msc-class><journal-ref>Physical Review A 94, 042705 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.042705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Radiative double electron capture (RDEC), the one-step process occurring in
ion-atom collisions, has been investigated for bare fluorine ions colliding
with carbon. RDEC is completed when two target electrons are captured to a
bound state of a projectile simultaneously with the emission of a single
photon. This work is a follow-up to our earlier measurement of RDEC for bare
oxygen projectiles, thus providing a recipient system free of electron-related
Coulomb fields in both cases and allowing for the comparison between the two
collision systems as well as with available theoretical studies. The most
significant mechanisms of x-ray emission that may contribute to the RDEC energy
region as background processes are also addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05088</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Pinku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Goutam Dev</forenames></author></authors><title>A new Measurement of Thermal Conductivity of Iron at high pressures and
  temperatures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal conductivity of the most abundant element in the planetary core, Iron
(Fe) is measured up to Earth's outer core pressure $\sim 120$ GPa. The
measurements are carried out using the laser heated diamond anvil cell
facility, where the absorbed power by Fe metal foil is calculated using
thermodynamical equation. The thermal conductivity of $\gamma-Fe$ linearly
increases up to a maximum experimental pressure 40 GPa. Thermal conductivity of
$\epsilon-Fe$ measured by us shows a saturated value $\sim$ 52 ($\pm$ 5)
$Wm^{-1}K^{-1}$ in the pressure range 77 - 120 GPa. At different pressures
temperature dependence of thermal conductivity show a sharp drop during
melting, which indicates the formation of liquid layer resulting in a thermal
buffer to the heat conduction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05612</id><created>2016-09-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hal&#xe1;sz</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Somorjai</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gy&#xfc;rky</keyname><forenames>Gy.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elekes</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xfc;l&#xf6;p</keyname><forenames>Zs.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sz&#xfc;cs</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiss</keyname><forenames>G. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szegedi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauscher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;rres</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiescher</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental study of the astrophysical gamma-process reaction
  124Xe(alpha,gamma)128Ba</title><categories>nucl-ex astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 045801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.045801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The synthesis of heavy, proton rich isotopes in the astrophysical
gamma-process proceeds through photodisintegration reactions. For the improved
understanding of the process, the rates of the involved nuclear reactions must
be known. The reaction 128Ba(g,a)124Xe was found to affect the abundance of the
p nucleus 124Xe. Since the stellar rate for this reaction cannot be determined
by a measurement directly, the aim of the present work was to measure the cross
section of the inverse 124Xe(a,g)128Ba reaction and to compare the results with
statistical model predictions. Of great importance is the fact that data below
the (a,n) threshold was obtained. Studying simultaneously the 124Xe(a,n)127Ba
reaction channel at higher energy allowed to further identify the source of a
discrepancy between data and prediction. The 124Xe + alpha cross sections were
measured with the activation method using a thin window 124Xe gas cell. The
studied energy range was between E = 11 and 15 MeV close above the
astrophysically relevant energy range. The obtained cross sections are compared
with statistical model calculations. The experimental cross sections are
smaller than standard predictions previously used in astrophysical
calculations. As dominating source of the difference, the theoretical alpha
width was identified. The experimental data suggest an alpha width lower by at
least a factor of 0.125 in the astrophysical energy range. An upper limit for
the 128Ba(g,a)124Xe stellar rate was inferred from our measurement. The impact
of this rate was studied in two different models for core-collapse supernova
explosions of 25 solar mass stars. A significant contribution to the 124Xe
abundance via this reaction path would only be possible when the rate was
increased above the previous standard value. Since the experimental data rule
this out, they also demonstrate the closure of this production path.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06398</id><created>2016-09-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gracia-Linares</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzman</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Accretion of Supersonic Winds on Boson Stars</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 10 pdf figures. Accepted for publication in Physical Review
  D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064077 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064077</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the evolution of a supersonic wind interacting with a Boson Star
(BS) and compare the resulting wind density profile with that of the shock cone
formed when the wind is accreted by a non-rotating Black Hole (BH) of the same
mass. The physical differences between these accretors are that a BS, unlike a
BH has no horizon, it does not have a mechanical surface either and thus the
wind is expected to trespass the BS. Despite these conditions, on the BS
space-time the gas achieves a stationary flux with the gas accumulating in a
high density elongated structure comparable to the shock cone formed behind a
BH. The highest density resides in the center of the BS whereas in the case of
the BH it is found on the downstream part of the BH near the event horizon. The
maximum density of the gas is smaller in the BS than in the BH case. Our
results indicate that the highest density of the wind is more similar on the BS
to that on the BH when the BS has high self-interaction, when it is more
compact and when the wind velocity is higher. We expect this and similar
analyses help to know whether BSs can still be Black Hole mimickers or can be
ruled out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06987</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Vallejo</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naydenova</keyname><forenames>Karina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monsoriu</keyname><forenames>Juan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrando</keyname><forenames>Vicente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furlan</keyname><forenames>Walter D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional relative peripheral refractive error induced by Fractal
  Contact Lenses for myopia control</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: To assess the peripheral refraction induced by Fractal Contact
Lenses (FCLs) in myopic eyes by means of a two-dimensional Relative Peripheral
Refractive Error (RPRE) map.
  Methods: FCLs prototypes were specially manufactured and characterized. This
study involved twenty-six myopic subjects ranging from -0.50 D to -7.00 D. The
two-dimensional RPRE was measured with an open-field autorefractor by means of
tracking targets distributed in a square grid from -30 degrees (deg) nasal to
30 deg temporal and 15 deg superior to -15 deg inferior. Corneal topographies
were taken in order to assess correlations between corneal asphericity, lens
decentration and RPRE represented in vector components M, J0 and J45.
  Results: The mean power of the FCLs therapeutic zones was 1.32 +/- 0.28 D.
Significant correlations were found between the corneal asphericity and vector
components of the RPRE in the nacked eyes. FCLs were decentered a mean of 0.7
+/- 0.19 mm to the temporal cornea. M decreased asymmetrically between nasal
and temporal retina after fitting the FCLs with a significant increment of the
myopic shift besides 10 deg (p&lt;0.05) and the induced myopic shift at 25 deg and
30 deg decreased with FCLs decentration to temporal cornea. The peak of maximum
myopic shift at the peripheral retina (M= -1.3 D) was located at 20 deg.
Two-dimensional maps showed uniform significant differences in extreme
positions of the visual field in comparison with the horizontal RPRE for M and
J0, but not for J45.
  Conclusions: FCLs measured in myopic eyes showed a similar performance than
the reported in previous ray-tracing studies with a small bias explained by the
manufacturing process and the lens decentration. Two-dimensional maps are
preferable for assessing J45 changes due to the lens.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07299</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bubba</keyname><forenames>Tatiana A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauptmann</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huotari</keyname><forenames>Simo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rimpel&#xe4;inen</keyname><forenames>Juho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siltanen</keyname><forenames>Samuli</forenames></author></authors><title>Tomographic X-ray data of a lotus root filled with attenuating objects</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.med-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1502.04064</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the documentation of the tomographic X-ray data of a lotus root,
filled with four different attenuating objects, of different sizes. Data are
available at www.fips.fi/dataset.php, and can be freely used for scientific
purposes with appropriate references to them, and to this document in
http://arxiv.org/arXiv. The data set consists of (1) the X-ray sinogram of a
single 2D slice of the lotus root with two different resolutions and (2) the
corresponding measurement matrices modeling the linear operation of the X-ray
transform. Each of these sinograms was obtained from a measured 360-projection
fan-beam sinogram by down-sampling and taking logarithms. The original
(measured) sinogram is also provided in its original form and resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08346</id><created>2016-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Andrew D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible associated signal with GW150914 in the LIGO data</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple method for the identification of weak signals associated
with gravitational wave events. Its application reveals a signal with the same
time lag as the GW150914 event in the released LIGO strain data with a
significance around $3.2\sigma$. This signal starts about 10 minutes before
GW150914 and lasts for about 45 minutes. Subsequent tests suggest that this
signal is likely to be due to external sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09508</id><created>2016-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>Ari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egedal</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daughton</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Stage Bulk Electron Heating in the Diffusion Region of Anti-Parallel
  Symmetric Reconnection</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas, 23, 102109 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964768</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron bulk energization in the diffusion region during anti-parallel
symmetric reconnection entails two stages. First, the inflowing electrons are
adiabatically trapped and energized by an ambipolar parallel electric field.
Next, the electrons gain energy from the reconnection electric field as they
undergo meandering motion. These collisionless mechanisms have been decribed
previously, and they lead to highly-structured electron velocity distributions.
Nevertheless, a simplified control-volume analysis gives estimates for how the
net effective heating scales with the upstream plasma conditions in agreement
with fully kinetic simulations and spacecraft observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00725</id><created>2016-10-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Szypryt</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazin</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulbricht</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bumble</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meeker</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bockstiegel</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>High Quality Factor Platinum Silicide Microwave Kinetic Inductance
  Detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, accepted by APL</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4964665</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the development of Microwave Kinetic Inductance Detectors
(MKIDs) using platinum silicide as the sensor material. MKIDs are an emerging
superconducting detector technology, capable of measuring the arrival times of
single photons to better than two microseconds and their energies to around ten
percent. Previously, MKIDs have been fabricated using either sub-stoichiometric
titanium nitride or aluminum, but TiN suffers from spatial inhomogeneities in
the superconducting critical temperature and Al has a low kinetic inductance
fraction, causing low detector sensitivity. To address these issues, we have
instead fabricated PtSi microresonators with superconducting critical
temperatures of 944$\pm$12~mK and high internal quality factors ($Q_i \gtrsim
10^6$). These devices show typical quasiparticle lifetimes of $\tau_{qp}
\approx 30$--$40~\mu$s and spectral resolution, $R = \lambda / \Delta \lambda$,
of 8 at 406.6~nm. We compare PtSi MKIDs to those fabricated with TiN and detail
the substantial advantages that PtSi MKIDs have to offer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00972</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Angelo</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>J. F. C.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Corradi</keyname><forenames>W. J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maia</keyname><forenames>F. F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piatti</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of Galactic open cluster remnants: the case of NGC 7193</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>32 pages, 20 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in Research
  in Astronomy and Astrophysics (RAA)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galactic open clusters (OCs) that survive the early gas-expulsion phase are
gradually destroyed over time by the action of disruptive dynamical processes.
Their final evolutionary stages are characterized by a poorly populated
concentration of stars called open cluster remnant (OCR). This study is devoted
to assess the real physical nature of the OCR candidate NGC 7193. GMOS/Gemini
spectroscopy of 53 stars in the inner target region were obtained to derive
radial velocities and atmospheric parameters. We also employed photometric and
proper motion data. The analysis method consists of the following steps: (i)
analysis of the statistical resemblance between the cluster and a set of field
samples with respect to the sequences defined in colour-magnitude diagrams
(CMDs); (ii) a 5-dimensional iteractive exclusion routine was employed to
identify outliers from kinematical and positional data; (iii) isochrone fitting
to the $K_{s}\times(J-K_{s})$ CMD of the remaining stars and the dispersion of
spectral types along empirical sequences in the $(J-H)\times(H-K_{s})$ diagram
was checked. A group of stars was identified for which the mean heliocentric
distance is compatible with that obtained via isochrone fitting and whose
metallicities are compatible with each other. Fifteen member stars observed
spectroscopically were identified together with other 19 probable members. Our
results indicate that NGC 7193 is a genuine OCR, of an once very populous OC,
for which the following parameters were derived: $d=501\,\pm\,46\,$pc,
$t=2.5\,\pm\,1.2\,$Gyr, $\langle\,[Fe/H]\,\rangle=-0.17\,\pm\,0.23$ and
$E(B-V)=0.05\,\pm\,0.05$. Its luminosity and mass functions show depletion of
low mass stars, confirming the OCR dynamically evolved state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01120</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Falaye</keyname><forenames>Babatunde James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Guo-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liman</keyname><forenames>Muhammed S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyewumi</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrogen atom in a Laser-Plasma</title><categories>quant-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Laser Phys. Lett. 13 (2016) 116003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1612-2011/13/11/116003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We scrutinize the behaviour of hydrogen atom's eigenvalues in a quantum
plasma as it interacts with electric field directed along $\theta=\pi$ and
exposed to linearly polarized intense laser field radiation. Using the
Kramers-Henneberger (KH) unitary transformation, which is semiclassical
counterpart of the Block-Nordsieck transformation in the quantized field
formalism, the squared vector potential that appears in the equation of motion
is eliminated and the resultant equation is expressed in KH frame. Within this
frame, the resulting potential and the corresponding wavefunction have been
expanded in Fourier series and using Ehlotzky's approximation, we obtain a
laser-dressed potential to simulate intense laser field. By fitting the
exponential-cosine-screened Coulomb potential into the laser-dressed potential,
and then expanding it in Taylor series up to $\mathcal{O}(r^4,\alpha_0^9)$, we
obtain the eigensolution (eigenvalues and wavefunction) of hydrogen atom in
laser-plasma encircled by electric field, within the framework of perturbation
theory formalism. Our numerical results show that for a weak external electric
field and gargantuan length of Debye screening parameter, the system is
strongly repulsive in contrast for strong external electric field and small
length of Debye screening parameter, the system is very attractive. This work
has potential application in the areas of atomic and molecular processes in
external fields including interactions with strong fields and short pulses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01454</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Saaltink</keyname><forenames>Rebecca Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giner</keyname><forenames>Lambert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karimi</keyname><forenames>Ebrahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundeen</keyname><forenames>Jeff S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Super-critical phasematching for photon pair generation in structured
  light modes</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express, Vol. 24, Issue 21, pp. 24495-24508 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.024495</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method for directly producing radially and azimuthally polarized
photon pairs through spontaneous parametric downconversion (SPDC). This method
constitutes a novel geometry for SPDC, in which a radially polarized
Bessel-Gauss pump beam is directed into a nonlinear crystal, with the central
propagation direction parallel to the crystal axis. The phasematching
conditions are controlled by changing the opening angle of the pump beam; as
the crystal axis cannot be tuned, we refer to this process as super-critical
phasematching. We model and plot the spatial and polarization output
distributions for Type-I and Type-II super-critical phasematching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02842</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lera</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gapped electron fractionalization in robustly one dimensional
  Li0.9Mo6O17</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The angle resolved photoemission spectroscopy lineshapes of quasi
one-dimensional (1d) Li0.9Mo6O17 display both agreement with and departures
from the one-band Tomonaga-Luttinger model. We show that the departures can be
understood by explicitly accounting for the four modes arising from the two
quasi-1d bands known to cross the Fermi energy. The key assumption is that the
antisymmetric charge mode is gapped with a magnitude near the temperature (T)
of a mysterious 25K powerlaw resistivity upturn. The gap is consistent with the
lack of a charge or spin density wave accompanying the upturn, is able to
control the upturn T, and prevents crossover to a Fermi liquid (FL) down to the
superconducting transition at 1.9K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03533</id><created>2016-10-09</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Xi-Qiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable Band-Gaps in Phononic Crystals by Harnessing Hyperelastic
  Transformation Media</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.class-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The band structure in phononic crystals (PCs) is usually affected by the
deformations of their soft components. In this work, hyperelastic
transformation media is proposed to be integrated in the PCs'design, to achieve
stable elastic band-gaps which is independent with finite mechanical
deformations. For a one-dimensional (1D) PC, we demonstrate the semi-linear
soft component can keep all elastic wave bands unchanged with the external
deformation field. While for neo-Hookean soft component, only S-wave bands can
be precisely retained. The change of the P-wave bands can be predicted by using
a lumped mass method. Numerical simulations are performed to validate our
theory predictions and the robustness of the proposed PCs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03722</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Z. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneegans</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fruchter</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of Perovskite SrIrO3 Thin Films by Sputtering Technique</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Corrected the peaks permutation in Fig. 4</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the synthesis of perovskite SrIrO3 thin films using sputtering
technique. Single phase (110) oriented SrIrO$_3$ thin films were epitaxially
grown on SrTiO3 (001) substrate. Using off-axis XRD $\theta-2\theta$ scans, we
demonstrate that these films exhibit (110) out-of-plane orientation with (001)
and (1-10) lying in-plane. The sputtering grown thin films have a smooth,
homogeneous surface, and excellent coherent interface with the substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03845</id><created>2016-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Changgeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial heterodyne scanning laser confocal holographic microscopy</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scanning laser confocal holographic microscopy using a spatial heterodyne
detection method is presented. Spatial heterodyne detection technique employs a
Mach-Zehnder interferometer with the reference beam frequency shifted by two
acousto-optic modulators (AOM) relative to the object beam frequency. Different
from the traditional temporal heterodyne detection technique in which hundreds
temporal samples are taken at each scanning point to achieve the complex
signal, the spatial heterodyne detection technique generates spatial
interference fringes by use of a linear tempo-spatial relation provided by
galvanometer scanning in a typical line-scanning confocal microscope or for the
slow-scanning on one dimension in a point-scanning confocal microscope, thereby
significantly reducing sampling rate and increasing the signal to noise ratio
under the same illumination compared to the traditional temporal heterodyne
counterpart. The proposed spatial heterodyne detection scheme applies to both
line-scanning and point-scanning confocal microscopes. In this paper, we
present the mathematical principles of the spatial heterodyne detection method
and experimental schemes for both line-scanning and point-scanning confocal
microscopes. Computer experiments are provided to demonstrate the validity of
this idea. The presented spatial heterodyne scanning laser confocal holographic
microscope (SH-SLCHM) can obtain both amplitude and quantitative phase
information of the object field without a significant increase in complexity of
optical and electronic design on the basis of a traditional scanning laser
confocal microscope (SLCM). SH-SLCHM may find applications in optical
metrology, in-vivo tissue imaging, and ophthalmic imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03854</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kroupa</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames><affiliation>Bonn, Prague</affiliation></author></authors><title>The observed spatial distribution of matter on scales ranging from
  100kpc to 1Gpc is inconsistent with the standard dark-matter-based
  cosmological models</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, LaTex, published in &quot;Cosmology on Small Scales 2016&quot;,
  Michal Krizek and Yurii Dumin (Eds.), Institute of Mathematics, Czech Academy
  of Sciences, Prague: ISBN 978-80-85823-66-0</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spatial arrangement of galaxies (of satellites on a scale of 100kpc) as
well as their three-dimensional distribution in galaxy groups such as the Local
Group (on a scale of 1Mpc), the distribution of galaxies in the nearby volume
of galaxies (on a scale of 8Mpc) and in the nearby Universe (on a scale of
1Gpc) is considered. There is further evidence that the CMB shows
irregularities and for anisotropic cosmic expansion. The overall impression one
obtains, given the best data we have, is matter to be arranged as not expected
in the dark-matter based standard model of cosmology (SMoC). There appears to
be too much structure, regularity and organisation. Dynamical friction on the
dark matter halos is a strong direct test for the presence of dark matter
particles, but this process does not appear to be operative in the real
Universe. This evidence suggests strongly that dynamically relevant dark matter
does not exist and therefore cosmology remains largely not understood
theoretically. More-accepted awareness of this case would by itself constitute
a major advance in research providing fabulous opportunities for bright minds,
and the observational data strongly suggest that gravitation must be
effectively Milgromian, corresponding to a generalized Poisson equation in the
classical limit. Thus, physical cosmology offers a significant historically
relevant opportunity for ground-breaking work, at least for those daring to do
so.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03857</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>McQuinn</keyname><forenames>Kristen B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skillman</keyname><forenames>Evan D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolphin</keyname><forenames>Andrew E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Danielle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennicutt</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>The Distance to M104</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables. Second paper in series. Paper I:
  McQuinn et al. 2016, ApJ, 826, 21 [arXiv:1606.04120]</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  M104 (NGC 4594; the Sombrero galaxy) is a nearby, well-studied elliptical
galaxy included in scores of surveys focused on understanding the details of
galaxy evolution. Despite the importance of observations of M104, a consensus
distance has not yet been established. Here, we use newly obtained Hubble Space
Telescope optical imaging to measure the distance to M104 based on the tip of
the red giant branch method. Our measurement yields the distance to M104 to be
9.55 +/- 0.13 +/- 0.31 Mpc equivalent to a distance modulus of 29.90 +/- 0.03
+/- 0.07 mag. Our distance is an improvement over previous results as we use a
well-calibrated, stable distance indicator, precision photometry in a optimally
selected field of view, and a Bayesian Maximum Likelihood technique that
reduces measurement uncertainties. The most discrepant previous results are due
to Tully-Fisher method distances, which are likely inappropriate for M104 given
its peculiar morphology and structure. Our results are part of a larger program
to measure accurate distances to a sample of well-known spiral galaxies
(including M51, M74, and M63) using the tip of the red giant branch method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03864</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Wenqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lezec</keyname><forenames>Henri J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface-Plasmon-Polariton Laser based on an Open-Cavity Fabry-Perot
  Resonator</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent years have witnessed growing interest in the development of
small-footprint lasers for potential applications in small-volume sensing and
on-chip optical communications. Surface-plasmons, electromagnetic modes
evanescently confined to metal-dielectric interfaces, offer an effective route
to achieving lasing at nanometer-scale dimensions when resonantly amplified in
contact with a gain-medium. Here, we achieve visible frequency ultra-narrow
linewidth lasing at room-temperature by leveraging surface plasmons propagating
in an open Fabry-Perot cavity formed by a flat metal surface coated with a
subwavelength-thick layer of optically-pumped gain medium and orthogonally
bound by a pair of flat metal sidewalls. Low perturbation
transmission-configuration sampling of the lasing plasmon mode is achieved via
an evanescently coupled recessed nanoslit, opening the way to
high-figure-of-merit refractive-index sensing of analytes interacting with the
open cavity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03875</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldsmith</keyname><forenames>John E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerling</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brennan</keyname><forenames>James S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A compact neutron scatter camera for field deployment</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 87, 083307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4961111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a very compact (0.9 m high, 0.4 m diameter, 40 kg) battery
operable neutron scatter camera designed for field deployment. Unlike most
other systems, the configuration of the sixteen liquid-scintillator detection
cells are arranged to provide omnidirectional (4{\pi}) imaging with sensitivity
comparable to a conventional two-plane system. Although designed primarily to
operate as a neutron scatter camera for localizing energetic neutron sources,
it also functions as a Compton camera for localizing gamma sources. In addition
to describing the radionuclide source localization capabilities of this system,
we demonstrate how it provides neutron spectra that can distinguish plutonium
metal from plutonium oxide sources, in addition to the easier task of
distinguishing AmBe from fission sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03878</id><created>2016-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Madeo</keyname><forenames>Angela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collet</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miniaci</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billon</keyname><forenames>K&#xe9;vin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouisse</keyname><forenames>Morvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neff</keyname><forenames>Patrizio</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling real phononic crystals via the weighted relaxed micromorphic
  model with free and gradient micro-inertia</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><msc-class>74A10, 74A30, 74A60, 74E15, 74M25, 74Q15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the relaxed micromorphic continuum model with weighted free and
gradient micro-inertia is used to describe the dynamical behavior of a real
two-dimensional phononic crystal for a wide range of wavelengths. In
particular, a periodic structure with specific micro-structural topology and
mechanical properties, capable of opening a phononic band-gap, is chosen with
the criterion of showing a low degree of anisotropy (the band-gap is almost
independent of the direction of propagation of the traveling wave). A Bloch
wave analysis is performed to obtain the dispersion curves and the
corresponding vibrational modes of the periodic structure. A linear-elastic,
isotropic, relaxed micromorphic model including both a free micro-inertia
(related to free vibrations of the microstructures) and a gradient
micro-inertia (related to the motions of the microstructure which are coupled
to the macro-deformation of the unit cell) is introduced and particularized to
the case of plane wave propagation. The parameters of the relaxed model, which
are independent of frequency, are then calibrated on the dispersion curves of
the phononic crystal showing an excellent agreement in terms of both dispersion
curves and vibrational modes. Almost all the homogenized elastic parameters of
the relaxed micromorphic model result to be determined. This opens the way to
the design of morphologically complex meta-structures which make use of the
chosen phononic structure as the basic building block and which preserve its
ability of &quot;stopping&quot; elastic wave propagation at the scale of the structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03901</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Almaatouq</keyname><forenames>Abdullah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radaelli</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pentland</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shmueli</keyname><forenames>Erez</forenames></author></authors><title>The Role of Reciprocity and Directionality of Friendship Ties in
  Promoting Behavioral Change</title><categories>cs.SI cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>The 9th International Conference on Social, Cultural, and Behavioral
  Modeling &amp; Prediction and Behavior Representation in Modeling and Simulation,
  SBP-BRiMS 2016</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-39931-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Friendship is a fundamental characteristic of human beings and usually
assumed to be reciprocal in nature. Despite this common expectation, in
reality, not all friendships by default are reciprocal nor created equal. Here,
we show that reciprocated friendships are more intimate and they are
substantially different from those that are not. We examine the role of
reciprocal ties in inducing more effective peer pressure in a cooperative
arrangements setting and find that the directionality of friendship ties can
significantly limit the ability to persuade others to act. Specifically, we
observe a higher behavioral change and more effective peer-influence when
subjects shared reciprocal ties with their peers compared to sharing unilateral
ones. Moreover, through spreading process simulation, we find that although
unilateral ties diffuse behaviors across communities, reciprocal ties play more
important role at the early stages of the diffusion process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03905</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Meizhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Junzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yantao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Shock responses of nanoporous aluminum by molecular dynamics simulations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present systematic investigations on the shock responses of nanoporous
aluminum (np-Al) by nonequilibrium molecular dynamics simulations. The
dislocation nucleation sites are found to concentrate in low latitude region
near the equator of the spherical void surfaces. We propose a continuum wave
reflection theory and a resolved shear stress model to explain the distribution
of dislocation nucleation sites. The simulations reveals two mechanisms of void
collapse: the plasticity mechanism and the internal jetting mechanism. The
plasticity mechanism, which leads to transverse collapse of voids, prevails
under relatively weaker shocks; while the internal jetting mechanism, which
leads to longitudinal filling of the void vacuum, plays more significant role
as the shock intensity increases. In addition, an abnormal thermodynamic
phenomenon (i.e., arising of temperature with pressure dropping) in shocked
np-Al is discovered. This phenomenon is incompatible with the conventional
Rankine-Hugoniot theory, and is explained by the nonequilibrium processes
involved in void collapse. The influences of void collapse on spall fracture of
np-Al is studied. Under the same loading velocity, the spall strength of np-Al
is found to be lower than that of single-crystal Al; but the spall resistance
is higher in np-Al than in single-crystal Al. This is explained by the combined
influences of thermal dissipation and stress attenuation during shock wave
propagation in np-Al.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03909</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Arms</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serna</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence-principle Analog of the Gravitational Redshift</title><categories>gr-qc physics.ins-det</categories><comments>11 pages and 4 figures. Presented at 4CS of APS October 2014</comments><msc-class>70E70, 83B01</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  What happens when two synchronized clocks on a rigid beam are both given the
exact same acceleration profile? Will they remain synchronized? What if we use
a rigid-rod Rindler acceleration profile? The special relativity prediction
surprises many people. This experimental setup is the special-relativity analog
of the gravitational redshift. Just like two clocks higher and lower in a
gravitational field lose synchronization, one sees a loss of synchronization in
these clocks with `identical' acceleration profiles. To the best of our
knowledge this equivalence principle analog has never been directly measured,
and current experimental techniques are sensitive enough to measure it. We
discuss the origin of the essential physics behind this synchronization loss,
and some special conditions which simplify its experimental observation. We
discuss the origin of the essential physics behind this synchronization loss,
and some special conditions which simplify its experimental observation. If
validated this effect will not only test the equivalence principle from a new
vantage, but it may one day aid in understanding and enhancing future
ultra-precise navigation systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03918</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03918</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Tai-Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Yasutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of Particle-in-Cell Simulation in a Two Dimensional Trench
  Geometry</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A two dimensional electrostatic Particle-in-Cell simulation code is developed
to investigate anisotropy of ions in a trench geometry for plasma etching. The
numerical simulation results suggest that if the trench width is larger than
Debye length scale, anisotropy can be lost due to potential development across
the trench. Furthermore, the effects of ion charge build up on the trench
bottom is investigated, which can degrade the anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03919</id><created>2016-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Yu-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Pei-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium quantum phase transition via entanglement decoherence
  dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 34804 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep34804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the decoherence dynamics of continuous variable entanglement
as the system-environment coupling strength varies from the weak-coupling to
the strong-coupling regimes. Due to the existence of localized modes in the
strong-coupling regime, the system cannot approach equilibrium with its
environment, which induces a nonequilibrium quantum phase transition. We
analytically solve the entanglement decoherence dynamics for an arbitrary
spectral density. The nonequilibrium quantum phase transition is demonstrated
as the system-environment coupling strength varies for all the Ohmic-type
spectral densities. The 3-D entanglement quantum phase diagram is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03953</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Byun</keyname><forenames>Young-Moo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ullrich</keyname><forenames>Carsten A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitons in solids from time-dependent density-functional theory:
  Assessing the Tamm-Dancoff approximation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Excitonic effects in solids can be calculated using the Bethe-Salpeter
equation (BSE) or the Casida equation of time-dependent density-functional
theory (TDDFT). In both methods, the Tamm-Dancoff approximation (TDA), which
decouples excitations and de-excitations, is widely used to reduce
computational cost. Here, we study the effect of the TDA on exciton binding
energies of solids obtained from the Casida equation using long-range corrected
(LRC) exchange-correlation kernels. We find that the TDA underestimates
TDDFT-LRC exciton binding energies of semiconductors slightly, but those of
insulators significantly (i.e., by more than 100%), and thus it is essential to
solve the full Casida equation to describe strongly bound excitons. These
findings are relevant in the ongoing search for accurate and efficient TDDFT
approaches for excitons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03954</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ditr&#xf3;i</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xe1;rk&#xe1;nyi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tak&#xe1;cs</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hermanne</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Activation cross-sections of proton induced reactions on vanadium in the
  37-65 MeV energy range</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Nuclear Instruments and Methods B 381(2016)16</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nimb.2016.05.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental excitation functions for proton induced reactions on natural
vanadium in the 37-65 MeV energy range were measured with the activation method
using a stacked foil irradiation technique. By using high resolution gamma
spectrometry cross-section data for the production of $^{51,48}$Cr, $^{48}$V,
$^{48,47,46,44m,44g,43}$Sc and $^{43,42}$K were determined. Comparisons with
the earlier published data are presented and results predicted by different
theoretical codes (EMPIRE and TALYS) are included. Thick target yields were
calculated from a fit to our experimental excitation curves and compared with
the earlier experimental yield data. Depth distribution curves to be used for
thin layer activation (TLA) are also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03968</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komarek</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct determination of the spin structure of Nd$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$ by means
  of neutron diffraction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>http://journals.aps.org/prb/pdf/10.1103/PhysRevB.94.161102</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 161102(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.161102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the spin structure of the pyrochlore iridate Nd$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$
that could be directly determined by means of powder neutron diffraction. Our
magnetic structure refinement unravels a so-called all-in/all-out magnetic
structure that appears in both, the Nd and the Ir sublattice. The ordered
magnetic moments at 1.8 K amount to 0.34(1) $\mu_\mathrm{B}$/Ir$^{4+}$ and
1.27(1) $\mu_\mathrm{B}$/Nd$^{3+}$. The Nd$^{3+}$ moment size at 1.8 K is
smaller than that expected for the Nd$^{3+}$ ground state doublet. On the other
hand, the size of the ordered moments of the Ir$^{4+}$ ions at 1.8 K agrees
very well with the value expected for a $J_\mathrm{eff}$ = 1/2 state based on
the presence of strong spin-orbit coupling in this system. Finally, our
measurements reveal a parallel alignment of the Nd$^{3+}$ moments with the net
moment of its six nearest neighboring Ir$^{4+}$ ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03981</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kol&#xe1;&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katkov</keyname><forenames>V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osipov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Tunneling Systems in Amorphous Organic Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Low Temp Phys (2014) 176: 64</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-014-1162-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the heat release data of organic glasses with that of amorphous
and glass like crystalline solids. Anomalous behavior was found in all these
materials, which disagrees with the standard tunneling model. We can explain
the most of the experimental observations within a phenomenological model,
where we assume that for a part of tunneling systems the barrier heights are
strongly reduced as a consequence of the local stress produced during the
cooling process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03983</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xfc;ler-K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7;</keyname><forenames>S&#xfc;meyra</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7;</keyname><forenames>&#xc7;etin</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure dependence of the band-gap energy in BiTeI</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 165203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.165203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evolution of the electronic structure of BiTeI, a layered semiconductor
with a van der Waals gap, under compression is studied by employing semilocal
and dispersion-corrected density-functional calculations. Comparative analysis
of the results of these calculations shows that the band-gap energy of BiTeI
decreases till it attains a minimum value of zero at a critical pressure, after
which it increases again. The critical pressure corresponding to the closure of
the band gap is calculated, at which BiTeI becomes a topological insulator.
Comparison of the critical pressure to the pressure at which BiTeI undergoes a
structural phase transition indicates that the closure of the band gap would
not be hindered by a structural transformation. Moreover, the band-gap pressure
coefficients of BiTeI are computed, and an expression of the critical pressure
is devised in terms of these coefficients. Our findings indicate that the
semilocal and dispersion-corrected approaches are in conflict about the
compressibility of BiTeI, which result in overestimation and underestimation,
respectively. Nevertheless, the effect of pressure on the atomic structure of
BiTeI is found to be manifested primarily as the reduction of the width of the
van der Waals gap according to both approaches, which also yield consistent
predictions concerning the interlayer metallic bonding in BiTeI under
compression. It is consequently shown that the calculated band-gap energies
follow qualitatively and quantitatively the same trend within the two
approximations employed here, and the transition to the zero-gap state occurs
at the same critical width of the van der Waals gap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03993</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Podivilov</keyname><forenames>Evgeniy V.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Automation and Electrometry, SB RAS, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation><affiliation>Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kharenko</keyname><forenames>Denis S.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Automation and Electrometry, SB RAS, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation><affiliation>Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bednyakova</keyname><forenames>Anastasia E.</forenames><affiliation>Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation><affiliation>Institute of Computational Technologies, SB RAS, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fedoruk</keyname><forenames>Mikhail P.</forenames><affiliation>Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation><affiliation>Institute of Computational Technologies, SB RAS, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Babin</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Automation and Electrometry, SB RAS, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation><affiliation>Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia</affiliation></author></authors><title>Dissipative soliton comb</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dissipative solitons are stable localized coherent structures with linear
frequency chirp generated in normal-dispersion mode-locked lasers. The soliton
energy in fiber lasers is limited by the Raman effect, but implementation of
intracavity feedback for the Stokes wave enables synchronous generation of a
coherent Raman dissipative soliton. Here we demonstrate a new approach for
generating chirped pulses at new wavelengths by mixing in a highly-nonlinear
fiber of two frequency-shifted dissipative solitons, as well as cascaded
generation of their clones forming a &quot;dissipative soliton comb&quot; in the
frequency domain. We observed up to eight equidistant components in a 400-nm
interval demonstrating compressibility from ~10 ps to ~300 fs. This approach,
being different from traditional frequency combs, can inspire new developments
in fundamental science and applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04011</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tannous</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gieraltowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic control of magnonic and spintronic devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Material Science: Materials for Electronics, 26, 4675
  (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10854-015-2751-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanometric magnonic and spintronic devices need magnetic field control in
addition to conventional electronic control. In this work we review ways to
replace magnetic field control by an electronic one in order to circumvent
appearance of stray magnetic fields or the difficulty of creating large
magnetic fields over nanometric distances. Voltage control is compared to
current control and corresponding devices are compared from their energetic
efficiency point of view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04013</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Brun</keyname><forenames>Todd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Min-Hsiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement-Assisted Quantum Error-Correcting Codes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This is a chapter in the book &quot;Quantum Error Correction&quot;, edited by
  Daniel A. Lidar and Todd A. Brun, (Cambridge University Press, 2013)</comments><journal-ref>In &quot;Quantum Error Correction&quot;, edited by Daniel A. Lidar and Todd
  A. Brun, Cambridge University Press, 2013 (ISBN: 9780521897877)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a self-contained introduction for entanglement-assisted quantum
error-correcting codes in this book chapter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04018</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Indrani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meester</keyname><forenames>Vera</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Wel</keyname><forenames>Casper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraft</keyname><forenames>Daniela J</forenames></author></authors><title>Colloidal Joints with Designed Motion Range and Tunable Joint
  Flexibility</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The miniaturization of machines towards the micron and nanoscales requires
the development of joint-like elements that enable and constrain motion. We
present a facile method to create colloidal joints, that is, anisotropic
colloidal particles containing surface mobile DNA linkers that control the
motion range of bonded particles. We demonstrate quantitatively that we can
control the flexibility of these colloidal joints by tuning the DNA linker
concentration in the bond area. We show that the colloidal shape controls the
range of motion that these colloidal joints enable, due to the finite-sized
patch of bonded linkers that cannot cross regions of high curvature. Finally we
demonstrate the potential of the colloidal joints for programmable bottom-up
self-assembly by creating flexible colloidal molecules and colloidal polymers.
The reconfigurability and motion constraint offered by our colloidal joints
make them promising building blocks for the development of switchable materials
and nanorobots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04066</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Neff</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feldmeier</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author></authors><title>The Wigner function and short-range correlations in the deuteron</title><categories>nucl-th quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $\textbf{Background:}$ The deuteron shows the essential features of
short-range correlations found in all nuclei. Experimental observables related
to short-range correlations are connected with the high-momentum components of
one- and two-body momentum distributions. An intuitive understanding of
short-range correlations is provided by the suppression of the two-body density
in coordinate space at small distances.
  $\textbf{Purpose:}$ The Wigner function provides a quasi-probability
distribution in phase-space that allows to investigate short-range correlations
as a function of distance and relative momentum in a unified picture.
  $\textbf{Method:}$ The Wigner function for the deuteron is calculated for
bare and SRG evolved AV8' and N3LO interactions and investigated as a function
of distance, relative momentum and angular orientation. Partial momentum and
coordinate space distributions are obtained by integrating over parts of phase
space.
  $\textbf{Results:}$ The Wigner function shows a pronounced low-momentum peak
that is not affected by short-range correlations and a high-momentum shoulder
at small distances that reflects short-range correlations. Oscillations of the
Wigner function are related to interference of low- and high-momentum
components.
  $\textbf{Conclusions:}$ Short-range correlations are a truly
quantum-mechanical phenomenon caused by interference of low- and high-momentum
components in the wave function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04068</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Burgos</keyname><forenames>Rhonald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewenkopf</keyname><forenames>Caio</forenames></author></authors><title>Weiss oscillations in graphene with a modulated height profile</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the electronic transport properties of a monolayer graphene with a
one-dimensional modulated height profile caused, for instance, by substrate
ondulations. We show that the combined effect of the resulting strain fields
induce modulated scalar and vector potentials that give rise to Weiss
oscillations in the magnetoconductivity. We also find that similar effects can
be obtained by applying a parallel magnetic field to the graphene-substrate
interface. The parameters of an experimental set-up for a physical realization
of these findings in graphene systems are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04072</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Dynes</keyname><forenames>James F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tam</keyname><forenames>Winci W-S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plews</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fr&#xf6;hlich</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucamarini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Zhiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radig</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straw</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edwards</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shields</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-high bandwidth quantum secured data transmission</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 35149 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep35149</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum key distribution (QKD) provides an attractive means for securing
communications in optical fibre networks. However, deployment of the technology
has been hampered by the frequent need for dedicated dark fibres to segregate
the very weak quantum signals from conventional traffic. Up until now the
coexistence of QKD with data has been limited to bandwidths that are orders of
magnitude below those commonly employed in fibre optic communication networks.
Using an optimised wavelength divisional multiplexing scheme, we transport QKD
and the prevalent 100 Gb/s data format in the forward direction over the same
fibre for the first time. We show a full quantum encryption system operating
with a bandwidth of 200 Gb/s over a 100 km fibre. Exploring the ultimate limits
of the technology by experimental measurements of the Raman noise, we
demonstrate it is feasible to combine QKD with 10 Tb/s of data over a 50 km
link. These results suggest it will be possible to integrate QKD and other
quantum photonic technologies into high bandwidth data communication
infrastructures, thereby allowing their widespread deployment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04074</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cerrito</keyname><forenames>Lucio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millar</keyname><forenames>Declan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Span&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Using asymmetry observables to discover and distinguish Z' signals in
  top pair production with the lepton-plus-jets final state at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, proceedings contribution for Fourth Annual Large Hadron
  Collider Physics, 13-18 June 2016, Lund, Sweden</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the sensitivity of top pair production with six-fermion decay at the
LHC to the presence and nature of an underlying Z' boson, accounting for full
tree-level Standard Model ttbar interference, with all intermediate particles
allowed off-shell. We concentrate on the lepton-plus-jets final state and
simulate experimental conditions, including kinematic requirements and top
quark pair reconstruction in the presence of missing transverse energy and
combinatorial ambiguity in jet-top assignment. We focus on the differential
mass spectra of the cross section and asymmetry observables, especially
demonstrating the use of the latter in probing the coupling structure of a new
neutral resonance, in addition to cases in which the asymmetry forms a
complementary discovery observable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04075</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Ke-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the Regge Trajectory Quasi-linear or Square-root Form?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are many orbital excited mesons discovered in recent years. In this
work we attempt to study whether the Regge trajectory is quasi-linear or
square-root form. In the framework of the quasi-linear Regge trajectory and
square-root Regge trajectory, the masses of the states lying on the well
established 11S0, 13S1, and 13P2 trajectories are estimated. Comparison of the
results given by the two trajectories with the existing experimental data
illustrates that both of them can give a reasonable description for the ground
mesons. For the orbital excited states, the quasi-linear trajectory describes
the existing meson spectrum to be more reasonable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04109</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Abramowicz</keyname><forenames>Halina</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle physics perspective</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, Talk presented at the 24th International Workshop
  on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 11-15 April, 2016, DESY
  Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A personal perspective on the future challenges of research in particle
physics is presented with emphasis on the role of DIS physics in this
endeavour.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04110</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Flores-Livas</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanna</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>Arkadiy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goedecker</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>Miguel A. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of superconductivity in doped H$_2$O ice at high pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possibility of achieving high-temperature
superconductivity in hydrides under pressure by inducing metallization of
otherwise insulating phases through doping, a path previously used to render
standard semiconductors superconducting at ambient pressure. Following this
idea, we study H$_2$O, one of the most abundant and well-studied substances, we
identify nitrogen as the most likely and promising substitution/dopant. We show
that for realistic levels of doping of a few percent, the phase X of ice
becomes superconducting with a critical temperature of about 60 K at 150GPa. In
view of the vast number of hydrides that are strongly covalent bonded, but that
remain insulating until rather large pressures, our results open a series of
new possibilities in the quest for novel high-temperature superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04130</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Lebiedowicz</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nachtmann</keyname><forenames>Otto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczurek</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author></authors><title>Exclusive production of two and four pions in proton-proton scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, talk presented by P. Lebiedowicz at the Low-x
  2016 conference, Gy\&quot;ongy\&quot;os, Hungary, June 6-11, 2016. arXiv admin note:
  text overlap with arXiv:1606.09046</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider exclusive $pp \to pp \pi^{+} \pi^{-}$ and $pp \to pp \pi^{+}
\pi^{-}\pi^{+} \pi^{-}$ reactions at high energies. The calculation is based on
a tensor pomeron model and the amplitudes for the processes are formulated in
an effective field-theoretic approach. In the case of $pp \to pp \pi^{+}
\pi^{-}$ process we consider both diffractive and photoproduction mechanisms
and we include the non-resonant $\pi^{+}\pi^{-}$ continuum and the resonance
$f_{0}(500)$, $f_{0}(980)$, $f_{2}(1270)$, $\rho(770)$ contributions. We
discuss how two pomerons couple to tensor meson $f_{2}(1270)$ and the
interference effects of resonance and dipion continuum. We find that the
relative contribution of resonances $\rho(770)$, $f_2(1270)$ and dipion
continuum strongly depends on the cut on proton transverse momenta. In the case
of exclusive central $4 \pi$ production we include the contribution via the
intermediate $\sigma\sigma$ and $\rho\rho$ states. For both processes the
theoretical results have been compared with the experimental data and
predictions for planned or being carried out experiments (e.g. STAR,
ATLAS-ALFA) are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04131</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sekulla</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilian</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohl</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Field Theory and Unitarity in Vector Boson Scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented at Fourth Annual Large Hadron Collider Physics
  conference (LHCP2016), 13-18 June 2016, Lund, Sweden (11 pages). arXiv admin
  note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1605.09594</comments><report-no>KA-TP-28-2016; SI-HEP-2016-27; DESY 16-177</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weak vector boson scattering at high energies will be one of the key
measurements in current and upcoming LHC runs. It is most sensitive to any new
physics associated with electroweak symmetry breaking. However, a conventional
EFT analysis will fail at high energies. To address this problem, we present a
parameter-free prescription valid for arbitrary perturbative and
non-perturbative models: the T-matrix unitarization. We describe its
implementation as an asymptotically consistent reference model matched to the
low-energy effective theory. We show examples of typical observables of
vector-boson scattering at the LHC in our unitarized framework. For many
strongly-coupled models like composite Higgs models, dimension-8 operators
might be actually the leading operators. In addition to those longitudinal and
transversal dimension eight EFT operators, the effects of generic tensor and
scalar resonances within simplified models are considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04136</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xuemei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Ar+-ion Bombardment of TiO2 Nanotubes Creates Co-catalytic Effect for
  Photocatalytic Open Circuit Hydrogen Evolution</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochemistry Communications, 49, 2014, 60</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elecom.2014.09.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, extended Argon ion bombardment was used to modify
anatase TiO2 nanotube (NTs) layers. In situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy
revealed a high content of sub-oxide formed (Ti3+, Ti2+ states) in the nanotube
layers. These samples were tested for their ability to show open-circuit
photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. We found for UV (cw laser 325nm)
illumination as well as for AM1.5 conditions, a strongly enhanced H2 evolution
activity in absence of the usual noble metal-nanoparticle decoration. We
conclude therefore that these sub-oxide states can play an important role in
the activation of TiO2 nanotubes - namely as a H2 evolution co-catalyst.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04139</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Geloni</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocharyan</keyname><forenames>Vitali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saldin</keyname><forenames>Evgeni</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Coupling of Fields and Particles in Accelerator and Plasma
  Physics</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1607.02928</comments><report-no>DESY 16-194</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In accelerator and plasma physics it is accepted that there is no need to
solve the dynamical equations for particles in covariant form, i.e. by using
the coordinate-independent proper time to parameterize particle world-lines in
space-time: to describe dynamics in the laboratory frame, there is no need to
use the laws of relativistic kinematics. It is sufficient to account for the
relativistic dependence of particles momenta on the velocity in the second
Newton's law. Then, the coupling of fields and particles is based on the use of
result from particle dynamics treated according to Newton's laws in terms of
the relativistic three-momentum and on the use of Maxwell's equations in
standard form. Previously, we argued that this is a misconception. Here we
describe in detail how to calculate the coupling between fields and particles
in a correct way and how to develop a new algorithm for a particle tracking
code in agreement with the use of Maxwell's equations in their standard form.
Advanced textbooks on classical electrodynamics correctly tell us that
Maxwell's equations in standard form in the laboratory frame and charged
particles are coupled by introducing particles trajectories as projections of
particles world-lines onto coordinates of the laboratory frame and then by
using the laboratory time to parameterize the trajectory curves. We show a
difference between conventional and covariant particle tracking results in the
laboratory frame. This essential point has never received attention in the
physical community. Only the solution of the dynamical equations in covariant
form gives the correct coupling between field equations in standard form and
particles trajectories in the laboratory frame. Previous theoretical and
simulation results in accelerator and plasma physics should be re-examined in
the light of the pointed difference between conventional and covariant particle
tracking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04140</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Hunter</keyname><forenames>Todd R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broguiere</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomalont</keyname><forenames>Ed B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dent</keyname><forenames>William R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>Neil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabanus</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlahakis</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of antenna position measurements and weather station network
  data during the ALMA Long Baseline Campaign of 2015</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>19 pages, 14 figures, 1 table; presented at SPIE Astronomical
  Telescopes + Instrumentation 2016, held in Edinburgh, UK on 26 June - 1 July
  2016</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE. 9914, Millimeter, Submillimeter, and Far-Infrared
  Detectors and Instrumentation for Astronomy VII, 99142L. (July 19, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2232585</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a radio interferometer, the determination of geometrical antenna positions
relies on accurate calibration of the dry and wet delay of the atmosphere above
each antenna. For the Atacama Large Millimeter/Submillimeter Array (ALMA),
which has baseline lengths up to 16 kilometers, the geography of the site
forces the height above mean sea level of the more distant antenna pads to be
significantly lower than the central array. Thus, both the ground level
meteorological values and the total water column can be quite different between
antennas in the extended configurations. During 2015, a network of six
additional weather stations was installed to monitor pressure, temperature,
relative humidity and wind velocity, in order to test whether inclusion of
these parameters could improve the repeatability of antenna position
determinations in these configurations. We present an analysis of the data
obtained during the ALMA Long Baseline Campaign of Oct. through Nov. 2015. The
repeatability of antenna position measurements typically degrades as a function
of antenna distance. Also, the scatter is more than three times worse in the
vertical direction than in the local tangent plane, suggesting that a
systematic effect is limiting the measurements. So far we have explored
correcting the delay model for deviations from hydrostatic equilibrium in the
measured air pressure and separating the partial pressure of water from the
total pressure using water vapor radiometer (WVR) data. Correcting for these
combined effects still does not provide a good match to the residual position
errors in the vertical direction. One hypothesis is that the current model of
water vapor may be too simple to fully remove the day-to-day variations in the
wet delay. We describe possible avenues of improvement, including measuring and
applying more accurate values of the sky coupling efficiency of the WVRs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04144</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Costello</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>M-theory in the Omega-background and 5-dimensional non-commutative gauge
  theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $\Omega$-background is defined for supergravity, and a very general class
of such backgrounds is constructed for 11-dimensional supergravity.
11-dimensional supergravity in a certain $\Omega$-background is shown to be
equivalent to a 5-dimensional non-commutative gauge theory of Chern-Simons
type. M2 and M5 branes are expressed as 1 and 2-dimensional extended objects in
the 5-dimensional gauge theory. This 5-dimensional gauge theory is shown to
admit a consistent quantization with two coupling constants, despite being
formally non-renormalizable.
  A check of a twisted version of AdS/CFT is performed relating this
5-dimensional non-commutative gauge theory to the theory on N M5 branes,
wrapping an $A_{k-1}$ singularity and placed in an $\Omega$-background. The
operators on the M5 branes, in the $\Omega$-background, are described by a
certain chiral algebra which in the large N limit becomes a $W_{k+\infty}$
algebra. This chiral algebra is recovered from the 5-dimensional gauge theory.
  This argument also provides a holographic explanation of the result of
Maulik-Okounkov and Schiffmann-Vasserot that the $W_{k+\infty}$ algebra acts on
the equivariant cohomology of the moduli of instantons on an $A_{k-1}$
singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04147</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Miao</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author></authors><title>On the formation of shock for quasilinear wave equations by pulse with
  weak intensity</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>93 pages, 1 figure, Comments are welcome. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1412.3058</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we continue to study the shock formation for the
$3$-dimensional quasilinear wave equation \begin{align}\label{main eq}
-(1+3G&quot;(0)(\partial_{t}\phi)^{2})\partial^{2}_{t}\phi+\Delta\phi=0,\tag{\textbf{$\star$}}
\end{align} with $G&quot;(0)$ being a non-zero constant. Since \eqref{main eq}
admits global-in-time solution with small initial data, to present shock
formation, we consider a class of large data. Moreover, no symmetric assumption
is imposed on the data. Compared to our previous work [18], here we pose data
on the hypersurface $\{(t,x)|t=-r_{0}\}$ instead of $\{(t,x)|t=-2\}$, with
$r_{0}$ being arbitrarily large. We prove an a priori energy estimate
independent of $r_{0}$. Therefore a complete description of the solution
behavior as $r_{0}\rightarrow\infty$ is obtained. This allows us to relax the
restriction on the profile of initial data which still guarantees shock
formation. Since \eqref{main eq} can be viewed as a model equation for
describing the propagation of electromagnetic waves in nonlinear dielectric,
the result in this paper reveals the possibility to use wave pulse with weak
intensity to form electromagnetic shocks in laboratory. A main new feature in
the proof is that all estimates in the present paper do \emph{not} depend on
the parameter $r_{0}$, which requires different methods to obtain energy
estimates. As a byproduct, we prove the existence of semi-global-in-time
solutions which lead to shock formation by showing that the limits of the
initial energies exist as $r_{0}\rightarrow\infty$. The proof combines the
ideas in [5] where the the formation of shocks for 3-dimensional relativistic
compressible Euler equations with small initial data is established, and the
short pulse method introduced in [6] and generalized in [15], where the
formation of black holes in general relativity is proved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04151</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cha</keyname><forenames>Gihoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Kiyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>JeongEun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Killian</keyname><forenames>Manuela S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Topographical study of TiO2 nanostructure surface for photocatalytic
  hydrogen production</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochimica Acta, Volume 179, 10 October 2015, 423</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.electacta.2015.02.127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work we investigate the photocatalytic hydrogen production
(water splitting) activity of different Pt loaded TiO2 nanotube layers.
Therefore, we fabricate free standing membranes and fix them in four different
configurations: top up (with initiation layer grass or without) and bottom up
(bottom closed or open), then decorate the tubes with various amounts of Pt and
measure the open-circuit photocatalytic H2 production rate. We find a strong
influence of the configuration with the open top morphology showing the highest
photocatalytic hydrogen production efficiency, these nanotubes yield 3.5 times
more H2 than the least efficient structure (bottom closed). The work therefore
provides valuable guidelines for optimizing TiO2 nanotube layers for
photocatalytic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04153</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Hejazi</keyname><forenames>Seyedsina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Nhat Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Aminated TiO2 nanotube as a Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting
  photoanode</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>In Catalysis Today, Available online 21 July 2016</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cattod.2016.07.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work reports on the enhancement of TiO2 nanotubes
photoelectrochemical water splitting rate by decorating the nanostructure with
an amine layer in a hydrothermal process using diethylenetriamine (DETA). The
aminate coated TiO2 tubes show a stable improvement of the photoresponse in
both UV and visible light spectrum and under hydrothermal conditions, 4-fold
increase of the photoelectrochemical water splitting rate is observed. From
intensity modulated photocurrent spectroscopy (IMPS) measurements significantly
faster electron transport times are observed indicating a surface passivating
effect of the N-decoration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04158</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Braides</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Causin</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solci</keyname><forenames>Margherita</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic analysis of a ferromagnetic lattice spin system with diffuse
  interfacial energy</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an example of a one-dimensional scalar spin energy with long-range
interactions not satisfying standard decay conditions and which admits a
continuum approximation defined for functions u in BV((0,L),[-1,1]) taking into
account the total variation of u. Related minimum problems show boundary and
size effects in dependence of L.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04159</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozkan</keyname><forenames>Selda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Nhat Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlled spacing of self-organized anodic TiO2 nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochemistry Communications, Volume 69, August 2016, Pages 76
  to 79</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elecom.2016.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on how to grow and control self-organized TiO2 nanotube arrays that
show defined and regular gaps between individual nanotubes. For this we use
electrochemical anodization of titanium in fluoride containing di-ethylene
glycol (DEG) electrolytes, with variations in voltage and water content in the
electrolyte. In these specific electrolytes, such nanotubes show a true
spacing, i.e. nanotubes are spaced both at top and at bottom in regular
intervals, this in contrast to classic nanotubes obtained in other organic
electrolytes showing a close-packed organization. We identify critical
parameters, that define the region of existence i.e. under which condition tube
spacing occurs as well as the intertube distance, to be the voltage and the
water content. Using these findings allows to grow tubes where diameter and
spacing can even be independently controlled.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04169</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Imgon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Tantalum nitride nanotube photoanodes: establishing a beneficial
  back-contact by lift-off and transfer to titanium nitride layer</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochemistry Communications, Volume 72, November 2016, Pages
  27 to 31</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elecom.2016.08.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we introduce the use of TiN/Ti2 N layers as a back contact for
lifted-off membranes of anodic Ta3N5 nanotube layers. In photoelectrochemical
H2 generation experiments under simulated AM 1.5G light, shift of the onset
potential for anodic photocurrents to lower potentials is observed, as well as
a higher magnitude of the photocurrents compared to conventional Ta3N5
nanotubes (~ 0.5 V RHE ). We ascribe this beneficial effect to the improved
conductive properties of the TiNx -based back contact layer that enables a
facilitated electron-transport for tantalum-nitride based materials to the
conductive substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04172</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Schlue</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay of the Weyl curvature in expanding black hole cosmologies</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc math.DG</categories><comments>124 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a partial proof of the non-linear stability of the
expanding region of Schwarzschild de Sitter cosmologies. We show that under
dynamically realistic assumptions the conformal Weyl curvature decays towards
null infinity. Our assumptions are consistent with the expectation that a
dynamical solution to Einstein's equations with positive cosmological constant
does not converge globally to a member of the Kerr de Sitter family. In
particular in this problem the geometry of null infinity is a priori unknown.
One expects this result to form an essential part of a global existence proof
for the cosmological region, which - along with the precise asymptotics of
these solutions - is the subject of a subsequent paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04175</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Gurtner</keyname><forenames>G&#xe9;rald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lillo</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author></authors><title>Strategic allocation of flight plans: an evolutionary point of view</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the simplified model of strategic allocation of trajectories in
the airspace presented in a previous publication. Two types of companies,
characterized by different cost functions, compete for allocation of
trajectories in the airspace. We study how the equilibrium state of the model
depends on the traffic demand and number of airports. We show that in a mixed
population environment the equilibrium solution is not the optimal at the
global level, but rather than it tends to have a larger fraction of companies
who prefer to delay the departure time rather taking a longer routes. Finally
we study the evolutionary dynamics investigating the fluctuations of airline
types around the equilibrium and the speed of convergence toward it in finite
populations. We find that the equilibrium point is shifted by the presence of
noise and is reached more slowly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04176</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Gallardo</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rold&#xe1;n-Molina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenz</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landeros</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-wave spectra in periodically surface-modulated ferromagnetic thin
  films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article presents theoretical results for the dynamic response of
periodically surface-modulated ferromagnetic thin films. For such system, the
role of the periodic dipolar field induced by the modulation is addressed by
using the plane-wave method. By controlling the geometry of the modulated
volumes within the film, the frequency modes and spatial profiles of spin waves
can be manipulated. The angular dependence of the frequency band-gaps unveils
the influence of both dynamic and static magnetic charges, which reside in the
edges of the etching periodic zones, and it is stablished that band-gap widths
created by static magnetic charges are broader than the one created by dynamic
magnetic charges. To corroborate the validity of the model, the theoretical
results are compared with ferromagnetic resonance simulations, where a very
good agreement is achieved between both methods. The theoretical model allows
for a detailed understanding of the physics underlying these kind of systems,
thereby providing an outlook to potential applications associated with magnonic
crystals-based devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04178</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Budavari</keyname><forenames>Tamas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loredo</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probabilistic record linkage in astronomy: Directional
  cross-identification and beyond</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annual Review of Statistics and Its Application 2015 Vol. 2:
  113-139</journal-ref><doi>10.1146/annurev-statistics-010814-020231</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern astronomy increasingly relies upon systematic surveys, whose dedicated
telescopes continuously observe the sky across varied wavelength ranges of the
electromagnetic spectrum; some surveys also observe non-electromagnetic
&quot;messengers,&quot; such as high-energy particles or gravitational waves. Stars and
galaxies look different through the eyes of different instruments, and their
independent measurements have to be carefully combined to provide a complete,
sound picture of the multicolor and eventful universe. The association of an
object's independent detections is, however, a difficult problem
scientifically, computationally, and statistically, raising varied challenges
across diverse astronomical applications. The fundamental problem is finding
records in survey databases with directions that match to within the direction
uncertainties. Such astronomical versions of the record linkage problem are
known by various terms in astronomy: cross-matching, cross-identification, and
directional, positional, or spatio-temporal coincidence assessment. Astronomers
have developed several statistical approaches for such problems, largely
independently of related developments in other disciplines. Here we review
emerging approaches that compute (Bayesian) probabilities for the hypotheses of
interest: possible associations, or demographic properties of a cosmic
population that depend on identifying associations. Many cross-identification
tasks can be formulated within a hierarchical Bayesian partition model
framework, with components that explicitly account for astrophysical effects
(e.g., source brightness vs. wavelength, source motion, or source extent),
selection effects, and measurement error. We survey recent developments, and
highlight important open areas for future research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04179</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Anguiano</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruchhausen</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jusserand</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Favero</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamperti</keyname><forenames>F. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanco</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagnes</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lema&#xee;tre</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanzillotti-Kimura</keyname><forenames>N. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senellart</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fainstein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-Resolved Cavity Nano-Optomechanics in the 20-100 GHz range</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Applications of cavity optomechanics span from gravitational wave detection
to the study of quantum motion states in mesoscopic mechanical systems. The
engineering of resonators supporting strongly interacting mechanical and
optical modes is central to these developments. However, current technological
and experimental approaches limit the accessible mechanical frequencies to a
few GHz, imposing hard constraints on quantum mechanical studies. Here we
demonstrate the optical control of 20-100~GHz mechanical modes confined in the
three dimensions within semiconductor nano-optomechanical pillar cavities. We
use a time-resolved transient optical reflectivity technique and access both
the energy spectrum and dynamics of the mechanical modes at the picosecond
timescale. A strong increase of the optomechanical coupling upon reducing the
pillar size is observed together with unprecedent room temperature Q-frequency
products above $10^{14}$. The measurements also reveal sideband generation in
the optomechanical response. Such resonators can naturally integrate quantum
wells and quantum dots, enabling novel applications in cavity quantum
electrodynamics and high frequency nanomechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04184</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Loget</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Jeung Eun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazare</keyname><forenames>Anca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmuki</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly controlled coating of a biomimetic polymer in TiO2 nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Electrochemistry Communications, Volume 52, March 2015, Pages 41
  to 44</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elecom.2015.01.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Highly controlled coating of biomimetic polydopamine (PDA) was achieved on
titanium dioxide nanotubes (TiO2 NTs) by exposing TiO2 NT arrays to a slightly
alkaline dopamine solution. The thin films act as photonic sensitizers
(enhancing photocurrents and photodegradation) in the visible light range. The
PDA coatings can furthermore be used as a platform for decorating the TiO2 NTs
with different co-catalysts and metal nanoparticles (NPs).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04186</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Downing</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robinson</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portnoi</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanohelices as superlattices: Bloch oscillations and electric dipole
  transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155306 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Subjecting a nanohelix to a transverse electric field gives rise to
superlattice behavior with tunable electronic properties. We theoretically
investigate such a system and find Bloch oscillations and negative differential
conductance when a longitudinal electric field (along the nanohelix axis) is
also applied. Furthermore, we study dipole transitions across the
transverse-electric-field-induced energy gap, which can be tuned to the
eulogized terahertz frequency range by experimentally attainable external
fields. We also reveal a photogalvanic effect by shining circularly polarized
light onto our helical quantum wire.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04188</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>T&#xf6;rek</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing gauge-invariant perturbation theory</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>PoS (LATTICE 2016), Combined proceedings of the talks of both authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gauge-invariant perturbation theory for theories with a Brout-Englert-Higgs
effect, as developed by Fr\&quot;ohlich, Morchio and Strocchi, starts out from
physical, exactly gauge-invariant quantities as initial and final states. These
are composite operators, and can thus be considered as bound states. In case of
the standard model, this reduces almost entirely to conventional perturbation
theory. This explains the success of conventional perturbation theory for the
standard model. However, this is due to the special structure of the standard
model, and it is not guaranteed to be the case for other theories. Here, we
review gauge-invariant perturbation theory. Especially, we show how it can be
applied and that it is little more complicated than conventional perturbation
theory, and that it is often possible to utilize existing results of
conventional perturbation theory. Finally, we present tests of the predictions
of gauge-invariant perturbation theory, using lattice gauge theory, in three
different settings. In one case, the results coincide with conventional
perturbation theory and with the lattice results. In a second case, it appears
that the results of gauge-invariant perturbation theory agree with the lattice,
but differ from conventional perturbation theory. In the third case both
approaches fail due to quantum fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04208</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Araya</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arcos</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cur&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disk formation in oblate B[e] stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the conference
  &quot;The B[e] Phenomenon: Forty Years of Studies&quot; (Prague, Czech Republic, 27
  June - 1 July 2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possible role of line-driven winds in the circumstellar
envelope in B[e] stars, mainly the role of the $\Omega$-slow wind solution,
which is characterized by a slower terminal velocity and higher mass-loss rate,
in comparison with the standard (m-CAK) wind solution. In this work, we assume
two scenarios: 1) a spherically symmetric star and 2) a scenario that considers
the oblate shape, considering only the oblate correction factor. For certain
values of the line force parameters (according to previous works), we obtain in
both scenarios a density contrast $\gtrsim10^{2}$ between equatorial and polar
densities, characterized for a fast polar wind and a slow and denser wind when
the $\Omega$-slow wind solution is obtained. All this properties are enhanced
when the oblate correction factor is included in our calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04220</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements of photon and jet production properties with ATLAS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures. Proceeding for The Fourth Annual Conference on
  Large Hadron Collider Physics, Lund, Sweden 13 June - 18 June 2016</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Summary of recent ATLAS measurements of jet and photon production using
proton-proton (pp) collisions from the Large Hadron Collider. The
charged-particle multiplicity in jets, and jet charge measurements are
presented using 8 TeV pp collisions. Differential measurements of jet and
photon cross-sections are shown for 7, 8 and 13 TeV pp collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0409538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0409538</id><created>2004-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Dean</keyname><forenames>David S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drummond</keyname><forenames>Ian T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horgan</keyname><forenames>Ron R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Satya N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equilibrium statistics of a slave estimator in Langevin processes</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 .eps figures, Phys. Rev. Style</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E. 71, 031103 (2005)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.71.031103</doi><abstract>  We analyze the statistics of an estimator, denoted by xi_t and referred to as
the slave, for the equilibrium susceptibility of a one dimensional Langevin
process x_t in a potential phi(x). The susceptibility can be measured by
evolving the slave equation in conjunction with the original Langevin process.
This procedure yields a direct estimate of the susceptibility and avoids the
need, when performing numerical simulations, to include applied external fields
explicitly. The success of the method however depends on the statistical
properties of the slave estimator. The joint probability density function for
x_t and xi_t is analyzed. In the case where the potential of the system has a
concave component the probability density function of the slave acquires a
power law tail characterized by a temperature dependent exponent. Thus we show
that while the average value of the slave, in the equilibrium state, is always
finite and given by the fluctuation dissipation relation, higher moments and
indeed the variance may show divergences. The behavior of the power law
exponent is analyzed in a general context and it is calculated explicitly in
some specific examples. Our results are confirmed by numerical simulations and
we discuss possible measurement discrepancies in the fluctuation dissipation
relation which could arise due to this behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0009081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0009081</id><created>2000-09-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sitenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames><affiliation>Bogolyubov Inst. Theor. Phys., Kiev</affiliation></author></authors><title>Absence of Axial Anomaly in the Background of the Bohm-Aharonov Vector
  Potential</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, LaTeX, no figures. To be published in Physics of Particles
  and Nuclei</comments><journal-ref>Particles&amp;Nuclei 31, No. 7B, 58-64 (2000)</journal-ref><abstract>  The problem of the axial anomaly in the presence of the Bohm-Aharonov gauge
vector field is exactly solved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
