<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:18:21Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-10-02" from="2016-10-02" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02473</id><created>2016-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Loyau</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>SATIE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>SATIE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chaplier</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>SATIE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lobue</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>SATIE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mazaleyrat</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>SATIE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Magnetoelectric effect in layered ferrite/PZT composites. Study of the
  demagnetizing effect on the magnetoelectric behavior</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics, American Institute of Physics, 2015,
  117 (18)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4919722</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the use of high magnetomechanical coupling ferrites in
magnetoelectric (ME) layered composites. Bilayer samples combining $(Ni_{0.973}
Co_{0.027})_{1-x} Zn_x Fe_2 O_4$ ferrites ($x = 0-0.5$) synthesized by non
conventional reactive Spark Plasma Sintering and commercial lead zirconate
titanate (PZT) were characterized in term of ME voltage coefficients measured
at sub-resonant frequency. Strong ME effects are obtained and we show that an
annealing at 1000$^\circ$C and a quenching in air improve the piezomagnetic
behavior of Zn-rich compositions. A theoretical model that predicts the ME
behavior was developed, focusing our work on the demagnetizing effects in the
transversal mode as well as the longitudinal mode. The model shows that: (i)
high ME coefficients are obtained when ferrites with high magnetomechanical
coupling are used in bilayer ME composites, (ii) the ME behavior in transversal
and longitudinal modes is quite similar, and differences in the shapes of the
ME curves are mainly due the demagnetizing effects, (iii) in the transversal
mode, the magnetic field penetration depends on the ferrite layer thickness and
the ME coefficient is affected accordingly. The two later points are confirmed
by measurements on ME samples and calculations. Performances of the ME
composites made with high magnetomechanical coupling ferrites are compared to
those obtained using Terfenol-D materials in the same conditions of size,
shape, and volume ratio. It appears that a ferrite with an optimized
composition has performances comparable to those obtained with Terfenol-D
material. Nevertheless, the fabrication processes of ferrites are quite
simpler. Finally, a ferrite/PZT based ME composite was used as a current
sensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00538</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Vadawale</keyname><forenames>Santosh V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Dipankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhalerao</keyname><forenames>Varun B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dewangan</keyname><forenames>Gulab Chand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vibute</keyname><forenames>Ajay M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S.</keyname><forenames>Mithun N. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chattopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Tanmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sreekumar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>In-orbit performance of AstroSat CZTI</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures in Proc. SPIE. 9905, Space Telescopes and
  Instrumentation 2016: Ultraviolet to Gamma Ray, 99051G. (July 18, 2016)</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2235373</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cadmium-Zinc-Telluride Imager (CZTI) is one of the five payloads on-board
recently launched Indian astronomy satellite AstroSat. CZTI is primarily
designed for simultaneous hard X-ray imaging and spectroscopy of celestial
X-ray sources. It employs the technique of coded mask imaging for measuring
spectra in the energy range of 20 - 150 keV. It was the first scientific
payload of AstroSat to be switched on after one week of the launch and was made
operational during the subsequent week. Here we present preliminary results
from the performance verification phase observations and discuss the in-orbit
performance of CZTI.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02183</id><created>2016-09-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Quinet</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fivet</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmeri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engstrom</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundberg</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental radiative lifetimes for highly excited states and
  calculated oscillator strengths for lines of astrophysical interest in singly
  ionized cobalt (Co II)</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>MNRAS 462, 3912 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1900</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work reports new experimental radiative lifetimes and calculated
oscillator strengths for transitions of astrophysical interest in singly
ionized cobalt. More precisely, nineteen radiative lifetimes in Co+ have been
measured with the time-resolved laser-induced fluorescence technique using one-
and two-step excitations. Out of these, seven belonging to the high lying
3d$^7$($^4$F)4d configuration in the energy range 90697 - 93738 cm$^{-1}$ are
new, and the other twelve from th3d$^7$($^4$F)F)4p configuration with energies
between 45972 and 49328 cm$^{-1}$1 are compared with previous measurements. In
addition, a relativistic Hartree-Fock model including core-polarization effects
has been employed to compute transition rates. Supported by the good agreement
between theory and experiment for the lifetimes, new reliable transition
probabilities and oscillator strengths have been deduced for 5080 Co II
transitions in the spectral range 114 - 8744 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02690</id><created>2016-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Nemitz</keyname><forenames>Ian R.</forenames><affiliation>E6</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ferris</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames><affiliation>E6</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lacaze</keyname><forenames>Emmanuelle</forenames><affiliation>E6</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rosenblatt</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral oily streaks in a smectic-A liquid crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Soft Matter, Royal Society of Chemistry, 2016, 12 (31),
  pp.6662-6668</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01238H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The liquid crystal octylcyanobiphenyl (8CB) was doped with the chiral agent
CB15 and spin-coated onto a substrate treated for planar alignment of the
director, resulting in a film of thickness several hundred nm in the smectic-A
phase. In both doped and undoped samples, the competing boundary conditions -
planar alignment at the substrate and vertical alignment at the free surface -
cause the liquid crystal to break into a series of flattened hemicylinders to
satisfy the boundary conditions. When viewed under an optical microscope with
crossed polarizers, this structure results in a series of dark and light
stripes (&quot;oily streaks&quot;) of period ~ 1 $\mu$m. In the absence of chiral dopant
the stripes run perpendicular to the substrate's easy axis. However, when doped
with chiral CB15 at concentrations up to c = 4 wt-%, the stripe orientation
rotates by a temperature-dependent angle $\phi$ with respect to the c = 0
stripe orientation, where $\phi$ increases monotonically with c. $\phi$ is
largest just below the nematic -- smectic-A transition temperature TNA and
decreases with decreasing temperature. As the temperature is lowered, $\phi$
relaxes to a steady-state orientation close to zero within ~1$^\circ$ C of TNA.
We suggest that the rotation phenomenon is a manifestation of the surface
electroclinic effect: The rotation is due to the weak smectic order parameter
and resulting large director tilt susceptibility with respect to the smectic
layer normal near TNA, in conjunction with an effective surface electric field
due to polar interactions between the liquid crystal and substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04073</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cuevas</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface plasmon enhancement of spontaneous emission in graphene
  waveguides</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optics 18, 105003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/10/105003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work analyzes the spontaneous emission of a single emitter placed near
the graphene waveguide formed by two parallel graphene monolayers, with an
insulator spacer layer. In this case, the eigenmodes supported by the
structure, such as surface plasmon and wave guided modes, provide decay
channels for the electric dipole placed close to the waveguide. We calculated
the contribution to the decay rate of symmetric and antisymmetric eigenmodes as
a function of frequency and the orientation of the emitter. Our results show
that the modification of the spontaneous emission due to excitation of guided
modes is much lower than the corresponding decays through the excitation of
symmetric and antisymmetric surface plasmons, for which, the spontaneous
emission is dramatically enhanced. As a consequence of the high confinement of
surface plasmons in the graphene waveguide, we found that the decay rate of the
emitter with vertical orientation (with respect to graphene sheets) is twice
the corresponding decay of the same emitter with parallel orientation in the
whole frequency range where surface plasmon modes exist. Differently from
metallo- dielectric structures, where structural parameters determine the range
and magnitude of this emission, our work shows that, by dynamically tuning the
chemical potential of graphene, the spectral region where the decay rate is
enhanced can be chosen over a wide range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06007</id><created>2016-09-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Richichi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dyachenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasuya</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balega</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beskakotov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rastegaev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhillon</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of asymmetries in the Aldebaran photosphere from
  multi-wavelength lunar occultations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2352</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have recorded three lunar occultations of Aldebaran (AlfTau) at different
telescopes and using various band-passes, from the ultraviolet to the far red.
The data have been analyzed using both model-dependent and model-independent
methods. The derived uniform-disc angular diameter values have been converted
to limb-darkened values using model atmosphere relations, and are found in
broad agreement among themselves and with previous literature values. The
limb-darkened diameter is about 20.3 milliarcseconds on average . However, we
have found indications that the photospheric brightness profile of Aldebaran
may have not been symmetric, a finding already reported by other authors for
this and for similar late-type stars. At the sampling scale of our brightness
profile, between one and two milliarcsecond, the uniform and limb-darkened disc
models may not be a good description for Aldebaran. The asymmetries appear to
differ with wavelength and over the 137 days time span of our measurements.
Surface spots appear as a likely explanation for the differences between
observations and the models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
