<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:47:08Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-11" from="2016-12-11" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0801.4612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0801.4612</id><created>2008-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Siodmiak</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meixner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugerman</keyname><forenames>B. E. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Steene</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczerba</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>HST Snapshot Survey of Post-AGB Objects</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1086/529115</doi><abstract>  The results from a Hubble Space Telescope (HST) snapshot survey of post-AGB
objects are shown. The aim of the survey is to complement existing HST images
of PPN and to connect various types of nebulosities with physical and chemical
properties of their central stars. Nebulosities are detected in 15 of 33
sources. Images and photometric and geometric measurements are presented. For
sources with nebulosities we see a morphological bifurcation into two groups,
DUPLEX and SOLE, as previous studies have found. We find further support to the
previous results suggesting that this dichotomy is caused by a difference in
optical thickness of the dust shell. The remaining 18 sources are classified as
stellar post-AGB objects, because our observations indicate a lack of
nebulosity. We show that some stellar sources may in fact be DUPLEX or SOLE
based on their infrared colors. The cause of the differences among the groups
are investigated. We discuss some evidence suggesting that high progenitor-mass
AGB stars tend to become DUPLEX post-AGB objects. Intermediate progenitor-mass
AGB stars tend to be SOLE post-AGB objects. Most of the stellar sources
probably have low mass progenitors and do not seem to develop nebulosities
during the post-AGB phase and therefore do not become planetary nebulae.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.2993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.2993</id><created>2013-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Barettin</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sibani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimization by Record Dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2013.10.030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large dynamical changes in thermalizing glassy systems are triggered by
trajectories crossing record sized barriers, a behavior revealing the presence
of a hierarchical structure in configuration space. The observation is here
turned into a novel local search optimization algorithm dubbed Record Dynamics
Optimization, or RDO. RDO uses the Metropolis rule to accept or reject
candidate solutions depending on the value of a parameter akin to the
temperature, and minimizes the cost function of the problem at hand through
cycles where its `temperature' is raised and subsequently decreased in order to
expediently generate record high (and low) values of the cost function. Below,
RDO is introduced and then tested by searching the ground state of the
Edwards-Anderson spin-glass model, in two and three spatial dimensions. A
popular and highly efficient optimization algorithm, Parallel Tempering (PT) is
applied to the same problem as a benchmark. RDO and PT turn out to produce
solution of similar quality for similar numerical effort, but RDO is simpler to
program and additionally yields geometrical information on the system's
configuration space which is of interest in many applications. In particular,
the effectiveness of RDO strongly indicates the presence of the above mentioned
hierarchically organized configuration space, with metastable regions indexed
by the cost (or energy) of the transition states connecting them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06303</id><created>2015-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Plihon</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>LPP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chabert</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>LPP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Corr</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames><affiliation>LPP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Experimental investigation of double layers in expanding plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas, American Institute of Physics (AIP), 2007, 14,
  pp.013506</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.2424429</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Double layers (DLs) have been observed in a plasma reactor composed of a
source chamber attached to a larger expanding chamber. Positive ion beams
generated across the DL were characterized in the low plasma potential region
using retarding field energy analyzers. In electropositive gases, DLs were
formed at very low pressures between 0.1 and 1 mTorr with the plasma expansion
forced by a strongly diverging magnetic field. The DL remains static, robust to
changes in boundary conditions, and its position is related to the magnetic
field lines. The voltage drop across the DL increases with decreasing pressure,
i.e., with increasing electron temperature around 20 V at 0.17 mTorr. DLs were
also observed in electronegative gases without a magnetic field over a greater
range of pressure 0.5 to 10 mTorr. The actual profile of the electronegative DL
is very sensitive to external parameters and intrusive elements, and they
propagate at high negative ion fraction. Electrostatic probes measurements and
laser-induced photodetachment show discontinuities in all plasma parameters
electron density, electron temperature, negative ion fraction at the DL
position. The voltage drop across the electronegative DL is about 8 V, is
independent of the gas pressure and therefore of the electron temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0702399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0702399</id><created>2007-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Krongold</keyname><forenames>Yair</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicastro</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elvis</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brickhouse</keyname><forenames>Nancy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binette</keyname><forenames>Luc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathur</keyname><forenames>Smita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jimenez-Bailon</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>The Compact, Conical, Accretion-Disk Warm Absorber of the Seyfert 1
  Galaxy NGC 4051 and its Implications for IGM-Galaxy Feedback Processes</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication on ApJ on Dec 15, 2006. 13 Figures, 4 Tables</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J.659:1022-1039,2007</journal-ref><doi>10.1086/512476</doi><abstract>  (Abridged) Using a 100 ks XMM-Newton exposure of NGC 4051, we show that the
time evolution of the ionization state of the X-ray absorbers in response to
the rapid and highly variable X-ray continuum constrains all the main physical
and geometrical properties of an AGN Warm Absorber wind. The absorber consists
of two different ionization components. By tracking the response in the opacity
of the gas in each component to changes in the ionizing continuum, we were able
to constrain the electron density of the system. The measured densities require
that the high and low ionization absorbing components of NGC 4051 must be
compact, at distances 0.5-1.0 l-d (2200 - 4400Rs) and &lt; 3.5 l-d (&lt; 15800Rs)
from the continuum source, respectively. This rules out an origin in the dusty
obscuring torus, as the dust sublimation radius is at least an order of
magnitude larger (&gt;12 l-d). An accretion disk origin for the warm absorber wind
is strongly suggested, and an association with the high ionization, HeII
emitting, broad emission line region (radius &lt;2 l-d) is possible. The two
detected phases are consistent with pressure equilibrium, which suggests that
the absorber consists of a two phase medium. A radial flow in a spherical
geometry is unlikely, and a conical wind geometry is preferred. The implied
mass outflow rate from this wind, can be well constrained, and is 2-5% of the
mass accretion rate. If the mass outflow rate scaling with accretion rate is
representative of all quasars, our results imply that warm absorbers in
powerful quasars are unlikely to produce important evolutionary effects on
their larger environment, unless we are observing the winds before they get
fully accelerated. Only in such a scenario can AGN winds be important for
cosmic feedback.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
