<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:46:40Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-09" from="2016-12-09" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0707.4675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0707.4675</id><created>2007-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Trice</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Hernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sureshkumar</keyname><forenames>Radhakrishna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalyanaraman</keyname><forenames>Ramki</forenames></author></authors><title>In silico design of metal-dielectric nanocomposites for solar energy
  applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>submitted to SPIE Optics+Photonics, 2007</comments><journal-ref>Proc. of SPIE, 6648, 66480L-1 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.734531</doi><abstract>  Recently, a homogenization procedure has been proposed, based on the tight
lower bounds of the Bergman-Milton formulation, and successfully applied to
dilute ternary nanocomposites to predict optical data without using any fitting
parameters [Garcia et al. Phys. Rev. B, 75, 045439 (2007)]. The procedure has
been extended and applied to predict the absorption coefficient of a quaternary
nanocomposite consisting of Cu, Ag, and Au nanospheres embedded in a SiO2 host
matrix. Significant enhancement of the absorption coefficient is observed over
the spectral range 350-800 nm. The magnitude of this enhancement can be
controlled by varying the nanosphere diameter and the individual metal volume
fraction with respect to the host matrix. We have determined the optimal
composition resulting in enhanced broadband (350nm-800nm) absorption of the
solar spectrum using a simulated annealing algorithm. Fabricating such
composite materials with a desired optical absorption has potential
applications in solar energy harvesting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1203.3561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1203.3561</id><created>2012-03-15</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Comp&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>The Kerr/CFT correspondence and its extensions: a comprehensive review</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>94 pages, accepted to Living Reviews in Relativity (revision)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a first-principles derivation of the main results of the Kerr/CFT
correspondence and its extensions using only tools from gravity and quantum
field theory. Firstly, we review properties of extremal black holes with in
particular the construction of an asymptotic Virasoro symmetry in the
near-horizon limit. The entropy of extremal spinning or charged black holes is
shown to match with a chiral half of Cardy's formula. Secondly, we show how a
thermal 2-dimensional conformal field theory (CFT) is relevant to reproduce the
dynamics of near-superradiant probes around near-extremal black holes in the
semi-classical limit. Thirdly, we review the hidden conformal symmetries of
asymptotically-flat black holes away from extremality and present how the
non-extremal entropy can be matched with Cardy's formula. We follow an
effective field theory approach and consider the Kerr-Newman black hole and its
generalizations in various supergravity theories. The interpretation of these
results by deformed dual conformal field theories is discussed and contrasted
with properties of standard 2-dimensional CFTs. We conclude with a list of open
problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1203.4679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1203.4679</id><created>2012-03-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>X. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Q. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yi.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>X. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Z. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>team</keyname><forenames>HL-2A</forenames></author></authors><title>EGAM Induced by Energetic-electrons and Nonlinear Interactions among
  EGAM, BAEs and Tearing Modes in a Toroidal Plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>5 pages,4 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2012.11.055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, it is reported that the first experimental results are
associated with the GAM induced by energetic electrons (eEGAM) in HL-2A Ohmic
plasma. The energetic-electrons are generated by parallel electric fields
during magnetic reconnection associated with tearing mode (TM). The eEGAM
localizes in the core plasma, i.e. in the vicinity of q=2 surface, and is very
different from one excited by the drift-wave turbulence in the edge plasma. The
analysis indicated that the eEGAM is provided with the magnetic components,
whose intensities depend on the poloidal angles, and its mode numbers are
jm/nj=2/0. Further, there exist intense nonlinear interactions among eEGAM,
BAEs and strong tearing modes (TMs). These new findings shed light on the
underlying physics mechanism for the excitation of the low frequency (LF)
Alfv\'enic and acoustic uctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.3527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.3527</id><created>2012-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chattopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Surajit</forenames><affiliation>Pailan College of Management and Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames><affiliation>Bhairab Ganguly College</affiliation></author></authors><title>A study of generalized second law of thermodynamics in modified f(R)
  Horava-Lifshitz gravity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, Accepted for publication Astrophysics and Space
  Science, 2012</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and Space Science, 341, 669-674, 2012</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-012-1088-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work investigates the validity of the generalized second law of
thermodynamics in modified f(R) Horava-Lifshitz gravity proposed by Chaichian
et al (2010) [Class. Quantum Grav. 27 (2010) 185021], which is invariant under
foliation-preserving diffeomorphisms. It has been observed that the equation of
state parameter behaves like quintessence (w &gt; -1). We study the thermodynamics
of the apparent, event and particle horizons in this modified gravity. We
observe that under this gravity, the time derivative of total entropy stays at
positive level and hence the generalized second law is validated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1211.4799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1211.4799</id><created>2012-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Blasi</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of Galactic Cosmic Rays</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Invited Review Talk in SciNeGHE 2012, 20-22 June 2012, Lecce (Italy)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2013.05.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the bulk of cosmic rays (CRs) observed at Earth is the topic of
a century long investigation, paved with successes and failures. From the
energetic point of view, supernova remnants (SNRs) remain the most plausible
sources of CRs up to rigidity ? 10^6-10^7 GV. This confidence somehow resulted
in the construction of a paradigm, the so-called SNR paradigm: CRs are
accelerated through diffusive shock acceleration in SNRs and propagate
diffusively in the Galaxy in an energy dependent way. Qualitative confirmation
of the SNR acceleration scenario has recently been provided by gamma ray and
X-ray observations. Diffusive propagation in the Galaxy is probed
observationally through measurement of the secondary to primary nuclei flux
ratios (such as B/C). There are however some weak points in the paradigm, which
suggest that we are probably missing some physical ingredients in our models.
The theory of diffusive shock acceleration at SNR shocks predicts spectra of
accelerated particles which are systematically too hard compared with the ones
inferred from gamma ray observations. Moreover, hard injection spectra
indirectly imply a steep energy dependence of the diffusion coefficient in the
Galaxy, which in turn leads to anisotropy larger than the observed one.
Moreover recent measurements of the flux of nuclei suggest that the spectra
have a break at rigidity ? 200 GV, which does not sit well with the common
wisdom in acceleration and propagation. In this paper I will review these new
developments and suggest some possible implications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.5955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.5955</id><created>2013-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Tzu-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Chang-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shy</keyname><forenames>Jow-Tsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable frequency-stabilization of UV laser using a Hallow-Cathode Lamp
  of atomic thallium</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figure2</comments><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.30.002966</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A frequency-stabilized ultraviolet laser system, locked to the thallium
resonant transition of 377.5 nm, was demonstrated using a novel bichromatic
spectroscopy technique for tuning the zero-crossing laser-lock point. The
atomic thallium system is a promising candidate in atomic parity violation and
permanent electric dipole moment experiments, and its 377.5 nm 6P1/2-&gt;7S1/2
transition is important for thallium laser cooling and trapping experiment. The
pressure shift, owing to the high pressure buffer gas of the hollow-cathode
lamp, was observed using an atomic beam resonance as reference. Such a shift
was corrected by adjusting the peak ratio of the two Doppler-free saturation
profiles resulted from two pumping beams with a 130 MHz frequency difference.
The resulted frequency stability of the ultraviolet laser is ?0.5 MHz at 0.1
sec integration time. This scheme is compact and versatile for stabilizing UV
laser systems, which acquire a sub-MHz stability and frequency tunability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.7146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.7146</id><created>2013-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Q. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Normand</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial order in Potts models on the generalized decorated square
  lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. Lett. Vol. 30, No. 7 (2013) 076402</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0256-307X/30/7/076402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the Potts model on the generalized decorated square lattice, with
both nearest (J1) and next-neighbor (J2) interactions. Using the tensor
renormalization-group method augmented by higher-order singular value
decompositions, we calculate the spontaneous magnetization of the Potts model
with q = 2, 3, and 4. The results for q = 2 allow us to benchmark our numerics
using the exact solution. For q = 3, we find a highly degenerate ground state
with partial order on a single sublattice, but with vanishing entropy per site,
and we obtain the phase diagram as a function of the ratio J2=J1. There is no
finite-temperature transition for the q = 4 case when J1 = J2, but the magnetic
susceptibility diverges as the temperature goes to zero, showing that the model
is critical at T = 0.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.1329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.1329</id><created>2013-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Donea</keyname><forenames>Alina</forenames><affiliation>Monash Univeristy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames><affiliation>Monash Univeristy</affiliation></author></authors><title>Enhanced sources of acoustic power surrounding AR11429</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, published, Journal of Physics: Conference Series Volume 440
  conference 2013 J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 440 012028</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series Volume, 2013</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/440/1/012028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multi-frequency power maps of the local acoustic oscillations show acoustic
enhancements (\acoustic-power halos&quot;) at high frequencies surrounding large
active region. Computational seismic holography reveals a high-frequency
\acoustic-emission halo&quot;, or \seismic glory&quot; surrounding large active regions.
In this study, we have applied computational seismic holography to map the
seismic seismic source density surrounding AR 11429. Studies of HMI/SDO Doppler
data, shows that the &quot;acoustic halos&quot; and the &quot;seismic glories&quot; are prominent
at high frequencies 5-8 mHz. We investigate morphological properties of
acoustic-power and acoustic emission halos around an active region to see if
they are spatially correlated. Details about the local magnetic field from
vectormagnetograms of AR 11429 are included. We identify a 15&quot; region of
seismic deficit power (dark moat) shielding the white-light boundary of the
active region. The size of the seismic moat is related to region of
intermediate magnetic field strength. The acoustic moat is circled by the halo
of enhanced seismic amplitude as well as enhanced seismic emission. Overall,
the results suggest that features are related. However, if we narrow the
frequency band to 5.5-6.5 mHz, we find that the seismic source density
dominates over the local acoustic power, suggesting the existence of sources
that emit more energy downward into the solar interior than upward toward the
solar surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.5105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.5105</id><created>2013-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Seizinger</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Speith</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kley</keyname><forenames>Wilhelm</forenames></author></authors><title>Tensile &amp; shear strength of porous dust agglomerates</title><categories>astro-ph.EP cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201322046</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Context.Within the sequential accretion scenario of planet formation, planets
are build up through a sequence sticking collisions. The outcome of collisions
between porous dust aggregates is very important for the growth from very small
dust particles to planetesimals. In this work we determine the necessary
material properties of dust aggregates as a function the porosity.
  Aims: Continuum models such as SPH that are capable of simulating collisions
of macroscopic dust aggregates require a set of material parameters. Some of
them such as the tensile and shear strength are difficult to obtain from
laboratory experiments. The aim of this work is to determine these parameters
from ab-initio molecular dynamics simulations.
  Methods: We simulate the behavior of porous dust aggregates using a detailed
micro-physical model of the interaction of spherical grains that includes
adhesion forces, rolling, twisting, and sliding. Using different methods of
preparing the samples we study the strength behavior of our samples with
varying porosity and coordination number of the material.
  Results: For the tensile strength, we can reproduce data from laboratory
experiments very well. For the shear strength, there are no experimental data
available. The results from our simulations differ significantly from previous
theoretical models, which indicates that the latter might not be sufficient to
describe porous dust aggregates.
  Conclusions: We have provided functional behavior of tensile and shear
strength of porous dust aggregates as a function of the porosity that can be
directly applied in continuum simulations of these objects in planet formation
scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.8229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.8229</id><created>2013-10-30</created><updated>2013-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Enokiya</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torii</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schultheis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asahina</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furuhashi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshiike</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furukawa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moribe</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohama</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sano</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okamoto</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanaoka</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayakawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okuda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawamura</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuno</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of possible molecular counterparts to the infrared Double
  Helix Nebula in the Galactic center</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>32 pages, 23 figures, Accepted by ApJ</comments><msc-class>85-05</msc-class><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/780/1/72</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have discovered two molecular features at radial velocities of -35 km/s
and 0 km/s toward the infrared Double Helix Nebula (DHN) in the Galactic center
with NANTEN2. The two features show good spatial correspondence with the DHN.
We have also found two elongated molecular ridges at these two velocities
distributed vertically to the Galactic plane over 0.8 degree. The two ridges
are linked by broad features in velocity and are likely connected physically
with each other. The ratio between the 12CO J=2-1 and J=1-0 transitions is 0.8
in the ridges which is larger than the average value 0.5 in the foreground gas,
suggesting the two ridges are in the Galactic center. An examination of the K
band extinction reveals a good coincidence with the CO 0 km/s ridge and is
consistent with a distance of 8 +/-2 kpc. We discuss the possibility that the
DHN was created by a magnetic phenomenon incorporating torsional Alfv\'en waves
launched from the circumnuclear disk (Morris, Uchida &amp; Do 2006) and present a
first estimate of the mass and energy involved in the DHN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.2787</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.2787</id><created>2014-04-10</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Laszlo</keyname><forenames>Andras</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence and error propagation results on a linear iterative
  unfolding method</title><categories>stat.AP math.ST physics.data-an stat.TH</categories><comments>27 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>62H99 (Primary) 46E30, 46E27 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>SIAM/ASA Journal of Uncertainty Quantification 4 (2016) 1345</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/15M1035744</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unfolding problems often arise in the context of statistical data analysis.
Such problematics occur when the probability distribution of a physical
quantity is to be measured, but it is randomized (smeared) by some well
understood process, such as a non-ideal detector response or a well described
physical phenomenon. In such case it is said that the original probability
distribution of interest is folded by a known response function. The
reconstruction of the original probability distribution from the measured one
is called unfolding. That technically involves evaluation of the non-bounded
inverse of an integral operator over the space of L^1 functions, which is known
to be an ill-posed problem. For the pertinent regularized operator inversion,
we propose a linear iterative formula and provide proof of convergence in a
probability theory context. Furthermore, we provide formulae for error
estimates at finite iteration stopping order which are of utmost importance in
practical applications: the approximation error, the propagated statistical
error, and the propagated systematic error can be quantified. The arguments are
based on the Riesz-Thorin theorem mapping the original L^1 problem to L^2
space, and subsequent application of ordinary L^2 spectral theory of operators.
A library implementation in C of the algorithm along with corresponding error
propagation is also provided. A numerical example also illustrates the method
in operation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.1337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.1337</id><created>2014-07-04</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Papavassiliou</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Gareth P</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbits of swimmers around obstacles</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures. This paper has been withdrawn by the author due
  to significant error in the calculation used</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a two dimensional model of hydrodynamic interaction between a
circular swimmer and a circular post at low Reynolds number, using a point
singularity description of the swimming activity. We derive a nonlinear
dynamical system fully describing the motion and discuss the generic features
of the phase portrait and typical trajectories for a variety of squirmer modes.
Contractile swimmers exhibit stable bound orbits arising from the contrasting
nature of monopolar and dipolar squirmer modes, which are robust with respect
to swimmer size and the inclusion of higher squirmer modes. The behaviour of
extensile swimmers is related through time reversal and their orbits are
unstable, in qualitative agreement with experimental observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6958</id><created>2014-11-25</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Elgindi</keyname><forenames>Tarek M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic Stability for some Stratified Stationary Solutions of the
  Inviscid Incompressible Porous Medium Equation</title><categories>math.AP physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We initiate the study of stability of solutions of the 2D inviscid
incompressible porous medium equation (IPM). We begin by classifying all
stationary solutions of the inviscid IPM under mild conditions. We then prove
some linear stability results. We then study solutions of the IPM equation
which are sufficiently regular perturbations of linearly stable steady states.
We prove that sufficiently regular perturbations which are also small must be
globally regular and strongly converge to a steady state. The mechanism behind
the stability is \emph{stratification} as opposed to previous stability results
based on dispersion and/or mixing \cite{BedrossianMasmoudi}. More or less, we
prove that stratified stationary solutions which do not go against gravity are
asymptotically stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04438</id><created>2015-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Exl</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauser</keyname><forenames>Norbert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate and efficient computation of nonlocal potentials based on
  Gaussian-sum approximation</title><categories>physics.comp-ph math.NA</categories><msc-class>33F05, 44A35, 65E05, 65R10, 65T50</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Comput. Phys. 327 (2016) 629-642</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.09.045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an accurate and efficient method for a class of nonlocal
potential evaluations with free boundary condition, including the 3D/2D
Coulomb, 2D Poisson and 3D dipolar potentials. Our method is based on a
Gaussian-sum approximation of the singular convolution kernel and Taylor
expansion of the density. Starting from the convolution formulation, for smooth
and fast decaying densities, we make a full use of the Fourier pseudospectral
(plane wave) approximation of the density and a separable Gaussian-sum
approximation of the kernel in an interval where the singularity (the origin)
is excluded. Hence, the potential is separated into a regular integral and a
near-field singular correction integral, where the first integral is computed
with the Fourier pseudospectral method and the latter singular one can be well
resolved utilizing a low-order Taylor expansion of the density. Both
evaluations can be accelerated by fast Fourier transforms (FFT). The new method
is accurate (14-16 digits), efficient ($O(N \log N)$ complexity), low in
storage, easily adaptable to other different kernels, applicable for
anisotropic densities and highly parallelable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07852</id><created>2015-05-28</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Junge</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultraproduct methods for mixed $q$-Gaussian algebras</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.FA math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>47 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a unified ultraproduct approach for constructing Wick words in
mixed $q$-Gaussian algebras, which are generated by $s_j=a_j+a_j^*$,
$j=1,\cdots,N$, where $a_ia^*_j - q_{ij}a^*_ja_i =\delta_{ij}$. Here we also
allow equality in $-1\le q_{ij}=q_{ji}\le 1$. Using the ultraproduct method, we
construct an approximate co-multiplication of the mixed $q$-Gaussian algebras.
Based on this we prove that these algebras are weakly amenable and strongly
solid in the sense of Ozawa and Popa. We also encode Speicher's central limit
theorem in the unified ultraproduct method, and show that the
Ornstein--Uhlenbeck semigroup is hypercontractive, the Riesz transform
associated to the number operator is bounded, and the number operator satisfies
the $L_p$ Poincar\'e inequalities with constants $C\sqrt{p}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06384</id><created>2015-09-21</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vargas-Maga&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fromenteau</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuesta</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The clustering of galaxies in the SDSS-III Baryon Oscillation
  Spectroscopic Survey: Effect of smoothing of density field on reconstruction
  and anisotropic BAO analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 18 figures, 11 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reconstruction algorithm introduced by \cite{Eis07}, which is widely used
in clustering analysis, is based on the inference of the first order Lagrangian
displacement field from the Gaussian smoothed galaxy density field in redshift
space. The \modif2{smoothing scale} applied to the density field affects the
inferred displacement field that is used to move {the galaxies}, and partially
\modif2{erases} the nonlinear evolution {of the density field}.
  In this article, we explore this crucial step \modif2{in} the reconstruction
algorithm. We study the performance of the reconstruction technique using two
metrics: first, we study the performance using the anisotropic clustering,
extending previous studies focused on isotropic clustering; second, we study
its effect on the displacement field. We find that smoothing has a strong
effect in the quadrupole of the correlation function and affects the accuracy
and precision \modif2{with} which we can measure $D_A (z)$ and $H(z)$. We find
that the optimal smoothing scale to use in the reconstruction algorithm applied
to BOSS-CMASS is between 5-10 $h^{-1}$Mpc. Varying from the &quot;usual&quot;
15$h^{-1}$Mpc to $5 h^{-1}$Mpc \modif2{shows} $\sim$ 0.3\% variations in
$D_A(z)$ and $\sim$ 0.4\% $H(z)$ and uncertainties are also reduced by 40\% and
30\% respectively. We also find that the accuracy of velocity field
reconstruction depends strongly on the smoothing scale used for the density
field. We measure the bias and uncertainties associated with different choices
of smoothing length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07512</id><created>2015-09-24</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Privon</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrero-Illana</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez-Torres</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armus</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Santos</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stierwalt</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aalto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzarella</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barcos-Munoz</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borish</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inami</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>D. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treister</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surace</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lord</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conway</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frayer</keyname><forenames>D. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alberdi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation Mechanisms for HCN (1-0) and HCO+ (1-0) in Galaxies from the
  Great Observatories All-sky LIRG Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>fix presentation of numerical value of y-intercept in eqs 1-3 to
  match forthcoming ApJ erratum. figure 6 and the conclusions are unaffected</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 814, 39 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/814/1/39</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new IRAM 30m spectroscopic observations of the $\sim88$ GHz band,
including emission from the CCH (n=1-0) multiplet, HCN (1-0), HCO+ (1-0), and
HNC (1-0), for a sample of 58 local luminous and ultraluminous infrared
galaxies from the Great Observatories All-sky LIRG Survey (GOALS). By combining
our new IRAM data with literature data and Spitzer/IRS spectroscopy, we study
the correspondence between these putative tracers of dense gas and the relative
contribution of active galactic nuclei (AGN) and star formation to the
mid-infrared luminosity of each system. We find the HCN (1-0) emission to be
enhanced in AGN-dominated systems ($\langle$L'$_{HCN (1-0)}$/L'$_{HCO^+
(1-0)}\rangle=1.84$), compared to composite and starburst-dominated systems
($\langle$L'$_{HCN (1-0)}$/L'$_{HCO^+ (1-0)}\rangle=1.14$, and 0.88,
respectively). However, some composite and starburst systems have L'$_{HCN
(1-0)}$/L'$_{HCO^+ (1-0)}$ ratios comparable to those of AGN, indicating that
enhanced HCN emission is not uniquely associated with energetically dominant
AGN. After removing AGN-dominated systems from the sample, we find a linear
relationship (within the uncertainties) between $\log_{10}$(L'$_{HCN (1-0)}$)
and $\log_{10}$(L$_{IR}$), consistent with most previous findings. L'$_{HCN
(1-0)}$/L$_{IR}$, typically interpreted as the dense gas depletion time,
appears to have no systematic trend with L$_{IR}$ for our sample of luminous
and ultraluminous infrared galaxies, and has significant scatter. The
galaxy-integrated HCN (1-0) and HCO+ (1-0) emission do not appear to have a
simple interpretation, in terms of the AGN dominance or the star formation
rate, and are likely determined by multiple processes, including density and
radiative effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04605</id><created>2015-10-15</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>B&#xe9;car</keyname><forenames>Ram&#xf3;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>V&#xe1;squez</keyname><forenames>Yerko</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasinormal modes of non-Abelian hyperscaling violating Lifshitz black
  holes</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in GERG. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1509.00802</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quasinormal modes of scalar field perturbations in the
background of non-Abelian hyperscaling violating Lifshitz black holes. We find
that the quasinormal frequencies have no real part so there is no oscillatory
behavior in the perturbations, only exponential decay, that is, the system is
always overdamped, which guarantees the mode stability of non-Abelian
hyperscaling violating Lifshitz black holes. We determine analytically the
quasinormal modes for massless scalar fields for a dynamical exponent $z=2$ and
hyperscaling violating exponent $\tilde{\theta}&gt;-2$. Also, we obtain
numerically the quasinormal frequencies for different values of the dynamical
exponent and the hyperscaling violating exponent by using the improved
asymptotic iteration method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06354</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Alpha A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic mechanism of thermomolecular orientation and polarization</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 12, 8661 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01927G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent molecular dynamics simulations show that thermal gradients can induce
electric fields in water that are comparable in magnitude to electric fields
seen in ionic thin films and biomembranes. This surprising non-equilibrium
phenomenon of thermomolecular orientation is also observed more generally in
simulations of polar and non-polar size-asymmetric dumbbell fluids. However, a
microscopic theory linking thermomolecular orientation and polarization to
molecular properties is yet unknown. Here, we formulate an analytically
solvable microscopic model of size-asymmetric dumbbell molecules in a
temperature gradient using a mean-field, local equilibrium approach. Our theory
reveals the relationship between the extent of thermomolecular orientation and
polarization, and molecular volume, size anisotropy and dipole moment.
Predictions of the theory agree quantitatively with molecular dynamics
simulations. Crucially, our framework shows how thermomolecular orientation can
be controlled and maximized by tuning microscopic molecular properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03457</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krumholz</keyname><forenames>Mark R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on Star Formation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>405 pages, 21 chapters; source for the book is available at
  https://github.com/Open-Astrophysics-Bookshelf/star_formation_notes; compared
  to previous version, this one has numerous corrections, and has a new chapter
  and problems on the first stars</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  This book provides an introduction to the field of star formation at a level
suitable for graduate students or advanced undergraduates in astronomy or
physics. The structure of the book is as follows. The first two chapters begin
with a discussion of observational techniques, and the basic phenomenology they
reveal. The goal is to familiarize students with the basic techniques that will
be used throughout, and to provide a common vocabulary for the rest of the
book. The next five chapters provide a similar review of the basic physical
processes that are important for star formation. Again, the goal is to provide
a basis for what follows. The remaining chapters discuss star formation over a
variety of scales, starting with the galactic scale and working down to the
scales of individual stars and their disks. The book concludes with a brief
discussion of the clearing of disks and the transition to planet formation. The
book includes five problem sets, complete with solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07796</id><created>2015-11-24</created><updated>2016-10-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsiaras</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waldmann</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rocchetto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varley</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morello</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damiano</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tinetti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new approach to analysing HST spatial scans: the transmission spectrum
  of HD 209458 b</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 15 figures, 7 tables, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/2/202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Wide Field Camera 3 (WFC3) on Hubble Space Telescope (HST) is currently
one of the most widely used instruments for observing exoplanetary atmospheres,
especially with the use of the spatial scanning technique. An increasing number
of exoplanets have been studied using this technique as it enables the
observation of bright targets without saturating the sensitive detectors. In
this work we present a new pipeline for analyzing the data obtained with the
spatial scanning technique, starting from the raw data provided by the
instrument. In addition to commonly used correction techniques, we take into
account the geometric distortions of the instrument, whose impact may become
important when combined to the scanning process. Our approach can improve the
photometric precision for existing data and also push further the limits of the
spatial scanning technique, as it allows the analysis of even longer spatial
scans. As an application of our method and pipeline, we present the results
from a reanalysis of the spatially scanned transit spectrum of HD 209458 b. We
calculate the transit depth per wavelength channel with an average relative
uncertainty of 40 ppm. We interpret the final spectrum with T-Rex, our fully
Bayesian spectral retrieval code, which confirms the presence of water vapor
and clouds in the atmosphere of HD 209458 b. The narrow wavelength range limits
our ability to disentangle the degeneracies between the fitted atmospheric
parameters. Additional data over a broader spectral range are needed to address
this issue.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04258</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-01-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qing-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Jian-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Ke-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Shin-Ted</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chang-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Hao-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Xun-Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of photoelectron yield of the prototype for the CDEX-10
  liquid argon detector</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures. Submitted to Chin. Phys. C</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C 40, 11(2016) 116002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/11/116002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The China Dark Matter Experiment (CDEX) is a low background experiment at
China Jinping Underground Laboratory (CJPL) designed to directly detect dark
matter with a high-purity Germanium (HPGe) detector. In the second phase
CDEX-10 with a 10 kg Germanium array detector system, the liquid argon (LAr)
anti-compton active shielding and cooling system is proposed. For purpose of
studying the properties of LAr detector, a prototype with an active volume of 7
liters of liquid argon was built and operated. The photoelectron yields, as a
critically important parameter for the prototype detector, have been measured
to be 0.051-0.079 p.e./keV for 662 keV Gamma lines at different positions. The
good agreement between the experimental and simulation results has provided a
quite reasonable understanding and determination of the important parameters
such as the Surviving Fraction of the Ar2 excimers, the absorption length for
128 nm photons in liquid argon, the reflectivity of Teflon and so on.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06530</id><created>2015-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Hayashi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanida</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sera</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsubayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uwatoko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochiai</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kondo effect in CeX$_{c}$ (X$_{c}$=S, Se, Te) studied by electrical
  resistivity under high pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 034704 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.034704</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the electrical resistivity of cerium monochalcogenices, CeS,
CeSe, and CeTe, under high pressures up to 8 GPa. Pressure dependences of the
antiferromagnetic ordering temperature $T_{N}$, crystal field splitting, and
the $\ln T$ anomaly of the Kondo effect have been studied to cover the whole
region from the magnetic ordering regime at low pressure to the Fermi liquid
regime at high pressure. $T_{N}$ initially increases with increasing pressure,
and starts to decrease at high pressure as expected from the Doniach's diagram.
Simultaneously, the $\ln T$ behavior in the resistivity is enhanced, indicating
the enhancement of the Kondo effect by pressure. It is also characteristic in
CeX$_{c}$ that the crystal field splitting rapidly decreases at a common rate
of $-12.2$ K/GPa. This leads to the increase in the degeneracy of the $f$ state
and further enhancement of the Kondo effect. It is shown that the pressure
dependent degeneracy of the $f$ state is a key factor to understand the
pressure dependence of $T_{N}$, Kondo effect, magnetoresistance, and the peak
structure in the temperature dependence of resistivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06622</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stockschl&#xe4;der</keyname><forenames>Pia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreismann</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hentschel</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author></authors><title>Ray picture and ray-wave correspondence in triangular microlasers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures; considerably expanded, especially results of
  wave simulations added</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. 18, 125605 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/12/125605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply ray-optical methods to dielectric optical microcavities in the shape
of triangles made of low refractive index material. We find ray trajectories
that maximize the intensity inside the cavity to determine the far-field
emission characteristics and to complement the concept of the unstable manifold
applicable to chaotic microlasers. As these maximum intensity trajectories need
not to be periodic, we suggest that they provide a more general explanation for
emission patterns of microlasers than short periodic orbits. Further, the
geometrical optics description is extended by the inclusion of intensity
amplification along the optical path to achieve a better description of active,
lasing cavities. Far-field emission patterns of equilateral triangle cavities
obtained in this way agree well with our full electromagnetic wave simulations
and with previously reported experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01004</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koller</keyname><forenames>Andrew P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wall</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mundinger</keyname><forenames>Josh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rey</keyname><forenames>Ana Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of interacting fermions in spin-dependent potentials</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>5.5 pages and 4 figures + 8 pages and 6 figures supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 195302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.195302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments with dilute trapped Fermi gases observed that weak
interactions can drastically modify spin transport dynamics and give rise to
robust collective effects including global demagnetization, macroscopic spin
waves, spin segregation, and spin self-rephasing. In this work we develop a
framework for studying the dynamics of weakly interacting fermionic gases
following a spin-dependent change of the trapping potential which illuminates
the interplay between spin, motion, Fermi statistics, and interactions. The key
idea is the projection of the state of the system onto a set of lattice spin
models defined on the single-particle mode space. Collective phenomena,
including the global spreading of quantum correlations in real space, arise as
a consequence of the long-ranged character of the spin model couplings. This
approach achieves good agreement with prior measurements and suggests a number
of directions for future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04628</id><created>2016-01-18</created><updated>2016-09-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>SK Firoz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benjamin</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author></authors><title>A scheme to realize the quantum spin-valley Hall effect in monolayer
  graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in CARBON (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 110, 304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2016.09.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum spin Hall effect was first predicted in graphene. However, the weak
spin orbit interaction in graphene meant that the search for quantum spin Hall
effect in graphene never fructified. In this work we show how to generate the
quantum spin-valley Hall effect in graphene via quantum pumping by
adiabatically modulating a magnetic impurity and an electrostatic potential in
a monolayer of strained graphene. We see that not only exclusive spin polarized
currents can be pumped in the two valleys in exactly opposite directions but
one can have pure spin currents flowing in opposite directions in the two
valleys, we call this novel phenomena the quantum spin-valley Hall effect. This
means that the twin effects of quantum valley Hall and quantum spin Hall can
both be probed simultaneously in the proposed device. This work will
significantly advance the field of graphene spintronics, hitherto hobbled by
the lack of spin-orbit interaction. We obviate the need for any spin orbit
interaction and show how graphene can be manipulated to posses features
exclusive to topological insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08113</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Conde</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzolla</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz Constraints on Massive Three-Point Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>31+10 pages, 0 figures. Relevant improvements of the results.
  Appendix B added. Version accepted by journal</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1609 (2016) 041</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the helicity-spinor language we explore the non-perturbative
constraints that Lorentz symmetry imposes on three-point amplitudes where the
asymptotic states can be massive. As it is well known, in the case of only
massless states the three-point amplitude is fixed up to a coupling constant by
these constraints plus some physical requirements. We find that a similar
statement can be made when some of the particles have mass. We derive the
generic functional form of the three-point amplitude by virtue of Lorentz
symmetry, which displays several functional structures accompanied by arbitrary
constants. These constants can be related to the coupling constants of the
theory, but in an unambiguous fashion only in the case of one massive particle.
Constraints on these constants are obtained by imposing that in the UV limit
the massive amplitude matches the massless one. In particular, there is a
certain Lorentz frame, which corresponds to projecting all the massive momenta
along the same null momentum, where the three-point massive amplitude is fully
fixed, and has a universal form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02322</id><created>2016-02-06</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalachev</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hemmer</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocharovskaya</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum storage based on controllable frequency comb</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest an all-optical scheme for the storage, retrieval and processing of
a single-photon wave packet through its off-resonant Raman interaction with a
series of coherent control beams. These control beams, each with distinct
carrier frequency, are distributed along the way of single-photon propagation,
thus effectively forming a gradient absorption structure which can be
controlled in various ways to achieve different single-photon processing
functionalities. Such a controllable frequency comb is a hybrid of Raman,
gradient echo memory (GEM) and atomic frequency comb (AFC) methods, therefore
demonstrates many of their advantages all together in one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00338</id><created>2016-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Strambini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vischi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeret</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarov</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giazotto</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>The $\omega$-SQUIPT: phase-engineering of Josephson topological
  materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 color figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Nanotechnology 11, 1055 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nnano.2016.157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multi-terminal superconducting Josephson junctions based on the proximity
effect offer the bright opportunity to tailor non trivial quantum states in
nanoscale weak-links. These structures can realize exotic topologies in
multidimensions as, for example, artificial topological superconductors able to
support Majorana bound states, and pave the way to emerging quantum
technologies and future quantum information schemes. Here, we report the first
realization of a three-terminal Josephson interferometer based on a proximized
nanosized weak-link. Our tunneling spectroscopy measurements reveal transitions
between gapped (i.e., insulating) and gapless (i.e., conducting) states, those
being controlled by the phase configuration of the three superconducting leads
connected to the junction. We demonstrate the $topological$ nature of these
transitions: a gapless state necessarily occurs between two gapped states of
different topological index, very much like the interface between two
insulators of different topology is necessarily conducting. The topological
numbers characterizing such gapped states are given by superconducting phase
windings over the two loops forming the Josephson interferometer. Since these
gapped states cannot be transformed to one another continuously withouth
passing through a gapless condition, these are topologically $protected$. Our
observation of the gapless state is pivotal for enabling phase engineering of
more sophisticated artificial topological materials realizing Weyl points or
the anomalous Josephson effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01596</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhentao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wen-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevidomskyy</keyname><forenames>Andriy H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Ferroquadrupolar Order in the Nematic Phase of FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures, Erratum added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 247203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.247203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide evidence that spin ferroquadrupolar (FQ) order is the likely
ground state in the nonmagnetic nematic phase of stoichiometric FeSe. By
studying the variational mean-field phase diagram of a bilinear-biquadratic
Heisenberg model up to the 2nd nearest neighbor, we find the FQ phase in close
proximity to the columnar antiferromagnet commonly realized in iron-based
superconductors; the stability of FQ phase is further verified by the density
matrix renormalization group. The dynamical spin structure factor in the FQ
state is calculated with flavor-wave theory, which yields a qualitatively
consistent result with inelastic neutron scattering experiments on FeSe at both
low and high energies. We verify that FQ can coexist with $C_4$ breaking
environments in the mean-field calculation, and further discuss the possibility
that quantum fluctuations in FQ act as a source of nematicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02495</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kammermeier</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wenk</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schliemann</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heedt</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;pers</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak (anti)localization in tubular semiconductor nanowires with
  spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 205306 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.205306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute analytically the weak (anti)localization correction to the Drude
conductivity for electrons in tubular semiconductor systems of zinc blende
type. We include linear Rashba and Dresselhaus spin-orbit coupling (SOC) and
compare wires of standard growth directions $\langle100\rangle$,
$\langle111\rangle$, and $\langle110\rangle$. The motion on the
quasi-two-dimensional surface is considered diffusive in both directions:
transversal as well as along the cylinder axis. It is shown that Dresselhaus
and Rashba SOC similarly affect the spin relaxation rates. For the
$\langle110\rangle$ growth direction, the long-lived spin states are of helical
nature. We detect a crossover from weak localization to weak anti-localization
depending on spin-orbit coupling strength as well as dephasing and scattering
rate. The theory is fitted to experimental data of an undoped
$\langle111\rangle$ InAs nanowire device which exhibits a top-gate-controlled
crossover from positive to negative magnetoconductivity. Thereby, we extract
transport parameters where we quantify the distinct types of SOC individually.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08021</id><created>2016-03-25</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Lauren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peloso</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorbo</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>The phenomenology of trapped inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>48 pages, 5 figures. Published version</comments><report-no>ACFI-T16-07, UMN--TH--3520/16</report-no><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/11/058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Trapped inflation is a mechanism in which particle production from the moving
inflaton is the main source of friction in the inflaton equation of motion. The
produced fields source inflaton perturbations, which dominate over the vacuum
ones. We employ the set of equations for the inflaton zero mode and its
perturbations which was developed in the original work on trapped inflation,
and which we extend to second order in the perturbations. We build on this
study by updating the experimental constraints, and by replacing the existing
approximate solutions with more accurate ones. We obtain a different numerical
value for the amplitude of the scalar power spectrum, and a parametrically
different result for the bispectrum. This has implications for the allowed
region of parameter space in models of trapped inflation, and for some of the
phenomenological results obtained in this region. The main results in the
allowed region are the following: monomial inflaton potentials, such as $V
\propto \varphi ,\, \varphi^2$ can be compatible with the data, and (in a
portion of the allowed region) the inflaton can be sub-Planckian over all the
&quot;observable&quot; stage of inflation; gravitational waves from this mechanism are
too small to be observed in the foreseeable future; a non-gaussianity parameter
$-60 &lt; f_{\rm NL} &lt; -20 $ is obtained in the allowed region for exactly
equilateral configurations, with a mild dependence on the parameters of the
model and of the inflaton potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06435</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Antoniadou</keyname><forenames>Kyriaki I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voyatzis</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-term orbital stability of exosolar planetary systems with highly
  eccentric orbits</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the International Astronomical Union 11(A29A)
  (2015) 38-39</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1743921316002362</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nowadays, many extrasolar planetary systems possessing at least one planet on
a highly eccentric orbit have been discovered. In this work, we study the
possible long-term stability of such systems. We consider the general three
body problem as our model. Highly eccentric orbits are out of the Hill
stability regions. However, mean motion resonances can provide phase protection
and orbits with long-term stability exist. We construct maps of dynamical
stability based on the computation of chaotic indicators and we figure out
regions in phase space, where the long-term stability is guaranteed. We focus
on regions where at least one planet is highly eccentric and attempt to
associate them with the existence of stable periodic orbits. The values of the
orbital elements, which are derived from observational data, are often given
with very large deviations. Generally, phase space regions of high
eccentricities are narrow and thus, our dynamical analysis may restrict
considerably the valid domain of the system's location.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08199</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Engle</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanusch</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinematical uniqueness of homogeneous isotropic LQC</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>7 pages, contribution to CQG focus issues on applications of loop
  quantum gravity to cosmology; Citations made consistent, minor typos
  corrected</comments><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav.34: 014001, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/34/1/014001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a paper by Ashtekar and Campiglia, invariance under volume preserving
residual diffeomorphisms has been used to single out the standard
representation of the reduced holonomy-flux algebra in homogeneous loop quantum
cosmology (LQC). In this paper, we use invariance under all residual
diffeomorphisms to single out the standard kinematical Hilbert space of
homogeneous isotropic LQC for both the standard configuration space
$\mathbb{R}_{\mathrm{Bohr}}$, as well as for the Fleischhack one $\mathbb{R}
\sqcup \mathbb{R}_{\mathrm{Bohr}}$. We first determine the scale invariant
Radon measures on these spaces, and then show that the Haar measure on
$\mathbb{R}_{\mathrm{Bohr}}$ is the only such measure for which the momentum
operator is hermitian w.r.t. the corresponding inner product. In particular,
the measure is forced to be identically zero on $\mathbb{R}$ in the Fleischhack
case, so that for both approaches, the standard kinematical LQC-Hilbert space
is singled out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03566</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deka</keyname><forenames>Jyoti Prasad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Amarendra K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbative Dynamics of Stationary States in Nonlinear Parity-Time
  Symmetric Coupler</title><categories>nlin.CD physics.class-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nonlinear parity-time (PT) symmetric coupler from a
dynamical perspective. As opposed to linear PT-coupler where the PT threshold
dictates the evolutionary characteristics of optical power in the two
waveguides, in a nonlinear coupler, the PT threshold governs the existence of
stationary points. We have found that the stability of the ground state
undergoes a phase transition when the gain/loss coefficient is increased from
zero to beyond the PT threshold. Moreover, we found that instabilities in
initial conditions can lead to aperiodic oscillations as well as exponential
growth and decay of optical power. At the PT threshold, we observed the
existence of a stable attractor under the influence of fluctuating gain/loss
coefficient. Phase plane analysis has shown us the presence of a toroidal
chaotic attractor. The chaotic dynamics can be controlled by a judicious choice
of the waveguide parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08469</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2016-08-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Dongliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Xiaokun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jajja</keyname><forenames>Saad Ayub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ronggui</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement Techniques for Thermal Conductivity and Interfacial Thermal
  Conductance of Bulk and Thin Film Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>48 pages, 20 figures. Accepted by ASME Journal of Electronic
  Packaging</comments><journal-ref>J. Electron. Packag 138, 040802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1115/1.4034605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal conductivity and interfacial thermal conductance play crucial roles
in the design of engineering systems where temperature and thermal stress are
of concerns. To date, a variety of measurement techniques are available for
both bulk and thin film solid-state materials with a broad temperature range.
For thermal characterization of bulk material, the steady-state absolute
method, laser flash diffusivity method, and transient plane source method are
most used. For thin film measurement, the 3{\omega} method and transient
thermoreflectance technique including both frequency-domain and time-domain
analysis are employed widely. This work reviews several most commonly used
measurement techniques. In general, it is a very challenging task to determine
thermal conductivity and interface contact resistance with less than 5% error.
Selecting a specific measurement technique to characterize thermal properties
need to be based on: 1) knowledge on the sample whose thermophysical properties
is to be determined, including the sample geometry and size, and preparation
method; 2) understanding of fundamentals and procedures of the testing
technique and equipment, for example, some techniques are limited to samples
with specific geometrics and some are limited to specific range of
thermophysical properties; 3) understanding of the potential error sources
which might affect the final results, for example, the convection and radiation
heat losses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01126</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2016-11-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>No&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urban</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Superfluid hydrodynamics in the inner crust of neutron stars</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures, figures and discussions added. Accepted in
  Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 065801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.065801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inner crust of neutron stars is supposed to be inhomogeneous and composed
of dense structures (clusters) that are immersed in a dilute gas of unbound
neutrons. Here we consider spherical clusters forming a BCC crystal and
cylindrical rods arranged in a hexagonal lattice. We study the relative motion
of these dense structures and the neutron gas using superfluid hydrodynamics.
Within this approach, which relies on the assumption that Cooper pairs are
small compared to the crystalline structures, we find that the entrainment of
neutrons by the clusters is very weak since neutrons of the gas can flow
through the clusters. Consequently, we obtain a low effective mass of the
clusters and a superfluid density that is even higher than the density of
unbound neutrons. Consequences for the constraints from glitch observations are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03085</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cianfrani</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalski-Glikman</keyname><forenames>Jerzy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pranzetti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosati</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries of quantum space-time in 3 dimensions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>In V2 some clarifying comments and references have been added
  according to the refereed version for Phys.Rev.D; in V3 we corrected the
  format of one figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 084044 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.084044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By applying loop quantum gravity techniques to 3D gravity with a positive
cosmological constant $\Lambda$, we show how the local gauge symmetry of the
theory, encoded in the constraint algebra, acquires the quantum group structure
of $so_q(4)$, with $ q = \exp{(i\hbar \sqrt{\Lambda}/2\kappa)}$. By means of an
Inonu-Wigner contraction of the quantum group bi-algebra, keeping $\kappa$
finite, we obtain the kappa-Poincar\'e algebra of the flat quantum space-time
symmetries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00388</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Chandran</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burnell</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The eigenstate thermalization hypothesis in constrained Hilbert spaces:
  a case study in non-Abelian anyon chains</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 235122 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many phases of matter, including superconductors, fractional quantum Hall
fluids and spin liquids, are described by gauge theories with constrained
Hilbert spaces. However, thermalization and the applicability of quantum
statistical mechanics has primarily been studied in unconstrained Hilbert
spaces. In this article, we investigate whether constrained Hilbert spaces
permit local thermalization. Specifically, we explore whether the eigenstate
thermalization hypothesis (ETH) holds in a pinned Fibonacci anyon chain, which
serves as a representative case study. We first establish that the constrained
Hilbert space admits a notion of locality, by showing that the influence of a
measurement decays exponentially in space. This suggests that the constraints
are no impediment to thermalization. We then provide numerical evidence that
ETH holds for the diagonal and off-diagonal matrix elements of various local
observables in a generic disorder-free non-integrable model. We also find that
certain non-local observables obey ETH.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01178</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Avirup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized geodesic deviation equations and an entanglement first law
  for rotating BTZ black holes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 4 figures, portion containing first law completely revised</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 126005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.126005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The change in Holographic entanglement entropy (HEE) for small fluctuations
about pure AdS is given by a perturbative expansion of the area functional in
terms of the change in the bulk metric and the embedded extremal surface.
However it is known that change in the embedding appear at second order or
higher. In this paper we show that these changes in the embedding can be
systematically calculated in the 2+1 dimensional case by accounting for the
deviation of the spacelike geodesics between a spacetime and perturbations over
it. Here we consider rotating BTZ as perturbation over $AdS_3$ and study
deviations of spacelike geodesics in them. We argue that these deviations arise
naturally as solutions of a &quot;generalized geodesic deviation equation&quot;. Using
this we perturbatively calculate the changes in HEE upto second order, for
rotating BTZ. This expression matches with the small system size expansion of
the change in HEE obtained by HRT (Hubeny, Rangamani and Takayanagi) proposal
for rotating BTZ. We also write an alternative form of entanglement first law
for rotating BTZ. To do this one needs to go beyond the leading order in the
perturbation series discussed above. That's precisely the reason we consider
finding a systematic way to calculate it. To put our result on a firm footing
we further show that it is this alternative first law that approaches the
thermal first law in the large subsystem size limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02532</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mehl</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hicks</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toher</keyname><forenames>Cormac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levy</keyname><forenames>Ohad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>Robert M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hart</keyname><forenames>Gus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curtarolo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>The AFLOW Library of Crystallographic Prototypes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>831 pages, 585 figures, 16 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An easily available resource of common crystal structures is essential for
researchers, teachers, and students. For many years this was provided by the
U.S. Naval Research Laboratory's $Crystal\ Lattice\ Structures$ web page, which
contained nearly 300 crystal structures, including a majority of those which
were given $Strukturbericht$ designations. This article presents the updated
version of the database, now including 288 standardized structures in 92 space
groups. Similar to what was available on the web page before, we present a
complete description of each structure, including the formulas for the
primitive vectors, all of the basis vectors, and the AFLOW commands to generate
the standardied cells. We also present a brief discussion of crystal systems,
space groups, primitive and conventional lattices, Wyckoff positions, Pearson
symbols and $Strukturbericht$ designations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03421</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Teaca</keyname><forenames>Bogdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navarro</keyname><forenames>Alejandro Ba&#xf1;&#xf3;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Told</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenko</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic intermittency in magnetized plasma turbulence</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph physics.space-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We employ magnetized plasma turbulence, described by a gyrokinetic formalism
in an interval ranging from the end of the fluid scales to the electron
gyroradius, to introduce the first study of kinetic intermittency, in which
nonlinear structures formed directly in the distribution functions are analyzed
by accounting for velocity space correlations generated by linear (Landau
resonance) and nonlinear phase mixing. Electron structures are found to be
strongly intermittent and dominated by linear phase mixing, while nonlinear
phase mixing dominates the weakly intermittent ions. This is the first time
spatial intermittency and linear phase mixing are shown to be self-consistently
linked for the electrons and, as the magnetic field follows the intermittency
of the electrons at small scales, explain why magnetic islands are places
dominated by Landau damping in steady state turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06715</id><created>2016-07-22</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Suomela</keyname><forenames>Samu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampaio</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ala-Nissila</keyname><forenames>Tapio</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison between quantum jumps and master equation in the presence of
  a finite environment</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, three appendices</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032138 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the equivalence between the recently proposed finite environment
quantum jump model and a master equation approach. We derive microscopically
the master equation for a qubit coupled to a finite bosonic environment and
show that the master equation is equivalent with the finite environment quantum
jump model. We analytically show that both the methods produce the same moments
of work when the work is defined through the two-measurement protocol excluding
the interaction energy. However, when compared to the work moments computed
using the power operator approach, we find a difference in the form of the work
moments. To numerically verify our results, we study a qubit coupled to an
environment consisting of ten two-level systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07877</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Carisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erickcek</keyname><forenames>Adrienne L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quartic Chameleons: Safely Scale-Free in the Early Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures. Updated to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 104049 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.104049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In chameleon gravity, there exists a light scalar field that couples to the
trace of the stress-energy tensor in such a way that its mass depends on the
ambient matter density, and the field is screened in local, high-density
environments. Recently it was shown that, for the runaway potentials commonly
considered in chameleon theories, the field's coupling to matter and the
hierarchy of scales between Standard Model particles and the energy scale of
such potentials result in catastrophic effects in the early Universe when these
particles become nonrelativistic. Perturbations with trans-Planckian energies
are excited, and the theory suffers a breakdown in calculability at the
relatively low temperatures of Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. We consider a
chameleon field in a quartic potential and show that the scale-free nature of
this potential allows the chameleon to avoid many of the problems encountered
by runaway potentials. Following inflation, the chameleon field oscillates
around the minimum of its effective potential, and rapid changes in its
effective mass excite perturbations via quantum particle production. The
quartic model, however, only generates high-energy perturbations at comparably
high temperatures and is able remain a well-behaved effective field theory at
nucleosynthesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08397</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kotlorz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotlorz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of DIS structure functions of the nucleon within truncated
  Mellin moments approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 31, 1650181 (2016) [13 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501815</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present generalized evolution equations and factorization in terms of the
truncated Mellin moments (TMM) of the parton distributions and structure
functions. We illustrate the $x$ and $Q^2$ dependence of TMM in the polarized
case. Using the TMM approach we compare the integrals of $g_1$ with HERMES and
COMPASS data from the limited $x$-ranges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03953</id><created>2016-08-13</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Luminosity determination in pp collisions at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV using
  the ATLAS detector at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>53 pages plus author list + cover page (72 pages total), 19 figures,
  9 tables, submitted to EPJC, All figures including auxiliary figures are
  available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/DAPR-2013-01</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2016-117</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 653</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4466-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The luminosity determination for the ATLAS detector at the LHC during pp
collisions at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV in 2012 is presented. The evaluation of the
luminosity scale is performed using several luminometers, and comparisons
between these luminosity detectors are made to assess the accuracy, consistency
and long-term stability of the results. A luminosity uncertainty of dL/L = +/-
1.9% is obtained for the 22.7 fb$^{-1}$ of pp collision data delivered to ATLAS
at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV in 2012.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05475</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2016-11-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Sachiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takizawa</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author></authors><title>The hidden charm pentaquarks are the hidden color-octet $uud$ baryons?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages 4 figures, to be published in Physics Letters B</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-249, J-PARC-TH-0063</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B Volume 764, 10 January 2017, Pages 254-259</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $I(J^P)={1\over 2}({1\over 2}^-)$, ${1\over 2}({3\over 2}^-)$, and
${1\over 2}({5\over 2}^-)$ $uudc\overline{c}$ pentaquarks are investigated by
the quark cluster model. This model, which reproduces the mass spectra of the
color-singlet $S$-wave $q^3$ baryons and $q\overline{q}$ mesons, also enables
us to evaluate the quark interaction in the color-octet $uud$ configurations.
It is shown that the color-octet isospin-${1\over 2}$ spin-${3\over 2}$ $uud$
configuration gains attraction. The $uudc\overline{c}$ states with this
configuration have structures around the $\Sigma_c{}^{(*)}\overline{D}{}^{(*)}$
thresholds: one bound state, two resonances, and one large cusp are found. We
argue that the negative parity pentaquark found by the LHCb experiments may be
given by these structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00825</id><created>2016-09-03</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Whalley</keyname><forenames>Lucy D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skelton</keyname><forenames>Jonathan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Jarvist M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon anharmonicity, lifetimes and thermal transport in
  CH$_3$NH$_3$PbI$_3$ from many-body perturbation theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 220301(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.220301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lattice vibrations in CH$_3$NH$_3$PbI$_3$ are strongly interacting, with
double well instabilities present at the Brillouin zone boundary. Analysis
within a first-principles lattice dynamics framework reveals anharmonic
potentials with short phonon quasi-particle lifetimes and mean-free paths. The
phonon behaviour is distinct from the inorganic semiconductors GaAs and CdTe
where three-phonon interaction strengths are three orders of magnitude smaller.
The implications for the applications of hybrid halide perovskites arising from
thermal conductivity, band-gap deformation, and charge-carrier scattering
through electron-phonon coupling, are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01694</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Raby</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion star collisions with Neutron stars and Fast Radio Bursts</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, published version without figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 103004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.103004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Axions may make a significant contribution to the dark matter of the
universe. It has been suggested that these dark matter axions may condense into
localized clumps, called &quot;axion stars.&quot; In this paper we argue that collisions
of dilute axion stars with neutron stars, of the type known as &quot;magnetars,&quot; may
be the origin of most of the observed fast radio bursts. This idea is a
variation of an idea originally proposed by Iwazaki. However, instead of the
surface effect of Iwazaki, we propose a perhaps stronger volume effect caused
by the induced time dependent electric dipole moment of neutrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07313</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zouabi</keyname><forenames>C</forenames><affiliation>LTDS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Scheibert</keyname><forenames>J</forenames><affiliation>LTDS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Perret-Liaudet</keyname><forenames>J</forenames><affiliation>LTDS</affiliation></author></authors><title>Memory in random bouncing ball dynamics</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>Final published version, 5 pages, 4 figures</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>EPL, European Physical Society/EDP Sciences/Societ{\`a} Italiana
  di Fisica/IOP Publishing, 2016, 115, pp.50006</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/50006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The bouncing of an inelastic ball on a vibrating plate is a popular model
used in various fields, from granular gases to nanometer-sized mechanical
contacts. For random plate motion, so far, the model has been studied using
Poincar{\'e} maps in which the excitation by the plate at successive bounces is
assumed to be a discrete Markovian (memoryless) process. Here, we investigate
numerically the behaviour of the model for continuous random excitations with
tunable correlation time. We show that the system dynamics are controlled by
the ratio of the Markovian mean flight time of the ball and the mean time
between successive peaks in the motion of the exciting plate. When this ratio,
which depends on the bandwidth of the excitation signal, exceeds a certain
value, the Markovian approach is appropriate; below, memory of preceding
excitations arises, leading to a significant decrease of the jump duration; at
the smallest values of the ratio, chattering occurs. Overall, our results open
the way for uses of the model in the low excitation regime, which is still
poorly understood.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07856</id><created>2016-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hongyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Shumin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Minggang</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Siyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Qifan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Yuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Hanqiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation of Non-uniform Double Helices for Elastic Rods under Torsion</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>31 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.12.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spontaneous formation of double helices for filaments under torsion is
common and significant. For example, the research on the supercoiling of DNA is
helpful for understanding the replication and transcription of DNA. Similar
double helices can appear in polymer chains, carbon nanotube yarns, cables,
telephone wires and so forth. We noticed that non-uniform double helices can be
produced due to the surface friction induced by the self-contact. Therefore an
ideal model was presented to investigate the formation of double helices for
elastic rods under torque. A general equilibrium condition which is valid for
both the smooth surface and the rough surface situations is derived by using
the variational method. Based on this, by adding further constraints, the
smooth and rough surface situations are investigated in detail respectively.
Additionally, the model showed that the specific process of how to twist and
slack the rod can determine the surface friction and hence influence the
configuration of the double helix formed by rods with rough surfaces. Based on
this principle, a method of manufacturing double helices with designed
configurations was proposed and demonstrated. Finally, experiments were
performed to verify the model and the results agreed well with the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08027</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2016-11-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotera</keyname><forenames>Kumiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>M. Coleman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oikonomou</keyname><forenames>Foteini</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying Ultrahigh-Energy Cosmic-Ray Accelerators with Future
  Ultrahigh-Energy Neutrino Detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures, minor revision, accepted for publication in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 12 (2016) 017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/12/017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The detection of ultrahigh-energy (UHE) neutrino sources would contribute
significantly to solving the decades-old mystery of the origin of the
highest-energy cosmic rays. We investigate the ability of a future UHE neutrino
detector to identify the brightest neutrino point sources, by exploring the
parameter space of the total number of observed events and the angular
resolution of the detector. The favored parameter region can be translated to
requirements for the effective area, sky coverage and angular resolution of
future detectors, for a given source number density and evolution history.
Moreover, by studying the typical distance to sources that are expected to emit
more than one event for a given diffuse neutrino flux, we find that a
significant fraction of the identifiable UHE neutrino sources may be located in
the nearby Universe if the source number density is above $\sim10^{-6}\,\rm
Mpc^{-3}$. If sources are powerful and rare enough, as predicted in blazar
scenarios, they can first be detected at distant locations. Our result also
suggests that if UHE cosmic-ray accelerators are neither beamed nor transients,
it will be possible to associate the detected UHE neutrino sources with nearby
UHE cosmic-ray and gamma-ray sources, and that they may also be observed using
other messengers, including ones with limited horizons such as TeV gamma rays,
UHE gamma rays and cosmic rays. We find that for a $\gtrsim5\sigma$ detection
of UHE neutrino sources with a uniform density,
$n_s\sim{10}^{-7}-{10}^{-5}~{\rm Mpc}^{-3}$, at least $\sim100-1000$ events and
sub-degree angular resolution are needed, and the results depend on the source
evolution model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08288</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Harukuni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyazaki</keyname><forenames>Kunimasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author></authors><title>Note: A replica liquid theory of binary mixtures</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>2 pages no figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 216101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4969072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been known that the binary replica liquid theory (RLT) is inconsistent
with its one-component counterpart; In the limit that all atoms are identical,
the configurational entropy and thus the glass transition point calculated by
the binary RLT differ from those obtained by the one-component RLT. More
specifically, an extra composition-dependent term, or the mixing entropy,
remains finite in the configurational entropy computed by the binary RLT. In
this Short Note, we reformulate the RLT in order to resolve this problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01652</id><created>2016-10-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Dil</keyname><forenames>Emre</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling q-deformed dark energy to dark matter</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This article has been accepted by the journal &quot;Advances in High
  Energy Physics&quot;. The DOI is not given, yet. It is in press in the journal
  link, https://www.hindawi.com/journals/ahep/aip/9753208/. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1607.03928</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, vol. 2016, Article ID 9753208, 20
  pages, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/9753208</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel coupled dark energy model which is assumed to occur as a
q-deformed scalar field and investigate whether it will provide an expanding
universe phase. We consider the q-deformed dark energy as coupled to dark
matter inhomogeneities. We perform the phase-space analysis of the model by
numerical methods and find the late-time accelerated attractor solutions. The
attractor solutions imply that the coupled q-deformed dark energy model is
consistent with the conventional dark energy models satisfying an acceleration
phase of universe. At the end, we compare the cosmological parameters of
deformed and standard dark energy models and interpret the implications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01739</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Chuyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yewei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tey</keyname><forenames>Meng Khoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of broad p-wave Feshbach resonances in ultracold
  $^{85}$Rb-$^{87}$Rb mixtures</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 062702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.062702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We observe new Feshbach resonances in ultracold mixtures of $^{85}$Rb and
$^{87}$Rb atoms in the $^{85}$Rb$|2, +2\rangle$+$^{87}$Rb$|1, +1\rangle$ and
$^{85}$Rb$|2, -2\rangle$+$^{87}$Rb$|1, -1\rangle$ scattering channels. The
positions and properties of the resonances are predicted and characterized
using the semi-analytic multichannel quantum-defect theory by Gao. Of
particular interest, a number of broad entrance-channel dominated p-wave
resonances are identified, implicating exciting opportunities for studying a
variety of p-wave interaction dominated physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05388</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Edson</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varizi</keyname><forenames>Adalberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampaio</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum estimation in neutrino oscillations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>v2 contains additional text that clarify arguments in the previous
  version, results unchanged. Shorter abstract, added references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutrino oscillations are at the forefront of advances in Physics beyond the
Standard Model. Increasing accuracy in measurements of the neutrino mixing
matrix is an important challenge in current experiments. It depends on
parameters that do not directly correspond to observables of the neutrino
system. This type of estimation problem is handled by Quantum Estimation Theory
(QET) via the Fisher Information (FI) and the Quantum Fisher Information (QFI).
In this work, we analyze two-flavor neutrino oscillations within the framework
of QET. We compute the QFI for the mixing angle $\theta$ and show that mass
measurements are the ones that achieve optimal precision. We also study the FI
associated with flavor measurements and show that they are optimized at
specific neutrino times-of-flight. Therefore, although the usual population
measurement does not realize the precision limit set by the QFI, it can in
principle be implemented with the best possible sensitivity to $\theta $. We
study how these quantifiers relate to the single-particle, mode entanglement.
We demonstrate that this form of entanglement does not enhance neither of them.
In particular, this shows that in single-particle settings, entanglement is not
directly connected with the optimal precision in metrological tasks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06626</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2016-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kouvaris</keyname><forenames>Nikos E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Requejo</keyname><forenames>Ruben J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hizanidis</keyname><forenames>Johanne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Guilera</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author></authors><title>Chimera states in a network-organized public goods game with destructive
  agents</title><categories>nlin.AO math.DS nlin.CD nlin.PS</categories><journal-ref>Chaos 26, 123108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4971974</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We found that a network-organized metapopulation of cooperators, defectors
and destructive agents playing the public goods game with mutations, can
collectively reach global synchronization or chimera states. Global
synchronization is accompanied by a collective periodic burst of cooperation,
whereas chimera states reflect the tendency of the networked metapopulation to
be fragmented in clusters of synchronous and incoherent bursts of cooperation.
Numerical simulations have shown that the system's dynamics alternates between
these two steady states through a first order transition. Depending on the
parameters determining the dynamical and topological properties, chimera states
with different numbers of coherent and incoherent clusters are observed. Our
results present the first systematic study of chimera states and their
characterization in the context of evolutionary game theory. This provides a
valuable insight into the details of their occurrence, extending the relevance
of such states to natural and social systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07870</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Dil</keyname><forenames>Emre</forenames></author></authors><title>Spinor quintom cosmology with intrinsic spin</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, vol. 2016, Article ID 3740957, 10
  pages, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/3740957</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a spinor quintom dark energy model with intrinsic spin, in the
framework of Eintein- Cartan-Sciama-Kibble theory. After constructing the
mathematical formalism of the model, we obtain the spin contributed total
energy-momentum tensor giving the energy density and the pressure of the
quintom model, and then we find the equation of state parameter in terms of the
spinor potential. Choosing suitable potentials leads to the quintom scenario
crossing between quintessence and phantom epochs, or vice versa. Analyzed three
quintom scenarios provides stable expansion phases avoiding Big Rip
singularities, and yielding matter dominated era through the stabilization of
the spinor pressure via spin contribution. The stabilization in spinor pressure
leads to neglecting it as compared to the increasing energy density, and
constituting a matter dominated stable expansion epoch.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08368</id><created>2016-10-26</created><updated>2016-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Staicova</keyname><forenames>Denitsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoilov</keyname><forenames>Michail</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological aspects of a unified dark energy and dust dark matter model</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures. Typos corrected. New comments added</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 32, No. 1 (2017) 1750006</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317500067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, a model of modified gravity plus single scalar field model was
proposed, in which the scalar couples both to the standard Riemannian volume
form given by the square root of the determinant of the Riemannian metric, as
well as to another non-Riemannian volume form given in terms of an auxiliary
maximal rank antisymmetric tensor gauge field. This model provides an exact
unified description of both dark energy (via dynamically generated cosmological
constant) and dark matter (as a &quot;dust&quot; fluid due to a hidden nonlinear Noether
symmetry).
  In this paper we test the model against Supernovae type Ia experimental data
and investigate the future Universe evolution which follows from it. Our
results show that this model has very interesting features allowing various
scenarios of Universe evolution and in the same time perfectly fits
contemporary observational data. It can describe exponentially expanding or
finite expanding Universe and moreover, a Universe with phase transition of
first kind. The phase transition occurs to a new, emerging at some time ground
state with lower energy density, which affects significantly the Universe
evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08744</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buoninfante</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ghost and singularity free theories of gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Master's thesis. Review. 139 pages. Supervisors: G. Lambiase and A.
  Mazumdar. References added, changes to text</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Albert Einstein's General Relativity (GR) from 1916 has become the widely
accepted theory of gravity and been tested observationally to a very high
precision at different scales of energy and distance. At the same time, there
still remain important questions to resolve. At the classical level
cosmological and black hole singularities are examples of problems which let us
notice that GR is incomplete at short distances (high energy). Furthermore, at
the quantum level GR is not ultraviolet (UV) complete, namely it is not
perturbatively renormalizable. Most of the work try to solve these problems
modifying GR by considering finite higher order derivative terms. Fourth
Derivative Gravity, for example, turns out to be renormalizable, but at the
same time it introduces ghost. To avoid both UV divergence and presence of
ghost one could consider sets of infinite higher derivative terms that can be
expressed in the form of entire functions satisfying the special property do
not introduce new poles other than GR graviton one. By making a special choice
for these entire functions, one could show that such a theory describes a
gravity that, at least in the linear regime, can avoid both the presence of
ghost and classical singularities (both black hole and cosmological
singularities). In this master's thesis we review some of these aspects
regarding gravitational interaction, focusing more on the classical level. Most
of the calculations are done in detail and an extended treatment of the
formalism of the spin projector operators is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00109</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Dian-Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Where are $\chi_{cJ}(3P)$?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 2 table, published by Eur.Phys.J. C</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76, 671 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4531-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, we propose $Y(4140)$ as the $\chi_{c1}(3P)$ state by
studying the $\chi_{c1} \pi^+ \pi^-$ invariant mass spectrum of the $B\to K
\chi_{c1} \pi^+ \pi^-$ process. In the $D\bar{D}$ invariant mass spectrum of
the $B\to K D\bar{D}$ process, we find a new resonance with the mass and width
to be $ (4083.0 \pm 5.0) $ and $ (24.1 \pm 15.4) $ MeV, respectively, which
could be a good candidate of the $\chi_{c0}(3P)$ state. The theoretical
investigations on the decay behaviors of the $\chi_{cJ}(3P)$ in the present
work support the assignments of the $Y(4140)$ and $Y(4080)$ as the
$\chi_{c1}(3P)$ and $\chi_{c0}(3P)$ states, respectively. In addition, the
$\chi_{c2}(3P)$ state is predicted to be a very narrow state. The results in
the present work could be tested by further experiments in the LHCb and
forthcoming Belle II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00523</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00523</id><created>2016-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsumura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michimura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inami</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fushiya</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higashinaka</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugawara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic displacements and lattice distortion in the
  magnetic-field-induced charge ordered state of SmRu$_{4}$P$_{12}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 184425 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.184425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Structural properties of SmRu$_4$P$_{12}$ in the anomalous magnetic ordered
phase between $T^*\sim 14 $ K and $T_{\text{N}}=16.5$ K in magnetic fields has
been studied by x-ray diffraction. Atomic displacements of Ru and P, reflecting
the field-induced charge order of the $p$ electrons, have been deduced by
analyzing the intensities of the forbidden Bragg peaks, assuming a cubic space
group $Pm\bar{3}$. Also, by utilizing high-resolution x-ray diffraction
experiment, we observed a splitting of fundamental Bragg peaks, clarifying that
the unit cell in the magnetic ordered phase is rhombohedral elongated along the
$[1\, 1\, 1]$ axis. Responses of the rhombohedral domains to the magnetic
field, which reflects the direction of the magnetic moment, is studied in
detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05745</id><created>2016-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kartashov</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konotop</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zezyulin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torner</keyname><forenames>Lluis</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic localization in optical and Zeeman lattices in the presence of
  spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures; accepted for Physical Review A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063606 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063606</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamic localization of a two-level atom in a periodic potential under
the action of spin-orbit coupling and a weak harmonically-varying linear force
is studied. We consider optical and Zeeman potentials that are either in-phase
or out-of-phase in two spinor components, respectively. The expectation value
for the position of the atom after one oscillation period of the linear force
is recovered in authentic resonances or in pseudo-resonances. The frequencies
of the linear force corresponding to authentic resonances are determined by the
band structure of the periodic potential and are affected by the spin-orbit
coupling. The width/dispersion of the wavepacket in authentic resonances is
usually minimal. The frequencies corresponding to pseudo-resonances do not
depend on the type of potential and on the strength of the spin-orbit coupling,
while the evolution of excitations at the corresponding frequencies is usually
accompanied by significant dispersion. Pseudo-resonances are determined by the
initial phase of the linear force and by the quasi-momentum of the wavepacket.
Due to the spinor nature of the system, the motion of the atom is accompanied
by periodic, but not harmonic, spin oscillations. Under the action of
spin-orbit coupling the oscillations of the wavepacket can be nearly completely
suppressed in optical lattices. Dynamic localization in Zeeman lattices is
characterized by doubling of the resonant oscillation periods due to band
crossing at the boundary of the Brillouin zone. We also show that higher
harmonics in the Fourier expansion of the energy band lead to effective
dispersion, which can be strong enough to prevent dynamic localization of the
Bloch wavepacket.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05778</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bessi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards the Modeling of Behavioral Trajectories of Users in Online
  Social Media</title><categories>cs.CY cs.SI physics.soc-ph stat.AP stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce a methodology that allows to model behavioral
trajectories of users in online social media. First, we illustrate how to
leverage the probabilistic framework provided by Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) to
represent users by embedding the temporal sequences of actions they performed
online. We then derive a model-based distance between trained HMMs, and we use
spectral clustering to find homogeneous clusters of users showing similar
behavioral trajectories. To provide platform-agnostic results, we apply the
proposed approach to two different online social media --- i.e. Facebook and
YouTube. We conclude discussing merits and limitations of our approach as well
as future and promising research directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00115</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ham</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective atom phase controls in photon echoes for quantum memory
  applications I: Population inversion removal</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages including 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photon echo-based quantum memories demonstrated in rare-earth doped solids
over the last decade have solved the major constraint of population inversion
in conventional photon echoes by using collective atom phase controls. Both
atomic frequency comb and gradient echoes have also made a breakthrough in
higher echo efficiency, where conventional photon echo efficiency remains at a
few per cent. Here we review, analyze, and discuss the collective atom phase
control applied to conventional photon echoes for quantum memory applications
to clarify fundamental physics of coherent transients in a three-level system
specifically for optical-spin coherence conversion in a controlled double
rephasing echoes. Some critical misunderstandings in various protocols are also
analyzed, and corrected for near unity echo efficiency under no population
inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00956</id><created>2016-12-03</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osano</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames></author></authors><title>Euler potentials and Magnetic fields</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is known that the cross product of gradients of two scalars, the Euler
potentials (EP), may represent magnetic fields lines. We examine the utility of
such potential in the broader magneto-genesis and dynamo theories, and find
that a reinterpretation of the potentials offer a new understanding of the role
EP may play in the evolution of magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01275</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author></authors><title>Transfer matrix algorithm for computing the exact partition function of
  a square lattice polymer</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I develop a transfer matrix algorithm for computing the exact partition
function of a square lattice polymer with nearest-neighbor interaction, by
extending a previous algorithm for computing the total number of self-avoiding
walks. The computation time scales as ~1.6^N with the chain length N, in
contrast to the explicit enumeration where the scaling is ~ 2.7^N. The exact
partition function can be obtained faster with the transfer matrix method than
with the explicit enumeration, for N&gt;25. The new results for up to N=42 are
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02446</id><created>2016-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Asvestari</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willamo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gil</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usoskin</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovaltsov</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhailov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayorov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of Ground Level Enhancements (GLE): Extreme solar energetic
  particle events have hard spectra</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Advances in Space Research (in press)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.asr.2016.08.043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nearly 70 Ground Level Enhancements (GLEs) of cosmic rays have been recorded
by the worldwide neutron monitor network since the 1950s depicting a big
variety of energy spectra of solar energetic particles (SEP). Here we studied a
statistical relation between the event-integrated intensity of GLEs (calculated
as count-rate relative excess, averaged over all available polar neutron
monitors, and expressed in percent-hours) and the hardness of the solar
particle energy spectra. For each event the integral omnidirectional
event-integrated fluences of particles with energy above 30 MeV ($F_{30}$) and
above 200 MeV ($F_{200}$) were computed using the reconstructed spectra, and
the ratio between the two fluences was considered as a simple index of the
event's hardness. We also provided a justification of the spectrum estimate in
the form of the Band-function, using direct PAMELA data for GLE 71
(17-May-2012). We found that, while there is no clear relation between the
intensity and the hardness for weak events, all strong events with the
intensity greater 100 \%*hr are characterized by a very hard spectrum. This
implies that a hard spectrum can be securely assumed for all extreme GLE
events, e.g., those studied using cosmogenic isotope data in the past.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02455</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kassandrov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizcallah</keyname><forenames>Jozeph A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic Algebra of Space-Time and Algebrodynamics</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>4 pages, twocolumn</comments><journal-ref>Gravitation and Cosmology, Vol. 22, No. 3, 230-233 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0202289316030087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a manifestly Lorentz invariant form $\mathbb L$ of the
biquaternion algebra and its generalization to the case of curved manifold. The
conditions of $\mathbb L$-differentiability of $\mathbb L$-functions are
formulated and considered as the primary equations for fundamental fields
modeled with such functions. The exact form of the effective affine connection
induced by $\mathbb L$-differentiability equations is obtained for the flat and
curved cases. In the flat case, the integrability conditions of the latter lead
to the self-duality of the corresponding curvature, thus ensuring that the
source-free Maxwell and $SL(2,\mathbb C)$ Yang-Mills equations hold on the
solutions of the $\mathbb L$-differentiability equations
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02465</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Transfer Matrix of Scatterers Connected in Parallel</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transport phenomena in parallel coupled scatterers are studied by transfer
matrix formulism. We derive a simple recurrence relation for transfer matrix of
one-dimensional two-terminal systems consisting of $N$ arbitrary scattering
unit cells connected in parallel. For identical scattering sub-units we find
that the effects of parallel connection on transport properties of the coupled
system can be described by a similarity transformation on the single scatterer,
with the similar matrix determined by the scattering matrix of the junction.
While for distinct single scatterers, the similar matrices depend on both
scattering properties of individual elements and structure of connection
topologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02469</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry-Breaking Transition and Spectral Singularity in Coupled
  $\mathcal{PT}$-Symmetric Quantum Potentials</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the scattering properties of $N$ identical one-dimensional localized
$\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric potentials, connected in series as well as in
parallel. We derive a general transfer matrix formalism for parallel coupled
quantum scatterers, and apply that theory to demonstrate that the spectral
singularities and $\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric transitions of single scattering
cells may be observed in coupled systems, at the same or distinct values of the
critical parameters, depending on the connection modes under which the
scattering objects are coupled. We analyse the influences of the connection
configuration on the related transport properties such as spectral
singularities and anisotropic transmission resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02471</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Deyo</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>A method to calculate inductance in systems of parallel wires</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper gives a method that maps the static magnetic field due to a system
of parallel current-carrying wires to a complex function. Using this function
simplifies the calculation of the magnetic field energy density and inductance
per length in the wires, and we reproduce well-known results for this case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02480</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaxiola</keyname><forenames>Armando Meza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Juan Antonio Nieto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espinoza</keyname><forenames>Edgar Alejandro Leon</forenames></author></authors><title>Qubits and STU Black Holes with Eight Electric and Magnetic Charges</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages and 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we consider a STU black-hole model containing eight magnetic
and eight electric charges ((8+8)-signature). We show that such model admits an
extremal black holes solution in which (8+8)-signature can be associated with
the entropy via the Cayley's hyperdeterminant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02484</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Freddy Cueva</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the effects of a double reconstruction on the growth rate of
  cosmic structure, using current observational data</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures and 7 tables, Prepared for submission to PRD</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on General Relativity (GR) we consider two different cosmological
scenarios in where reconstruct the energy exchange (Q) between cold dark matter
(DM) fluid and dark energy (DE) fluid, which is modelled with a DE varying
equation of state (EoS) parameter {\omega}. We here investigate the main
cosmological effects on the growth rate of matter density perturbations
(f{\sigma}8), on the effective Hubble friction term (Heff ), on the effective
Newton constant (Geff ) and on the growth index of the linear matter
fluctuations ({\gamma}). Our study demonstrates that in the coupled models the
evolution of these quantities are modified with respect to the predictions in
the uncoupled models, and therefore could be used to distinguish among coupled
DE scenarios. Finally, we also perform a combined statistical analysis using
current observational data (geometric and dynamical probes) to put more
stringent constraints on the parameters space of the cosmic scenarios studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02488</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Isabela A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filgueiras</keyname><forenames>Jefferson G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auccaise</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Alexandre M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marx</keyname><forenames>Raimund</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glaser</keyname><forenames>Steffen J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonagamba</keyname><forenames>Tito J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarthour</keyname><forenames>Roberto S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>deAzevedo</keyname><forenames>Eduardo R.</forenames></author></authors><title>NMR Contributions to the study of Quantum Correlations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 14 figures. Contribution to &quot;Lectures on general quantum
  correlations and their applications&quot;, edited by Felipe Fanchini, Diogo
  Soares-Pinto, and Gerardo Adesso. Sorry for being late!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this chapter we review the contributions of Nuclear Magnetic Resonance to
the study of quantum correlations, including its capabilities to prepare
initial states, generate unitary transformations, and characterize the final
state. These are the three main demands to implement quantum information
processing in a physical system, which NMR offers, nearly to perfection, though
for a small number of qubits. Our main discussion will concern liquid samples
at room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02494</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Amin</keyname><forenames>Rubab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suer</keyname><forenames>Can</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Zhizhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khurgin</keyname><forenames>Jacob B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>Ritesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorger</keyname><forenames>Volker J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Active Material, Optical Mode and Cavity Impact on electro-optic
  Modulation Performance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>31 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, three different materials Si, ITO and graphene; and three
different types of mode structures bulk, slot and hybrid; based on their
electrooptical and electro absorptive aspects in performance are analyzed. The
study focuses on three major characteristics of electrooptic tuning, i.e.
material, modal and cavity dependency. The materials are characterized with
established models and the allowed ranges for their key parameter spectra are
analyzed with desired tuning in mind; categorizing into n and k dominant
regions for plausible electrooptic and electro absorptive applications,
respectively. A semi analytic approach, with the aid of FEM simulations for the
eigenmode calculations, was used for this work. Electrooptic tuning i.e.
resonance shift properties inside Fabry Perot cavities are investigated with
modal and scaling concerns in mind. Tuning changes the effective complex
refractive index of the mode dictated by the Kramers Kronig relations which
subsequently suggest a tradeoff between the resonance shift and increasing
losses. The electrical tuning properties of the different modes in the cavity
are analyzed, and subsequently a figure of merit, delta-lambda/delta-alpha was
chosen with respect to carrier concentration and cavity scaling to find
prospective suitable regions for desired tuning effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02498</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Florindo</keyname><forenames>Jo&#xe3;o B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>Odemir M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Schroedinger Transform For Texture Recognition</title><categories>cs.CV physics.data-an</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents a new procedure to extract features of grey-level texture
images based on the discrete Schroedinger transform. This is a non-linear
transform where the image is mapped as the initial probability distribution of
a wave function and such distribution evolves in time following the
Schroedinger equation from Quantum Mechanics. The features are provided by
statistical moments of the distribution measured at different times. The
proposed method is applied to the classification of three databases of textures
used for benchmark and compared to other well-known texture descriptors in the
literature, such as textons, local binary patterns, multifractals, among
others. All of them are outperformed by the proposed method in terms of
percentage of images correctly classified. The proposal is also applied to the
identification of plant species using scanned images of leaves and again it
outperforms other texture methods. A test with images affected by Gaussian and
&quot;salt \&amp; pepper&quot; noise is also carried out, also with the best performance
achieved by the Schroedinger descriptors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02502</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoshimatsu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakata</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohtomo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in higher titanium oxides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>25 pages, 4 figures in main text, 14 pages, 11 figures in
  supplemental information</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent renewal of the highest transition temperature in a conventional
superconductor of the sulfer hydride attracts much attention to exploring
simple compounds with the lighter elements, situated in unconventional
conditions. We report the discovery of superconductivity in simple oxides of
Ti4O7 and g-Ti3O5 in a thin-film form having deliberately tuned epitaxial
structures and off-stoichiometry. These higher titanium oxides join in a class
of simple-oxide superconductors, and g-Ti3O5 now holds the highest
superconducting transition temperature of 7.1 kelvin among them. The mechanism
behind the superconductivity is discussed on the basis of electrical
measurements and theoretical predictions. We conclude that superconductivity
arises from unstabilized bipolaronic insulating states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02517</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Shuangyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Zhihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Lipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ruibin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Haizheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Bingsuo</forenames></author></authors><title>EMP Lasing from Mn doped lead bromide perovskites nanorods</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>this manscript have 4 pagers, 4 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Diluted magnetic semiconductor (DMS) nanostructures are promising platform to
modulate carriers and spins for new information devices. Here we report that
the high quality pure CH3NH3PbBr3 nanorods and Mn doped CH3NH3PbBr3 nanorods
have been prepared by solution method and in which the exciton magnetic
polarons (EMP) formed in Mn doped NRs, and a single mode lasing phenomenon from
collective EMP in single NR have been detected when excited by fs pulse laser.
This finding helps to understand the exciton and spin interactions and pave
ways to the realization of new type of bosonic laser.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02525</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ordaz-Mendoza</keyname><forenames>B. E.</forenames><affiliation>University of Connecticut</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yelin</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames><affiliation>University of Connecticut</affiliation><affiliation>Harvard University</affiliation></author></authors><title>A novel regime for the dynamical Casimir effect</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages + Supplementary Material</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamical Casimir effect (DCE) is the production of photons by the
amplification of vacuum fluctuations. In this paper we demonstrate new
resonance conditions in DCE that potentially allow the production of optical
photons when the mechanical frequency is smaller than the lowest frequency of
the cavity field. We consider a cavity with one mirror fixed and the other
allowed to oscillate. In order to identify the region where production of
photons takes place, we do a linear stability analysis and investigate the
dynamic stability of the system under small fluctuations. By using a numerical
solution of the Heisenberg equations of motion, the time evolution of the
number of photons produced in the unstable region is studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02530</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Chorsi</keyname><forenames>Hamid T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gedney</keyname><forenames>Stephen D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate and Versatile High-Order Modeling of Electromagnetic Scattering
  on Plasmonic Nanostructures</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Radio Science Meeting (USNC-URSI NRSM), Boulder, Colorado, USA, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents high-order (HO) electromagnetic modeling of plasmonic
nanostructures based on the Locally Corrected Nystrom (LCN) method. Advanced
nanophotonic and nanoplasmonic structures involve electrically large
electromagnetic structures that are very complex in both geometry and material
composition. Hence, advanced analysis and design tools are required in order to
predict the performance of such structures and optimize the geometrical
parameters prior to costly prototype development. In this perspective, the LCN
is exploited to solve the electromagnetic scattering of plasmonic
nanostructures. The LCN utilizes basis functions of higher orders defined on
large geometrical elements, which significantly reduces the number of unknowns
for a given problem. Compared to other well-known methods for EM modeling of
plasmonic nanostructures, the LCN is computationally efficient, straightforward
to implement and provides exponential convergence. A full comparison, in terms
of time and complexity between the proposed method and previous works for a few
3D nanoplasmonic structures are presented to validate the accuracy, efficiency
and flexibility of the proposed method to simulate the behavior of
electromagnetic fields in real nanoplasmonic problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02535</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Annapurni</keyname><forenames>Subramaniam</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>N.</keyname><forenames>Sindhu</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation><affiliation>School of Advanced Sciences, VIT University, Vellore 632014, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>N.</keyname><forenames>Tandon S.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation><affiliation>Inter-University Center for Astronomy and Astrophysics, Pune, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kameswara</keyname><forenames>Rao N.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>J.</keyname><forenames>Postma</forenames><affiliation>University of Calgary, Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>Cot'e</forenames><affiliation>National Research Council, Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>J.</keyname><forenames>Hutchings</forenames><affiliation>National Research Council, Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K.</keyname><forenames>Ghosh S.</forenames><affiliation>National Centre for Radio Astrophysics, Pune, India</affiliation><affiliation>Tata Institute of Fundamental Research, Mumbai, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K.</keyname><forenames>George</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>V.</keyname><forenames>Girish</forenames><affiliation>ISRO Satellite Centre, HAL Airport Road, Bangalore 560017</affiliation></author><author><keyname>R.</keyname><forenames>Mohan</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>J.</keyname><forenames>Murthy</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K.</keyname><forenames>Sankarasubramanian</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation><affiliation>ISRO Satellite Centre, HAL Airport Road, Bangalore 560017</affiliation><affiliation>Center of Excellence in Space Sciences India, Indian Institute of Science Education and Research</affiliation></author><author><keyname>S.</keyname><forenames>Stalin C.</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>F.</keyname><forenames>Sutaria</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>C.</keyname><forenames>Mondal</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>S.</keyname><forenames>Sahu</forenames><affiliation>Indian Institute of Astrophysics, Koramangala II Block, Bangalore-560034, India</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Hot Companion to a Blue Straggler in NGC188 as Revealed by the
  Ultra-violet Imaging Telescope (UVIT) on ASTROSAT</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, two tables, To appear in ApJ Letters</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present early results from the Ultra-Violet Imaging Telescope (UVIT)
onboard the ASTROSAT observatory. We report the discovery of a hot companion
associated with one of the blue straggler stars (BSSs) in the old open cluster,
NGC188. Using fluxes measured in four filters in UVIT's Far-UV (FUV) channel,
and two filters in the near-UV (NUV) channel, we have constructed the spectral
energy distribution (SED) of the star WOCS-5885, after combining with flux
measurements from GALEX, UIT, UVOT, SPITZER, WISE and several ground-based
facilities. The resulting SED spans a wavelength range of 0.15~${\mu}$m to
7.8~${\mu}$m. This object is found to be one of the brightest FUV sources in
the cluster. An analysis of the SED reveals the presence of two components. The
cooler component is found to have a temperature of 6,000$\pm$150~K, confirming
that it is a BSS. Assuming it to be a main-sequence star, we estimate its mass
to be $\sim$ 1.1 - 1.2M$_\odot$. The hotter component, with an estimated
temperature of 17,000$\pm$500~K, has a radius of $\sim$ 0.6R$_\odot$ and L
$\sim$ 30L$_\odot$. Bigger and more luminous than a white dwarf, yet cooler
than a sub-dwarf, we speculate that it is a post-AGB/HB star that has recently
transferred its mass to the BSS, which is known to be a rapid rotator. This
binary system, which is the first BSS with a post-AGB/HB companion identified
in an open cluster, is an ideal laboratory to study the process of BSS
formation via mass transfer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02537</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Stivala</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keeler</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Another phase transition in the Axelrod model</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures. Includes Supplemental Material as a PDF file</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Axelrod's model of cultural dissemination, despite its apparent simplicity,
demonstrates complex behavior that has been of much interest in statistical
physics. Despite the many variations and extensions of the model that have been
investigated, a systematic investigation of the effects of changing the size of
the neighborhood on the lattice in which interactions can occur has not been
made. Here we investigate the effect of varying the radius R of the von Neumann
neighborhood in which agents can interact. We show, in addition to the
well-known phase transition at the critical value of q, the number of traits,
another phase transition at a critical value of R, and draw a q -- R phase
diagram for the Axelrod model on a square lattice. In addition, we present a
mean-field approximation of the model in which behavior on an infinite lattice
can be analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02540</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yucheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Minwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Xiaolu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaowei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tiejun</forenames></author></authors><title>City traffic forecasting using taxi GPS data: A coarse-grained cellular
  automata model</title><categories>cs.OH physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  City traffic is a dynamic system of enormous complexity. Modeling and
predicting city traffic flow remains to be a challenge task and the main
difficulties are how to specify the supply and demands and how to parameterize
the model. In this paper we attempt to solve these problems with the help of
large amount of floating car data. We propose a coarse-grained cellular
automata model that simulates vehicles moving on uniform grids whose size are
much larger compared with the microscopic cellular automata model. The car-car
interaction in the microscopic model is replaced by the coupling between
vehicles and coarse-grained state variables in our model. To parameterize the
model, flux-occupancy relations are fitted from the historical data at every
grids, which serve as the coarse-grained fundamental diagrams coupling the
occupancy and speed. To evaluate the model, we feed it with the historical
travel demands and trajectories obtained from the floating car data and use the
model to predict road speed one hour into the future. Numerical results show
that our model can capture the traffic flow pattern of the entire city and make
reasonable predictions. The current work can be considered a prototype for a
model-based forecasting system for city traffic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02544</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Choudhuri</keyname><forenames>Arnab Rai</forenames></author></authors><title>Starspots, Stellar Cycles and Stellar Flares: Lessons from Solar Dynamo
  Models</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>30 pages, 16 figures, invited review published in Science China -
  Physics, Mechanics &amp; Astronomy</comments><journal-ref>Sci. China-Phys. Mech. Astron. 60, 019601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11433-016-0413-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this review, we discuss whether the present solar dynamo models can be
extrapolated to explain various aspects of stellar activity. We begin with a
summary of the following kinds of data for solar-like stars: (i) data
pertaining to stellar cycles from Ca H/K emission over many years; (ii) X-ray
data indicating hot coronal activity; (iii) starspot data (especially about
giant polar spots); and (iv) data pertaining to stellar superflares. Then we
describe the current status of solar dynamo modelling---giving an introduction
to the flux transport dynamo model, the currently favoured model for the solar
cycle. While an extrapolation of this model to solar-like stars can explain
some aspects of observational data, some other aspects of the data still remain
to be theoretically explained. It is not clear right now whether we need a
different kind of dynamo mechanism for stars having giant starspots or
producing very strong superflares.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02552</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Jose Raul Gonzalez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brun</keyname><forenames>Todd</forenames></author></authors><title>Recovering Quantum Information in Orbital Angular Momentum of Photons by
  Adaptive Optics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Orbital angular momentum of photons is an intriguing system for the storage
and transmission of quantum information, but it is rapidly degraded by
atmospheric turbulence. We explore the ability of adaptive optics to compensate
for this disturbance by measuring and correcting cumulative phase shifts in the
wavefront. These shifts can be represented as a sum of Zernike functions; we
analyze the residual errors after correcting up to a certain number of Zernike
modes when an orbital angular momentum state is transmitted through a turbulent
atmosphere whose density fluctuations have a Kolmogorov spectrum. We
approximate the superoperator map that represents these residual errors and
find the solution in closed form. We illustrate with numerical examples how
this perturbation depends on the the number of Zernike modes corrected and the
orbital angular momentum state of the light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02553</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>YuanYao</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Vortex Beam Propagation in Turbulent Atmosphere</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Propagation of optical vortex beamlet (OVB) in turbulent atmospheric
environment is studied theoretically by normalized models. Our simulation shows
that optical vortex beamlet is superior to traditional Gaussian beam in terms
of diffraction behavior of long haul propagation. Formation of vortex beam let
is experimentally demonstrated by using a spatial light modulator (SLM), which
achieve a power efficiency of more than 90% when the intrinsic loss in SLM is
excluded.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02558</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Bou&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Gwena&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correia</keyname><forenames>Alexandre C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laskar</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete spin and orbital evolution of close-in bodies using a Maxwell
  viscoelastic rheology</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>31 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, Volume 126, Issue
  1-3, pp. 31-60 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10569-016-9708-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present a formalism designed to model tidal interaction
with a viscoelastic body made of Maxwell material. Our approach remains regular
for any spin rate and orientation, and for any orbital configuration including
high eccentricities and close encounters. The method is to integrate
simultaneously the rotation and the position of the planet as well as its
deformation. We provide the equations of motion both in the body frame and in
the inertial frame. With this study, we generalize preexisting models to the
spatial case and to arbitrary multipole orders using a formalism taken from
quantum theory. We also provide the vectorial expression of the secular tidal
torque expanded in Fourier series. Applying this model to close-in exoplanets,
we observe that if the relaxation time is longer than the revolution period,
the phase space of the system is characterized by the presence of several
spin-orbit resonances, even in the circular case. As the system evolves, the
planet spin can visit different spin-orbit configurations. The obliquity is
decreasing along most of these resonances, but we observe a case where the
planet tilt is instead growing. These conclusions derived from the secular
torque are successfully tested with numerical integrations of the instantaneous
equations of motion on HD 80606b. Our formalism is also well adapted to
close-in super-Earths in multiplanet systems which are known to have non-zero
mutual inclinations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02570</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Volotka</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surzhykov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trotsenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plunien</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xf6;hlker</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritzsche</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear excitation by two-photon electron transition</title><categories>physics.atom-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 243001 (2016); Editors' Suggestion</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.243001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new mechanism of nuclear excitation via two-photon electron transitions
(NETP) is proposed and studied theoretically. As a generic example, detailed
calculations are performed for the $E1E1$ $1s2s\,^1S_0 \rightarrow 1s^2\,^1S_0$
two-photon decay of He-like $^{225}$Ac$^{87+}$ ion with the resonant excitation
of the $3/2+$ nuclear state with the energy 40.09(5) keV. The probability for
such a two-photon decay via the nuclear excitation is found to be $P_{\rm NETP}
= 3.5 \times 10^{-9}$ and, thus, is comparable with other mechanisms, such as
nuclear excitation by electron transition and by electron capture. The
possibility for the experimental observation of the proposed mechanism is
thoroughly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02600</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Salman</forenames></author></authors><title>Tripartite entanglement of fermionic system in accelerated frames</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 348, 270 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2014.05.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of tripartite entanglement of fermionic system in noninertial
frames through linear contraction criterion when one or two observers are
accelerated is investigated. In one observer accelerated case the entanglement
measurement is not invariant with respect to the partial realignment of
different subsystems and for two observers accelerated case it is invariant. It
is shown that the acceleration of the frame does not generate entanglement in
any bipartite subsystems. Unlike the bipartite states, the genuine tripartite
entanglement does not completely vanish in both one observer accelerated and
two observers accelerated cases even in the limit of infinite acceleration. The
degradation of tripartite entanglement is fast when two observers are
accelerated than when one observer is accelerated. It is shown that tripartite
entanglement is a better resource for quantum information processing than the
bipartite entanglement in noninertial frames .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02602</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Feldmeier</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neff</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Clustering in Fermionic Molecular Dynamics</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Clustering plays an important role in the structure of nuclei, especially for
light nuclei in the $p$-shell. In nuclear cluster models these degrees of
freedom are introduced explicitly. In the Resonating Group Method or in the
Generator Coordinate Method the clusters are built from individual nucleons
interacting via an effective nucleon-nucleon interaction; the total wave
function is antisymmetrized. Fermionic Molecular Dynamics (FMD) goes beyond
pure cluster models. It is a microscopic many-body approach using a Gaussian
wave packet basis that includes the harmonic oscillator shell model and
Brink-type cluster model wave functions as special cases. Clustering is not
imposed but appears dynamically in the calculations. The importance of
clustering for the understanding of bound states, resonances and scattering
states is illustrated with examples discussing the charge radii of the Neon
isotopes, the $^3$He($\alpha$,$\gamma$)$^7$Be capture reaction and the cluster
states in the $^{12}$C continuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02609</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Boujo</keyname><forenames>Edouard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denisov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuermans</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noiray</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying acoustic damping using flame chemiluminescence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures (+2 supp.)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics (2016), vol. 808, pp. 245-257</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.663</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermoacoustic instabilities in gas turbines and aeroengine combustors falls
within the category of complex systems. They can be described
phenomenologically using nonlinear stochastic differential equations, which
constitute the grounds for output-only model-based system identification. It
has been shown recently that one can extract the governing parameters of the
instabilities, namely the linear growth rate and the nonlinear component of the
thermoacoustic feedback, using dynamic pressure time series only. This is
highly relevant for practical systems, which cannot be actively controlled due
to a lack of cost-effective actuators. The thermoacoustic stability is given by
the linear growth rate, which results from the combination of the acoustic
damping and the coherent feedback from the flame. In this paper, it is shown
that it is possible to quantify the acoustic damping of the system, and thus to
separate its contribution to the linear growth rate from the one of the flame.
This is achieved by post-processing in a simple way simultaneously acquired
chemiluminescence and acoustic pressure data. It provides an additional
approach to further unravel from observed time series the key mechanisms
governing the system dynamics. This straightforward method is illustrated here
using experimental data from a combustion chamber operated at several linearly
stable and unstable operating conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02627</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Tokas</keyname><forenames>R. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jena</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishal</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>K. Divakar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polaki</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratap</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Udupa</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakur</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Sanjiv</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of ZrO2 Thin Films Deposited at Glancing Angle by Magnetron
  Sputtering under Varying Substrate Rotation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>34 pages, 14 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, a set of ZrO2 thin films have been deposited at 82
degree angle of deposition at several substrate rotation speeds and at 0
degree. The effect of substrate rotation on optical, structural, morphological
properties and residual stress has been studies thoroughly. Refractive index
estimated from ellipsometric measurement and suitable modeling depicts an
interesting decreasing behavior with substrate rotation and has been explained
in the light of varying columnar structure with substrate rotation. Refractive
index of GLAD ZrO2 films varies between and 1.901 to 2.011. Normally deposited
film exhibits refractive index value of 2.178 which is substantially greater
than that of GLAD films. Lowering in refractive index of glancing angle
deposited films is the attribute of dominant atomic shadowing at glancing
angles. Further, correlation length which is the representative of surface
grain size was obtained from suitable modeling of atomic force microscopy data
and it exhibits a decreasing trend with substrate rotation. The trend has also
been attributed to the varying columnar microstructure with substrate rotation.
All the glancing angle deposited ZrO2 films possess root mean square roughness
between 4.6 and 5.1 nm whereas normally deposited film depicts 1.0 nm rms
roughness. Dominant atomic shadowing is responsible for high roughness of GLAD
films. Both glancing angle and normally deposited films exhibit preferential
growth of monoclinic phase oriented in different directions. GLAD films also
depict a tetragonal peak which has been attributed to the fine nano-crystallite
size (~13 nm). Residual stress depicts a great switching from large compressive
to small tensile as the deposition angle switches from normal to glancing angle
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02637</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Bochkin</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenchuk</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimization of remote one- and two-qubit state creation via multi-qubit
  unitary transformations at sender and receiver sides</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the optimization problem for remote one- and two-qubit state
creation via a homogeneous spin-1/2 communication line using the local unitary
transformations of the multi-qubit sender and extended receiver. We show that
the maximal length of a communication line used for the needed state creation
(the critical length) increases with an increase in the dimensionality of the
sender and extended receiver. The model with the sender and extended receiver
consisting of up to 10 nodes is used for the one-qubit state creation and we
consider two particular states: the almost pure state and the maximally mixed
one. Regarding the two-qubit state creation, we numerically study the
dependence of the critical length on a particular triad of independent
eigenvalues to be created, the model with four-qubit sender without an extended
receiver is used for this purpose.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02665</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurent</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jehanno</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Royer</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prada</keyname><forenames>Claire</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser beam shaping for enhanced Zero-Group Velocity Lamb modes
  generation</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 140, 2829 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1121/1.4965291</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optimization of Lamb modes induced by laser can be achieved by adjusting the
spatial source distribution to the mode wavelength ($\lambda$). The
excitability of Zero-Group Velocity (ZGV) resonances in isotropic plates is
investigated both theoretically and experimentally for axially symmetric
sources. Optimal parameters and amplitude gains are derived analytically for
spot and annular sources of either Gaussian or rectangular energy profiles. For
a Gaussian spot source, the optimal radius is found to be $\lambda_{ZGV}/\pi$.
Annular sources increase the amplitude by at least a factor of 3 compared to
the optimal Gaussian source. Rectangular energy profiles provide higher gain
than Gaussian ones. These predictions are confirmed by semi-analytical
simulation of the thermoelastic generation of Lamb waves, including the effect
of material attenuation. Experimentally, Gaussian ring sources of controlled
width and radius are produced with an axicon-lens system. Measured optimal
geometric parameters obtained for Gaussian and annular beams are in good
agreement with theoretical predictions. A ZGV resonance amplification factor of
2.1 is obtained with the Gaussian ring. Such source should facilitate the
inspection of highly attenuating plates made of low ablation threshold
materials like composites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02678</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Nedelko</keyname><forenames>Sergei N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir E.</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD Vacuum as Domain Wall Network</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk given at The Helmholtz International Summer School (HISS) -
  Dubna International Advanced School of Theoretical Physics (DIAS-TH) &quot;Quantum
  Field Theory at the Limits: from Strong Fields to Heavy Quarks&quot;, 18 July - 30
  July, Dubna (Russia); 5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Domain model of confinement, chiral symmetry breaking and hadronization is
based on description of QCD vacuum gluon configurations as an ensemble of
almost everywhere homogeneous Abelian (anti-)self-dual fields. The ensemble can
be explicitly constructed as domain wall network. We shortly overview this
approach and within this framework discuss the effects of QCD vacuum
polarization by strong electromagnetic fields. It is stressed that such
polarization effects can play the role of trigger for deconfinement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02679</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author></authors><title>Global attractor of the three dimensional primitive equations of
  large-scale ocean and atmosphere dynamics in an unbounded domain</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:math/0503028 by other
  authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is concerned with the long-time behavior of solutions for the
three dimensional primitive equations of large-scale ocean and atmosphere
dynamics in an unbounded domain. Since the Sobolev embedding is no longer
compact in an unbounded domain, we cannot obtain the asymptotical compactness
of the semigroup generated by problem (2.4)-(2.6) by the Sobolev compactness
embedding theorem even if we obtain the existence of an absorbing set in more
regular phase space. To overcome this difficulty, we first prove the
asymptotical compactness in a weak phase space of the semigroup generated by
problem (2.4)-(2.6) by combining the tail-estimates and the energy methods.
Thanks to the existence of an absorbing set in more regular phase space, we
establish the existence of a global attractor of problem (2.4)-(2.6) by virtue
of Sobolev interpolation inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02680</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Cabello</keyname><forenames>Ad&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>The unspeakable why</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures in R. Bertlmann and A. Zeilinger (eds.), Quantum
  [Us]Speakables II (Springer, Switzerland, 2016), p. 189</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-38987-5_11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For years, the biggest unspeakable in quantum theory has been why quantum
theory and what is quantum theory telling us about the world. Recent efforts
are unveiling a surprisingly simple answer. Here we show that two
characteristic limits of quantum theory, the maximum violations of
Clauser-Horne-Shimony-Holt and Klyachko-Can-Binicio\u{g}lu-Shumovsky
inequalities, are enforced by a simple principle. The effectiveness of this
principle suggests that non-realism is the key that explains why quantum
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02693</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sotiriadis</keyname><forenames>Sotiris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libert</keyname><forenames>Anne-Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bitsch</keyname><forenames>Bertram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crida</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly inclined and eccentric massive planets. II. Planet-planet
  interactions during the disc phase</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures, Accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628470</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim to investigate the influence of the eccentricity and inclination
damping due to planet-disc interactions on the final configurations of the
systems, generalizing previous studies on the combined action of the gas disc
and planet-planet scattering during the disc phase. Instead of the simplistic
$K$-prescription, our n-body simulations adopt the damping formulae for
eccentricity and inclination provided by the hydrodynamical simulations of our
companion paper. We follow the evolution of $11000$ numerical experiments of
three giant planets in the late stage of the gas disc, exploring different
initial configurations, planetary mass ratios and disc masses. The dynamical
evolutions of the planetary systems are studied along the simulations, with
emphasis on the resonance captures and inclination-growth mechanisms. Most of
the systems are found with small inclinations ($\le10^{\circ}$) at the
dispersal of the disc. Even though many systems enter an inclination-type
resonance during the migration, the disc usually damps the inclinations on a
short timescale. Although the majority of the multiple systems in our results
are quasi-coplanar, $\sim5\%$ of them end up with high mutual inclinations
($\ge10^{\circ}$). Half of these highly mutually inclined systems result from
two- or three-body MMR captures, the other half being produced by orbital
instability and/or planet-planet scattering. When considering the long-term
evolution over $100$ Myr, destabilization of the resonant systems is common,
and the percentage of highly mutually inclined systems still evolving in
resonance drops to $30\%$. Finally, the parameters of the final system
configurations are in very good agreement with the semi-major axis and
eccentricity distributions in the observations, showing that planet-planet
interactions during the disc phase could have played an important role in
sculpting planetary systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02713</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Merker</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohn</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>V&#xf6;llinger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siegel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>NbN/AlN/NbN Josephson junctions on sapphire for receiver applications</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><doi>10.1109/TASC.2016.2631841</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most developed integrated receivers for THz radiation nowadays are based
on Josephson junction SIS devices. In this kind of devices, the highest
receivable frequency is determined by the energy gap of the superconducting
electrodes and limited to approximately 700 GHz in case of Nb/AlOx/Nb
multilayers. We have developed a technology for NbN/AlN/NbN Josephson junctions
on sapphire substrates which allow operation at frequencies above 1 THz. The
trilayers are deposited in-situ in a 3-chamber DC-magnetron sputtering system
at temperatures as high as 775 {\deg}C. Each layer is reactively sputtered in
an argon and nitrogen atmosphere. By variation of the partial gas pressures and
discharge current of the plasma, optimum deposition conditions for the
tri-layers were found. So far, gap voltages as high as 5.1 mV at 4.2 K have
been achieved which allows the operation frequency of the JJ devices to exceed
1 THz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02718</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Shao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Hong-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Rui-Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing Higgs Coupling Precision and New Physics Scales at Lepton
  Colliders</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>15pp. Presentation at IAS Program on HEP (Jan-2016). -- Our updated
  analyses and fits appeared in journal paper JHEP 1610 (2016) 007
  [arXiv:1603.03385]</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 31 (2016) 1644004</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16440048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The next-generation lepton colliders, such as CEPC, FCC-ee, and ILC will make
precision measurement of the Higgs boson properties. We first extract the Higgs
coupling precision from Higgs observables at CEPC to illustrate the potential
of future lepton colliders. Depending on the related event rates, the precision
can reach percentage level for most couplings. Then, we try to estimate the new
physics scales that can be indirectly probed with Higgs and electroweak
precision observables. The Higgs observables, together with the existing
electroweak precision observables, can probe new physics up to 10TeV (40TeV for
the gluon-related operator $\mathcal O_g$) at 95% C.L. Including the $Z/W$ mass
measurements and $Z$-pole observables at CEPC further pushes the limit up to
35TeV. Although $Z$-pole running is originally for the purpose of machine
calibration, it can be as important as the Higgs observables for probing the
new physics scales indirectly. The indirect probe of new physics scales at
lepton colliders can mainly cover the energy range to be explored by the
following hadron colliders of pp (50-100TeV), such as SPPC and FCC-hh.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02726</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ablowitz</keyname><forenames>Mark J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xu-Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musslimani</keyname><forenames>Ziad H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse scattering transform for the nonlocal nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
  equation with nonzero boundary conditions</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2013 a new nonlocal symmetry reduction of the well-known AKNS scattering
problem was found; it was shown to give rise to a new nonlocal $PT$ symmetric
and integrable Hamiltonian nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger (NLS) equation.
Subsequently, the inverse scattering transform was constructed for the case of
rapidly decaying initial data and a family of spatially localized, time
periodic one soliton solution were found. In this paper, the inverse scattering
transform for the nonlocal NLS equation with nonzero boundary conditions at
infinity is presented in the four cases when the data at infinity have constant
amplitudes. The direct and inverse scattering problems are analyzed.
Specifically, the direct problem is formulated, the analytic properties of the
eigenfunctions and scattering data and their symmetries are obtained. The
inverse scattering problem is developed via a left-right Riemann-Hilbert
problem in terms of a suitable uniformization variable and the time dependence
of the scattering data is obtained. This leads to a method to linearize/solve
the Cauchy problem. Pure soliton solutions are discussed and explicit 1-soliton
solution and two 2-soliton solutions are provided for three of the four
different cases corresponding to two different signs of nonlinearity and two
different values of the phase difference between plus and minus infinity. In
the one other case there are no solitons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02744</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaufman</keyname><forenames>I. Kh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorenko</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luchinsky</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibby</keyname><forenames>W. A. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McClintock</keyname><forenames>S. K. Roberts. P. V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenberg</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ionic Coulomb blockade and anomalous mole fraction effect in NaChBac
  bacterial ion channels</title><categories>q-bio.SC physics.bio-ph q-bio.CB</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 32 references, submitted to EPJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental study of the influences of the fixed charge and
bulk ionic concentrations on the conduction of biological ion channels, and we
consider the results within the framework of the ionic Coulomb blockade model
of permeation and selectivity. Voltage clamp recordings were used to
investigate the Na$^+$/Ca$^{2+}$ anomalous mole fraction effect (AMFE)
exhibited by the bacterial sodium channel NaChBac and its mutants.
Site-directed mutagenesis was used to study the effect of either increasing or
decreasing the fixed charge in their selectivity filters for comparison with
the predictions of the Coulomb blockade model. The model was found to describe
well some aspects of the experimental (divalent blockade and AMFE) and
simulated (discrete multi-ion conduction and occupancy band) phenomena,
including a concentration-dependent shift of the Coulomb staircase. These
results substantially extend the understanding of ion channel selectivity and
may also be applicable to biomimetic nanopores with charged walls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02750</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osborn</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames></author></authors><title>QEX: a framework for lattice field theories</title><categories>hep-lat physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figures, presented at the 38th International Conference on
  High Energy Physics, August 3 - 10, 2016, Chicago</comments><journal-ref>PoS(ICHEP2016)187</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new software framework for simulating lattice field theories. It
features an intuitive programming interface, while simultaneously achieving
high performance supercomputing, all in one programming language, Nim. With a
macro system based on its abstract syntax tree, the language enables us to
check and optimize our code at compile time. It also allows us to code
intrinsics that map directly to machine instructions, and generates efficient
native code. We show how we use Nim's metaprogramming features in our code, and
present the current status of the code and future plans.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02755</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaojian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Jinxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Xianran</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative thermal expansion and local lattice distortion in the
  (Sc1-xTix)F3 and related solid solutions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>main: 18 pages, 4 figures; supporting information: 10 pages, 8
  figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Negative thermal expansion (NTE) is unusual but important property for
control of thermal expansion. In the present study, the chemical modification
is utilized to engineer controllable thermal expansion in cubic NTE ScF3. A
broad window of the coefficient of thermal expansion (CTE = -1.51 ~ -3.4*10^-6
K-1, 300-800 K) has been achieved in Sc1-xMxF3 (M = Ti, Al and Ga). The
long-range crystallographic structure of (Sc1-xTix)F3 adheres to the cubic
Pm-3m symmetry according to the analysis of high-energy synchrotron X-ray
powder diffraction. Pair distribution function (PDF) analysis of synchrotron
X-ray total scattering was performed to investigate the local lattice
distortion. It was found that the weakness of NTE has a close correlation with
the local lattice distortion. Based on the coupled rotation model, it is
presumably that this local distortion might dampen the transverse vibration of
F atoms and thus reduce NTE. The present work provides a possible reference for
the design of controllable NTE in open framework solids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02779</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Mundoor</keyname><forenames>Haridas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senyuk</keyname><forenames>Bohdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smalyukh</keyname><forenames>Ivan I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Triclinic nematic colloidal crystals from competing elastic and
  electrostatic interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>27 Pages</comments><journal-ref>Science, 352, 69-73 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aaf0801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-assembly of nanoparticles can enable composites with pre-designed
properties but remains challenged by reproducing structural diversity of atomic
and molecular crystals. We combine anisotropic elastic and weakly screened
electrostatic interactions to guide both orientational and triclinic positional
self-ordering of inorganic nanocrystals in a nematic fluid host. The lattice
periodicity of these low-symmetry colloidal crystals is more than an order of
magnitude larger than the nanoparticle size. Orientations of nanocrystals, as
well as crystallographic axes of ensuing triclinic colloidal crystals, are
coupled to the uniform alignment direction of the nematic host, which can be
readily controlled on large scales. We probe colloidal pair and many-body
interactions and demonstrate how triclinic crystals with orientational ordering
of the semiconductor nanorods emerge from competing long-range elastic and
electrostatic forces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02781</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Makarov</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovchinnikov</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooperative effect of doping and temperature on the polaronic band
  structure in strongly correlated electron systems with strong electron-phonon
  interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, 22 references. arXiv admin note: substantial
  text overlap with arXiv:1611.05836</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we investigate doping and temperature dependences of electronic
structure of system with strong electronic correlations and strong
electron-phonon interaction modeling cuprates in the frameworks of the
three-band p-d-Holstein model by a polaronic version of the generalized tight
binding (GTB) method. Within this approach the electronic structure is formed
by polaronic quasiparticles constructed as excitations between initial and
final polaronic multielectron states. Doping and temperature effects are taken
into account by occupation numbers of local excited polaronic states and
variations in the magnitude of spin-spin correlation functions. Both effects
are manifested in the reconstruction of band structure, Fermi contours, density
of states and redistribution of the spectral weight over the Hubbard polaron
subbands. Doping leads to transformation of Fermi contour from small hole
pockets around k=(pi/2,pi/2) with inhomogeneous spectral weight distribution at
small hole concentration to large contour around k=(pi,pi) in the overdoped
compound as a result of two quantum phase transitions. In the system with
phonon subsystem and EPI doping results in the top of the valence band
splitting off and new polaron subbands appearance. Temperature increasing in
the system with doped holes and moderate EPI leads to formation of the flatband
around k=(pi,pi) and transfer of the spectral weight to the splitted off top of
the valence band.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
