<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:45:05Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-05" from="2016-12-05" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1004.2937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1004.2937</id><created>2010-04-16</created><updated>2010-09-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clarke</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guffin</keyname><forenames>Josh</forenames></author></authors><title>On the existence of affine Landau-Ginzburg phases in gauged linear sigma
  models</title><categories>math.AG hep-th math.SG</categories><comments>Added theorem (3.18) showing uniqueness of affine quotients, typos
  corrected</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Theoretical and Mathematical Physics, Vol. 19, No. 4
  (2015), pp. 725-745</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a simple criterion for the existence of an affine Landau-Ginzburg
point in the K\&quot;ahler moduli space of a gauged linear sigma model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.2693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.2693</id><created>2012-05-11</created><updated>2016-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>Matthias J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilker</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumgardt</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xf4;t&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebel</keyname><forenames>Eva K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haghi</keyname><forenames>Hosein</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;pper</keyname><forenames>Andreas H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djorgovski</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The velocity dispersion and mass function of the outer halo globular
  cluster Palomar 4</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>17 pages, accepted for publication in MNRAS; Fig. 8 surface
  brightness/density data at github.com/matthiasjfrank/pal4_surface_brightness</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 423, 3 (2012) 2917-2932</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21105.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtained precise line-of-sight radial velocities of 23 member stars of the
remote halo globular cluster Palomar 4 (Pal 4) using the High Resolution
Echelle Spectrograph (HIRES) at the Keck I telescope. We also measured the mass
function of the cluster down to a limiting magnitude of V~28 mag using archival
HST/WFPC2 imaging. We derived the cluster's surface brightness profile based on
the WFPC2 data and on broad-band imaging with the Low-Resolution Imaging
Spectrometer (LRIS) at the Keck II telescope. We find a mean cluster velocity
of 72.55+/-0.22 km/s and a velocity dispersion of 0.87+/-0.18 km/s. The global
mass function of the cluster, in the mass range 0.55&lt;=M&lt;=0.85 M_solar, is
shallower than a Kroupa mass function and the cluster is significantly depleted
in low-mass stars in its center compared to its outskirts. Since the relaxation
time of Pal 4 is of the order of a Hubble time, this points to primordial mass
segregation in this cluster. Extrapolating the measured mass function towards
lower-mass stars and including the contribution of compact remnants, we derive
a total cluster mass of 29800 M_solar. For this mass, the measured velocity
dispersion is consistent with the expectations of Newtonian dynamics and below
the prediction of Modified Newtonian Dynamics (MOND). Pal 4 adds to the growing
body of evidence that the dynamics of star clusters in the outer Galactic halo
can hardly be explained by MOND.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.4140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.4140</id><created>2012-10-15</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zhensheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Blow-up criterion of classical solutions for the incompressible nematic
  liquid crystal flows</title><categories>math.AP cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to a crucial sign
  error in equation 1 You may also update the abstract</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider the short time classical solution to a simplified
hydrodynamic flow modeling incompressible, nematic liquid crystal materials in
dimension three. We establish a criterion for possible breakdown of such
solutions at a finite time. More precisely, if $(u,d)$ is smooth up to time $T$
provided that $\int_0^T|\nabla\times u(t,\cdot)|_{BMO(\mathbb R^3)}+|\nabla
d(t,\cdot)|^8_{L^4(\mathbb R^3)}dt&lt;\infty $
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.1333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.1333</id><created>2013-03-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Weyrauch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakov</keyname><forenames>Mykhailo V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient MPS algorithm for periodic boundary conditions and
  applications</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, 3 tables, the article was accepted for Ukrainian
  Journal of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Ukr. J. Phys. (2013), Vol. 58, No. 7, pages 657-665</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ujpe58.07.0657</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an implementation of an efficient algorithm for the calculation of
the spectrum of one-dimensional quantum systems with periodic boundary
conditions. This algorithm is based on a matrix product representation for
quantum states (MPS), and a similar representation for Hamiltonians and other
operators (MPO). It is significantly more efficient for systems of about 100
sites and more than for small quantum systems. We apply the formalism to
calculate the ground state and first excited state of a spin-1 Heisenberg ring
and deduce the size of the Haldane gap. The results are compared to previous
high-precision DMRG calculations. Furthermore, we study spin-1 systems with a
biquadratic nearest-neighbor interaction and show first results of an
application to a mesoscopic Hubbard ring of spinless Fermions which carries a
persistent current.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.4427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.4427</id><created>2014-06-17</created><updated>2015-03-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lederer</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>The Quantum Hall Effects: Philosophical Approach</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>43 pages, 3 figures, revised version, accepted for publication in
  Studies in History and Philosophy of Modern Physics</comments><journal-ref>Studies in History and Philosophy of Modern Physics, 50, (2015),
  25-42</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Quantum Hall Effects offer a rich variety of theoretical and experimental
advances. They provide interesting insights on such topics as complementarity,
gauge invariance, strong interactions, emergence of new theoretical concepts.
This paper focuses on some related philosophical questions. Hacking's views on
Scientific Realism, Chalmers' on Non Figurative Realism are discussed. It is
argued that the difficulties with those versions of realism may be resolved
within a dialectical materialist approach. The latter is shown to provide a
rational approach to the phenomena, the theory and the ontology of the Quantum
Hall Effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00949</id><created>2015-01-05</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Astrauskas</keyname><forenames>Arvydas</forenames></author></authors><title>From Extreme Values of I.I.D. Random Fields to Extreme Eigenvalues of
  Finite-volume Anderson Hamiltonian</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>81 pages.Substantially revised; includes new Section: Applications to
  the PAM</comments><msc-class>60G70, 60H25, 82B44, 35P05 (Primary), 60F05, 60F15, 60G60, 82C44,
  35P15, 15B52, 26A12 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Probability Surveys, 2016, vol. 13, p. 156--244</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/15-PS252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to study asymptotic geometric properties almost
surely or/and in probability of extreme order statistics of an i.i.d. random
field (potential) indexed by sites of multidimensional lattice cube, the volume
of which unboundedly increases. We discuss the following topics: (I) high level
exceedances, in particular, clustering of exceedances; (II) decay rate of
spacings in comparison with increasing rate of extreme order statistics; (III)
minimum of spacings of successive order statistics; (IV) asymptotic behavior of
values neighboring to extremes and so on. The conditions of the results are
formulated in terms of regular variation (RV) of the cumulative hazard function
and its inverse. A relationship between RV classes of the present paper as well
as their links to the well-known RV classes (including domains of attraction of
max-stable distributions) are discussed.
  The asymptotic behavior of functionals (I)--(IV) determines the asymptotic
structure of the top eigenvalues and the corresponding eigenfunctions of the
large-volume discrete Schr\&quot; odinger operators with an i.i.d. potential
(Anderson Hamiltonian). Thus, another aim of the present paper is to review and
comment a recent progress on the extreme value theory for eigenvalues of random
Schr\&quot; odinger operators as well as to provide a clear and rigorous
understanding of the relationship between the top eigenvalues and extreme
values of i.i.d. random potentials. We also discuss their links to the
long-time intermittent behavior of the parabolic problems associated with the
Anderson Hamiltonian via spectral representation of solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07235</id><created>2015-02-25</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Nittis</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lein</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>Derivation of Ray Optics Equations in Photonic Crystals Via a
  Semiclassical Limit</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>49 pages, added Section 5.2 with a more detailed discussion of
  previous results, to appear in Annales of Henri Poincar\'e</comments><msc-class>81Q20, 35Q60, 35Q61, 35S05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present a novel approach to the ray optics limit: we rewrite
the dynamical Maxwell equations in Schr\&quot;odinger form and prove Egorov-type
theorems, a robust semiclassical technique. We implement this scheme for
periodic light conductors, photonic crystals, thereby making the quantum-light
analogy between semiclassics for the Bloch electron and ray optics in photonic
crystals rigorous. Our main results, Theorems 3.3 and 4.1, give a ray optics
limit for quadratic observables and, among others, apply to local averages of
energy density, the Poynting vector and the Maxwell stress tensor. Ours is the
first rigorous derivation of ray optics equations which include all sub-leading
order terms, some of which are also new to the physics literature. While the
ray optics limit we prove initially (Theorem 3.3) applies to photonic crystals
of any topological class, we also consider the ray optics limit for real
electromagnetic fields propagating in non-gyrotropic photonic crystals. Such an
extension is non-trivial, because the ray optic limit for real fields is
necessarily a multiband problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03904</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03904</id><created>2015-07-14</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dalwadi</keyname><forenames>Mohit P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapman</keyname><forenames>S. Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>Sarah L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliver</keyname><forenames>James M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the boundary layer structure near a highly permeable porous interface</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>49 pages with 15 figures. J. Fluid Mech</comments><journal-ref>J. Fluid Mech., 798 pp. 88-139 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The method of matched asymptotic expansions is used to study the canonical
problem of steady laminar flow through a narrow two-dimensional channel blocked
by a tight-fitting finite-length highly permeable porous obstacle. We
investigate the behaviour of the local flow close to the interface between the
single-phase and porous regions (governed by the incompressible Navier--Stokes
and Darcy flow equations, respectively). We solve for the flow in these inner
regions in the limits of low and high Reynolds number, facilitating an
understanding of the nature of the transition from Poiseuille to plug to
Poiseuille flow in each of these limits. Significant analytic progress is made
in the high-Reynolds-number limit, and we explore in detail the rich boundary
layer structure that occurs. We consider the three-dimensional generalization
to unsteady laminar flow through and around a tight-fitting highly permeable
cylindrical porous obstacle within a Hele-Shaw cell. For the
high-Reynolds-number limit, we give the coupling conditions and interfacial
stress in terms of the outer flow variables, allowing information from a
nonlinear three-dimensional problem to be obtained by solving a linear
two-dimensional problem. Finally, we illustrate the utility of our analysis by
considering the specific example of time-dependent forced far-field flow in a
Hele-Shaw cell containing a porous cylinder with a circular cross-section. We
determine the internal stress within the porous obstacle, which is key for
tissue engineering applications, and the interfacial stress on the boundary of
the porous obstacle, which has applications to biofilm erosion. In the
high-Reynolds-number limit, we demonstrate that the fluid inertia can result in
the cylinder experiencing a time-independent net force, even when the far-field
forcing is periodic with zero mean.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08868</id><created>2015-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Seipt</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surzhykov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritzsche</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampfer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Caustic structures in the spectrum of x-ray Compton scattering off
  electrons driven by a short intense laser pulse</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 18, 023044 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/023044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Compton scattering of x-rays off electrons that are driven by a
relativistically intense short optical laser pulse. The frequency spectrum of
the laser-assisted Compton radiation shows a broad plateau in the vicinity of
the laser-free Compton line due to a nonlinear mixing between x-ray and laser
photons. Special emphasis is placed on how the shape of the short assisting
laser pulse affects the spectrum of the scattered x-rays. In particular, we
observe sharp peak structures in the plateau region, whose number and locations
are highly sensitive to the laser pulse shape. These structures are interpreted
as spectral caustics by using a semiclassical analysis of the laser-assisted
QED matrix element.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03823</id><created>2015-10-13</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Performance of pile-up mitigation techniques for jets in $pp$ collisions
  at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV using the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>38 pages, plus author list - 54 pages (total), 19 figures. Published
  in EPJC. All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/PERF-2014-03/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-206</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:581</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4395-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The large rate of multiple simultaneous proton--proton interactions, or
pile-up, generated by the Large Hadron Collider in Run 1 required the
development of many new techniques to mitigate the adverse effects of these
conditions. This paper describes the methods employed in the ATLAS experiment
to correct for the impact of pile-up on jet energy and jet shapes, and for the
presence of spurious additional jets, with a primary focus on the large 20.3
fb$^{-1}$ data sample collected at a centre-of-mass energy of $\sqrt{s} = 8$
TeV. The energy correction techniques that incorporate sophisticated estimates
of the average pile-up energy density and tracking information are presented.
Jet-to-vertex association techniques are discussed and projections of
performance for the future are considered. Lastly, the extension of these
techniques to mitigate the effect of pile-up on jet shapes using subtraction
and grooming procedures is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08808</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lederer</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>The battle of High Temperature Superconductivity</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>25 pages 1 figure. This version replaces a first one with a title
  mentioning &quot;scientific pluralism&quot;. The new version has a new section entitled
  &quot;The limits of the no-contradiction principle&quot; devoted to an introduction to
  some basic principles of dialectic materialism</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The early development of conflicting theories about the microscopic mechanism
of High Temperature Superconductivity is described. The biographical roots of
this diversity are stressed, as well as its subjective/objective roots. This
study of a specific case of knowledge about a specific fact of nature allows to
discuss the subjective and objective roots of scientific pluralism. Relativism,
the Duhem-Quine thesis on the underdetermination of theory by facts, are
discussed from the stand point of the materialist view on the dialectics of
knowledge and nature. Developments of dialectic materialism seem to be
suggested by this study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02839</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-09-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Speelman</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author></authors><title>Instantaneous non-local computation of low T-depth quantum circuits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><doi>10.4230/LIPIcs.TQC.2016.9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Instantaneous non-local quantum computation requires multiple parties to
jointly perform a quantum operation, using pre-shared entanglement and a single
round of simultaneous communication. We study this task for its close
connection to position-based quantum cryptography, but it also has natural
applications in the context of foundations of quantum physics and in
distributed computing. The best known general construction for instantaneous
non-local quantum computation requires a pre-shared state which is
exponentially large in the number of qubits involved in the operation, while
efficient constructions are known for very specific cases only.
  We partially close this gap by presenting new schemes for efficient
instantaneous non-local computation of several classes of quantum circuits,
using the Clifford+T gate set. Our main result is a protocol which uses
entanglement exponential in the T-depth of a quantum circuit, able to perform
non-local computation of quantum circuits with a (poly-)logarithmic number of
layers of T gates with quasi-polynomial entanglement. Our proofs combine ideas
from blind and delegated quantum computation with the garden-hose model, a
combinatorial model of communication complexity which was recently introduced
as a tool for studying certain schemes for quantum position verification. As an
application of our results, we also present an efficient attack on a
recently-proposed scheme for position verification by Chakraborty and
Leverrier.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03978</id><created>2015-12-12</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Donini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A scalar field coupled to a brane in ${\cal M}_4 \times {\cal S}_1$.
  Part I: Kaluza-Klein spectrum and zero-mode localization</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Replaced version with significant changes: shorter introduction;
  computation of the exact spectrum with BLKT; KK-decomposition of the model
  when a self-interaction is added. 32 pages, 7 pdf figures</comments><report-no>IFIC 15-90</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A toy model where a massless, real, scalar field $\Phi$ in a compact
space-time ${\cal M}_4 \times {\cal S}_1$ is coupled to a brane (parametrized
as a $\delta$-function) through the unique relevant operator $\delta (y) \Phi^2
(x,y)$ is considered. The exact Kaluza-Klein spectrum of the model is computed
for any value of the coupling between field and brane using the
Burniston-Siewert method to solve analytically transcendental equations. The
exact KK-spectrum of a model with a Brane-Localized Kinetic Term is also
computed. Weak- and strong-coupling limits are derived, matching or extending
mathematically equivalent existing results. For a negative coupling, the
would-be zero-mode $\psi_{0^-}^e$ is found to localize into the brane, behaving
as an effective four-dimensional field. The 4-dimensional KK-decomposition of
the model once a renormalizable cubic self-interaction $\Phi^3 (x,y)$ is added
to the action is derived computing the overlaps between the KK-modes. It is
found that the localized would-be zero-mode $\psi_{0^-}^e$ decouples from the
massive KK-spectrum in the limit of large brane-to-bulk coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04427</id><created>2015-11-24</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Ahmad T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Suhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alghanemi</keyname><forenames>Azeb</forenames></author></authors><title>Homothetic Vectors of Bianchi Type I Spacetimes in Lyra Geometry and
  General Relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, Section 3 is added, Some new notations are introduced and
  results are improved</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper Bianchi type I spacetimes are completely classified by their
homothetic vectors in the context of Lyra geometry. The non-linear coupled Lyra
homothetic equations are obtained and solved completely for different cases. In
some cases, Bianchi type I spacetimes admit proper Lyra homothetic vectors
(LHVs) for special choices of the metric functions, while there exist other
cases where the spacetime under consideration admits only Lyra Killing vectors
(LKVs). In all the possible cases where Bianchi type I spacetimes admit proper
LHVs or LKVs, we obtained homothetic and Killing vectors for Bianchi type I
spacetimes in general relativity by taking the displacement vector of Lyra
geometry as zero. Matter collineation symmetry is explained by taking the
matter field as a perfect fluid. The obtained proper LHVs and LKVs are used in
matter collineation equations and a barotropic equation of state having
$\rho(t)\,=\,\gamma\,p(t)$, $0\,\leq\,\gamma\,\leq\,1$ form is always obtained
when the displacement vector is considered as a function of $t$ or treated as a
constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07037</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Melanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kravtsov</keyname><forenames>Vasily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paarmann</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raschke</keyname><forenames>Markus B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ernstorfer</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author></authors><title>A nanofocused plasmon-driven sub-10 femtosecond electron point source</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, supplementary information available</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 3, 611 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.5b00710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Progress in ultrafast electron microscopy relies on the development of
efficient laser-driven electron sources delivering femtosecond electron pulses
to the sample. In particular, recent advances employ photoemission from metal
nanotips as coherent point-like femtosecond low-energy electron sources. We
report the nonlinear emission of ultrashort electron wave packets from a gold
nanotip generated by nonlocal excitation and nanofocusing of surface plasmon
polaritons. We verify the nanoscale localization of plasmon-induced electron
emission by its electrostatic collimation characteristics. With a plasmon
polariton pulse duration below 8 fs at the apex, we identify multiphoton
photoemission as the underlying emission process. The quantum efficiency of the
plasmon-induced emission exceeds that of photoemission from direct apex
illumination. We demonstrate the application for plasmon-triggered
point-projection imaging of an individual semiconductor nanowire at 3 $\mu$m
tip-sample distance. Based on numerical simulations we estimate an electron
pulse duration at the sample below 10 fs for tip-sample distances up to few
micrometers. Plasmon-driven nanolocalized electron emission thus enables
femtosecond point-projection microscopy with unprecedented temporal and spatial
resolution, femtosecond low-energy electron in-line holography, and opens a new
route towards femtosecond scanning tunneling microscopy and spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00724</id><created>2016-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Yelong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Hongyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Dashuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Lichun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>In Situ Simultaneous Measuring Forces Acted on Individual Legs of Water
  Striders According to Archimedes' Principle</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 2016, 109 (16), 163701</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964788</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The supporting forces of all the legs have been simultaneously measured
through a natural phenomenon inspired shadow method, by capturing water strider
leg shadows to calculate the expelled water volume and the equivalent floating
forces according to Archimedes' principle, with a sensitivity up to
nN~pN/pixel. The method was verified by comparing to electronic balance to
weight water striders. The supporting force acted on legs was found to linearly
proportional to its shadow area, which geometry clearly indicated the
hydrophobicity of legs. The pressed depth of legs, vertical weight focus
position change and body pitch angle during leg refreshing, sculling and
jumping forward of water striders have been achieved with resolutions of
5um/pixel, 2 um/pixel, and 0.02 degree, respectively, which is difficult for
general imaging technologies. The shadow method was also developed into a force
measuring device and characterized the adhesion force of a hair/polymer surface
contact in a few uN with a 0.3 nN/pixel resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07282</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beterov</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saffman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakshina</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyakov</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Entin</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamzina</keyname><forenames>G. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryabtsev</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulated quantum process tomography of quantum gates with Rydberg
  superatoms</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, to appear in Special issue on Rydberg atomic
  physics of Journal of Physics B. Typos in Table 2 corrected in version 3</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 114007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/11/114007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have numerically simulated quantum tomography of single-qubit and
two-qubit quantum gates with qubits represented by mesoscopic ensembles
containing random numbers of atoms. Such ensembles of strongly interacting
atoms in the regime of Rydberg blockade are known as Rydberg superatoms. The
Stimulated Raman Adiabatic Passage (STIRAP) in the regime of Rydberg blockade
is used for deterministic Rydberg excitation in the ensemble, required for
storage of quantum information in the collective state of the atomic ensemble
and implementation of two-qubit gates. The optimized shapes of the STIRAP
pulses are used to achieve high fidelity of the population transfer. Our
simulations confirm validity and high fidelity of single-qubit and two-qubit
gates with Rydberg superatoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08143</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kniehl</keyname><forenames>Bernd A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pikelner</keyname><forenames>Andrey F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veretin</keyname><forenames>Oleg L.</forenames></author></authors><title>mr: a C++ library for the matching and running of the Standard Model
  parameters</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, minor changes, references added, matches journal version,
  Highlighted Article in Comput. Phys. Commun., featured by Abigail Beall as &quot;A
  time machine to explore the universe&quot;
  (http://www.journals.elsevier.com/computer-physics-communications/highlighted-articles/a-time-machine-to-explore-the-universe)</comments><report-no>DESY 16-019</report-no><journal-ref>Comput. Phys. Commun. 206 (2016) 84-96</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2016.04.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the C++ program library mr that allows us to reliably calculate
the values of the running parameters in the Standard Model at high energy
scales. The initial conditions are obtained by relating the running parameters
in the $\overline{\mathrm{MS}}$ renormalization scheme to observables at lower
energies with full two-loop precision. The evolution is then performed in
accordance with the renormalization group equations with full three-loop
precision. Pure QCD corrections to the matching and running are included
through four loops. We also provide a Mathematica interface for this program
library.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02157</id><created>2016-03-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Dusek</keyname><forenames>Jeff E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triantafyllou</keyname><forenames>Michael S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Piezoresistive Foam Sensor Arrays for Marine Applications</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1016/j.sna.2016.07.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spatially-dense pressure measurements are needed on curved surfaces in marine
environments to provide marine vehicles with the detailed, real-time
measurements of the near-field flow necessary to improve performance through
flow control. To address this challenge, a waterproof and conformal pressure
sensor array comprising carbon black-doped-silicone closed-cell foam (CBPDMS
foam) was developed for use in marine applications. The response of the CBPDMS
foam sensor arrays was characterized using periodic hydrodynamic pressure
stimuli from vertical plunging, from which a piecewise polynomial calibration
was developed to describe the sensor response. Inspired by the distributed
pressure and velocity sensing capabilities of the fish lateral line, the CBPDMS
foam sensor arrays have significant advantages over existing commercial sensors
for distributed flow reconstruction and control. Experimental results have
shown the sensor arrays to have sensitivity on the order of 5 Pascal, dynamic
range of 50-500 Pascal; are contained in a waterproof and completely flexible
package, and have material cost less than $10 per sensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04589</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Hechang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Weiqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure Induced Stripe-order Antiferromagnetism and First-order Phase
  Transition in FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures. This paper has been accepted by Physical Review
  Letters</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 237001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.237001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To elucidate the magnetic structure and the origin of the nematicity in FeSe,
we perform a high-pressure $^{77}$Se NMR study on FeSe single crystals. We find
a suppression of the structural transition temperature with pressure up to
about 2 GPa from the anisotropy of the Knight shift. Above 2 GPa, a
stripe-order antiferromagnetism that breaks the spatial four-fold rotational
symmetry is determined by the NMR spectra under different field orientations
and with temperatures down to 50 mK. The magnetic phase transition is revealed
to be first-order type, implying the existence of a concomitant structural
transition via a spin-lattice coupling. Stripe-type spin fluctuations are
observed at high temperatures, and remain strong with pressure. These results
provide clear evidences for strong coupling between nematicity and magnetism in
FeSe, and therefore support a universal scenario of magnetic driven nematicity
in iron-based superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00248</id><created>2016-04-01</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roma</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustingorry</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gleiser</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonequilibrium dynamics of the three-dimensional Edwards-Anderson
  spin-glass model with Gaussian couplings: Strong heterogeneities and the
  backbone picture</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2016) 89: 259</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70414-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically study the three-dimensional Edwards-Anderson model with
Gaussian couplings, focusing on the heterogeneities arising in its
nonequilibrium dynamics. Results are analyzed in terms of the backbone picture,
which links strong dynamical heterogeneities to spatial heterogeneities
emerging from the correlation of local rigidity of the bond network. Different
two-times quantities as the flipping time distribution and the correlation and
response functions, are evaluated over the full system and over high- and
low-rigidity regions. We find that the nonequilibrium dynamics of the model is
highly correlated to spatial heterogeneities. Also, we observe a similar
physical behavior to that previously found in the Edwards-Anderson model with a
bimodal (discrete) bond distribution. Namely, the backbone behaves as the main
structure that supports the spin-glass phase, within which a sort of
domain-growth process develops, while the complement remains in a paramagnetic
phase, even below the critical temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00762</id><created>2016-04-04</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Hayafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sano</keyname><forenames>Yukie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takayasu</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takayasu</keyname><forenames>Misako</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical properties of fluctuations of time series representing the
  appearance of words in nationwide blog data and their applications: An
  example of observations and the modelling of fluctuation scalings of
  nonstationary time series</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To elucidate the non-trivial empirical statistical properties of fluctuations
of a typical non-steady time series representing the appearance of words in
blogs, we investigated approximately five billion Japanese blogs over a period
of six years and analyse some corresponding mathematical models. First, we
introduce a solvable non-steady extension of the random diffusion model, which
can be deduced by modelling the behaviour of heterogeneous random bloggers.
Next, we deduce theoretical expressions for both the temporal and ensemble
fluctuation scalings of this model, and demonstrate that these expressions can
reproduce all empirical scalings over eight orders of magnitude. Furthermore,
we show that the model can reproduce other statistical properties of time
series representing the appearance of words in blogs, such as functional forms
of the probability density and correlations in the total number of blogs. As an
application, we quantify the abnormality of special nationwide events by
measuring the fluctuation scalings of 1771 basic adjectives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03048</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Norman</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Herbertsmithite and the Search for the Quantum Spin Liquid</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>colloquium article for RMP; v4 - final version</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Mod. Phys. 88, 041002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/RevModPhys.88.041002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum spin liquids form a novel class of matter where, despite the
existence of strong exchange interactions, spins do not order down to the
lowest measured temperature. Typically, these occur in lattices that act to
frustrate the appearance of magnetism. In two dimensions, the classic example
is the kagome lattice composed of corner sharing triangles. There are a variety
of minerals whose transition metal ions form such a lattice. Hence, a number of
them have been studied, and were then subsequently synthesized in order to
obtain more pristine samples. Of particular note was the report in 2005 by Dan
Nocera's group of the synthesis of herbertsmithite, composed of a lattice of
copper ions sitting on a kagome lattice, which indeed does not order down to
the lowest measured temperature despite the existence of a large exchange
interaction of 17 meV. Over the past decade, this material has been extensively
studied, yielding a number of intriguing surprises that have in turn motivated
a resurgence of interest in the theoretical study of the spin 1/2 Heisenberg
model on a kagome lattice. In this colloquium article, I will review these
developments, and then discuss potential future directions, both experimental
and theoretical, as well as the challenge of doping these materials with the
hope that this could lead to the discovery of novel topological and
superconducting phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05093</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum entropy derived from first principles</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Final version to be published</comments><msc-class>81P15, 47A63</msc-class><journal-ref>J Stat Phys (2016) 165:799-808</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1651-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most fundamental properties of quantum entropy are derived by considering
the union of two ensembles. We discuss the limits these properties put on an
entropy measure and obtain that they uniquely determine the form of the entropy
functional up to normalisation. In particular, the result implies that all
other properties of quantum entropy may be derived from these first principles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08032</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-11-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>dS</keyname><forenames>U. Camara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>A. L. Alves</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sotkov</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scale Factor Duality for Conformal Cyclic Cosmologies</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>v3; 41 pages; Sect.6 extended by discussion of scale factor duality
  properties of the adiabatic fluctuations; references added; to appear in JHEP</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The scale factor duality is a symmetry of dilaton gravity which is known to
lead to pre-big-bang cosmologies. A conformal time version of the scale factor
duality (SFD) was recently implemented as a UV/IR symmetry between decelerated
and accelerated phases of the post-big-bang evolution within Einstein gravity
coupled to a scalar field. The problem investigated in the present paper
concerns the employment of the conformal time SFD methods to the construction
of pre-big-bang and cyclic extensions of these models. We demonstrate that each
big-bang model gives rise to two qualitatively different pre-big-bang
evolutions: a contraction/expansion SFD model and Penrose's Conformal Cyclic
Cosmology (CCC). A few examples of SFD symmetric cyclic universes involving
certain gauged K\&quot;ahler sigma models minimally coupled to Einstein gravity are
studied. We also describe the specific SFD features of the thermodynamics and
the conditions for validity of the generalized second law in the case of
Gauss-Bonnet (GB) extension of these selected CCC models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08366</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Awata</keyname><forenames>Hidetoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanno</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Takuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohkubo</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenkevich</keyname><forenames>Yegor</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit examples of DIM constraints for network matrix models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>46 pages</comments><report-no>FIAN/TD-09/16; IITP/TH-06/16; ITEP/TH-08/16; INR-TH-2016-011</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, 07 (2016) 1-67</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dotsenko-Fateev and Chern-Simons matrix models, which describe Nekrasov
functions for SYM theories in different dimensions, are all incorporated into
network matrix models with the hidden Ding-Iohara-Miki (DIM) symmetry. This
lifting is especially simple for what we call balanced networks. Then, the Ward
identities (known under the names of Virasoro/W-constraints or loop equations
or regularity condition for qq-characters) are also promoted to the DIM level,
where they all become corollaries of a single identity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04316</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-10-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#x141;&#x105;cki</keyname><forenames>Mateusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damski</keyname><forenames>Bogdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakrzewski</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author></authors><title>Locating the quantum critical point of the Bose-Hubbard model through
  singularities of simple observables</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, rewritten title, abstract &amp; introduction</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 38340 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the critical point of the two-dimensional Bose-Hubbard model can
be easily found through studies of either on-site atom number fluctuations or
the nearest-neighbor two-point correlation function (the expectation value of
the tunnelling operator). Our strategy to locate the critical point is based on
the observation that the derivatives of these observables with respect to the
parameter that drives the superfluid-Mott insulator transition are singular at
the critical point in the thermodynamic limit. Performing the quantum Monte
Carlo simulations of the two-dimensional Bose-Hubbard model, we show that this
technique leads to the accurate determination of the position of its critical
point. Our results can be easily extended to the three-dimensional Bose-Hubbard
model and different Hubbard-like models. They provide a simple
experimentally-relevant way of locating critical points in various cold atomic
lattice systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05873</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leite</keyname><forenames>L. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucena</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potiguar</keyname><forenames>F. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>W. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Depletion forces on circular and elliptical obstacles induced by active
  matter</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, Accepted to Physical Review E (APS)</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Depletion forces exerted by self-propelled particles on circular and
elliptical passive objects are studied using numerical simulations. We show
that a bath of active particles can induce repulsive and attractive forces
which are sensitive to the shape and orientation of the passive objects (either
horizontal or vertical ellipses). The resultant force on the passive objects
due to the active particles is studied as a function of the shape and
orientation of the passive objects, magnitude of the angular noise, distance
between the passive objects. By increasing the distance between obstacles the
magnitude of the repulsive depletion force increases, as long as such a
distance is less than one active particle diameter. For longer distances, the
magnitude of the force always decrease with increasing distance. We also found
that attractive forces may arise for vertical ellipses at high enough area
fraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09694</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Becattini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>U. Florence</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Steinheimer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>FIAS Frankfurt</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stock</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>U. Frankfurt</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bleicher</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>FIAS Frankfurt</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hadronization conditions in relativistic nuclear collisions and the QCD
  pseudo-critical line</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures. Minor corrections, version published in PLB</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the reconstructed hadronization conditions in relativistic nuclear
collisions in the nucleon-nucleon centre-of-mass energy range 4.7-2760 GeV in
terms of temperature and baryon-chemical potential with lattice QCD
calculations, by using hadronic multiplicities. We obtain hadronization
temperatures and baryon chemical potentials with a fit to measured
multiplicities by correcting for the effect of post-hadronization rescattering.
The post-hadronization modification factors are calculated by means of a
coupled hydrodynamical-transport model simulation under the same conditions of
approximate isothermal and isochemical decoupling as assumed in the statistical
hadronization model fits to the data. The fit quality is considerably better
than without rescattering corrections, as already found in previous work. The
curvature of the obtained &quot;true&quot; hadronization pseudo-critical line kappa is
found to be 0.0048 +- 0.0026, in agreement with lattice QCD estimates; the
pseudo-critical temperature at vanishing mu_B is found to be 164.3+-1.8 MeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00457</id><created>2016-06-01</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Masnadi</keyname><forenames>Naeem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duncan</keyname><forenames>James H.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Generation of Gravity-Capillary Solitary Waves by a Pressure Source
  Moving at a Trans-critical Speed</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>27 pages, 21 Figures, Submitted to Journal of Fluid Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mech. 810 (2017) 448-474</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.658</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unsteady response of a water free surface to a localized pressure source
moving at constant speed $U$ in the range $0.95c_\mathrm{min} \lesssim U \leq
1.02 c_\mathrm{min}$, where $c_\mathrm{min}$ is the minimum phase speed of
linear gravity-capillary waves in deep water, is investigated through
experiments and numerical simulations. This unsteady response state, which
consists of a V-shaped pattern behind the source and features periodic shedding
of pairs of depressions from the tips of the V, was first observed
qualitatively by Diorio et al. (Phys. Rev. Let., 103, 214502, 2009) and called
state III. In the present investigation, cinematic shadowgraph and
refraction-based techniques are utilized to measure the temporal evolution of
the free surface deformation pattern downstream of the source as it moves along
a towing tank, while numerical simulations of the model equation described by
Cho et al. (J. Fluid Mech., 672, 288-306, 2011) are used to extend the
experimental results over longer times than are possible in the experiments.
From the experiments, it is found that the speed-amplitude characteristics and
the shape of the depressions are nearly the same as those of the freely
propagating gravity-capillary lumps of inviscid potential theory. The decay
rate of the depressions is measured from their height-time characteristics,
which are well fitted by an exponential decay law with an order 1 decay
constant. It is found that the shedding period of the depression pairs
decreases with increasing source strength and speed. As the source speed
approaches $c_\mathrm{min}$, this period tends to about 1~s for all source
magnitudes. At the low-speed boundary of state III, a new response with
unsteady asymmetric shedding of depressions is found. This response is also
predicted by the model equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06169</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magain</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauret</keyname><forenames>Cl&#xe9;mentine</forenames></author></authors><title>Variable time flow as an alternative to dark energy</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to an error in
  equation 2.5</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time is a parameter playing a central role in our most fundamental modelling
of natural laws. Relativity theory shows that the comparison of times measured
by different clocks depends on their relative motions and on the strength of
the gravitational field in which they are embedded. In standard cosmology, the
time parameter is the one measured by fundamental clocks, i.e. clocks at rest
with respect to the expanding space. This proper time is assumed to flow at a
constant rate throughout the whole history of the Universe. We make the
alternative hypothesis that the rate at which cosmological time flows depends
on the global geometric curvature the Universe. Using a simple one-parameter
model for the relation between proper time and curvature, we build a
cosmological model that fits the Type Ia Supernovae data (the best cosmological
standard candles) without the need for dark energy nor probably exotic dark
matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00193</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Atri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enberg</keyname><forenames>Rikard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>Yu Seon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reno</keyname><forenames>Mary Hall</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarcevic</keyname><forenames>Ina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stasto</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Prompt atmospheric neutrino fluxes: perturbative QCD models and nuclear
  effects</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>61 pages, 25 figures, 11 tables</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1611 (2016) 167</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)167</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate the prompt atmospheric neutrino flux at high energies using three
different frameworks for calculating the heavy quark production cross section
in QCD: NLO perturbative QCD, $k_T$ factorization including low-$x$
resummation, and the dipole model including parton saturation. We use QCD
parameters, the value for the charm quark mass and the range for the
factorization and renormalization scales that provide the best description of
the total charm cross section measured at fixed target experiments, at RHIC and
at LHC. Using these parameters we calculate differential cross sections for
charm and bottom production and compare with the latest data on forward charm
meson production from LHCb at $7$ TeV and at $13$ TeV, finding good agreement
with the data. In addition, we investigate the role of nuclear shadowing by
including nuclear parton distribution functions (PDF) for the target air
nucleus using two different nuclear PDF schemes. Depending on the scheme used,
we find the reduction of the flux due to nuclear effects varies from $10\%$ to
$50 \%$ at the highest energies. Finally, we compare our results with the
IceCube limit on the prompt neutrino flux, which is already providing valuable
information about some of the QCD models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00408</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chwalla</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danzmann</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barranco</keyname><forenames>Germ&#xe1;n Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fitzsimons</keyname><forenames>Ewan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerberding</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinzel</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Killow</keyname><forenames>Christian J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lieser</keyname><forenames>Maike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perreur-Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robertson</keyname><forenames>David I</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>S&#xf6;nke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwarze</keyname><forenames>Thomas S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tr&#xf6;bs</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwetz</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>Design and construction of an optical test bed for LISA imaging systems
  and tilt-to-length coupling</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Classical and Quantum Gravity, 33(24):245015, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/24/245015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA) is a future space-based
interferometric gravitational-wave detector consisting of three spacecraft in a
triangular configuration. The interferometric measurements of path length
changes between satellites will be performed on optical benches in the
satellites. Angular misalignments of the interfering beams couple into the
length measurement and represent a significant noise source. Imaging systems
will be used to reduce this tilt-to-length coupling.
  We designed and constructed an optical test bed to experimentally investigate
tilt-to-length coupling. It consists of two separate structures, a minimal
optical bench and a telescope simulator. The minimal optical bench comprises
the science interferometer where the local laser is interfered with light from
a remote spacecraft. In our experiment, a simulated version of this received
beam is generated on the telescope simulator. The telescope simulator provides
a tilting beam, a reference interferometer and an additional static beam as a
phase reference. The tilting beam can either be a flat-top beam or a Gaussian
beam. We avoid tilt-to-length coupling in the reference interferometer by using
a small photo diode placed at an image of the beam rotation point. We show that
the test bed is operational with an initial measurement of tilt-to-length
coupling without imaging systems.
  Furthermore, we show the design of two different imaging systems whose
performance will be investigated in future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01240</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nascimento</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the radiative corrections in the Horava-Lifshitz z=2 QED</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, minor corrections</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B764, 277 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate one-loop contributions to the two and three point spinor-vector
functions in z=2 Horava-Lifshitz QED. This allows us to obtain the anomalous
magnetic moment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04512</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Carelli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiarello</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torrioli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellano</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>THz Discrimination of materials: demonstration of a bioinspired
  apparatus based on metasurfaces selective filters</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, to be submitted to Infrared Milli Terahz Waves</comments><doi>10.1007/s10762-016-0343-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an apparatus for terahertz fingerprint discrimination of materials
designed to be fast, simple, compact and economical in order to be suitable for
preliminary on-field analysis. The system working principles, bioinspired by
the human vision of colors, are based on the use of microfabricated
metamaterials selective filters and of a very compact optics based on metallic
ellipsoidal mirrors in air. We experimentally demonstrate the operation of the
apparatus in discriminating simple substances such as salt, staple foods and
grease in an accurate and reproducible manner. We present the system and the
obtained results and discuss issues and possible developments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06547</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Hsin-Chia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lingfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author></authors><title>Second Stop and Sbottom Searches with a Stealth Stop</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>46 pages, 9 figures, updated experimental constraints and benchmark
  points after the ICHEP2016 data, published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1611 (2016) 181</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)181</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The top squarks (stops) may be the most wanted particles after the Higgs
boson discovery. The searches for the lightest stop have put strong constraints
on its mass. However, there is still a search gap in the low mass region if the
spectrum of the stop and the lightest neutralino is compressed. In that case,
it may be easier to look for the second stop since naturalness requires both
stops to be close to the weak scale. The current experimental searches for the
second stop are based on the simplified model approach with the decay modes
$\tilde{t}_2 \to \tilde{t}_1 Z$ and $\tilde{t}_2 \to \tilde{t}_1 h$. However,
in a realistic supersymmetric spectrum there is always a sbottom lighter than
the second stop, hence the decay patterns are usually more complicated than the
simplified model assumptions. In particular, there are often large branching
ratios of the decays $\tilde{t}_2 \to \tilde{b}_1 W$ and $\tilde{b}_1 \to
\tilde{t}_1 W$ as long as they are open. The decay chains can be even more
complex if there are intermediate states of additional charginos and
neutralinos in the decays. By studying several MSSM benchmark models at the 14
TeV LHC, we point out the importance of the multi-$W$ final states in the
second stop and the sbottom searches, such as the same-sign dilepton and
multilepton signals, aside from the traditional search modes. The observed
same-sign dilepton excesses at LHC Run 1 and Run 2 may be explained by some of
our benchmark models. We also suggest that the vector boson tagging and a new
kinematic variable may help to suppress the backgrounds and increase the signal
significance for some search channels. Due to the complex decay patterns and
lack of the dominant decay channels, the best reaches likely require a
combination of various search channels at the LHC for the second stop and the
lightest sbottom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06975</id><created>2016-07-23</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of electroweak production of a W boson and two forward jets
  in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added journal reference and DOI. All
  the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SMP-13-012/</comments><report-no>CMS-SMP-13-012, CERN-EP-2016-093</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 11 (2016) 147</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)147</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement is presented of the cross section for the electroweak
production of a W boson in association with two jets in proton-proton
collisions at a center-of-mass energy of 8 TeV. The data set was collected with
the CMS detector and corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 19.3 inverse
femtobarns. The measured fiducial cross section for W bosons decaying to
electrons or muons and for pT(j1) &gt; 60 GeV, pT(j2) &gt; 50 GeV, |eta(j)| &lt; 4.7,
and m(jj) &gt; 1000 GeV is 0.42 +/- 0.04 (stat) +/- 0.09 (syst) +/- 0.01 (lumi)
pb. This result is consistent with the standard model leading-order prediction
of 0.50 +/- 0.02 (scale) +/- 0.02 (PDF) pb obtained with MADGRAPH5_aMC@NLO 2.1
interfaced to PYTHIA 6.4. This is the first cross section measurement for this
process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07022</id><created>2016-07-24</created><updated>2016-11-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsukamoto</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong deflection limit analysis and gravitational lensing of an Ellis
  wormhole</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages, 1 figure, minor correction, title changed, accepted for
  publication in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 124001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.124001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observations of gravitational lenses in strong gravitational fields give us a
clue to understanding dark compact objects. In this paper, we extend a method
to obtain a deflection angle in a strong deflection limit provided by Bozza
[Phys. Rev. D 66, 103001 (2002)] to apply to ultrastatic spacetimes. We also
discuss on the order of an error term in the deflection angle. Using the
improved method, we consider gravitational lensing by an Ellis wormhole, which
is an ultrastatic wormhole of the Morris-Thorne class.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08786</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonetti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filho</keyname><forenames>Lu&#xed;s R. dos Santos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helay&#xeb;l-Neto</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spallicci</keyname><forenames>Alessandro D. A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive photons from Super and Lorentz symmetry breaking</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Lett B, 764, 203 (2017). Final title:Effective photon mass
  from Super and Lorentz symmetry breaking</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of Standard Model Extensions (SMEs), we analyse four general
classes of Super Symmetry (SuSy) and Lorentz Symmetry (LoSy) breaking, leading
to {observable} imprints at our energy scales. The photon dispersion relations
show a non-Maxwellian behaviour for the CPT (Charge-Parity-Time reversal
symmetry) odd and even sectors. The group velocities exhibit also a directional
dependence with respect to the breaking background vector (odd CPT) or tensor
(even CPT). In the former sector, the group velocity may decay following an
inverse squared frequency behaviour. Thus, we extract a massive and gauge
invariant Carroll-Field-Jackiw photon term in the Lagrangian and show that the
mass is proportional to the breaking vector. The latter is estimated by ground
measurements and leads to a photon mass upper limit of $10^{-19}$ eV or $2
\times 10^{-55}$ kg and thereby to a potentially measurable delay at low radio
frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02162</id><created>2016-08-06</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Byrnes</keyname><forenames>Christian T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cort&#xea;s</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liddle</keyname><forenames>Andrew R</forenames></author></authors><title>Curvaton scenarios with inflaton decays into curvatons</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages PDFLatex with 6 incorporated figures. Minor updates to match
  PRD published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 063525 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.063525</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the possible decay of the inflaton into curvaton particles during
reheating and analyse its effect on curvaton scenarios. Typical decay curvatons
are initially relativistic then become non-relativistic, changing the
background history of the Universe. We show that this change to the background
is the only way in which observational predictions of the scenario are
modified. Moreover, once the required amplitude of perturbations is fixed by
observation there are no signatures of such decays in other cosmological
observables. The decay curvatons can prevent the Universe from becoming
dominated by the curvaton condensate, making it impossible to match
observations in parts of parameter space. This constrains the branching ratio
of the inflaton to curvaton to be less than of order $0.1$ typically. If the
branching ratio is below about $10^{-4}$ it has negligible impact on the model
parameter space and can be ignored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08308</id><created>2016-08-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Mendl</keyname><forenames>Christian B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Jianfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukkarinen</keyname><forenames>Jani</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermalization of oscillator chains with onsite anharmonicity and
  comparison with kinetic theory</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform microscopic molecular dynamics simulations of particle chains with
an onsite anharmonicity to study relaxation of spatially homogeneous states to
equilibrium, and directly compare the simulations with the corresponding
Boltzmann-Peierls kinetic theory. The Wigner function serves as common
interface between the microscopic and kinetic level. We demonstrate
quantitative agreement after an initial transient time interval. In particular,
besides energy conservation, we observe the additional quasi-conservation of
the phonon density, defined via an ensemble average of the related microscopic
field variables and exactly conserved by the kinetic equations. On
super-kinetic time scales, density quasi-conservation is lost while energy
remains conserved, and we find evidence for eventual relaxation of the density
to its canonical ensemble value. However, the precise mechanism remains unknown
and is not captured by the Boltzmann-Peierls equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08858</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karlovets</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing phase of a scattering amplitude beyond the plane-wave
  approximation</title><categories>hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure; the effect persists for relativistic energies</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 116 (2016) 31001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/31001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within a plane-wave approach, a number of scattering events in a collision is
insensitive to a general phase of a transition amplitude, although this phase
is extremely important for a number of problems, especially in hadronic
physics. In reality the particles are better described as wave packets, and
here we show that the observables grow dependent upon this phase if one lays
aside the simplified plane-wave model. We discuss two methods for probing how
the Coulomb- and hadronic phases change with a transferred momentum $t$, either
by colliding two beams at a non-vanishing impact-parameter or by employing such
novel states as the vortex particles carrying orbital angular momentum or the
Airy beams. For electron-electron collision, the phase contribution to a cross
section can reach the values higher than $10^{-4} -- 10^{-3}$ for well-focused
beams with energies of hundreds of keV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00078</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carro</keyname><forenames>Adri&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toral</keyname><forenames>Ra&#xfa;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miguel</keyname><forenames>Maxi San</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupled dynamics of node and link states in complex networks: A model
  for language competition</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.SI nlin.AO</categories><comments>21 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 113056 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/11/113056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by language competition processes, we present a model of coupled
evolution of node and link states. In particular, we focus on the interplay
between the use of a language and the preference or attitude of the speakers
towards it, which we model, respectively, as a property of the interactions
between speakers (a link state) and as a property of the speakers themselves (a
node state). Furthermore, we restrict our attention to the case of two socially
equivalent languages and to socially inspired network topologies based on a
mechanism of triadic closure. As opposed to most of the previous literature,
where language extinction is an inevitable outcome of the dynamics, we find a
broad range of possible asymptotic configurations, which we classify as: frozen
extinction states, frozen coexistence states, and dynamically trapped
coexistence states. Moreover, metastable coexistence states with very long
survival times and displaying a non-trivial dynamics are found to be abundant.
Interestingly, a system size scaling analysis shows, on the one hand, that the
probability of language extinction vanishes exponentially for increasing system
sizes and, on the other hand, that the time scale of survival of the
non-trivial dynamical metastable states increases linearly with the size of the
system. Thus, non-trivial dynamical coexistence is the only possible outcome
for large enough systems. Finally, we show how this coexistence is
characterized by one of the languages becoming clearly predominant while the
other one becomes increasingly confined to &quot;ghetto-like&quot; structures: small
groups of bilingual speakers arranged in triangles, with a strong preference
for the minority language, and using it for their intra-group interactions
while they switch to the predominant language for communications with the rest
of the population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01591</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gudnason</keyname><forenames>Sven Bjarke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Baiyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Nana</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Skyrme model with the loosely bound potential</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>RevTeX: 33 pages, 14 figures; V2: comments and references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 125004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.125004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a generalization of the loosely bound Skyrme model which consists of
the Skyrme model with a sixth-order derivative term - motivated by its
fluid-like properties - and the second-order loosely bound potential -
motivated by lowering the classical binding energies of higher-charged
Skyrmions. We use the rational map approximation for the Skyrmion of
topological charge B=4, calculate the binding energy of the latter and estimate
the systematic error in using this approximation. In the parameter space that
we can explore within the rational map approximation, we find classical binding
energies as low as 1.8% and once taking into account the contribution from
spin-isospin quantization we obtain binding energies as low as 5.3%. We also
calculate the contribution from the sixth-order derivative term to the electric
charge density and axial coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01626</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pilachowski</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinkle</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chlorine Abundances in Cool Stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>22 pages, 10 figures, Accepted for publication in The Astronomical
  Journal</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-6256/152/6/196</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chlorine abundances are reported in 15 evolved giants and one M dwarf in the
solar neighborhood. The Cl abundance was measured using the vibration-rotation
1-0 P8 line of H$^{35}$Cl at 3.69851 $\mu$m. The high resolution L-band spectra
were observed using the Phoenix infrared spectrometer on the Kitt Peak Mayall
4m telescope. The average [$^{35}$Cl/Fe] abundance in stars with
--0.72$&lt;$[Fe/H]$&lt;$0.20 is [$^{35}$Cl/Fe]=(--0.10$\pm$0.15) dex. The mean
difference between the [$^{35}$Cl/Fe] ratios measured in our stars and chemical
evolution model values is (0.16$\pm$0.15) dex. The [$^{35}$Cl/Ca] ratio has an
offset of $\sim$0.35 dex above model predictions suggesting chemical evolution
models are under producing Cl at the high metallicity range. Abundances of C,
N, O, Si, and Ca were also measured in our spectral region and are consistent
with F and G dwarfs. The Cl versus O abundances from our sample match Cl
abundances measured in planetary nebula and \ion{H}{2} regions. In one star
where both H$^{35}$Cl and H$^{37}$Cl could be measured, a $^{35}$Cl/$^{37}$Cl
isotope ratio of 2.2$\pm$0.4 was found, consistent with values found in the
Galactic ISM and predicted chemical evolution models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02218</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kleinert</keyname><forenames>Michaela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahl</keyname><forenames>M. E. Gold</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeson</keyname><forenames>Scott D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the Yb I $^1S_0 - ^1P_1$ transition frequency at 399 nm
  using an optical frequency comb</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>http://journals.aps.org/pra/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevA.94.052511</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 052511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.052511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the frequency of the Yb I $^1S_0 - ^1P_1$ transition at 399 nm
using an optical frequency comb. Although this transition was measured
previously using an optical transfer cavity [D. Das et al., Phys. Rev. A 72,
032506 (2005)], recent work has uncovered significant errors in that method. We
compare our result of 751 526 533.49 $\pm$ 0.33 MHz for the Yb-174 isotope with
those from the literature and discuss observed differences. We verify the
correctness of our method by measuring the frequencies of well-known
transitions in Rb and Cs, and by demonstrating proper control of systematic
errors in both laser metrology and atomic spectroscopy. We also demonstrate the
effect of quantum interference due to hyperfine structure in a divalent atomic
system and present isotope shift measurements for all stable isotopes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02435</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Glasser</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirac</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sierra</keyname><forenames>Germ&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Anne E. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice effects on Laughlin wave functions and parent Hamiltonians</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate lattice effects on wave functions that are lattice analogues
of bosonic and fermionic Laughlin wave functions with number of particles per
flux $\nu=1/q$ in the Landau levels. These wave functions are defined
analytically on lattices with $\mu$ particles per lattice site, where $\mu$ may
be different than $\nu$. We give numerical evidence that these states have the
same topological properties as the corresponding continuum Laughlin states for
different values of $q$ and for different fillings $\mu$. These states define,
in particular, particle-hole symmetric lattice Fractional Quantum Hall states
when the lattice is half-filled. On the square lattice it is observed that for
$q\leq 4$ this particle-hole symmetric state displays the topological
properties of the continuum Laughlin state at filling fraction $\nu=1/q$, while
for larger $q$ there is a transition towards long-range ordered
anti-ferromagnets. This effect does not persist if the lattice is deformed from
a square to a triangular lattice, or on the Kagome lattice, in which case the
topological properties of the state are recovered. We then show that changing
the number of particles while keeping the expression of these wave functions
identical gives rise to edge states that have the same correlations in the bulk
as the reference lattice Laughlin states but a different density at the edge.
We derive an exact parent Hamiltonian for which all these edge states are
ground states with different number of particles. In addition this Hamiltonian
admits the reference lattice Laughlin state as its unique ground state of
filling factor $1/q$. Parent Hamiltonians are also derived for the lattice
Laughlin states at other fillings of the lattice, when $\mu\leq 1/q$ or
$\mu\geq 1-1/q$ and when $q=4$ also at half-filling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02481</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belloni</keyname><forenames>Diogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giersz</keyname><forenames>Mirek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rocha-Pinto</keyname><forenames>Helio J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leigh</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Askar</keyname><forenames>Abbas</forenames></author></authors><title>MOCCA-SURVEY database I. Accreting white dwarf binary systems in
  globular clusters -- II. Cataclysmic variables -- progenitors and population
  at birth</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables; minor changes made to the text,
  accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second in a series of papers associated with cataclysmic
variables (CVs) and related objects, formed in a suite of simulations for
globular cluster evolution performed with the MOCCA Monte Carlo code. We study
the properties of our simulated CV populations throughout the entire cluster
evolution. We find that dynamics extends the range of binary CV progenitor
properties, causing CV formation from binary progenitors that would otherwise
not become CVs. The CV formation rate in our simulations can be separated into
two regimes: an initial burst ($\lesssim$ 1 Gyr) connected with the formation
of the most massive white dwarfs, followed by a nearly constant formation rate.
This result holds for all models regardless of the adopted initial conditions,
even when most CVs form dynamically. Given the cluster age-dependence of CV
properties, we argue that direct comparisons to observed Galactic field CVs
could be misleading, since cluster CVs can be up to 4 times older than their
field counterparts. Our results also illustrate that, due mainly to unstable
mass transfer, some CVs that form in our simulations are destroyed before the
present-day. Finally, some field CVs might have originated from globular
clusters, as found in our simulations, although the fraction of such escapers
should be small relative to the entire Galactic field CV population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05120</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krichever</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilyina</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Triangular reductions of 2D Toda hierarchy</title><categories>math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>Misprints are corrected,26 pages, Latex</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New reductions of the 2D Toda equations associated with low-triangular
difference operators are proposed. Their explicit Hamiltonian description is
obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02303</id><created>2016-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retore</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimerman</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Miura and Generalized B\&quot;acklund Transformation for KdV Hierarchy</title><categories>nlin.SI hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 504003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/50/504003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the fact that Miura transformation can be expressed in the form of
gauge transformation connecting the KdV and mKdV equations, we discuss the
derivation of the B\&quot;acklund transformation and its Miura-gauge transformation
connecting both hierarchies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08324</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jani&#x107;evi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Sanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurson</keyname><forenames>Lasse</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe5;l&#xf8;y</keyname><forenames>Knut J&#xf8;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santucci</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alava</keyname><forenames>Mikko J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inter-event correlations from avalanches hiding below the detection
  threshold</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, Supplemental Material as an ancillary file,
  accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 230601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.230601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerous systems ranging from deformation of materials to earthquakes exhibit
bursty dynamics, which consist of a sequence of events with a broad event size
distribution. Very often these events are observed to be temporally correlated
or clustered, evidenced by power-law distributed waiting times separating two
consecutive activity bursts. We show how such inter-event correlations arise
simply because of a finite detection threshold, created by the limited
sensitivity of the measurement apparatus, or used to subtract background
activity or noise from the activity signal. Data from crack propagation
experiments and numerical simulations of a non-equilibrium crack line model
demonstrate how thresholding leads to correlated bursts of activity by
separating the avalanche events into sub-avalanches. The resulting temporal
sub-avalanche correlations are well-described by our general scaling
description of thresholding-induced correlations in crackling noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09360</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Jungfleisch</keyname><forenames>Matthias B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Junjia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Wanjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearson</keyname><forenames>John E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novosad</keyname><forenames>Valentine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>Insulating nanomagnets driven by spin torque</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b02794</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic insulators, such as yttrium iron garnet (Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$), are
ideal materials for ultra-low power spintronics applications due to their low
energy dissipation and efficient spin current generation and transmission.
Recently, it has been realized that spin dynamics can be driven very
effectively in micrometer-sized Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$/Pt heterostructures by
spin-Hall effects. We demonstrate here the excitation and detection of spin
dynamics in Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$/Pt nanowires by spin-torque ferromagnetic
resonance. The nanowires defined via electron-beam lithography are fabricated
by conventional room temperature sputtering deposition on Gd$_3$Ga$_5$O$_{12 }$
substrates and lift-off. We observe field-like and anti-damping-like torques
acting on the magnetization precession, which are due to simultaneous
excitation by Oersted fields and spin-Hall torques. The Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$/Pt
nanowires are thoroughly examined over a wide frequency and power range. We
observe a large change in the resonance field at high microwave powers, which
is attributed to a decreasing effective magnetization due to microwave
absorption. These heating effects are much more pronounced in the investigated
nanostructures than in comparable micron-sized samples. By comparing different
nanowire widths, the importance of geometrical confinements for magnetization
dynamics becomes evident: quantized spin-wave modes across the width of the
wires are observed in the spectra. Our results are the first stepping stones
toward the realization of integrated magnonic logic devices based on
insulators, where nanomagnets play an essential role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09563</id><created>2016-10-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Habibi</keyname><forenames>Asiyeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbassi</keyname><forenames>Shahram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shadmehri</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact analytical solutions for ADAFs</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>to appear in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 464, 5028 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2817</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain two-dimensional exact analytic solutions for the structure of the
hot accretion flows without wind. We assume that the only non-zero component of
the stress tensor is $T_{r\varphi}$. Furthermore we assume that the value of
viscosity coefficient $\alpha$ varies with $\theta$. We find radially
self-similar solutions and compare them with the numerical and the analytical
solutions already studied in the literature. The no-wind solution obtained in
this paper may be applied to the nuclei of some cool-core clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02799</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wei-Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wangyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Gui-Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Shuangchun</forenames></author></authors><title>Interfacial interaction in monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides
  (MX2)/metal oxide heterostructures and its effects on electronic and optical
  properties: The case of MX2/CeO2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Express, 10, 011201, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/APEX.10.011201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides (MX2)/metal oxide
heterostructures have shown unique physical properties, making them promising
materials for various applications ranging from photocatalysis to solar energy
conversion. Understanding the interfacial interactions is highly desirable for
designing these heterostructures having excellent performance. Here we
systematically study the interfacial interaction in monolayer MX2 (M=Mo, W;
X=S, Se)/CeO2 heterostructures and its effects on electronic and optical
properties by density functional theory. It is found that the interfacial
interaction in the MX2/CeO2 depends predominantly on the chalcogen (X) element.
Particularly, the band gap variation and important electronic states at
conduction band minimum or valence band maximum of the heterostructures are
determined by the strength of interfacial interaction. The MX2/CeO2
heterostructures with the same chalcogen (X) element have similar absorption
spectra from ultraviolet to near-infrared regions. These results suggest that
the chalcogen (X) element is a key factor in tuning the properties of MX2/metal
oxide heterostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03329</id><created>2016-11-10</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Y. -L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional multiple-relaxation-time lattice Boltzmann model for
  convection heat transfer in porous media at the REV scale</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>35 pages,14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a three-dimensional (3D) multiple-relaxation-time (MRT)
lattice Boltzmann (LB) model is presented for convection heat transfer in
porous media at the representative elementary volume (REV) scale. The model is
developed in the framework of the double-distribution-function (DDF) approach:
an MRT-LB model of the density distribution function with the D3Q19 lattice (or
D3Q15 lattice) is proposed to simulate the flow field based on the generalized
non-Darcy model, while an MRT-LB model of the temperature distribution function
with the D3Q7 lattice is proposed to simulate the temperature filed. The
present model is employed to simulate mixed convection flow in a porous channel
and natural convection in a cubical porous cavity. The numerical results
demonstrate the effectiveness and accuracy of the present model in solving 3D
convection heat transfer problems in porous media. The numerical results also
demonstrate that the present model is approximately second-order accuracy in
space. In addition, an enthalpy-based DDF-MRT model for 3D solid-liquid phase
change with convection heat transfer in porous media is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06075</id><created>2016-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Wanas</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Youssef</keyname><forenames>Nabil L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanafy</keyname><forenames>W. El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osman</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Einstein Geometrization Philosophy and Differential Identities in
  PAP-Geometry</title><categories>gr-qc math.DG</categories><comments>LaTeX file, 17 pages, comments and criticism are welcome</comments><msc-class>53B05, 53B20, 53B50, 83C05, 83D05</msc-class><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics, vol. 2016, Article ID 1037849, 8
  pages, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/1037849</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The importance of Einstein's geometrization philosophy, as an alternative to
the least action principle, in constructing general relativity (GR), is
illuminated. The role of differential identities in this philosophy is
clarified. The use of Bianchi identity to write the field equations of GR is
shown. Another similar identity in the absolute parallelism geometry is given.
A more general differential identity in the parameterized absolute parallelism
geometry is derived. Comparison and interrelationships between the above
mentioned identities and their role in constructing field theories are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07037</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gautason</keyname><forenames>Fridrik Freyr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schillo</keyname><forenames>Marjorie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Riet</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Is inflation from unwinding fluxes IIB?</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we argue that the mechanism of unwinding inflation is naturally
present in warped compactifications of type IIB string theory with local
throats. The unwinding of flux is caused by its annihilation against branes.
The resulting inflaton potential is linear with periodic modulations. We
initiate an analysis of the inflationary dynamics and cosmological observables,
which are highly constrained by moduli stabilization. For the simplified model
of single-K\&quot;ahler Calabi-Yau spaces we find that many, though not all of the
consistency constraints can be satisfied. Particularly, in this simple model
geometric constraints are in tension with obtaining the observed amplitude of
the scalar power spectrum. However, we do find 60 efolds of inflation with a
trans-Planckian field excursion which offers the hope that slightly more
complicated models can lead to a fully consistent explicit construction of
large field inflation of this kind.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07342</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawakami</keyname><forenames>Takuto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Light Nodal Lines in FCC Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light cone with the speed of light independent of its wavelength in vacuum
has been known for long time. In the present work, we unveil that in a
face-centered-cubic (fcc) lattice of dielectric spheres novel light cones can
be created over closed loops in momentum space, dubbed as nodal lines (NL), and
that as a consequence of the nontrivial topology of NL interface states with a
drumhead-shaped band structure appear where light can be slowed down
significantly. We discuss that photonic pseudogaps found in previous
experimental and theoretical studies for fcc photonic crystals are consistent
with the present finding of NL. This offers a unique chance to confirm the
existence of NL as a novel topological state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08970</id><created>2016-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear fragmentation induced by low-energy antiprotons within a
  microscopic transport approach</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 064601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.064601</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Within the framework of the Lanzhou quantum molecular dynamics (LQMD)
transport model, the nuclear fragmentation induced by low-energy antiprotons
has been investigated thoroughly. A coalescence approach is developed for
constructing the primary fragments in phase space. The secondary decay process
of the fragments is described by the well-known statistical code. It is found
that the localized energy released in antibaryon-baryon annihilation is
deposited in a nucleus mainly via pion-nucleon collisions, which leads to the
emissions of pre-equilibrium particles, fission, evaporation of nucleons and
light fragments etc. The strangeness exchange reactions dominate the hyperon
production. The averaged mass loss increases with the mass number of target
nucleus. A bump structure in the domain of intermediate mass for heavy targets
appears owing to the contribution of fission fragments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09514</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Muraki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamiya</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koga</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A photon observed by the SEDA-FIB detector on the arrival of the
  gravitational wave</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, presented talk at JSPS in September 016, Miyazaki
  University</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reported a photon detection at the arrival time of the gravitational wave
on December 26th, 2015. According to the LIGO-Virgo collaboration, the
gravitational wave was produced by the merging process of the two black holes.
The merged time was determined at 03:38:53.6 UT on December 26th. At
03:38:54.05 GPS time, one of the detectors of SEDA-FIB on board the
International Space Station (ISS) detected a photon, arriving from the
direction of Corona Australis near the Galactic Bulge (GB). The energy of the
photon was about (35+-7) MeV. A 3.0 sigma level detection of the photon is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09544</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Siyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hongyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronine</keyname><forenames>Dmitri V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tip-enhanced Raman spectroscopic detection of aptamers</title><categories>q-bio.BM physics.bio-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single molecule detection, sequencing and conformational mapping of aptamers
are important for improving medical and biosensing technologies and for better
understanding of biological processes at the molecular level. We obtain
vibrational signals of single aptamers immobilized on gold substrates using
tip-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (TERS). We compare topographic and optical
signals and investigate the fluctuations of the position-dependent TERS
spectra. TERS mapping provides information about the chemical composition and
conformation of aptamers, and paves the way to future single-molecule
label-free sequencing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09667</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monahan</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Na</keyname><forenames>Heechang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchard</keyname><forenames>Chris M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepage</keyname><forenames>G. Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shigemitsu</keyname><forenames>Junko</forenames></author></authors><title>$B_{(s)}\to D_{(s)}$ semileptonic decays with NRQCD-HISQ valence quarks</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>Proceedings of the 34th annual International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory. PoS(LATTICE2016) 298. v2 corrects some minor typographical
  errors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a calculation of the form factors, $f_0$ and $f_+$, for the
$B_{(s)} \to D_{(s)}$ semileptonic decays. Our work uses the MILC $n_f=2+1$
AsqTad configurations with NRQCD and HISQ valence quarks at four values of the
momentum transfer $q^2$. We provide results for the chiral-continuum
extrapolations of the scalar and vector form factors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00274</id><created>2016-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobelev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice of infinite bending-resistant fibers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Multidiscipline Modeling in Materials and Structures Vol. 12 No.
  2, 2016 pp. 397-422</journal-ref><doi>10.1108/MMMS-08-2015-0040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article present the double-periodical lattice made of infinite elastic
fibers that withstand bending and tension. The model describes the elastic
properties of flat periodic structure. With this model the behavior of a
two-dimensional array of infinite fibers is simulated. The material that
contains a row of broken fibers is considered. These broken fibers form the
failure in the material that shapes like a long straight crack. The lattice is
tensioned in the direction, which is orthogonal to the direction of straight
crack. The conditions of fracture of this lattice are investigated. The closed
form expression for the stress in the first unbroken fiber and the expression
for fracture toughness are given. These values are the functions of mechanical
parameters of lattice and tensions in both families of fibers. The closed form
solution demonstrates a notable behavior of the material. Namely, the fracture
behavior of two-dimensional lattice is cardinally depends upon the pre-stress
in the material in the direction, parallel to crack direction. If the tension
in fibers that parallel to the crack direction exists, it stabilizes the crack
growth and makes the load distribution in the unbroken fibers more even. The
two-dimensional lattice behaves in the presence of tension in both directions
similarly to the plane elastic media. The finite length crack assumes the shape
of the elongated elliptic split. Another behavior of lattice occurs if the
fibers, parallel to crack direction, are unstressed. The character of stress
concentration near the crack differs. The load distribution at the crack tip
varies considerably. The first unbroken fiber carries higher load. The crack is
lens-shaped and the crack borders form at the tip the finite angle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00323</id><created>2016-12-01</created><updated>2016-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lepri</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staiano</keyname><forenames>Jacopo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangokoya</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Letouz&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliver</keyname><forenames>Nuria</forenames></author></authors><title>The Tyranny of Data? The Bright and Dark Sides of Data-Driven
  Decision-Making for Social Good</title><categories>cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>preprint version; book chapter to appear in &quot;Transparent Data Mining
  for Big and Small Data&quot;, Studies in Big Data Series, Springer</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unprecedented availability of large-scale human behavioral data is
profoundly changing the world we live in. Researchers, companies, governments,
financial institutions, non-governmental organizations and also citizen groups
are actively experimenting, innovating and adapting algorithmic decision-making
tools to understand global patterns of human behavior and provide decision
support to tackle problems of societal importance. In this chapter, we focus
our attention on social good decision-making algorithms, that is algorithms
strongly influencing decision-making and resource optimization of public goods,
such as public health, safety, access to finance and fair employment. Through
an analysis of specific use cases and approaches, we highlight both the
positive opportunities that are created through data-driven algorithmic
decision-making, and the potential negative consequences that practitioners
should be aware of and address in order to truly realize the potential of this
emergent field. We elaborate on the need for these algorithms to provide
transparency and accountability, preserve privacy and be tested and evaluated
in context, by means of living lab approaches involving citizens. Finally, we
turn to the requirements which would make it possible to leverage the
predictive power of data-driven human behavior analysis while ensuring
transparency, accountability, and civic participation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00440</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bylund</keyname><forenames>Olga Bessidskaia</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling Wt and tWZ production at NLO for ATLAS analyses</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Conference: The 9th International Workshop of Top Quark Physics 2016
  5 pages including title page, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The generation of single top production in the $Wt$ channel at NLO gives rise
to doubly-resonant diagrams that overlap with $t \bar t$, and similarly for
associated production with a $Z$ or Higgs boson. Several methods exist to
remove this overlap, thus avoiding double counting and separating the two
processes. In Diagram Removal 1, the amplitudes of doubly-resonant diagrams are
set to zero, which also removes the interference of $Wt$ with $t \bar t$. If a
measurement is performed in a region where this interference is not negligible,
it would be of interest to take it into account. Another method, Diagram
Subtraction, preserves the interference. However, it relies upon momentum
reshuffling, which introduces uncertainties to the prediction. An alternative
method, Diagram Removal 2, does not involve reshuffling and preserves the
interference by subtracting the amplitude squared of the doubly-resonant
diagrams from the total. The predictions of Diagram Removal 2 from MG5_aMC@NLO
are compared with other predictions for $Wt$ and $tWZ$ production in the
context of analyses at the ATLAS experiment. Implications of using Diagram
Removal 2 are discussed, both for measurements of single top processes and when
$Wt$ or $tWZ$ are treated as a background. Differential distributions are
shown, investigating in what regions the predictions differ the most.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00444</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kiselev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novoselov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagiev</keyname><forenames>E. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Production of quarkonia and doubly heavy baryons in $pp$-collisions with
  duality approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In present work we discuss the production of heavy quarkonia and diquarks in
$pp$-interactions. The aim is to take into account the production of bound
states of quarks originating from independent parton scatterings. This
production is regulated by constraints on the invariant mass of constituents.
Such an approach leads to larger value of the diquark production cross section
than traditional consideration in single parton scattering. This production
mechanism of doubly heavy baryons can sooner be verified by modern experiments
(e.g. LHCb). We also discuss related contributions to double and associated
quarkonium production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00463</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Lobo</keyname><forenames>Matheus P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Edison T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sotomayor</keyname><forenames>Nilo M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Felipe R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chaos in the Y-chromosome evolution?</title><categories>nlin.CD physics.bio-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Y-chromosome degeneration is still an intriguing mechanism and comprises
the very origin of sex. We present a coupled version of the well known logistic
map and the logistic equation describing the evolution of XY chromosomes.
Although chaos was found in X, Y chromosomes do not evolve chaotically. A
mathematical constraint is shown as the responsible for this behaviour. In
addition, analytical solutions are presented for the differential equations
herein.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00466</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Curtin</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meade</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramani</keyname><forenames>Harikrishnan</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Resummation and Phase Transitions</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>38 pages, 6 figures, plus appendix and references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The consequences of phase transitions in the early universe are becoming
testable in a variety of manners, from colliders physics to gravitational wave
astronomy. In particular one phase transition we know of, the Electroweak Phase
Transition (EWPT), could potentially be first order in BSM scenarios and
testable in the near future. If confirmed this could provide a mechanism for
Baryogenesis, which is one of the most important outstanding questions in
physics. To reliably make predictions it is necessary to have full control of
the finite temperature scalar potentials. However, as we show the standard
methods used in BSM physics to improve phase transition calculations, resumming
hard thermal loops, introduces significant errors into the scalar potential. In
addition, the standard methods make it impossible to match theories to an EFT
description reliably. In this paper we define a thermal resummation procedure
based on Partial Dressing (PD) for general BSM calculations of phase
transitions beyond the high-temperature approximation. Additionally, we
introduce the modified Optimized Partial Dressing (OPD) procedure, which is
numerically nearly as efficient as old incorrect methods, while yielding
identical results to the full PD calculation. This can be easily applied to
future BSM studies of phase transitions in the early universe. As an example,
we show that in unmixed singlet scalar extensions of the SM, the (O)PD
calculations make new phenomenological predictions compared to previous
analyses. An important future application is the study of EFTs at finite
temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00492</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Helesfai</keyname><forenames>Gabor</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Field Quantization Method</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Today it still remains a challenge whether quantum mechanics has an
underlying statistical explanation or not. While there are and were a lot of
models trying to explain quantum phenomena with statistical methods these all
failed on certain levels. In this paper a method is proposed that is not only
based on a classical statistical framework but it has an underlying physical
model behind it and it can explain some of the basic characteristics of quantum
mechanics. It will be shown that if look at the properties of a charged
particle in a random electric field one can obtain the discrete energy values
of the harmonic oscillator and the infinite potential well, and also gives a
good qualitative description of the double-slit experiment and measurement
theory. Also the side-effect of the model is the emergence of a constant with
an action dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00493</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Khawaja</keyname><forenames>U. Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Refai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carr</keyname><forenames>Lincoln D.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-accuracy power series solutions with arbitrarily large radius of
  convergence for fractional nonlinear differential equations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.PS</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fractional nonlinear differential equations present an interplay between two
common and important effective descriptions used to simplify high dimensional
or more complicated theories: nonlinearity and fractional derivatives. These
effective descriptions thus appear commonly in physical and mathematical
modeling. We present a new series method providing systematic controlled
accuracy for solutions of fractional nonlinear differential equations. The
method relies on spatially iterative use of power series expansions. Our
approach permits an arbitrarily large radius of convergence and thus solves the
typical divergence problem endemic to power series approaches. We apply our
method to the fractional nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation and its imaginary
time rotation, the fractional nonlinear diffusion equation. For the fractional
nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation we find fractional generalizations of cnoidal
waves of Jacobi elliptic functions as well as a fractional bright soliton. For
the fractional nonlinear diffusion equation we find the combination of
fractional and nonlinear effects results in a more strongly localized solution
which nevertheless still exhibits power law tails, albeit at a much lower
density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00494</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Vanslette</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>How Kirkwood and Probability Distributions Differ: A Coxian Perspective</title><categories>quant-ph math.PR physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kolmogorov's first axiom of probability is probability takes values between 0
and 1; however, in Cox's derivation of probability having a maximum value of
unity is arbitrary since he derives probability as a tool to rank degrees of
plausibility. Probability can then be used to make inferences in instances of
incomplete information, which is the foundation of Baysian probability theory.
This article formulates a rule, which if obeyed, allows probability to take
complex values and still be consistent with the interpretation of probability
theory as being a tool to rank plausibility. It is then shown that Kirkwood
distributions and the conditional complex probability distributions proposed by
Hofmann do not obey this rule and therefore cannot rank plausibility. Not only
do these quasiprobability distributions relax Kolmogorov's first axiom of
probability, they also are void of the defining property of a probability
distribution from a Coxian and Baysian perspective - they lack the ability to
rank plausibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00502</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Vitanov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitanov</keyname><forenames>Kaloyan N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanova</keyname><forenames>Tsvetelina</forenames></author></authors><title>Box model of migration in channels of migration networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>16 pagesq no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a box model of migration in channels of networks with possible
application for modelling motion of migrants in migration networks. The channel
consists of nodes of the network (nodes may be considered as boxes representing
countries) and edges that connect these nodes and represent possible ways for
motion of migrants. The nodes of the migration channel have different
&quot;leakage&quot;, i.e. the probability of change of the status of a migrant (from
migrant to non-migrant) may be different in the different countries along the
channel. In addition the nodes far from the entry node of the channel may be
more attractive for migrants in comparison to the nodes around the entry node
of the channel. We discuss below channels containing infinite number of nodes.
Two regimes of functioning of these channels are studied: stationary regime and
non-stationary regime. In the stationary regime of the functioning of the
channel the distribution of migrants in the countries of the channel is
described by a distribution that contains as particular case the Waring
distribution. In the non-stationary regime of functioning of the channel one
observes exponential increase or exponential decrease of the number of migrants
in the countries of the channel. It depends on the situation in the entry
country of the channel for which scenario will be realized. Despite the
non-stationary regime of the functioning of the channel the asymptotic
distribution of the migrants in the nodes of the channel is stationary. From
the point of view of the characteristic features of the migrants we discuss the
cases of (i) migrants having the same characteristics and (ii) two classes of
migrants that have differences in some characteristic (e.g., different
religions).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00518</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sang Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Um</keyname><forenames>Jaegon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Hyunggyu</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficiency at the maximum power output for simple two-level heat engine</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a simple two-level heat engine to study the efficiency in the
condition of the maximum power output, depending on the energy levels from
which the net work is extracted. In contrast to the quasi-statically operated
Carnot engine whose efficiency reaches the theoretical maximum, recent research
on more realistic engines operated in finite time has revealed other classes of
efficiency such as the Curzon-Ahlborn efficiency maximizing the power output.
We investigate yet another side with our heat engine model, which consists of
pure relaxation and net work extraction processes from the population
difference caused by different transition rates. Due to the nature of our
model, the time-dependent part is completely decoupled from the other terms in
the generated work. We derive analytically the optimal condition for transition
rates maximizing the generated power output and discuss its implication on
general premise of realistic heat engines. In particular, the optimal engine
efficiency of our model is different from the Curzon-Ahlborn efficiency,
although they share the universal linear and quadratic coefficients at the
near-equilibrium limit. We further confirm our results by taking an alternative
approach in terms of the entropy production at hot and cold reservoirs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00545</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Huan</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Chunrong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Xiaopeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dendritic cell-cluster metasurface manipulation of visible light</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The manipulation of visible light is important in science and technology
research. Metasurfaces can enable flexible and effective regulation of the
phase, polarization, and propagation modes of an electromagnetic wave.
Metasurfaces have become a research hotspot in optics and electromagnetics, and
cross-polarization conversion is an important application for visible-light
manipulation using a metasurface. A metasurface composed of nano-antenna arrays
and bilayer plasma can reportedly convert the direction of linear polarized
light efficiently. However, the metasurface of cross-polarization conversion
operating in short-wavelength visible light is problematic. In addition,
previous metasurfaces prepared using the top-down etching method is unsuitable
for practical applications because of the necessary harsh experimental
conditions and the high construction cost of preparation. In the present work,
we suggest a dendritic cell-cluster metasurface achieve cross-polarization in
transmission mode within 550, 570, 590 and 610 nm wavelength. Preparation is
accomplished using a bottom-up electrochemical deposition method, which is easy
and low cost. The dendritic cell-cluster metasurface is an important step in
cross-polarization conversion research and has broad application prospects and
development potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00546</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>S Y</forenames></author></authors><title>An AB-KdV Equation, Exact Solutions, Symmetry Reductions and
  B\&quot;{a}cklund Transformations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a nonlocal AB-KdV system obtained directly from the KdV equation to
describe two-area physical event. The exact solutions of the AB-KdV system,
including $P_s T_d$ invariant and $P_s T_d$ symmetric breaking solutions are
shown by different methods. These solutions, such as single soliton solutions,
infinitely many singular soliton solutions, cnoidal wave solutions, and
symmetry reduction solutions etc., show the AB-KdV system possesses rich
structures. Also, a special B\&quot;{a}cklund transformation related to residual
symmetry is presented via the localization of the residual symmetry to find
interactive solutions between the solitons and other types of the AB-KdV
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00551</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rempel</keyname><forenames>Trevor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freidel</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author></authors><title>A Classical and Spinorial Description of the Relativistic Spinning
  Particle</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous work we showed that spin can be envisioned as living in a phase
space that is dual to the standard phase space of position and momentum. In
this work we demonstrate that the second class constraints inherent in this
&quot;Dual Phase Space&quot; picture can be solved by introducing a spinorial
parameterization of the spinning degrees of freedom. This allows for a purely
first class formulation that generalizes the usual relativistic description of
spinless particles and provides several insights into the nature of spin and
its relationship with spacetime and locality. In particular, we find that the
spin motion acts as a Lorentz contraction on the four-velocity and that, in
addition to proper time, spinning particles posses a second gauge invariant
observable which we call proper angle. Heuristically, this proper angle
represents the amount of Zitterbewegung necessary for a spin transition to
occur. Additionally, we show that the spin velocity satisfies a causality
constraint, and even more stringently, that it is constant along classical
trajectories. This leads to the notion of &quot;half-quantum&quot; states which violate
the classical equations of motion, and yet do not experience an exponential
suppression in the path integral. Finally we give a full analysis of the
Poisson bracket structure of this new parametrization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00557</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Li-Sha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Bao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>A precise measure of avian magnetoreception based on quantum metrology</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>have submitted, 11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radical pair (RP) mechanism, which describes the quantum dynamics of a
spatially separated electron pair, is considered as one of the principal models
of avian magnetoreception. Different from the conventional phenomenological
approach where the sensitivity of avian magnetoreception is characterized by
the singlet yield $\Phi_{S}$, we introduce the quantum Fisher information
(QFI), which represents the maximum information about the magnetic field's
direction extracted from the RP state, to give a precise measure of sensitivity
of avian compass essentially. The consistency between our results and
experimental observations suggests that QFI plays a decisive role in avian
magnetoreception. Besides, within the framework of quantum metrology, we can
judge the feasibility of any possible measurement scheme for avian
magnetoreception, and shed light on an intrinsic relevance between the singlet
yield and a concrete measurement scheme of our approach. The present work
allows us to understand many things about avian magnetoreception from a fully
new perspective of quantum metrology, and provide a new route to establish a
direct connection between quantum information and many other biological
functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00569</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Per</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drumm</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollenberg</keyname><forenames>L. C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russo</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio calculation of energy levels for phosphorus donors in silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The s manifold energy levels for phosphorus donors in silicon are important
input parameters for the design and modelling of electronic devices on the
nanoscale. In this paper we calculate these energy levels from first principles
using density functional theory. The wavefunction of the donor electron's
ground state is found to have a form that is similar to an atomic s orbital,
with an effective Bohr radius of 1.8 nm. The corresponding binding energy of
this state is found to be 41 meV, which is in good agreement with the currently
accepted value of 45.59 meV. We also calculate the energies of the excited
1s(T) and 1s(E) states, finding them to be 32 and 31 meV respectively. These
results constitute the first ab initio confirmation of the s manifold energy
levels for phosphorus donors in silicon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00578</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Friedland</keyname><forenames>Shmuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemp</keyname><forenames>Todd</forenames></author></authors><title>Most Boson quantum states are almost maximally entangled</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The geometric measure of entanglement $E$ of an $m$ qubit quantum state takes
maximal possible value $m$. In previous work of Gross, Flammia, and Eisert, it
was shown that $E \ge m-O(\log m)$ with high probability as $m\to\infty$. They
showed, as a consequence, that the vast majority of states are too entangled to
be computationally useful. In this paper, we show that for $m$ qubit {\em
Boson} quantum states (those that are actually available in current designs for
quantum computers), the maximal possible geometric measure of entanglement is
$\log_2 m$, opening the door to many computationally universal states. We
further show the corresponding concentration result that $E \ge \log_2 m -
O(\log \log m)$ with high probability as $m\to\infty$. We extend these results
also to $m$-mode $n$-bit Boson quantum states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00588</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Feinsilver</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author></authors><title>Krawtchouk-Griffiths Systems II: As Bernoulli Systems</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><msc-class>Primary 81S05, 62H99, Secondary 20H20, 35R99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We call Krawtchouk-Griffiths systems, KG-systems, systems of multivariate
polynomials orthogonal with respect to corresponding multinomial distributions.
The original Krawtchouk polynomials are orthogonal with respect to a binomial
distribution. Here we present a Fock space construction with raising and
lowering operators. The operators of &quot;multiplication by X&quot; are found in terms
of boson operators and corresponding recurrence relations presented. The
Riccati partial differential equations for the differentiation operators,
Berezin transform and associated partial differential equations are found.
These features provide the specifications for a Bernoulli system as a
quantization formulation of multivariate Krawtchouk polynomials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00592</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Humberset</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gjerloev</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michell</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>I. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal characteristics and energy deposition of pulsating auroral
  patches</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><proxy>Kavitha &#xc3;&#x83;&#xc2;&#x98;stgaard</proxy><doi>10.1002/2016JA022921</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a careful statistical analysis of pulsating aurora (PA) using
all-sky green line (557.7 nm) images obtained at 3.3 Hz. Six well-defined
individual PA patches are identified and extracted using a contouring
technique. Quantitative parameters such as the patch duration (on-time and
off-time), peak intensity, and integrated intensity are determined for each
patch and each pulsation. The resulting characteristics serve as strict
observational constraints that any of the many competing theories attempting to
explain PA must predict. The purpose of this paper is to determine the
characteristics of PA patches in order to provide better observational
constraints on the suggested mechanisms. All aspects of the temporal behavior
of the individual patches appear to be erratic. Historically, PA has been
defined very loosely and we argue that the use of the term &quot;pulsating&quot; is
inappropriate since our findings and other published results are not regularly
periodic and thus a more appropriate term may be fluctuating aurora. Further,
we find that the observational constraints do not fit well with the flow
cyclotron maser theory, which in particular is suggested to create PA patches.
There is no clear candidate of the suggested mechanisms and drivers to explain
the observational constraints set by the PA patches in a satisfactory manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00598</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous symmetry breaking induced by complex fermion determinant ---
  yet another success of the complex Langevin method</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, Proceedings of the 34th International Symposium
  on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016, University of
  Southampton, UK</comments><report-no>KEK-TH/1948</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In many interesting systems, the fermion determinant becomes complex and its
phase plays a crucial role in the determination of the vacuum. For instance, in
finite density QCD at low temperature and high density, exotic fermion
condensates are conjectured to form due to such effects. When one applies the
complex Langevin method to such a complex action system naively, one cannot
obtain the correct results because of the singular-drift problem associated
with the appearance of small eigenvalues of the Dirac operator. Here we propose
to avoid this problem by adding a fermion bilinear term to the action and
extrapolating its coefficient to zero. We test this idea in an SO(4)-invariant
matrix model with a Gaussian action and a complex fermion determinant, whose
phase is expected to induce the spontaneous breaking of the SO(4) symmetry. Our
results agree well with the previous results obtained by the Gaussian expansion
method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00602</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhongjian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koh</keyname><forenames>Kuang Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezentsev</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enno</keyname><forenames>Sven-Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugier</keyname><forenames>Jacqueline</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xfc;llekrug</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Variable phase propagation velocity for long-range lightning location
  system</title><categories>physics.space-ph physics.ao-ph</categories><proxy>Kavitha &#xc3;&#x83;&#xc2;&#x98;stgaard</proxy><doi>10.1002/2016RS006058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electromagnetic wave propagation velocity at low radio frequencies is an
important input parameter for lightning location systems that use time of
arrival (TOA) method. This velocity is normally fixed at or near the speed of
light. However, this study finds that the radio waves from two submarine
communication transmitters at 20.9 kHz and 23.4 kHz exhibit phase propagation
velocities that are $\sim$0.51% slower and $\sim$0.64% faster than the speed of
light as a result of sky wave contributions and ground effects. Therefore, a
novel technique with a variable phase propagation velocity is implemented for
the first time in the TOA method and applied to electric field recordings with
a long-baseline lightning location system that consists of four radio receivers
in western Europe. The lightning locations inferred from variable velocities
improve the accuracy of locations inferred from a fixed velocity by
$\sim$0.89-1.06 km when compared to the lightning locations reported by the UK
MetOffice. The normal distributions of the observed phase propagation
velocities in small geographic areas are not centered at the speed of light.
Consequently, representative velocities can be calculated for many small
geographic areas to produce a velocity map over central France where numerous
lightning discharges occurred. This map reflects the impact of sky waves and
ground effects on the calculation of lightning locations as a result of the
network configuration. It is concluded that the use of variable phase
propagation velocities mitigates the influence of sky waves and ground effects
in long-range lightning location networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00608</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Betta</keyname><forenames>Gian-Franco Dalla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boscardin</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendicino</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronchin</keyname><forenames>Sabina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultan</keyname><forenames>DMS</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of New 3D Pixel Sensors for Phase 2 Upgrades at LHC</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>4 pages, 8 figures, 2015 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium and Medical
  Imaging Conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the development of new 3D pixel sensors for the Phase 2 Upgrades
at the High-Luminosity LHC (HL-LHC). To cope with the requirements of increased
pixel granularity (e.g., 50x50 or 25x100 um2 pixel size) and extreme radiation
hardness (up to a fluence of 2e16 neq cm-2), thinner 3D sensors (~100 um) with
electrodes having narrower size (~ 5 um) and reduced spacing (~ 30 um) are
considered. The paper covers TCAD simulations, as well as technological and
design aspects relevant to the first batch of these 3D sensors, that is
currently being fabricated at FBK on 6-inch wafers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00621</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Niedermayer</keyname><forenames>Ferenc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Ulli</forenames></author></authors><title>O(3) model with Nienhuis action</title><categories>hep-lat cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, Lattice 2016 (Southampton, UK)</comments><report-no>HU-EP-16/37</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the O(3) sigma model in $D=2$ on the lattice with a Boltzmann weight
linearized in $\beta$ on each link. While the spin formulation now suffers from
a sign-problem the equivalent loop model remains positive and becomes
particularly simple. By studying the transfer matrix and by performing Monte
Carlo simulations in the loop form we study the mass gap coupling in a step
scaling analysis. The question addressed is, whether or not such a simplified
action still has the right universal continuum limit. If the answer is
affirmative this would be helpful in widening the applicability of worm
algorithm methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00624</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Betta</keyname><forenames>Gian-Franco Dalla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boscardin</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darbo</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendicino</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meschini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messineo</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronchin</keyname><forenames>Sabina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultan</keyname><forenames>DMS</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of a new generation of 3D pixel sensors for HL-LHC</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>2 pages, 3 figures, 2015 Pisa Meeting</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2015.08.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper covers the main technological and design aspects relevant to the
development of a new generation of thin 3D pixel sensors with small pixel size
aimed at the High-Luminosity LHC upgrades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00626</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Betta</keyname><forenames>Gian-Franco Dalla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boscardin</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bomben</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brianzi</keyname><forenames>Mirko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calderini</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darbo</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orso</keyname><forenames>Roberto Dell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaudiello</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacomini</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendicino</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meschini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messineo</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronchin</keyname><forenames>Sabina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultan</keyname><forenames>D M S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>The INFN-FBK Phase-2 R{\&amp;}D Program</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>4 pages, 7 figures, 2015 Pisa Meeting</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2015.08.074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the 3-year INFN ATLAS-CMS joint research activity in
collaboration with FBK, started in 2014, and aimed at the development of new
thin pixel detectors for the High Luminosity LHC Phase-2 upgrades. The program
is concerned with both 3D and planar active-edge pixel sensors to be made on
6-inch p-type wafers. The technology and the design will be optimized and
qualified for extreme radiation hardness (2e16 neq cm-2). Pixel layouts
compatible with present (for testing) and future (RD53 65nm) front-end chips of
ATLAS and CMS are considered. The paper covers the main aspects of the research
program, from the sensor design and fabrication technology, to the results of
initial tests performed on the first prototypes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00629</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Joana</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Loock</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byrnes</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author></authors><title>Steady-state generation of negative-Wigner-function light using feedback</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063802</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method of producing steady-state coherent light with negative
Wigner functions in nonlinear media combined with feedback control. While the
nonlinearities are essential to produce the Wigner negativities, this alone is
insufficient to stabilize steady-state light with negativities. Using feedback
control to control the phase in the cavity, we find that this produces
significant total negativities for reasonable experimental parameters. The
negative Wigner function is produced continuously and does not appear to be
restricted to low-amplitude light. The technique is applicable to systems such
as exciton-polaritons, where strong natural nonlinearities are present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00631</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Soeken</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roetteler</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiebe</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Micheli</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Design Automation and Design Space Exploration for Quantum Computers</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure, in 2017 Design, Automation &amp; Test in Europe
  Conference &amp; Exhibition, DATE 2017, Lausanne, Switzerland, March 27-31, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major hurdle to the deployment of quantum linear systems algorithms and
recent quantum simulation algorithms lies in the difficulty to find inexpensive
reversible circuits for arithmetic using existing hand coded methods. Motivated
by recent advances in reversible logic synthesis, we synthesize arithmetic
circuits using classical design automation flows and tools. The combination of
classical and reversible logic synthesis enables the automatic design of large
components in reversible logic starting from well-known hardware description
languages such as Verilog. As a prototype example for our approach we
automatically generate high quality networks for the reciprocal $1/x$, which is
necessary for quantum linear systems algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00643</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Quevillon</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;mie</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for New Physics in Scalar Top-Pair Resonance</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Talk given at the 9th International Workshop on Top Quark Physics
  (TOP 2016), 19-23 September 2016, Olomouc, Czech Republic, to appear in the
  proceedings</comments><report-no>KCL-PH-TH/2016-67</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the effects in the production via gluon fusion in LHC collisions
of one or two spin-zero new resonant particles $\Phi$ that decay into a top
quark pair. We revisit previous analyses of the interferences between the
heavy-fermion loop-induced $gg \rightarrow \Phi \rightarrow t\bar{t}$ signal
and the continuum QCD background $gg \rightarrow t\bar{t}$. We show that in the
presence of standard model fermions only in the $gg \rightarrow \Phi$ loops,
the interference effect is destructive causing a dip in the $t \bar t$ mass
distribution. Including New Physics such as additional vector-like quarks leads
to a totally different picture as the line-shape can be distorted by peaks and
dips. For the time being, the absence of such effects in ATLAS and CMS data
constrain models of the production and decays of the $\Phi$ state(s).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00658</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Pinto</keyname><forenames>Rafael S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Remote synchronization in networks of coupled oscillators</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study under which conditions systems of coupled oscillators on complex
networks display remote synchronization, a situation where pairs of vertices,
not necessarily physically linked, but with the same network symmetry, are
synchronized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00672</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Guiance</keyname><forenames>S. N. Hern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coria</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irurzun</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mola</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>A preliminary DFT study of the adsorption and dissociation of
  $CH_{4}$,$SO_{2}$ and $O_{2}$ reactions on $Cr_{2}O_{3}(0001)$</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, 5 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, we study the structures and molecular geometries of
$CH_{4}$, $SO_{2}$ and $O_{2}$ adsorbed on $Cr_{2}O_{3}(0001)$. Using
computational calculations based on the density functional theory (DFT), we
analyze the most suitable sites to carry out the adsorption of each of the
molecules mentioned, and the influence of each species on the adsorption and
dissociation of the others. The results allow us to understand the activation
of the $Cr_{2}O_{3}(0001)$ surface, which leads to the presence of $SO_{2}$
during the oxidation of $CH_{4}$, as was experimentally verified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00673</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sopkova</keyname><forenames>Filomena</forenames></author></authors><title>Top quark pair asymmetries</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study top quark pair charge, energy and incline asymmetry
at parton level using Powheg Monte-Carlo generator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00676</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sivasundaram</keyname><forenames>Sujeevan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Kristian Hvidtfelt</forenames></author></authors><title>Surveying the Attitudes of Physicists Concerning Foundational Issues of
  Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>physics.hist-ph physics.ed-ph physics.soc-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 20 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Even though quantum mechanics has existed for almost 100 years, questions
concerning the foundation and interpretation of the theory still remain. These
issues have gathered more attention in recent years, but does this mean that
physicists are more aware of foundational issues concerning quantum mechanics?
A survey was sent out to 1234 physicists affiliated to 8 different
universities. 149 responded to the questions, which both concerned foundational
issues related to quantum mechanics, specifically, as well as questions
concerning interpretations of physical theories in general. The answers to the
survey revealed that foundational concepts in quantum mechanics are still a
topic that only a minority of physicists are familiar with, although a clear
majority of physicists find that interpretations of physical theories are
important. The various questions, as well as how the respondents answered, are
presented. The survey intends to give an overview of what the opinion of the
physics community, in general, is concerning issues related to quantum
mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00679</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Radaelli</keyname><forenames>Greta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Mengdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fina</keyname><forenames>Ignasi</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>Florencio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldrati</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heidler</keyname><forenames>Jakoba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piamonteze</keyname><forenames>Cinthia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertacco</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontcuberta</keyname><forenames>Josep</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain-controlled responsiveness of slave half-doped manganite
  La0.5Sr0.5MnO3 layers inserted in BaTiO3 ferroelectric tunnel junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Electron. Mater. 2016, 1600368</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/aelm.201600368</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Insertion of layers displaying field-induced metal-to-insulator (M/I)
transition in ferroelectric tunnel junctions (FTJs) has received attention as a
potentially useful way to enlarge junction tunnel electroresistance (TER).
Half-doped manganites being at the verge of metal-insulator character are thus
good candidates to be slave layers in FTJs. However, the phase diagram of these
oxides is extremely sensitive to strain and thus can be radically different
when integrated in epitaxial FTJs. Here we report a systematic study of
large-area (A = 4 to 100 um2) Pt/La0.5Sr0.5MnO3/BaTiO3/La0.7Sr0.3MnO3
(Pt/HD/BTO/LSMO) FTJs, having different thicknesses of the ferroelectric
(2-3nm) and HD layers (1-2nm), grown on substrates imposing either tensile
(SrTiO3) or compressive (LaAlO3) strains. Room-temperature electric
characterization of the FTJs shows polarization-controlled ON/ OFF states.
Clear evidences of field-induced M/I transition (difference between junction
resistance in OFF and ON state is increased of more than one order of
magnitude) are observed in junctions prepared on SrTiO3 but the HD layer is
generally metallic on LaAlO3. Moreover, the M/I transition is only confined in
an interfacial layer of the slave film thus entailing an overall reduction of
TER. The orderly results reported here give some hints towards selection of HD
materials and substrates for optimal FTJ responsiveness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00684</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Liberto</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceotto</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>The Importance of the Pre-exponential Factor in Semiclassical Molecular
  Dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 145, 144107 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper deals with the critical issue of approximating the pre-exponential
factor in semiclassical molecular dynamics. The pre-exponential factor is
important because it accounts for the quantum contribution to the semiclassical
propagator of the classical Feynman path fluctuations. Pre-exponential factor
approximations are necessary when chaotic or complex systems are simulated. We
introduced pre-exponential factor approximations based either on analytical
considerations or numerical regularization. The approximations are tested for
power spectrum calculations of more and more chaotic model systems and on
several molecules, for which exact quantum mechanical values are available. The
results show that the pre-exponential factor approximations introduced are
accurate enough to be safely employed for semiclassical simulations of complex
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00701</id><created>2016-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Sakti</keyname><forenames>Muhammad F A R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagita</keyname><forenames>Philin Y D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suroso</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zen</keyname><forenames>Freddy P</forenames></author></authors><title>Near Horizon Extreme Magnetized Kerr Geometry</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, to be submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conjectured magnetized Kerr/CFT correspondence states that the quantum
theory of gravity in the near horizon of extreme Kerr black holes immersed by
the magnetic field, Near Horizon Extreme Magnetized Kerr black holes, is
holographic dual to a two-dimensional chiral conformal field theory. To obtain
Near Horizon Extreme Magnetized Kerr geometry, the extreme limit of the
magnetized Kerr metric is taken so, $ a=M $ and then continued by transforming
the coordinates to have a warped and twisted product of $ \textrm{AdS}_2 \times
\textrm{S}^2 $, and also with the Near Horizon Extreme Kerr metric one.
Consequently, we can obtain also the new Ernst potentials for those geometries.
Finally, the transformed central charge from the extremal non-magnetized one to
the magnetized one in the Ernst-Papapetrou formalism is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00704</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Higler</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krausser</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Gucht</keyname><forenames>Jasper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaccone</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sprakel</keyname><forenames>Joris</forenames></author></authors><title>Connectivity dynamics in the vitrification of colloidal liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures. Supplementary Information available as an
  ancillary file</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While various structural and dynamical precursors to vitrification have been
identified, a predictive and quantitative description of how subtle changes at
the microscopic scale give rise to the steep growth in macroscopic viscosity is
missing. It was proposed that the presence of long-lived bonded structures
within the liquid may provide this connection. Here we directly observe and
quantify the connectivity dynamics in liquids of charged colloids en-route to
vitrification. Based on these data, we extend Dyre's elastic model for the
glass transition to account for particle-level dynamics; this results in a
parameter-free expression for the slowing down of relaxations in the liquid
that is in quantitative agreement with our experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00706</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames><affiliation>Bundesdeutsche Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Ver&#xe4;nderliche Sterne e.V</affiliation><affiliation>American Association of Variable Star Observers</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Uttenthaler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>Kuffner Observatory, Johann Staud-Stra&#xdf;e 10, 1160 Wien, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;mmerich</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>Bundesdeutsche Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Ver&#xe4;nderliche Sterne e.V</affiliation><affiliation>American Association of Variable Star Observers</affiliation></author></authors><title>A New Sample of Mid-Infrared Bright, Long-Period Mira Variables from the
  MACHO Galactic Bulge Fields</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>50 pages, 389 figures in BAV Journal No. 10, Sept. 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mid-infrared bright objects in the direction of the Galactic Bulge were
investigated using time series photometry from the MACHO data archive, which
led to the discovery of a large number of long-period variables. Among these, a
total of 192 bona-fide Mira variables was identified, which, to the best of our
knowledge, are reported here for the first time. Together with the results from
our previous investigations, we thereby bring the number of Mira variables
found in the MACHO Galactic Bulge fields to a new total of 1286 stars. Light
curves, folded light curves and summary data for all new Mira variables are
presented and their properties in colour-colour, period-colour and
period-magnitude space are investigated. In agreement with our expectations,
the present sample of mid-infrared bright objects is composed mostly of
luminous, long-period variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00707</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Sida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassani</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kharitonov</keyname><forenames>Svyatoslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brilland</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caillaud</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;line</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trol&#xe8;s</keyname><forenames>Johann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xe8;s</keyname><forenames>Camille-Sophie</forenames></author></authors><title>Mid-infrared continuous wave parametric amplification in tapered
  chalcogenide microstructured fibers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As photon mixing is not inherently limited to any specific spectral region,
parametric processes represent a compelling solution for all-optical signal
processing in spectral windows not easily accessible by other technologies.
Particularly, the continuous-wave pumping scheme is essential for any
application requiring modulated signals or precise spectroscopic
characterization. Highly nonlinear fibers enabled record performances for
wavelength conversion and amplification in the telecommunication band, however
no waveguiding platforms have yet solved the trade-off between
high-nonlinearity, low propagation losses and dispersion in the mid-infrared.
Here, we show mid-infrared continuous-wave parametric amplification in a GeAsSe
fiber. Leveraging state-of-the-art fabrication techniques, a novel tapered
photonic crystal fiber geometry enabling 4.5 dB signal amplification and 2 dB
idler conversion efficiency is experimentally demonstrated using only 125 mW of
pump in the 2 micron wavelength range. This result is not only the first ever
continuous-wave parametric amplification measured at 2 micron, in any
waveguide, but also establishes GeAsSe PCF tapers as the most promising
all-fibered, high efficiency continuous-wave parametric converter for advanced
applications in the mid-infrared.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00711</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00711</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Masciadri</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lascaux</keyname><forenames>Franck</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Turchi</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fini</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical turbulence forecast: ready for an operational application</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>This is a pre-copyedited, author-produced PDF of an article accepted
  for publication in MNRAS following peer review. The version of record [doi:
  10.1093/mnras/stw3111] is available online at:
  http://mnras.oxfordjournals.org/content/early/2016/11/30/mnras.stw3111.abstract?keytype=ref&amp;ijkey=te4TKA10zzdydVK.
  13 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the main goals of the feasibility study MOSE (MOdellig ESO Sites) is
to evaluate the performances of a method conceived to forecast the optical
turbulence above the ESO sites of the Very Large Telescope and the
European-Extremely Large Telescope in Chile. The method implied the use of a
dedicated code conceived for the optical turbulence (OT) called Astro-Meso-Nh.
In this paper we present results we obtained at conclusion of this project
concerning the performances of this method in forecasting the most relevant
parameters related to the optical turbulence (CN2, seeing , isoplanatic angle
theta_0 and wavefront coherence time tau_0). Numerical predictions related to a
very rich statistical sample of nights uniformly distributed along a solar year
and belonging to different years have been compared to observations and
different statistical operators have been analyzed such as classical bias, RMSE
and and more sophisticated statistical operators derived by the contingency
tables that are able to quantify the score of success of a predictive method
such as the percentage of correct detection (PC) and the probability to detect
a parameter within a specific range of values (POD). The main conclusions of
the study tell us that the Astro-Meso-Nh model provides performances that are
already very good to definitely guarantee a not negligible positive impact on
the Service Mode of top-class telescopes and ELTs. A demonstrator for an
automatic and operational version of the Astro-Meso-Nh model will be soon
implemented on the sites of VLT and E-ELT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00741</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00741</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Siyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronine</keyname><forenames>Dmitri V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Raman spectroscopy of chocolate bloom</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Raman spectroscopy has been widely applied to the chemical analysis of food
quality and, in particular, of chocolate. We perform Raman analysis of bloom
formation in white and dark chocolates. We show evidence of sugar and fat bloom
and investigate spectroscopic signatures of polymorphic changes in different
phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00772</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kakofengitis</keyname><forenames>Dimitris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steuernagel</keyname><forenames>Ole</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Wigner phase space description of a Morse oscillator'' [J.
  Chem. Phys. 77, 4604 (1982)]</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Comment on ``Wigner phase space description of a Morse oscillator''
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00777</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kunitomo</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okawa</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukeno</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takezaki</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermion scattering amplitudes from gauge-invariant actions for open
  superstring field theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>52 pages, 18 figures</comments><report-no>UT-Komaba/16-9, YITP-16-130</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate on-shell scattering amplitudes involving fermions at the tree
level in open superstring field theory. We confirm that four-point and
five-point amplitudes in the world-sheet path integral with the standard
prescription using picture-changing operators are reproduced. For the
four-point amplitudes, we find that the quartic interaction required by gauge
invariance adjusts the different assignment of picture-changing operators in
the $s$-channel and in the $t$-channel of Feynman diagrams with two cubic
vertices. For the five-point amplitudes, the correct amplitudes are reproduced
in a more intricate way via the quartic and quintic interactions. Our
calculations can be interpreted as those for a complete action with a
constraint on the Ramond sector or as those for the covariant formulation
developed by Sen with spurious free fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00781</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>Kristin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krellner</keyname><forenames>Cornelius</forenames></author></authors><title>Single crystal growth and characterization of GdRh$_2$Si$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Crystal Growth, Volume 419, p. 37-41 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2015.02.079</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-temperature indium flux growth was applied to prepare single crystals of
GdRh$_2$Si$_2$ by a modified Bridgman method leading to mm-sized single
crystals with a platelet habitus. Specific heat and susceptibility data of
GdRh$_2$Si$_2$ exhibit a pronounced anomaly at $T_N = 107\rm \,K$, where the
AFM ordering sets in. Magnetic measurements on the single crystals were
performed down to $T = 2$\,K in external fields from B = 0 - 9\,T applied along
the $[100]$-, $[110]$- and $[001]$-direction of the tetragonal lattice. The
effective magnetic moment determined from a Curie-Weiss fit agrees well with
values from literature, and is larger than the theoretically predicted value.
Electrical transport data recorded for current flow parallel and perpendicular
to the $[001]$-direction show a large anisotropy below $T_N$. The residual
resistivity ratio $\rm RRR=\rho_{300K}/\rho_{0}\sim 23$ demonstrates that we
succeeded in preparing high-quality crystals using high-temperature indium
flux-growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00793</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Munk</keyname><forenames>Madicken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slaybaugh</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandya</keyname><forenames>Tara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Seth R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>FW/CADIS-$\Omega$: An angle-informed hybrid method for deep-penetration
  radiation transport</title><categories>math.NA physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>M. Munk, R.N. Slaybaugh, Tara M. Pandya, Seth R. Johnson, T. M.
  Evans, &quot;An Angle-Informed Hybrid Method for CADIS and FW-CADIS.&quot; Proceedings
  of the PHYSOR 2016 Meeting in Sun Valley, ID, May 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new method for generating variance reduction parameters for strongly
anisotropic, deep-penetration radiation shielding studies is presented. This
method generates an alternate form of the adjoint scalar flux quantity,
$\phi^{\dagger}_{\Omega}$, which is used by both CADIS and FW-CADIS to generate
variance reduction parameters for local and global response functions,
respectively. The new method, called CADIS-$\Omega$, was implemented in the
Denovo/ADVANTG software suite, and results are presented for a concrete
labyrinth test problem. Results indicate that the flux generated by
CADIS-$\Omega$ incorporates localized angular anisotropies in the flux
effectively. CADIS-$\Omega$ outperformed CADIS in the test problem while
obtaining accurate results. This initial work indicates that CADIS-$\Omega$ may
be highly useful for shielding problems with strong angular anisotropies. A
future test plan to fully characterize the new method is proposed, which should
reveal more about the types of realistic problems for which the CADIS-$\Omega$
will be suited.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00809</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Cordova</keyname><forenames>Clay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumitrescu</keyname><forenames>Thomas T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Intriligator</keyname><forenames>Kenneth</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiplets of Superconformal Symmetry in Diverse Dimensions</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>165 pages, 1 figure, 32 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We systematically analyze the operator content of unitary superconformal
multiplets in $d &gt; 3$ spacetime dimensions. We present a simple, general, and
efficient algorithm that generates all of these multiplets by correctly
eliminating possible null states. The algorithm is conjectural, but passes a
vast web of consistency checks. We apply it to tabulate a large variety of
superconformal multiplets. In particular, we classify and construct all
multiplets that contain conserved currents or free fields, which play an
important role in superconformal field theories (SCFTs). Some currents that are
allowed in conformal field theories cannot be embedded in superconformal
multiplets, and hence they are absent in SCFTs. We use the structure of
superconformal stress tensor multiplets to show that SCFTs with more than 16
Poincar\'e supercharges cannot arise in $d \geq 4$, even when the corresponding
superconformal algebras exist. We also show that such theories do arise in $d =
3$, but are necessarily free.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00826</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kozachuk</keyname><forenames>Anastasiia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikitin</keyname><forenames>Nikolai</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak annihilation rare radiative B-decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, Contribution to the proceedings of HSQCD 2016,
  June 27 -- July 1, 2016, Gatchina, Russia</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give predictions for the branching ratios of several rare radiative
B-decays which proceed only through weak annihilation mechanism. In addition to
previous analysis we estimate the branching ratios of $\bar{B}^0_s\to
D^{*0}\gamma$ and $B_c^-\to\rho^-\gamma$ decays and obtain $2.87\cdot 10^{-9}$
and $2.59\cdot 10^{-7}$ for them correspondingly. The accuracy of the
predictions is at the level of 20\%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00834</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Merrifield</keyname><forenames>Michael R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Meghan E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haran</keyname><forenames>Brady</forenames></author></authors><title>Gaia Shows That Messier 40 is Definitely Not a Binary Star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>1 page. Refereed and accepted for publication in Observatory</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  M40 has always been something of an oddity in the Messier Catalogue, since it
is just a pair of stars rather than an extended object. Doubts have also been
expressed as to whether it is even a physical binary. Here, we note that the
Hipparcos/Gaia parallaxes for these two stars remove all doubt: Messier 40
comprises a pair of entirely unrelated stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
