<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:51:56Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-26" from="2016-12-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1003.5208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1003.5208</id><created>2010-03-26</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wuliang</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter Particles with Low Mass (and FTL)</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>9 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:0804.2680</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From the observed results, we deduced that the mass of the neutrino is about
10^(-1) eV and the mass of the fourth stable elementary particle (delta) is
about 10^(0) eV. While neutrino is related to electro-weak field, the fourth
stable elementary particle delta is related to gravitation-&quot;strong&quot; field, and
some new meta-stable baryons may appear near the TeV region. Therefore, a
twofold standard model diagram is proposed, and involves some experiment
phenomena: The new meta-stable baryons' decays produce delta particles, which
are helpful in explaining the Dijet asymmetry phenomena at LHC of CERN, the
different results for the Fermilab's data peak, etc; However, according to the
(B-L) invariance, the sterile &quot;neutrino&quot; about the event excess in MiniBooNe is
not the fourth neutrino but rather the delta particle; We think that the delta
particles are related to the phenomenon about neutrinos FTL, and that
anti-neutrinos are faster than neutrinos. FTL is also related to cosmic
inflation, singular point disappearance, a finite universe, and abnormal red
shift of SN Ia. Besides, the dark matter particles with low mass are helpful in
explaining missing solar neutrinos, the CMB angular power spectrum measured by
WMAP etc. Some experiments and observations are suggested, especially about the
measurement for the speed of gravitational wave c'. c' and c, in physics,
represent the limit speeds of moving particles made by different categories of
matter with different Lorentz factors. Lorentz transformation is compatible
with FTL. This will be helpful to look for new particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1202.1171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1202.1171</id><created>2012-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Czyz</keyname><forenames>Henryk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivashyn</keyname><forenames>Sergiy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korchin</keyname><forenames>Alexandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shekhovtsova</keyname><forenames>Olga</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-photon form factors of the pi0, eta and eta-prime mesons in the
  chiral theory with resonances</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables; two-column revtex4 style</comments><report-no>IFIC/11-63; FTUV/2011-1110</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 85 (2012) 094010</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.85.094010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a phenomenological approach which describes very well the
pi0, eta and eta-prime meson production in the two-photon interactions. The
simultaneous description of the pi0, eta and eta-prime meson two-photon form
factors is consistent with data in the space-like region. The obtained form
factors are implemented in the event generator EKHARA and the simulated cross
sections are presented. Uncertainties in the measured form factors coming from
the model dependence in Monte Carlo simulations are studied. The model
predictions for the form factor slopes at the origin are given and the high-Q2
limit is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4176</id><created>2014-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Souichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay and structure of the Hoyle state</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.90.061604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first $0^+$ resonant state of the $^{12}$C nucleus ${}^{12}$C$(0_2^+)$,
so called the Hoyle state, is investigated in a three-$\alpha$-particle
(3-$\alpha$) model. A wave function for the photodisintegration reaction of a
$^{12}$C bound state to 3-$\alpha$ final states is defined and calculated by
the Faddeev three-body formalism, in which three-body bound- and continuum
states are treated consistently. From the wave function at the Hoyle state
energy, I calculated distributions of outgoing $\alpha$-particles and density
distributions at interior region of the Hoyle state. Results show that a
process through a two-$\alpha$ resonant state is dominant in the decay and
contributions of the rest process are very small, less than 1 \%. There appear
some peaks in the interior density distribution corresponding to configurations
of an equilateral- and an isosceles triangles. It turns out that these results
are obtained independently of the choice of $\alpha$-particle interaction
models, when they are made to reproduce the Hoyle state energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04898</id><created>2015-01-20</created><updated>2015-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yucheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Raman fingerprint of semi-metal WTe2 from bulk to monolayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures and 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6 (2016) 19624</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep19624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tungsten ditelluride (WTe2), a layered transition-metal dichalcogenide (TMD),
has recently demonstrated an extremely large magnetoresistance effect, which is
unique among TMDs. This fascinating feature seems to be correlated with its
special electronic structure. Here, we report the observation of 6 Raman peaks
corresponding to the A_2^4, A_1^9, A_1^8, A_1^6, A_1^5 and A_1^2 phonons, from
the 33 Raman-active modes predicted for WTe2. This provides direct evidence to
distinguish the space group of WTe2 from that of other TMDs. Moreover, the
Raman evolution of WTe2 from bulk to monolayer is clearly revealed. It is
interesting to find that the A_2^4 mode, centered at ~109.8 cm-1, is forbidden
in a monolayer, which may be attributable to the transition of the point group
from C2v (bulk) to C2h (monolayer). Our work characterizes all observed Raman
peaks in the bulk and few-layer samples and provides a route to study the
physical properties of two-dimensional WTe2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.06506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.06506</id><created>2015-02-23</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adshead</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giblin</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Scully</keyname><forenames>Timothy R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sfakianakis</keyname><forenames>Evangelos I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge-preheating and the end of axion inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>32 pages, 13 Figures. V3: matches published version</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/12/034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the onset of the reheating epoch at the end of axion-driven
inflation where the axion is coupled to an Abelian, $U(1)$, gauge field via a
Chern-Simons interaction term. We focus primarily on $m^2\phi^2$ inflation and
explore the possibility that preheating can occur for a range of coupling
values consistent with recent observations and bounds on the overproduction of
primordial black holes. We find that for a wide range of parameters preheating
is efficient. In certain cases the inflaton is seen to transfer all its energy
to the gauge fields within a few oscillations. In most cases, we find that the
gauge fields on sub-horizon scales end preheating in an unpolarized state due
to the existence of strong rescattering between the inflaton and gauge-field
modes. We also present a preliminary study of an axion monodromy model coupled
to $U(1)$ gauge fields, seeing a similarly efficient preheating behavior as
well as indications that the coupling strength has an effect on the creation of
oscillons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00891</id><created>2015-08-04</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adshead</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sfakianakis</keyname><forenames>Evangelos I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermion production during and after axion inflation</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>36 pages, 12 Figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1511, no. 11, 021 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2015/11/021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study derivatively coupled fermions in axion-driven inflation,
specifically $m_\phi^2\phi^2$ and monodromy inflation, and calculate particle
production during the inflationary epoch and the post-inflationary axion
oscillations. During inflation, the rolling axion acts as an effective chemical
potential for helicity which biases the gravitational production of one fermion
helicity over the other. This mechanism allows for efficient gravitational
production of heavy fermion states that would otherwise be highly suppressed.
Following inflation, the axion oscillates and fermions with both helicities are
produced as the effective frequency of the fermion field changes
non-adiabatically. For certain values of the fermion mass and axion-fermion
coupling strength, the two helicity states are produced asymmetrically,
resulting in unequal number-densities of left- and right-helicity fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00414</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanel</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corominas-Murtra</keyname><forenames>Bernat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thurner</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical computation of frequency distributions of path-dependent
  processes by means of a non-multinomial maximum entropy approach</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Path-dependent stochastic processes are often non-ergodic and observables can
no longer be computed within the ensemble picture. The resulting mathematical
difficulties pose severe limits to the analytical understanding of
path-dependent processes. Their statistics is typically non-multinomial in the
sense that the multiplicities of the occurrence of states is not a multinomial
factor. The maximum entropy principle is tightly related to multinomial
processes, non-interacting systems, and to the ensemble picture; It loses its
meaning for path-dependent processes. Here we show that an equivalent to the
ensemble picture exists for path-dependent processes, such that the
non-multinomial statistics of the underlying dynamical process, by
construction, is captured correctly in a functional that plays the role of a
relative entropy. We demonstrate this for self-reinforcing P\'olya urn
processes, which explicitly generalise multinomial statistics. We demonstrate
the adequacy of this constructive approach towards non-multinomial pendants of
entropy by computing frequency and rank distributions of P\'olya urn processes.
We show how microscopic update rules of a path-dependent process allow us to
explicitly construct a non-multinomial entropy functional, that, when
maximized, predicts the time-dependent distribution function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01958</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walczak</keyname><forenames>Aleksandra M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Castello</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ginelli</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melillo</keyname><forenames>Stefania</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parisi</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viale</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavagna</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giardina</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author></authors><title>Local equilibrium in bird flocks</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph q-bio.QM</categories><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 1153-1157 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3846</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The correlated motion of flocks is an instance of global order emerging from
local interactions. An essential difference with analogous ferromagnetic
systems is that flocks are active: animals move relative to each other,
dynamically rearranging their interaction network. The effect of this
off-equilibrium element is well studied theoretically, but its impact on actual
biological groups deserves more experimental attention. Here, we introduce a
novel dynamical inference technique, based on the principle of maximum entropy,
which accodomates network rearrangements and overcomes the problem of slow
experimental sampling rates. We use this method to infer the strength and range
of alignment forces from data of starling flocks. We find that local bird
alignment happens on a much faster timescale than neighbour rearrangement.
Accordingly, equilibrium inference, which assumes a fixed interaction network,
gives results consistent with dynamical inference. We conclude that bird
orientations are in a state of local quasi-equilibrium over the interaction
length scale, providing firm ground for the applicability of statistical
physics in certain active systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06650</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruns</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pion correlation functions in position space from chiral perturbation
  theory with resonance exchange</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>Two minor typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Explicit expressions for pion correlators are derived in position-space,
employing Chiral Perturbation Theory (ChPT). Resonance exchange contributions
are included to test the range of applicability of the leading-order ChPT
expressions. The obtained results will be useful for a forthcoming Lattice-QCD
study of double parton distributions in the pion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09048</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kanemura</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishiwaki</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okada</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orikasa</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Seong Chan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Ryoutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>LHC 750 GeV Diphoton excess in a radiative seesaw model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 3 figures, 1 table (v1); 33 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables (v2,
  accepted version to PTEP)</comments><report-no>CTPU-15-29, KIAS-P15067, UT-HET-110</report-no><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2016) 123B04</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw164</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a possibility for explaining the recently announced 750\,GeV
diphoton excess by the ATLAS and the CMS experiments at the CERN LHC in a model
with multiple doubly charged particles, which was originally suggested for
explaining tiny neutrino masses through a three-loop effect in a natural way.
The enhanced radiatively generated effective coupling of a new singlet scalar
$S$ with diphoton with multiple charged particles in the loop enlarges the
production rate of $S$ in $pp\to S+X$ via photon fusion process and also the
decay width $\Gamma(S\to \gamma\gamma)$ even without assuming a tree level
production mechanism. We provide detailed analysis on the cases with or without
allowing the mixing between $S$ and the standard model Higgs doublet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02805</id><created>2016-01-12</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lionni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivasseau</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on the Intermediate Field Representation of Phi^2k Theory in Zero
  Dimension</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This expanded version corrects some misprints of the first version, details
completely the poof of Borel-Leroy summability and for $k=3$ in the complex
case provides a new improved representation which relies on ordinary convergent
Gaussian integrals rather than oscillatory integrals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05780</id><created>2016-01-21</created><updated>2016-12-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zi-Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Majorana-time-reversal symmetries: a fundamental principle for
  sign-problem-free quantum Monte Carlo simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con hep-lat</categories><comments>Accepted by Phys. Rev. Lett. Added more references and moved part of
  the paper into the Supplemental Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 267002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.267002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental open issue in physics is whether and how the fermion sign
problem in quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) simulations can be solved generically.
Here, we show that Majorana-time-reversal (MTR) symmetries can provide a
unifying principle to solve the fermion sign problem in interacting fermionic
models. By systematically classifying Majorana-bilinear operators according to
the anti-commuting MTR symmetries they respect, we rigorously proved that there
are two and only two fundamental symmetry classes which are sign-problem-free
and which we call the &quot;Majorana class&quot; and &quot;Kramers class&quot;, respectively. Novel
sign-problem-free models in the Majorana class include interacting topological
superconductors and interacting models of charge-4e superconductors. We believe
that our MTR unifying principle could shed new light on sign-problem-free QMC
simulation on strongly correlated systems and interacting topological matters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01056</id><created>2016-02-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Barry</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schloss</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glenn</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukin</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsworth</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical magnetic detection of single-neuron action potentials using
  quantum defects in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.atom-ph q-bio.NC</categories><comments>23 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>PNAS 2016 113 (49) 14133-14138; November 22, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1601513113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A key challenge for neuroscience is noninvasive, label-free sensing of action
potential (AP) dynamics in whole organisms with single-neuron resolution. Here,
we present a new approach to this problem: using nitrogen-vacancy (NV) quantum
defects in diamond to measure the time-dependent magnetic fields produced by
single-neuron APs. Our technique has a unique combination of features: (i) it
is noninvasive, as the light that probes the NV sensors stays within the
biocompatible diamond chip and does not enter the organism, enabling activity
monitoring over extended periods; (ii) it is label-free and should be widely
applicable to most organisms; (iii) it provides high spatial and temporal
resolution, allowing precise measurement of the AP waveforms and conduction
velocities of individual neurons; (iv) it directly determines AP propagation
direction through the inherent sensitivity of NVs to the associated AP magnetic
field vector; (v) it is applicable to neurons located within optically opaque
tissue or whole organisms, through which magnetic fields pass largely
unperturbed; and (vi) it is easy-to-use, scalable, and can be integrated with
existing techniques such as wide-field and superresolution imaging. We
demonstrate our method using excised single neurons from two invertebrate
species, marine worm and squid; and then by single-neuron AP magnetic sensing
exterior to whole, live, opaque marine worms for extended periods with no
adverse effect. The results lay the groundwork for real-time, noninvasive 3D
magnetic mapping of functional neuronal networks, ultimately with synapse-scale
(~10 nm) resolution and circuit-scale (~1 cm) field-of-view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08310</id><created>2016-02-26</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akal</keyname><forenames>Ibrahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egger</keyname><forenames>Reinhold</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villalba-Ch&#xe1;vez</keyname><forenames>Selym</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-dimensional approach to pair production in an oscillating electric
  field: Application to bandgap graphene layers</title><categories>hep-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 116006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.116006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of particle-antiparticle pairs from the quantum field
theoretic ground state in the presence of an external electric field is
studied. Starting with the quantum kinetic Boltzmann-Vlasov equation in
four-dimensional spacetime, we obtain the corresponding equations in lower
dimensionalities by way of spatial compactification. Our outcomes in
$2+1$-dimensions are applied to bandgap graphene layers, where the charge
carriers have the particular property of behaving like light massive Dirac
fermions. We calculate the single-particle distribution function for the case
of an electric field oscillating in time and show that the creation of
particle-hole pairs in this condensed matter system closely resembles
electron-positron pair production by the Schwinger effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08508</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-07-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Guoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kenan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Shijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Eryin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Mingzhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Huaqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhilin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denlinger</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Haitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Shoushan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Haijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Shuyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental observation of topological Fermi arcs in type-II Weyl
  semimetal MoTe2</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>submitted on 01/29/2016. Nature Physics, in press. Spectroscopic
  evidence of the Fermi arcs from two complementary surface sensitive probes -
  ARPES and STS. A comparison of the calculated band structure for T_d and 1T'
  phase to identify the topological Fermi arcs in the T_d phase is also
  included in the supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 1105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3871</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weyl semimetal is a new quantum state of matter [1-12] hosting the condensed
matter physics counterpart of relativisticWeyl fermion [13] originally
introduced in high energy physics. The Weyl semimetal realized in the TaAs
class features multiple Fermi arcs arising from topological surface states [10,
11, 14-16] and exhibits novel quantum phenomena, e.g., chiral anomaly induced
negative mag-netoresistance [17-19] and possibly emergent supersymmetry [20].
Recently it was proposed theoretically that a new type (type-II) of Weyl
fermion [21], which does not have counterpart in high energy physics due to the
breaking of Lorentz invariance, can emerge as topologically-protected touching
between electron and hole pockets. Here, we report direct spectroscopic
evidence of topological Fermi arcs in the predicted type-II Weyl semimetal
MoTe2 [22-24]. The topological surface states are confirmed by directly
observing the surface states using bulk-and surface-sensitive angle-resolved
photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES), and the quasi-particle interference (QPI)
pattern between the two putative Fermi arcs in scanning tunneling microscopy
(STM). Our work establishes MoTe2 as the first experimental realization of
type-II Weyl semimetal, and opens up new opportunities for probing novel
phenomena such as exotic magneto-transport [21] in type-II Weyl semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06945</id><created>2016-04-23</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pavlosiuk</keyname><forenames>Orest</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swatek</keyname><forenames>Przemys&#x142;aw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wi&#x15b;niewski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant magnetoresistance, three-dimensional Fermi surface and origin of
  resistivity plateau in YSb semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 1 table + Supplementary Materials (3 pages, 2
  figures, 1 table)</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 38691 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep38691</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Very strong magnetoresistance and a resistivity plateau impeding low
temperature divergence due to insulating bulk are hallmarks of topological
insulators and are also present in topological semimetals where the plateau is
induced by magnetic field, when time-reversal symmetry (protecting surface
states in topological insulators) is broken. Similar features were observed in
a simple rock-salt-structure LaSb, leading to a suggestion of the possible
non-trivial topology of 2D states in this compound. We show that its sister
compound YSb is also characterized by giant magnetoresistance exceeding one
thousand percent and low-temperature plateau of resistivity. We thus performed
in-depth analysis of YSb Fermi surface by band calculations, magnetoresistance,
and Shubnikov--de Haas effect measurements, which reveals only
three-dimensional Fermi sheets. Kohler scaling applied to magnetoresistance
data accounts very well for its low-temperature upturn behavior. The
field-angle-dependent magnetoresistance demonstrates a 3D-scaling yielding
effective mass anisotropy perfectly agreeing with electronic structure and
quantum oscillations analysis, thus providing further support for 3D-Fermi
surface scenario of magnetotransport, without necessity of invoking
topologically non-trivial 2D states. We discuss data implying that analogous
field-induced properties of LaSb can also be well understood in the framework
of 3D multiband model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08031</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Vicente</keyname><forenames>Julio I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Streltsov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>The power of the resource theory of genuine quantum coherence</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages. The content of this paper has been merged with another, see
  arXiv:1511.08346</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Any quantum resource theory is based on free states and free operations,
i.e., states and operations which can be created and performed at no cost. In
the resource theory of coherence free states are diagonal in some fixed basis,
and free operations are those which cannot create coherence for some particular
experimental realization. Recently, some problems of this approach have been
discussed, and new sets of operations have been proposed to resolve these
problems. As an example for such a problem, a quantum operation can be
incoherent in one particular experimental realization, but it still can create
large amount of coherence in another. This problem is resolved by the framework
of genuine quantum coherence. Here, we investigate this concept further and
study other more general sets of operations which cannot create coherence in
any experimental realization. We analyze in detail the mathematical structure
of this class of maps and use this to study possible state transformations
under these operations. We show that deterministic manipulation is severely
limited, even in the asymptotic settings. In particular, this framework does
not have a unique golden unit, i.e., there is no single state from which all
other states can be created deterministically with the free operations. On the
other hand, we show that these theories allow for a richer structure in what
comes to stochastic manipulation of states. In particular, we determine the
optimal probability of conversion among pure states with genuinely incoherent
operations. Still, the aforementioned limitations suggest that any reasonably
powerful resource theory of coherence must contain free operations which can
potentially create coherence in some experimental realization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08193</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jafari</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Transformation of Baryon- and Lepton-Nonconserving Processes</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, LATEX2e; revised to clarify the claim, conclusion persist</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider discrete transformations ($C, P, T$ and $CP$) of baryon- and
lepton-nonconserving processes. It has long been thought that values ($\pm 1,
\pm i$) form the correct set of fermionic arbitrary phases for discrete
transformations. In this paper we show that this idea is not generally true. In
order to count the number of fundamental fermions in a process, $F$ number has
been introduced. According to our evaluation for any operator which breaks
$B-L$ symmetry and violate $F$ number the set of values ($\pm 1, \pm i$) is not
the correct set of fermionic arbitrary phases, due to the fact that discrete
transformations of such operators will change by altering the fermionic phases
from $\pm 1$ to $\pm i$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08281</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dell'Anna</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salberger</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbiero</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trombettoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korepin</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Violation of Cluster Decomposition and Absence of Light-Cones in Local
  Integer and Half-Integer Spin Chains</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155140 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the ground state correlation functions of an exactly solvable
chain of integer spins, recently introduced in [R. Movassagh and P. W. Shor,
arXiv:1408.1657], whose ground-state can be expressed in terms of a uniform
superposition of all colored Motzkin paths. Our analytical results show that
for spin s$\ge$2 there is a violation of the cluster decomposition property.
This has to be contrasted with s=1, where the cluster property holds.
Correspondingly, for s=1 one gets a light-cone profile in the propagation of
excitations after a local quench, while the cone is absent for s=2, as shown by
time dependent density-matrix-renormalization-group. Moreover, we introduce an
original solvable model of half-integer spins which we refer to as Fredkin spin
chain, whose ground-state can be expressed in terms of superposition of all
Dyck paths. For this model we exactly calculate the magnetization and
correlation functions, finding that for s=1/2, a cone-like propagation occurs
while for higher spins, s$\ge$3/2, the colors prevent any cone formation and
clustering is violated, together with square root deviation from the area law
for the entanglement entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00599</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertrand</keyname><forenames>Thibault</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peixinho</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Shomeek</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacMinn</keyname><forenames>Christopher W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of swelling and drying in a spherical gel</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 6, 064010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.6.064010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Swelling is a volumetric-growth process in which a porous material expands by
spontaneous imbibition of additional pore fluid. Swelling is distinct from
other growth processes in that it is inherently poromechanical: Local expansion
of the pore structure requires that additional fluid be drawn from elsewhere in
the material, or into the material from across the boundaries. Here, we study
the swelling and subsequent drying of a sphere of hydrogel. We develop a
dynamic model based on large-deformation poromechanics and the theory of ideal
elastomeric gels, and we compare the predictions of this model with a series of
experiments performed with polyacrylamide spheres. We use the model and the
experiments to study the complex internal dynamics of swelling and drying, and
to highlight the fundamentally transient nature of these strikingly different
processes. Although we assume spherical symmetry, the model also provides
insight into the transient patterns that form and then vanish during swelling
as well as the risk of fracture during drying.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08474</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08474</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adshead</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giblin</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Scully</keyname><forenames>Timothy R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sfakianakis</keyname><forenames>Evangelos I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetogenesis from axion inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>38 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1610 (2016) 039</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we compute the production of magnetic fields in models of axion
inflation coupled to the hypercharge sector of the Standard Model through a
Chern-Simons interaction term. We make the simplest choice of a quadratic
inflationary potential and use lattice simulations to calculate the magnetic
field strength, helicity and correlation length at the end of inflation. For
small values of the axion-gauge field coupling strength the results agree with
no-backreaction calculations and estimates found in the literature. For larger
couplings the helicity of the magnetic field differs from the no-backreaction
estimate and depends strongly on the comoving wavenumber. We estimate the
post-inflationary evolution of the magnetic field based on known results for
the evolution of helical and non-helical magnetic fields. The magnetic fields
produced by axion inflation with large couplings to $U(1)_Y$ can reach $B_{\rm
eff} \gtrsim 10^{-16}\, {\rm G}$, exhibiting a field strength $B_{\rm phys}
\approx 10^{-13}\, {\rm G}$ and a correlation length $\lambda_{\rm
phys}\approx10\, {\rm pc}$. This result is insensitive to the exact value of
the coupling, as long as the coupling is large enough to allow for
instantaneous preheating. Depending on the assumptions for the physical
processes that determine blazar properties, these fields can be found
consistent with blazar observations based on the value of $B_{\rm eff}$.
Finally, the intensity of the magnetic field for large coupling can be enough
to satisfy the requirements for a recently proposed baryogenesis mechanism,
which utilizes the chiral anomaly of the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08889</id><created>2016-06-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gardella</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marre</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author></authors><title>A tractable method for describing complex couplings between neurons and
  population rate</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>eNeuro 3(4) e0160-15.2016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1523/ENEURO.0160-15.2016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neurons within a population are strongly correlated, but how to simply
capture these correlations is still a matter of debate. Recent studies have
shown that the activity of each cell is influenced by the population rate,
defined as the summed activity of all neurons in the population. However, an
explicit, tractable model for these interactions is still lacking. Here we
build a probabilistic model of population activity that reproduces the firing
rate of each cell, the distribution of the population rate, and the linear
coupling between them. This model is tractable, meaning that its parameters can
be learned in a few seconds on a standard computer even for large population
recordings. We inferred our model for a population of 160 neurons in the
salamander retina. In this population, single-cell firing rates depended in
unexpected ways on the population rate. In particular, some cells had a
preferred population rate at which they were most likely to fire. These complex
dependencies could not be explained by a linear coupling between the cell and
the population rate. We designed a more general, still tractable model that
could fully account for these non-linear dependencies. We thus provide a simple
and computationally tractable way to learn models that reproduce the dependence
of each neuron on the population rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09293</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09293</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-08-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berezinsky</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gazizov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalashev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cascade photons as test of protons in UHECR</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Version accepted for publication in Astroparticle Physics. Most
  recent neutrino flux limits by IceCube were included to the tables. 14 pages,
  13 figures</comments><report-no>INR-TH-2016-020</report-no><journal-ref>Astroparticle Physics, Volume 84, November 2016, Pages 52-61</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2016.08.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An isotropic component of high energy $\gamma$-ray spectrum measured by Fermi
LAT constrains the proton component of UHECR. The strongest restriction comes
from the highest, $(580-820)$ GeV, energy bin. One more constraint on the
proton component is provided by the IceCube upper bound on ultrahigh energy
cosmogenic neutrino flux. We study the influence of these restrictions on the
source properties, such as evolution and distribution of sources, their energy
spectrum and admixture of nuclei. We also study the sensitivity of restrictions
to various Fermi LAT galactic foreground models (model B being less
restrictive), to the choice of extragalactic background light model and to
overall normalization of the energy spectrum. We claim that the
$\gamma$-ray-cascade constraints are stronger than the neutrino ones, and that
however many proton models are viable. The basic parameters of such models are
relatively large $\gamma_g$ and not very large $z_{\max}$. The allowance for
H$e^4$ admixture also relaxes the restrictions. However we foresee that future
CTA measurements of $\gamma$-ray spectrum at $E_\gamma \simeq (600 - 800)$ GeV,
as well as resolving of more individual $\gamma$-ray sources, may rule out the
proton-dominated cosmic ray models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09595</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Oitmaa</keyname><forenames>Jaan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Rajiv R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spiral versus modulated collinear phases in the quantum ANNNH model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214430, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the discovery of spiral and modulated collinear phases in
several magnetic materials, we investigate the magnetic properties of
Heisenberg spin S=1/2 antiferromagnets in 2 and 3 dimensions, with frustration
arising from 2nd-neighbor couplings in one axial direction (the ANNNH model).
Our results clearly demonstrate the presence of an incommensurate spiral phase
at T=0 in 2 dimensions, extending to finite temperatures in 3 dimensions. The
crossover between N\'eel and spiral order occurs at a value of the frustration
parameter considerably above the classical value 0.25, a sign of substantial
quantum fluctuations. We also investigate a possible modulated collinear phase
with a wavelength of 4 lattice spacings, and find that it has substantially
higher energy and hence is not realized in the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04251</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Degrassi</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giardino</keyname><forenames>Pier Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maltoni</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagani</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the Higgs self coupling via single Higgs production at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>34 pages, 13 figures, 5 tables; V2: New appendix A added on the
  comparison with the Effective Field Theory approach; V3: Journal version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1612, 080 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2016)080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to determine the trilinear Higgs self coupling that is
alternative to the direct measurement of Higgs pair production total cross
sections and differential distributions. The method relies on the effects that
electroweak loops featuring an anomalous trilinear coupling would imprint on
single Higgs production at the LHC. We first calculate these contributions to
all the phenomenologically relevant Higgs production ($gg{\rm F}$, VBF, $WH$,
$ZH$, $t\bar tH$) and decay ($\gamma \gamma$, $WW^{*}/ZZ^{*}\to 4f$, $b\bar b$,
$\tau \tau$) modes at the LHC and then estimate the sensitivity to the
trilinear coupling via a one-parameter fit to the single Higgs measurements at
the LHC 8 TeV. We find that the bounds on the self coupling are already
competitive with those from Higgs pair production and will be further improved
in the current and next LHC runs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07808</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Cong Son</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Seng Ghee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jalil</keyname><forenames>Mansoor B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zilong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivitsky</keyname><forenames>Leonid A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of exchange interaction in nitrogen vacancy centre-based
  magnetometry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245424 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a multilayer device comprising of a thin-film-based ferromagnetic
hetero-structure (FMH) deposited on a diamond layer doped with nitrogen vacancy
centers (NVC's). We find that when the NVC's are in close proximity (1-2 nm)
with the FMH, the exchange energy is comparable to, and may even surpass the
magnetostatic interaction energy. This calls for the need to consider and
utilize both effects in magnetometry based on NVC's in diamond. As the distance
between the FMH and NVC is decreased to the sub-nanometer scale, the
exponential increase in the exchange energy suggests spintronic applications of
NVC beyond magnetometry, such as detection of spin-Hall effect or spin
currents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07927</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Baoyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Tiecheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yunpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Pengfei</forenames></author></authors><title>Cold and Hot Nuclear Matter Effects on Charmonium Production in p+Pb
  Collisions at LHC Energy</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 765 (2017) 323-327</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.12.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study cold and hot nuclear matter effects on charmonium production in p+Pb
collisions at $\sqrt{s_\text{NN}}=5.02$ TeV in a transport approach. At the
forward rapidity, the cold medium effect on all the $c\bar c$ states and the
hot medium effect on the excited $c\bar c$ states only can explain well the
$J/\psi$ and $\psi'$ yield and transverse momentum distribution measured by the
ALICE collaboration, and we predict a significantly larger $\psi'$ $p_\text{T}$
broadening in comparison with $J/\psi$. However, we can not reproduce the
$J/\psi$ and $\psi'$ data at the backward rapidity with reasonable cold and hot
medium effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02786</id><created>2016-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum phase transition induced by real-space topology</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep, 6, 39416 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep39416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum phase transition (QPT), including both topological and symmetry
breaking types, is usually induced by the change of global parameters, such as
external fields or global coupling constants. In this work, we demonstrate the
existence of QPT induced by the real-space topology of the system. We
investigate the groundstate properties of the tight-binding model on a
honeycomb lattice with the torus geometry based on exact results. It is shown
that the ground state experiences a second- order QPT, exhibiting the scaling
behavior, when the torus switches to a tube, which reveals the connection
between quantum phase and the real-space topology of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03869</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robe</keyname><forenames>Dominic M.</forenames><affiliation>Emory U</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boettcher</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>Emory U</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sibani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames><affiliation>Odense U</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yunker</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames><affiliation>Georgia Tech</affiliation></author></authors><title>Record Dynamics: Direct Experimental Evidence from Jammed Colloids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, RevTex, changed title, many updates and corrections; for
  related information, see http://www.physics.emory.edu/faculty/boettcher/</comments><journal-ref>EPL 116 (2016) 38003</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/38003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a broad class of complex materials a quench leads to a multi-scaled
relaxation process known as aging. To explain its commonality and the
astounding insensitivity to most microscopic details, record dynamics (RD)
posits that a small set of increasingly rare and irreversible events, so called
quakes, controls the dynamics. While key predictions of RD are known to concur
with a number of experimental and simulational results, its basic assumption on
the nature of quake statistics has proven extremely difficult to verify
experimentally. The careful distinction of rare (&quot;record&quot;) cage-breaking events
from in-cage rattle accomplished in previous experiments on jammed colloids,
enables us to extract the first direct experimental evidence for the
fundamental hypothesis of RD that the rate of quakes decelerates with the
inverse of the system age. The resulting description shows the predicted growth
of the particle mean square displacement and of a mesoscopic lengthscale with
the logarithm of time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05719</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krajewski</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lalak</keyname><forenames>Zygmunt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewicki</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olszewski</keyname><forenames>Pawe&#x142;</forenames></author></authors><title>Domain walls and gravitational waves in the Standard Model</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><journal-ref>JCAP12(2016)036</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/12/036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study domain walls which can be created in the Standard Model under the
assumption that it is valid up to very high energy scales. We focus on domain
walls interpolating between the physical electroweak vacuum and the global
minimum appearing at very high field strengths. The creation of the network
which ends up in the electroweak vacuum percolating through the Universe is not
as difficult to obtain as one may expect, although it requires certain tuning
of initial conditions. Our numerical simulations confirm that such domain walls
would swiftly decay and thus cannot dominate the Universe. We discuss the
possibility of detection of gravitational waves produced in this scenario. We
have found that for the standard cosmology the energy density of these
gravitational waves is too small to be observed in present and planned
detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08958</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khojali</keyname><forenames>Mohammed Omer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goyal</keyname><forenames>Ashok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Mukesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornell</keyname><forenames>Alan S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimal Spin-3/2 Dark Matter in a simple $s$-channel model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, Version accepted for publication in EPJC</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4589-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a spin~-~3/2 fermionic dark matter candidate (DM) interacting
with Standard Model fermions through a vector mediator in the $s$-channel. We
find that for pure vector couplings almost the entire parameter space of the DM
and mediator mass consistent with the observed relic density is ruled out by
the direct detection observations through DM-nucleon elastic scattering
cross-sections. In contrast, for pure axial-vector coupling, the most stringent
constraints are obtained from mono-jet searches at the Large Hadron Collider.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00422</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Sherman</keyname><forenames>Nicholas E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imai</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Rajiv R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear relaxation rates in the Herbertsmithite Kagome antiferromagnets
  ZnCu3(OH)6Cl2</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 140415(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.140415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Local spectral functions and Nuclear Magnetic Relaxation (NMR) rates, 1/T1,
for the spin-half Heisenberg antiferromagnet on the Kagome Lattice are
calculated using Moriyas Gaussian approximation, as well as through an
extrapolation of multiple frequency moments. The temperature dependence of the
calculated rates is compared with the oxygen 1/T1 NMR data in Herbertsmithite.
We find that the Gaussian approximation for 1/T1 shows behavior qualitatively
similar to experiments with a sharp drop in rates at low temperatures,
consistent with a spin-gapped behavior. However, this approximation
significantly underestimates the magnitude of 1/T1 even at room temperature.
Rates obtained from extrapolation of multiple frequency moments give very good
agreement with the room temperature NMR data with J = 195 +/- 20 K and
hyperfine couplings determined independently from other measurements. The use
of multiple frequency moments also leads to additional low frequency weight in
the local structure factors. The convergence of our calculations with higher
frequency moments breaks down at low temperatures suggesting the existence of
longer range dynamic correlations in the system despite the very short-range
static correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00119</id><created>2016-10-01</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruns</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the sigma sigma term</title><categories>nucl-th hep-lat</categories><comments>Two minor typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give some estimates for the light-quark mass dependence of the pole
position of the sigma ($f_{0}(500)$) resonance in the complex energy plane,
with the help of a chiral Lagrangian for the resonance field and some input
from hadronic models constrained by Chiral Perturbation Theory and elastic
unitarity. We also speculate on the fate of the sigma resonance when the quark
masses become unphysically large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02142</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02142</id><created>2016-10-07</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xc1;valos-Ovando</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastrogiuseppe</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulloa</keyname><forenames>Sergio E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries and hybridization in the indirect interaction between
  magnetic moments in MoS$_{2}$ nanoflakes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245429 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245429</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Ruderman-Kittel-Kasuya-Yosida interaction between magnetic
impurities embedded in $p$-doped transition metal dichalcogenide triangular
flakes. The role of underlying symmetries is exposed by analyzing the
interaction as a function of impurity separation along zigzag and armchair
trajectories, in specific parts of the sample. The large spin-orbit coupling in
these materials produces strongly anisotropic interactions, including a
Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya component that can be sizable and tunable. We consider
impurities hybridized to different orbitals of the host transition-metal and
identify specific characteristics for onsite and hollow site adsorption. In the
onsite case, the different components of the interaction have similar
magnitude, while for the hollow site, the Ising component dominates. We also
study the dependence of the interaction with the level of hole doping, which
supplies a further degree of tunability. Our results could provide ways of
controlling helical long range spin order in magnetic impurity arrays embedded
in these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03519</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heinze</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jorjadze</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantization of the ${\rm AdS}_3$ Superparticle on ${\rm
  OSP}(1|2)^2/{\rm SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25+1 pages; v2: minor changes, references added and updated; v3:
  minor changes, one reference added, matches published version</comments><report-no>FU-Ph 10/2016 (06), NORDITA-2016-100, ZMP-HH/16-22</report-no><msc-class>17B08, 53D50, 81S10</msc-class><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B915 (2017) 44-68</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.11.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze ${\rm AdS}_3$ superparticle dynamics on the coset ${\rm OSP}(1|2)
\times {\rm OSP}(1|2)/{\rm SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$. The system is quantized in
canonical coordinates obtained by gauge invariant Hamiltonian reduction. The
left and right Noether charges of a massive particle are parametrized by
coadjoint orbits of a timelike element of $\frak{osp}(1|2)$. Each chiral sector
is described by two bosonic and two fermionic canonical coordinates
corresponding to a superparticle with superpotential $W=q-m/q$, where $m$ is
the particle mass. Canonical quantization then provides a quantum realization
of $\frak{osp}(1|2)\oplus\frak{osp}(1|2)$. For the massless particle the chiral
charges lie on the coadjoint orbit of a nilpotent element of $\frak{osp}(1|2)$
and each of them depends only on one real fermion, which demonstrates the
underlying $\kappa$-symmetry. These remaining left and right fermionic
variables form a canonical pair and the system is described by four bosonic and
two fermionic canonical coordinates. Due to conformal invariance of the
massless particle, the $\frak{osp}(1|2)\oplus\frak{osp} (1|2)$ extends to the
corresponding superconformal algebra $\frak{osp}(2|4)$. Its 19 charges are
given by all real quadratic combinations of the canonical coordinates, which
trivializes their quantization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03578</id><created>2016-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maekawa</keyname><forenames>Sadamichi</forenames></author></authors><title>New p- and n-type ferromagnetic semiconductors: Cr-doped BaZn2As2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1601.05165</comments><journal-ref>AIP Advances 7, 055805 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973208</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find new ferromagnetic semiconductors, Cr-doped BaZn2As2, by employing a
combined method of the density functional theory and the quantum Monte Carlo
simulation. Due to a narrow band gap of 0.2 eV in host BaZn2As2 and the
different hybridization of 3d orbitals of Cr impurity, the impurity bound
states have been induced both below the top of valence band and above the
bottom of conduction band. The long-range ferromagnetic coupling between Cr
impurities is obtained with both p- and n-type carriers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08334</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nassif</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo Francisco do</forenames></author></authors><title>Connection between Symmetrical Special Relativity and the Gravitational
  Bose Einstein Condensate of a Gravastar/Dark Energy Star: Are there
  singularities in spacetime like black holes?</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures. See correlated paper in arXiv:1308.5258 or in
  http://www.worldscientific.com/worldscinet/ijmpd?journalTabs=read</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim to search for a connection between an invariant minimum speed that
breaks down the Lorentz symmetry and the Gravitational Bose Einstein Condensate
(GBEC), which is the central core of a star of gravitating vacuum
(Gravastar/Dark Energy Star) by introducing a cosmological constant into
compact objects. This model was designed to circumvent the embarrassment
generated by the paradoxes of a singularity as the final stage of a
gravitational collapse, by introducing in place of the singularity of event
horizon a spatial-temporal phase transition, a concept with which the causal
structure of Symmetrical Special Relativity (SSR) helps us to elucidate by
providing a quantum interpretation for GBEC and explaining the origin of
anisotropy, which has been introduced in ad-hoc way before in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08585</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Magana-Loaiza</keyname><forenames>Omar S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Leon</keyname><forenames>Israel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirhosseini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fickler</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Safari</keyname><forenames>Akbar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mick</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author><author><keyname>McIntyre</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banzer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodenburg</keyname><forenames>Brandon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exotic Looped Trajectories of Photons in Three-Slit Interference</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7, 13987 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13987</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The validity of the superposition principle and of Born's rule are
well-accepted tenants of quantum mechanics. Surprisingly, it has recently been
predicted that the intensity pattern formed in a three-slit experiment is
seemingly in contradiction with the predictions of the most conventional form
of the superposition principle when exotic looped trajectories are taken into
account. However, the probability of observing such paths is typically very
small and thus rendering them extremely difficult to measure. In this work, we
confirm the validity of Born's rule and present the first experimental
observation of these exotic trajectories as additional paths for the light by
directly measuring their contribution to the formation of optical interference
fringes. We accomplish this by enhancing the electromagnetic near-fields in the
vicinity of the slits through the excitation of surface plasmons. This process
effectively increases the probability of occurrence of these exotic
trajectories, demonstrating that they are related to the near-field component
of the photon's wavefunction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01045</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Toppaladoddi</keyname><forenames>Srikanth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wettlaufer</keyname><forenames>John S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Mechanics and the Climatology of the Arctic Sea Ice
  Thickness Distribution</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures; Journal of Statistical Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1704-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the seasonal changes in the thickness distribution of Arctic sea
ice, $g(h)$, under climate forcing. Our analytical and numerical approach is
based on a Fokker-Planck equation for $g(h)$ (Toppaladoddi \&amp; Wettlaufer
\emph{Phys. Rev. Lett.} {\bf 115}, 148501, 2015), in which the thermodynamic
growth rates are determined using observed climatology. In particular, the
Fokker-Planck equation is coupled to the observationally consistent
thermodynamic model of Eisenman \&amp; Wettlaufer (\emph{Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci.
USA} {\bf 106}, pp. 28-32, 2009). We find that due to the combined effects of
thermodynamics and mechanics, $g(h)$ spreads during winter and contracts during
summer. This behavior is in agreement with recent satellite observations from
CryoSat-2 (Kwok \&amp; Cunningham, \emph{Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A} {\bf 373},
20140157, 2015). Because $g(h)$ is a probability density function, we quantify
all of the key moments (e.g., mean thickness, fraction of thin/thick ice, mean
albedo, relaxation time scales) as greenhouse-gas radiative forcing, $\Delta
F_0$, increases. The mean ice thickness decays exponentially with $\Delta F_0$,
but {\em much slower} than do solely thermodynamic models. This exhibits the
crucial role that ice mechanics plays in maintaining the ice cover, by
redistributing thin ice to thick ice--far more rapidly than can thermal growth
alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03271</id><created>2016-11-10</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Loiseau</keyname><forenames>Jean-Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunton</keyname><forenames>Steven L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained Sparse Galerkin Regression</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although major advances have been achieved over the past decades for the
reduction and identification of linear systems, deriving nonlinear low-order
models still is a chal- lenging task. In this work, we develop a new
data-driven framework to identify nonlinear reduced-order models of a fluid by
combining dimensionality reductions techniques (e.g. proper orthogonal
decomposition) and sparse regression techniques from machine learn- ing. In
particular, we extend the sparse identification of nonlinear dynamics (SINDy)
algorithm to enforce physical constraints in the regression, namely
energy-preserving quadratic nonlinearities. The resulting models, hereafter
referred to as Galerkin regression models, incorporate many beneficial aspects
of Galerkin projection, but without the need for a full-order or high-fidelity
solver to project the Navier-Stokes equations. Instead, the most parsimonious
nonlinear model is determined that is consistent with observed mea- surement
data and satisfies necessary constraints. Galerkin regression models also
readily generalize to include higher-order nonlinear terms that model the
effect of truncated modes. The effectiveness of Galerkin regression is
demonstrated on two different flow configurations: the two-dimensional flow
past a circular cylinder and the shear-driven cavity flow. For both cases, the
accuracy of the identified models compare favorably against reduced-order
models obtained from a standard Galerkin projection procedure. Present results
highlight the importance of cubic nonlinearities in the construction of
accurate nonlinear low-dimensional approximations of the flow systems,
something which cannot be readily obtained using a standard Galerkin projection
of the Navier-Stokes equations. Finally, the entire code base for our
constrained sparse Galerkin regression algorithm is freely available online.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05259</id><created>2016-11-16</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agliozzo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikutta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pignata</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ingallinera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buemi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umana</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leto</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trigilio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noriega-Crespo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paladini</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bufano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavallaro</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>New ATCA, ALMA and VISIR observations of the candidate LBV SK-67266
  (S61): the nebular mass from modelling 3D density distributions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures. Authors list corrected. In press in MNRAS.
  RHOCUBE code available online ( https://github.com/rnikutta/rhocube )</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2986</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new observations of the nebula around the Magellanic candidate
Luminous Blue Variable S61. These comprise high-resolution data acquired with
the Australia Telescope Compact Array (ATCA), the Atacama Large
Millimetre/Submillimetre Array (ALMA), and VISIR at the Very Large Telescope
(VLT). The nebula was detected only in the radio, up to 17 GHz. The 17 GHz ATCA
map, with 0.8 arcsec resolution, allowed a morphological comparison with the
H$\alpha$ Hubble Space Telescope image. The radio nebula resembles a spherical
shell, as in the optical. The spectral index map indicates that the radio
emission is due to free-free transitions in the ionised, optically thin gas,
but there are hints of inhomogeneities. We present our new public code RHOCUBE
to model 3D density distributions, and determine via Bayesian inference the
nebula's geometric parameters. We applied the code to model the electron
density distribution in the S61 nebula. We found that different distributions
fit the data, but all of them converge to the same ionised mass, ~0.1 $\rm
M\odot$, which is an order of magnitude smaller than previous estimates. We
show how the nebula models can be used to derive the mass-loss history with
high-temporal resolution. The nebula was probably formed through stellar winds,
rather than eruptions. From the ALMA and VISIR non-detections, plus the derived
extinction map, we deduce that the infrared emission observed by space
telescopes must arise from extended, diffuse dust within the ionised region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10128</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hong-Bang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Yi-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Dao-Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Yang-Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of a sealed high gas pressure THGEM detector and response of Alpha
  particle spectra</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>8 pages, 15 figures, to be published in Chinese Physics C</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/4/046001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A sealed high gas pressure detector working in pure argon is assembled. It
consists of a 5 cm $\times$ 5 cm PCB THGEM (THick Gaseous Electron
Multipliers). The detector structure and experimental setup are described. The
performances under high pressure of 2 atm mainly consist in selecting optimal
voltages for ionization region and induction region. The dependence of the
shape of Alpha particle spectra measured with relative gas gain on gas pressure
(1.3 $\sim$ 2.0 atm) has been studied. The 8 groups of relative gas gain versus
working voltage of THGEM expressed by weighting filed $E/P$ are normalized,
being consistent with theory. The results show that the air tightness of the
chamber is good measured by a sensitive barometer and checked with gas gain.
The experimental results are compared with Monte Carlo simulation on energy
deposition without gas gain involved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00820</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grudinin</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huet</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorodetsky</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsko</keyname><forenames>Andrey B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maleki</keyname><forenames>Lute</forenames></author></authors><title>High-contrast Kerr Frequency Combs</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kerr frequency combs with depressed harmonic at the optical pump frequency
are theoretically explained and experimentally demonstrated. This result is
achieved in a MgF$_2$ photonic belt resonator having reduced density of modes
in its spectrum and configured with the add-drop optical couplers. \copyright
2016 California Institute of Technology. Government sponsorship
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00952</id><created>2016-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Lamura</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiroka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordignon</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moroni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Renzi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretta</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caglieris</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurmehl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimoyama</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gastiasoro</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of magnetic dopants in the phase diagram of Sm1111 pnictides: The
  Mn case</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 13 figures. Accepted on Physical Review B</comments><report-no>NBI CMT 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214517 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deliberate insertion of magnetic Mn dopants in the Fe sites of the
optimally-doped SmFeAsO0.88-F0.12 iron-based superconductor can modify in a
controlled way its electronic properties. The resulting phase diagram was
investigated across a wide range of manganese contents (x) by means of
muon-spin spectroscopy (muSR), both in zero- and in transverse fields,
respectively, to probe the magnetic and the superconducting order. The pure
superconducting phase (at x &lt; 0.03) is replaced by a crossover region at
intermediate Mn values (0.03 =&lt; x &lt; 0.08), where superconductivity coexists
with static magnetic order. After completely suppressing superconductivity for
x = 0.08, a further increase in Mn content reinforces the natural tendency
towards antiferromagnetic correlations among the magnetic Mn ions. The sharp
drop of Tc and the induced magnetic order in the presence of magnetic
disorder/dopants, such as Mn, are both consistent with a recent theoretical
model of unconventional superconductors [M. Gastiasoro et al., ArXiv
1606.09495], which includes correlation-enhanced RKKY-couplings between the
impurity moments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02270</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Ron W</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Reactions: Mechanism and Spectroscopy. Volume I</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>251 pages; 75,542 words</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Volume I of two. This document could be of interest to anyone who wants to
have a comprehensive inside information about the research in nuclear physics
from its early beginnings to later years. It describes highlights of my
research work from the late 1950s to the late 1980s. It presents a panorama of
experimental and theoretical methods used in the study of nuclear reactions
(their mechanism and their application to the study of nuclear structure), the
panorama ranging from simple detection techniques used in the early research to
more complicated in later years, from simple theoretical interpretations to
more complicated descriptions. This document describes my research work in
Poland, Australia, Switzerland and Germany using various particle accelerators
and a wide range of experimental and theoretical techniques. It presents a
typical cross section of experimental and theoretical work in the early and
later stages of nuclear research in the field of nuclear reactions
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02271</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2016-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Ron W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Reactions: Mechanism and Spectroscopy. Volume II</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>234 pages; 64,187 words</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Volume II of two. This document could be of interest to anyone who wants to
have a comprehensive inside information about the research in nuclear physics
from its early beginnings to later years. It describes highlights of my
research work from the late 1950s to the late 1980s. It presents a panorama of
experimental and theoretical methods used in the study of nuclear reactions
(their mechanism and their application to the study of nuclear structure), the
panorama ranging from simple detection techniques used in the early research to
more complicated in later years, from simple theoretical interpretations to
more complicated descriptions. This document describes my research work in
Poland, Australia, Switzerland and Germany using various particle accelerators
and a wide range of experimental and theoretical techniques. It presents a
typical cross section of experimental and theoretical work in the early and
later stages of nuclear research in the field of nuclear reactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02520</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Matano</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yatagai</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maeda</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Guo-qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Full-gap superconductivity in non-centrosymmetric Re$_6$Zr,
  Re$_{27}$Zr$_{5}$ and Re$_{24}$Zr$_{5}$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Phys. Rev. B (in press)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214513 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214513</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-centrosymmetric superconductor Re$_6$Zr has attracted much interest, for
its possible unconventional superconducting state with time reversal symmetry
broken. Here we report the $^{185/187}$Re nuclear quadrupole resonance (NQR)
measurements on Re$_6$Zr ($T_c$ = 6.72 K) and the isostructural compounds
Re$_{27}$Zr$_{5}$ ($T_c$ = 6.53 K) and Re$_{24}$Zr$_{5}$ ($T_c$ = 5.00 K). The
nuclear spin-lattice relaxation rate $1/T_1$ shows a coherence peak below $T_c$
and decreases exponentially at low temperatures in all three samples. The
superconducting gap $\Delta$ derived from the $1/T_1$ data is $2\Delta =3.58 $
$k_BT_c$, 3.55 $k_BT_c$, and 3.51 $k_BT_c$ for Re$_6$Zr ,Re$_{27}$Zr$_{5}$, and
Re$_{24}$Zr$_{5}$, respectively, which is close to the value of 3.53 $k_BT_c$
expected for weak-coupling superconductivity. These data suggest conventional
$s$-wave superconductivity with a fully-opened gap in this series of compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04257</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yangqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yuhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Youjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yanzheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenhao</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of Toroidal Alfven Eigenmodes during Minor Disruptions in
  Ohmic Plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, accepted by Physics of Plasmas</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4973230</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Toroidal Alfven eigenmodes (TAEs) excited in purely ohmically heated plasmas
without any auxiliary heating have been identified for the first time in the
SUNIST spherical tokamak. The TAE modes are observed during minor disruptions
and have a frequency range of 150-500 kHz. The mode structure analysis
indicates the existence of both m/n=-3/-1 and -4/-1 harmonics, propagating in
the electron diamagnetic direction in the laboratory frame of reference. These
TAEs appear simultaneously with the generation of runaway electrons in the
current quench phase, accompanying with the density sweeping during the minor
disruption. Possible driving mechanisms and potential applications of these
TAEs are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06004</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2016-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xayavong</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnova</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennaceur</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shell-model calculation of isospin-symmetry breaking correction to
  superallowed Fermi beta-decay</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>Poster presented at the XXIII Nuclear Physics Workshop &quot;Marie &amp;
  Pierre Curie&quot;, Kazimierz, Poland, September 27 to 2 October, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the radial-overlap part of the isospin-symmetry breaking
correction to superallowed $0^+\to 0^+$-decay using the shell-model approach
similar to that of Refs. [1, 2]. The 8 sd-shell emitters with masses between
$A=22$ and $A=38$ have been re-examined. The Fermi matrix element is evaluated
with realistic spherical single-particle wave functions, obtained from
spherical Woods-Saxon (WS) or Hartree-Fock (HF) potentials, fine-tuned to
reproduce the experimental data on charge radii and separation energies for
nuclei of interest. The elaborated adjustment procedure removes any sensitivity
of the correction to a specific parametrisation of the WS potential or to
various versions of the Skyrme interaction. The present results are generally
in good agreement with those reported in Refs. [3, 4]. At the same time, we
find that the calculations with HF wave functions result in systematically
lower values of the correction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07805</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Foss-Feig</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Zhe-Xuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorshkov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Charles W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement and spin-squeezing without infinite-range interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>4+ pages, 4 figures, and supplemental material</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Infinite-range interactions are known to facilitate the production of highly
entangled states with applications in quantum information and metrology.
However, many experimental systems have interactions that decay with distance,
and the achievable benefits in this context are much less clear. Combining
recent exact solutions with a controlled expansion in the system size, we
analyze quench dynamics in Ising models with power-law ($1/r^{\alpha}$)
interactions in $D$ dimensions, thereby expanding the understanding of spin
squeezing into a broad and experimentally relevant context. In spatially
homogeneous systems, we show that for small $\alpha$ the scaling of squeezing
with system size is identical to the infinite-range ($\alpha=0$) case. This
indifference to the interaction range persists up to a critical value
$\alpha=2D/3$, above which squeezing degrades continuously. Boundary-induced
inhomogeneities present in most experimental systems modify this picture, but
it nevertheless remains qualitatively correct for finite-sized systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07812</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>2016 Update of the $\mathrm{t\bar{t}H}$ Multilepton Analysis at
  $\sqrt{s} = 13$ TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>9th International Workshop on Top Quark Physics Olomouc, Czech
  Republic, September 19-23, 2016. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap
  with arXiv:1612.07703</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The latest results from the search for a Standard Model Higgs boson produced
in association with a top quark pair ($\mathrm{t\bar{t}H}$) at $\sqrt{s} = 13$
TeV decaying to final states with multiple leptons is presented using the 2016
dataset from the CMS experiment. The Higgs decays into either WW*, ZZ*, or
$\tau\tau$, and the top quark pair decays considered are either fully leptonic,
or semi-leptonic. The leptons defining the final states are muons and/or
electrons. The overall analysis strategy, as well as new techniques with
respect to the 2015 results are outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07831</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Beskrovnaya</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikhsanov</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>AR Scorpii is a new white dwarf in the ejector state</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, to appear in Proc. of the conference &quot;Stars from collapse to
  collapse&quot; (held in 2016 October 3-7, Nizhnij Arkhyz, Karachai-Cherkessian
  Republic, Special Astrophysical Observatory of the Russian Acad. of Sci.)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Marsh et al. (2016) have recently reported the discovery of a radio-pulsing
white dwarf in the cataclysmic variable AR Sco. The period of pulsations which
are also seen in the optical and UV is about 117 seconds. High intensity of
pulsing radiation and non-thermal character of its spectrum leave little room
for doubt that the white dwarf in AR Sco operates as a spin-powered pulsar and,
therefore, is in the ejector state. We show that this system is very much
resembling a well-known object AE Aqr. In both systems the compact components
are spin-powered and have relatively strong surface magnetic field of order of
100-500 MG. They originated due to accretion spin-up in the previous epoch
during which the magnetic field of the white dwarf had substantially evolved
being initially buried by the accreted matter and recovered to its initial
value after the spin-up phase had ended.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07840</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Xuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ditto</keyname><forenames>William L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spano</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carney</keyname><forenames>Paul R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ying-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting and characterizing high frequency oscillations in epilepsy - A
  case study of big data analysis</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.CE physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a framework to uncover and analyze dynamical anomalies from
massive, nonlinear and non-stationary time series data. The framework consists
of three steps: preprocessing of massive data sets to eliminate erroneous data
segments, application of the empirical mode decomposition and Hilbert transform
paradigm to obtain the fundamental components embedded in the time series at
distinct time scales, and statistical/scaling analysis of the components. As a
case study, we apply our framework to detecting and characterizing high
frequency oscillations (HFOs) from a big database of rat EEG recordings. We
find a striking phenomenon: HFOs exhibit on-off intermittency that can be
quantified by algebraic scaling laws. Our framework can be generalized to big
data-related problems in other fields such as large-scale sensor data and
seismic data analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07849</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simbotin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xf4;t&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Milne's Equation revisited: Exact Asymptotic Solutions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present novel approaches for solving Milne's equation, which was
introduced in 1930 as an efficient numerical scheme for the Schr\&quot;odinger
equation. Milne's equation appears in a wide class of physical problems,
ranging from astrophysics and cosmology, to quantum mechanics and quantum
optics. We show how a third order linear differential equation is equivalent to
Milne's non-linear equation, and can be used to accurately calculate Milne's
amplitude and phase functions. We also introduce optimization schemes to
achieve a convenient, fast, and accurate computation of wave functions using an
economical parametrization. These new optimization procedures answer the long
standing question of finding non-oscillatory solutions of Milne's equation. We
apply them to long-range potentials and find numerically exact asymptotic
solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07858</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Leonhardt</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay of excitation transport and atomic motion in flexible Rydberg
  aggregates</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Ph.D. thesis (Dissertation), submitted to the school of science,
  Technische Universit\&quot;at Dresden,
  http://nbn-resolving.de/urn:nbn:de:bsz:14-qucosa-213759, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong resonant dipole-dipole interactions in flexible Rydberg aggregates
enable the formation of exciton pulses, the interplay of atomic motion and
electronic excitation transfer which feature high fidelity entanglement
transport.
  Here, we demonstrate the coherent splitting of such pulses into two modes,
which induce strongly different atomic motion, leading to clear signatures of
nonadiabatic effects in atomic density profiles. The mechanism exploits local
nonadiabatic effects at a conical intersection, turning them from a decoherence
source into an asset. The conical intersection is a consequence of the exciton
pulses moving along a linear Rydberg chain and approaching an additional
linear, perpendicularly aligned Rydberg chain. The intersection provides a
sensitive knob controlling the propagation direction and coherence properties
of exciton pulses.
  We demonstrate that this scenario can be exploited as an exciton switch,
controlling direction and coherence properties of the joint pulse on the second
of the chains. Initially, we demonstrate the pulse splitting on planar
aggregates with atomic motion one-dimensionally constrained and employing
isotropic interactions. Subsequently, we confirm the splitting mechanism for a
fully realistic scenario in which all spatial restrictions are removed and the
full anisotropy of the dipole-dipole interactions is taken into account. Our
results enable the experimental observation of non-adiabatic electronic
dynamics and entanglement transport with Rydberg atoms. The conical
intersection crossings are clearly evident, both in atomic mean position
information and excited state spectra of the Rydberg system. This suggests
flexible Rydberg aggregates as a test-bench for quantum chemical effects in
experiments on much-inflated length scales. The fundamental ideas discussed
here have general implications for excitons on a dynamic network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07865</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Baocheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author></authors><title>Infinite Volume of Noncommutative Black Hole Wrapped by Finite Surface</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Physics Letter B 765, 226 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.12.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The volume of a black hole under noncommutative spacetime background is found
to be infinite, in contradiction with the surface area of a black hole, or its
Bekenstein-Hawking (BH) entropy, which is well-known to be finite. Our result
rules out the possibility of interpreting the entropy of a black hole by
counting the number of modes wrapped inside its surface if the final
evaporation stage can be properly treated. It implies the statistical
interpretation for the BH entropy can be independent of the volume, provided
spacetime is noncommutative. The effect of radiation back reaction is found to
be small and doesn't influence the above conclusion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07873</id><created>2016-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jo&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>B&#xe1;lint</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strelchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambhir</keyname><forenames>Arjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brower</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Accelerating Lattice QCD Multigrid on GPUs Using Fine-Grained
  Parallelization</title><categories>hep-lat physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3014904.3014995}</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the International Conference for High Performance
  Computing, Networking, Storage and Analysis (SC '16), Article 68 (November,
  2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The past decade has witnessed a dramatic acceleration of lattice quantum
chromodynamics calculations in nuclear and particle physics. This has been due
to both significant progress in accelerating the iterative linear solvers using
multi-grid algorithms, and due to the throughput improvements brought by GPUs.
Deploying hierarchical algorithms optimally on GPUs is non-trivial owing to the
lack of parallelism on the coarse grids, and as such, these advances have not
proved multiplicative. Using the QUDA library, we demonstrate that by exposing
all sources of parallelism that the underlying stencil problem possesses, and
through appropriate mapping of this parallelism to the GPU architecture, we can
achieve high efficiency even for the coarsest of grids. Results are presented
for the Wilson-Clover discretization, where we demonstrate up to 10x speedup
over present state-of-the-art GPU-accelerated methods on Titan. Finally, we
look to the future, and consider the software implications of our findings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07874</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07874</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Hodgson</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rani</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Algaba</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple simultaneous Gamma-ray emission sites in 3C 84</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Submitted to the proceedings of the 13th EVN Symposium and Users
  Meeting held in St. Petersburg, Russia, 20-23 September 2016. Contributed
  poster: 4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mis-aligned active galactic nuclei (AGN), 3C\,84, has been observed
approximately monthly at four frequencies simultaneously (22\,GHz -- 129\,GHz)
on the Korean VLBI Network (KVN) since 2013 as part of the interferometric
monitoring of $\gamma$-ray bright AGN (iMOGABA) program. 3C\,84 is known to
have to sites of bright radio emission, with the first thought to be near the
central super-massive black hole and the second in a slowly moving emission
feature, several milliarcseconds south of the core. Analysis of this data
suggests that the highly variable Gamma-ray emission originates near the SMBH
and the slowly rising $\gamma$-ray emission originates in the slow moving
feature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07890</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Pikhitsa</keyname><forenames>Peter V</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct relation between the excess current noise spectral density and
  the complex conductivity of disordered conductor</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We put forward a fundamental relationship between the normalized spectral
density of excess current noise and the imaginary part of complex conductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07891</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Knurenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radio Emission of Air Showers with Energy E$_0$ $\geq$ 10$^{19}$ eV by
  Yakutsk Array Data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present results obtained from the measurements of radio
emission at frequency of 32 MHz with energy more than 10$^{19}$ eV. Generalized
formula that describe lateral distribution and depends on main characteristic
of the air showers: energy E$_0$ and depth of maximum X$_{max}$ was derived.
The formula has a good agreement with data at average and large distances from
shower axis. Employing the ratio of radio emission amplitude at distances 175 m
and 725 m we determined the depth of maximum X$_{max}$ for air shower with
energy 3.7$\cdot$10$^{19}$ eV, which in our case is equal to X$_{max}$ =
769$\pm$34g$\cdot$cm$^{-2}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07905</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Menglin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brinkmann</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagonabarraga</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seemann</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleury</keyname><forenames>Jean-Baptiste</forenames></author></authors><title>Programmable Active Janus Droplets Driven by Water/Alcohol Phase
  Separation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the existence of self-propelled Janus droplets driven by phase
separation, which are able to deliver cargo in a programmable manner. The
self-propelling droplets are initially formed by a water/ethanol mixture in a
squalane/monoolein solution, and evolve in up to three stages depending on
ethanol concentration. In the first stage, the droplet propulsion is generated
by Marangoni flow originating from the solubilization of ethanol in the oily
phase. During this process the droplets absorb surfactant molecules; in
combination with the continuous loss of ethanol this leads to a phase
separation of the water/ethanol/monoolein mixture and the formation of Janus
droplets, i.e. a water-rich droplet connected to an ethanol-rich droplet that
is able to deliver cargo. We characterize the different evolution stages of
self-propulsion by the flow field around the droplet that evolves from a weak
pusher, over a neutral swimmer, to a dimer of neutral swimmers. Finally, we
utilize this active system to deliver DNA as a cargo. Tuning the delay time
before phase separation, by varying the chemical composition of the droplets,
several different cargo delivery processes can be programmed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07911</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Raghavendra</keyname><forenames>N. Venkata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>S. V. Raghurama</forenames></author></authors><title>A Boltzmann scheme with physically relevant discrete velocities for
  Euler equations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kinetic or Boltzmann schemes are interesting alternatives to the macroscopic
numerical methods for solving the hyperbolic conservation laws of gas dynamics.
They utilize the particle-based description instead of the wave propagation
models. While the continuous particle velocity based upwind schemes were
developed in the earlier decades, the discrete velocity Boltzmann schemes
introduced in the last decade are found to be simpler and are easier to handle.
In this work, we introduce a novel way of introducing discrete velocities which
correspond to the physical wave speeds and formulate a discrete velocity
Boltzmann scheme for solving Euler equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07917</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>van Cappellen</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macquart</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petroff</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siemion</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidson</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broderick</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woudt</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrett</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faulkner</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torchinsky</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Bemmel</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hessels</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>MANTIS: The Mid-Frequency Aperture Array Transient and Intensity-Mapping
  System</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>White paper of the MANTIS MFAA science demonstrator</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The objective of this paper is to present the main characteristics of a
wide-field MFAA precursor that we envisage to be built at the SKA site in South
Africa. Known as MANTIS (the Mid-Frequency Aperture Array Transient and
Intensity-Mapping System), this ambitious instrument will represent the next
logical step towards the MFAA based SKA telescope. The goal is to use
innovative aperture array technology at cm wavelengths, in order to demonstrate
the feasibility of deploying huge collecting areas at modest construction and
operational cost. Such a transformative step is required in order to continue
the exponential progress in radio telescope performance, and to make the
ambitious scale of the SKA Phase 2 a realistic near-time proposition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07932</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Dakova</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dakova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slavchev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovachev</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solitons in non-paraxial optics</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optoelectronics and Advanced Materials, Vol. 18, 5-6,
  2016, p. 435-439</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The well-known (1+1D) nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation (NSE) governs the
propagation of narrow-band pulses in optical fibers and others one-dimensional
structures. For exploration the evolution of broad-band optical pulses
(femtosecond and attosecond) it is necessary to use the more general nonlinear
amplitude equation (GNAE) which differs from NSE with two additional
non-paraxial terms. That is way, it is important to make clear the difference
between the solutions of these two equations. We found a new analytical soliton
solution of GNAE and compare it with the well-known NSE one. It is shown that
for the fundamental soliton the main difference between the two solutions is in
their phases. It appears that, this changes significantly the evolution of
optical pulses in multisoliton regime of propagation and admits a behavior
different from that of the higher-order NSE solitons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07933</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Biondini</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective field theories for heavy Majorana neutrinos in a thermal bath</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>PhD thesis, 220 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heavy Majorana neutrinos enter in many scenarios of physics beyond the
Standard Model and play a special role in the leptogenesis framework as origin
of the baryon asymmetry in the universe. In this thesis, we develop an
effective field theory for non-relativistic Majorana particles. We apply the
effective field theory so obtained to address calculations in a hot medium
which models the early stages of the universe evolution. In particular, we
apply it to the case of a heavy Majorana neutrino decaying in a hot plasma of
Standard Model particles, whose temperature is much smaller than the mass of
the Majorana neutrino but still much larger than the electroweak scale, and the
derivation of the neutrino thermal width is revisited in an EFT fashion.
Assuming the same hierarchy between heavy neutrino masses and the temperature,
we compute systematically thermal corrections to the direct and indirect CP
asymmetries in the Majorana neutrino decays. These are key ingredients entering
the equations that describe the thermodynamic evolution of the induced
lepton-number asymmetry eventually leading to the baryon asymmetry in the
universe. We consider the case of two Majorana neutrinos with nearly degenerate
masses, that allows for a resonant enhancement of the CP asymmetry, and a
hierarchical spectrum with one heavy neutrino much lighter than the other
neutrino species. Flavour effects are also taken into account in the derivation
of the CP asymmetries at finite temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07934</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Compressible Viscous Flows in a Symmetric Domain with Complete Slip
  Boundary</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work is devoted to study the global behavior of viscous flows contained
in a symmetric domain with complete slip boundary. In such scenario the
boundary no longer provides friction and therefore the perturbation of angular
velocity lacks decaying structure. In fact, we show the existence of uniformly
rotating solutions as steady states for the compressible Navier-Stokes
equations. By manipulating the conservation law of angular momentum, we
establish a suitable Korn's type inequality to control the perturbation and
show the asymptotic stability of the uniformly rotating solutions with small
angular velocity. In particular, the initial perturbation which preserves the
angular momentum would decay exponentially in time and the solution to the
Navier-Stokes equations converges to the steady state as time grows up.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07943</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Vita-Finzi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>The contribution of the Joule-Thomson effect to solar coronal heating</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two of the three gases that display isenthalpic Joule-Thomson (J-T) warming
under laboratory conditions are hydrogen and helium, the main constituents of
the solar plasma, but the temperatures that are attained by this route are at
most a few hundred K. Increases in ion temperature by several orders of
magnitude are claimed for hydrogen plasmas subject to expansion into a vacuum;
modest increases are reported for the shortlived tests of this effect that have
been carried out in space in the wakes of artificial satellites and of the
Moon. Attempts to calculate the J-T coefficient at very high temperatures using
equations of state and thermodynamics remain very preliminary. The potential
contribution of plasma expansion to heating of the solar corona must therefore
be assessed empirically, but this is consistent with how the J-T effect was
first identified. The sunspot record, EUV measurements by the EVE instrument on
the SDO satellite, and solar wind fluctuations documented by the ACE satellite
indicate broadly coherent periodicity from the photosphere to the outer corona
consistent with a non-pulsatory heating process. It comprises three successive
stages characterised by induction, the J-T mechanism, and plasma expansion.
Astronomical data may therefore be used to derive rather than to test an
extension of the J-T effect which could help to explain heating in other solar
system bodies and other stellar coronae.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07946</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferrie</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blume-Kohout</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Bayes estimator for multinomial parameters and Bhattacharyya distances</title><categories>math.ST quant-ph stat.TH</categories><comments>Code available at
  https://gist.github.com/csferrie/d7a9dcbf10c5667348613dfe5980e543</comments><report-no>SAND2016-12817 J</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the Bayes estimator for the parameters of a multinomial
distribution under two loss functions ($1-B$ and $1-B^2$) that are based on the
Bhattacharyya coefficient $B(\vec{p},\vec{q}) = \sum{\sqrt{p_kq_k}}$. We
formulate a non-commutative generalization relevant to quantum probability
theory as an open problem. As an example application, we use our solution to
find minimax estimators for a binomial parameter under Bhattacharyya loss
($1-B^2$).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07948</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Pipolo</keyname><forenames>Silvio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corni</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-Time Description of the Electronic Dynamics for a Molecule close to
  a Plasmonic Nanoparticle</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>This is the final peer-reviewed manuscript accepted for publication
  of an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice License, which
  permits copying and redistribution of the article or any adaptations for
  non-commercial purposes. Link to the original article:
  http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b11084</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, 2016, 120, 28774-28781</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b11084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The optical properties of molecules close to plasmonic nanostructures greatly
differ from their isolated molecule counterparts. To theoretically investigate
such systems in a Quantum Chemistry perspective, one has to take into account
that the plasmonic nanostructure (e.g., a metal nanoparticle - NP) is often too
large to be treated atomistically. Therefore, a multiscale description, where
the molecule is treated by an ab initio approach and the metal NP by a lower
level description, is needed. Here we present an extension of one such
multiscale model [Corni, S.; Tomasi, J. {\it J. Chem. Phys.} {\bf 2001}, {\it
114}, 3739] originally inspired by the Polarizable Continuum Model, to a
real-time description of the electronic dynamics of the molecule and of the NP.
In particular, we adopt a Time-Dependent Configuration Interaction (TD CI)
approach for the molecule, the metal NP is described as a continuous dielectric
of complex shape characterized by a Drude-Lorentz dielectric function and the
molecule- NP electromagnetic coupling is treated by an equation-of-motion (EOM)
extension of the quasi-static Boundary Element Method (BEM). The model includes
the effects of both the mutual molecule- NP time-dependent polarization and the
modification of the probing electromagnetic field due to the plasmonic
resonances of the NP. Finally, such an approach is applied to the investigation
of the light absorption of a model chromophore, LiCN, in the presence of a
metal NP of complex shape.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07951</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Pritimita</keyname><forenames>Prativa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dash</keyname><forenames>Nitali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Sudhanwa</forenames></author></authors><title>Lepton Number Violation in Low Scale Seesaw Mechanism and its Collider
  Complementarity</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, ICHEP Conference Proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the TeV scale left-right symmetric theory which can accommodate
low scale seesaw mechanisms consistent with neutrino oscillation data and find
new physics contributions to neutrinoless double beta decay. The model
facilitates natural type-II seesaw dominance and the presence of extra
particles make the Dirac neutrino mass matrix $M_D$ large that leads to large
light heavy neutrino mixing. The spontaneous symmetry breaking through
doublets, triplets and bidoublet scalars at TeV scale offers rich phenomenology
accessible to LHC. From the numerical studies of the new physics contributions
to neutrinoless double beta decay we derive a lower limit on absolute scale of
lightest neutrino mass and find that normal hierarchy (NH) pattern is favorable
taking into account the cosmology and oscillation data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07967</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kitahara</keyname><forenames>Teppei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nierste</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremper</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct CP violation in $K\to \pi \pi$ decays and supersymmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk at ICHEP 2016, Chicago</comments><report-no>TTP16-059</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantities $\epsilon_K^\prime$ and $\epsilon_K$ measure the amount of
direct and indirect CP violation in $K\to \pi\pi$ decays, respectively. Using
the recent lattice results from the RBC and UKQCD Collaborations and a new
compact implementation of the $\Delta S=1$ renormalization group evolution we
predict $ \mbox{Re}\, \frac{\epsilon_{K}'}{\epsilon_{K}} = \left(1.06 \pm 5.07
\right) \times 10^{-4}$ in the Standard Model. This value is $2.8\,\sigma$
below the experimental value of $ \mbox{Re}\,
\frac{\epsilon_{K}'}{\epsilon_{K}} = \left(16.6 \pm 2.3 \right) \times
10^{-4}.$ In generic models of new physics the well-understood $\epsilon_K$
precludes large contributions to $\epsilon_K^\prime$, if the new contributions
enter at loop level. However, one can resolve the tension in
$\epsilon_{K}'/\epsilon_{K}$ within the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model.
To this end two features of supersymmetry are crucial: First, one can have
large isospin-breaking contributions (involving the strong instead of the weak
interaction) which enhance $\epsilon_K^\prime$. Second, the Majorana nature of
gluinos permits a suppression of the MSSM contribution to $\epsilon_K$, because
two box diagrams interfere destructively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07974</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Haimi</keyname><forenames>Antti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wennman</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author></authors><title>A Central Limit Theorem for Fluctuations in Polyanalytic Ginibre
  Ensembles</title><categories>math-ph math.CV math.MP math.PR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study fluctuations of linear statistics in Polyanalytic Ginibre ensembles,
a family of point processes describing planar free fermions in a uniform
magnetic field at higher Landau levels. Our main result is asymptotic normality
of fluctuations, extending a result of Rider and Vir\'ag. As in the analytic
case, the variance is composed of independent terms from the bulk and the
boundary. Our methods rely on a structural formula for polyanalytic polynomial
Bergman kernels which separates out the different pure $q$-analytic kernels
corresponding to different Landau levels. The fluctuations with respect to
these pure $q$-analytic Ginibre ensembles are also studied, and a central limit
theorem is proved. The results suggest a stabilizing effect on the variance
when the different Landau levels are combined together.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07985</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Saumen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Sourendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lytle</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Looking at the deconfinement transition using Wilson flow</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, contribution to Lattice 2016, held in Southampton, UK</comments><report-no>TIFR/TH/16-52</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wilson flow is an effective tool for constructing renormalized composite
operators. We explore use of the Wilson flow to construct renormalized order
parameters for the deconfinement transition in SU(3) gauge theory. We discuss
renormalization of the Polyakov loop, and of gluon condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07987</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Arleo</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Aspects of hard QCD processes in proton-nucleus collisions</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 pages, contribution to Hard Probes 2016 proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hard processes in high-energy proton-nucleus collisions are a powerful tool
in order to investigate several importants aspects of QCD in a nuclear medium,
such as nuclear shadowing, parton multiple scattering or medium-induced gluon
radiation. I review in these proceedings recent progress in that field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07996</id><created>2016-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Arminjon</keyname><forenames>Mayeul</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum dynamics and the electromagnetic field in the scalar ether
  theory of gravitation</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>33 pages. Published version is Open Access, see DOI</comments><journal-ref>Open Physics Vol. 14, pp. 395-409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/phys-2016-0045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An alternative, scalar theory of gravitation has been proposed, based on a
mechanism/interpretation of gravity as being a pressure force: Archimedes'
thrust. In it, the gravitational field affects the physical standards of space
and time, but motion is governed by an extension of the relativistic form of
Newton's second law. This implies Einstein's geodesic motion for free particles
only in a constant gravitational field. In this work, equations governing the
dynamics of a continuous medium subjected to gravitational and
non-gravitational forces are derived. Then, the case where the
non-gravitational force is the Lorentz force is investigated. The gravitational
modification of Maxwell's equations is obtained under the requirement that a
charged continuous medium, subjected to the Lorentz force, obeys the equation
derived for continuum dynamics under external forces. These Maxwell equations
are shown to be consistent with the dynamics of a &quot;free&quot; photon, and thus with
the geometrical optics of this theory. However, these equations do not imply
local charge conservation, except for a constant gravitational field.
  Keywords: Alternative theories of gravitation; preferred reference frame;
curved spacetime; Maxwell equations; charge conservation
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08001</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Herlemont</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogievetsky</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rings of $\h$-deformed differential operators</title><categories>math.RA math-ph math.MP math.QA math.RT</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the center of the ring $\Diff(n)$ of $\h$-deformed differential
operators of type A. We establish an isomorphism between certain localizations
of $\Diff(n)$ and the Weyl algebra $\text{W}_n$ extended by $n$ indeterminates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08002</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Deligny</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic-Ray Anisotropies: A Review</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Important observational results have been recently reported on the angular
distributions of cosmic rays (CRs) at all energies, calling into question the
perception of CRs a decade ago. These results together with their in-progress
interpretations are summarized in this short overview paper, following the
contribution presented at the XXV European Cosmic Ray Symposium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08003</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Loehr</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortiz-Ambriz</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tierno</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Defect Dynamics in Artificial Colloidal Ice: Real-Time Observation,
  Manipulation and Logic Gate</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 168001 , 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.168001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the defect dynamics in a colloidal spin ice system realized by
filling a square lattice of topographic double well islands with repulsively
interacting magnetic colloids. We focus on the contraction of defects in the
ground state, and contraction/expansion in a metastable biased state. Combining
real-time experiments with simulations, we prove that these defects behave like
emergent topological monopoles obeying a Coulomb law with an additional line
tension. We further show how to realize a completely resettable &quot;NOR&quot; gate,
which provides guidelines for fabrication of nanoscale logic devices based on
the motion of topological magnetic monopoles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08005</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bieniasz</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berciu</keyname><forenames>Mona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ole&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>Andrzej M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Green function variational approximation: Significance of physical
  constraints</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Acta Physica Polonica A 130, 659 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.12693/APhysPolA.130.659</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a calculation of the spectral properties of a single charge doped
at a Cu($3d$) site of the Cu-F plane in KCuF$_{3}$. The problem is treated by
generating the equations of motion for the Green's function by means of
subsequent Dyson expansions and solving the resulting set of equations. This
method, dubbed the variational approximation, is both very dependable and
flexible, since it is a systematic expansion with precise control over
elementary physical processes. It allows for deep insight into the underlying
physics of polaron formation as well as for inclusion of many physical
constraints, such as excluding crossing diagrams and double occupation
constraint, which are not included in the Self-Consistent Born Approximation.
Here we examine the role and importance of such constraints by analyzing
various spectral functions obtained in second order VA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08009</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bieniasz</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berciu</keyname><forenames>Mona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daghofer</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ole&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>Andrzej M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Green's function variational approach to orbital polarons in KCuF3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 085117 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop an $e_g$ orbital, $t$-$J$-like model of a single charge doped into
a two-dimensional plane with ferromagnetic spin order and alternating orbital
order, and present its solution by Green's functions in the variational
approximation framework. The model is designed to represent the orbital physics
within ferromagnetic $(a,b)$ planes of KCuF$_3$ and K$_2$CuF$_4$. The
variational approximation (VA) relies on the systematic generation of equations
of motion for the Green's function, taking into account the real-space
constraints coming from the exclusion of doubly occupied sites. This method is
compared to the firmly established self-consistent Born approximation, and to
the variational cluster approximation (VCA) which relies on the itinerant
regime of the model. We find that the present variational approximation
captures the essential aspects of the spectral weight distribution of the
coherent quasiparticle state and gives a result similar to the VCA, while also
reproducing well the momentum dependence of the spectral moments. In contrast,
the spectral function obtained within the self-consistent Born approximation is
more incoherent and its quasiparticle is heavier, at strong effective
couplings, than observed with VCA and VA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08011</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teo</keyname><forenames>Ji Bin Melvin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Weng Kong</forenames></author></authors><title>A new model for fluid velocity slip on a solid surface</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter, Vol. 12, No. 40, pp. 8388-8397, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6sm01178k</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general adsorption model is developed to describe the interactions between
near-wall fluid molecules and solid surface. This model serves as a framework
for the theoretical modelling of the boundary slip phenomena. Based on this
adsorption model, a new general model for the slip velocity of fluids on solid
surfaces is introduced. The slip boundary condition at a fluid-solid interface
has hitherto been considered separately for gases and liquids. In this paper,
we show that the slip velocity in both gases and liquids may originate from
dynamical adsorption processes at the interface. A unified analytical model
that is valid for both gas-solid and liquid-solid slip boundary conditions is
proposed based on surface science theory. The corroboration with experimental
data extracted from the literature shows that the proposed model provides an
improved prediction compared to existing analytical models for gases at higher
shear rates and close agreement for liquid-solid interfaces in general.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08014</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teo</keyname><forenames>Ji Bin Melvin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Weng Kong</forenames></author></authors><title>A new model for temperature jump at a fluid-solid interface</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>PLoS One, Vol. 11, No. 10, pp. e0165175, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0165175</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem presented involves the development of a new analytical model for
the general fluid-solid temperature jump. To the best of our knowledge, there
are no analytical models that provide the accurate predictions of the
temperature jump for both gas and liquid systems. In this paper, a unified
model for the fluid-solid temperature jump has been developed based on our
adsorption model of the interfacial interactions. Results obtained from this
model are validated with available results from the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08016</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Snamina</keyname><forenames>Mateusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ole&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>Andrzej M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbital order in undoped manganite LaMnO3 at finite temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 214426 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the evolution of spin and orbital order in undoped LaMnO$_3$
under increasing temperature with a model including both superexchange and
Jahn-Teller interactions. We used several cluster mean field calculation
schemes and find coexisting $A$-type antiferromagnetic ($A$-AF) and $C$-type
alternating orbital order at low temperature. The value of the Jahn-Teller
coupling between strongly correlated $e_g$ orbitals is estimated from the
orbital transition temperature at $T_{\rm OO}\simeq 780$ K. By a careful
analysis of on-site and on-bond correlations we demonstrate that spin-orbital
entanglement is rather weak. We have verified that the magnetic transition
temperature is influenced by entangled spin-orbital operators as well as by
entangled orbital operators on the bonds but the errors introduced by
decoupling such operators partly compensate each other. Altogether, these
results justify why the commonly used disentangled spin-orbital model is so
successful in describing the magnetic properties and the temperature dependence
of the optical spectral weights for LaMnO$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08023</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghavamirad</keyname><forenames>Roohollah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babashah</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sebt</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear FM Waveform Design to Reduction of sidelobe level in
  Autocorrelation Function</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper will design non-linear frequency modulation (NLFM) signal for
Chebyshev, Kaiser, Taylor, and raised-cosine power spectral densities (PSDs).
Then, the variation of peak sidelobe level with regard to mainlobe width for
these four different window functions are analyzed. It has been demonstrated
that reduction of sidelobe level in NLFM signal can lead to increase in
mainlobe width of autocorrelation function. Furthermore, the results of power
spectral density obtained from the simulation and the desired PSD are compared.
Finally, error percentage between simulated PSD and desired PSD for different
peak sidelobe level are illustrated. The stationary phase concept is the
possible source for this error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08046</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Schwider</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kellermann</keyname><forenames>Christine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindlein</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rothau</keyname><forenames>Sergej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mantel</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Grazing incidence interferometry for rough convex aspherics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Grazing incidence interferometry has been applied to rough planar and
cylindrical surfaces. As suitable beam splitters diffractive optical phase
elements are quite common because these allow for the same test sensitivity for
all surface points. But a rotational-symmetric convex aspheric has two
curvatures which reduces the measurable region to a meridian through the vortex
of the aspheric, which is in contrast to cylindrical surfaces having a
one-dimensional curvature which allows the test of the whole surface in gracing
incidence. The meridional limitation for rotational-symmetric aspherics
nevertheless offers the possibility to measure single meridians in a one-step
measurement. An extension to the complete surface can be obtained by rotating
the aspheric around its vortex within the frame of the test interferometer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08047</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Braaten</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>Hans-Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepage</keyname><forenames>G. Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Open Effective Field Theories from Highly Inelastic Reactions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, presented at 38th International Conference on High Energy
  Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The loss of particles due to highly inelastic reactions has previously been
taken into account in effective field theories for low-energy particles by
adding local anti-Hermitian terms to the effective Hamiltonian. An additional
modification is required in the time evolution equation for the density matrix
of a multi-particle system. An effective density matrix can be defined by
tracing over states containing high-momentum particles produced by the highly
inelastic reactions and by a time average that eliminates short-time
correlations. The effective density matrix satisfies the Lindblad equation,
with local Lindblad operators that are determined by the anti-Hermitian terms
in the effective Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08054</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Miles-P&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osorio</keyname><forenames>M. R. Zapatero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pall&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>K. Pe&#xf1;a</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical and near-infrared linear polarization of low and
  intermediate-gravity ultra-cool dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures, accepted in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3278</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim to study the optical and near-infrared linear polarimetric properties
of a sample of young M7-L7 dwarfs ($\approx$1-500 Myr) with spectroscopic
signatures of low- and intermediate-gravity atmospheres. We collected optical
($RIZ$) and near-infrared ($YJHK_{\rm s}$) linear polarimetry images on various
time scales from $\sim$0.2 h to months. Linear polarization degrees in the
interval 0-1.5\% ($I$- and $J$-bands) were measured with accuracies ranging
from $\pm$0.1 $\%$ to $\pm$0.9 $\%$ depending on the observing filter and the
target brightness. We found that the young field dwarfs in our sample show
similar polarimetric degrees at both $I$- and $J$-bands, and that there is no
obvious trend with the spectral type. The two Taurus sources in our sample show
intense levels of $J$-band linear polarization probably due to surrounding
disks. By compiling data from the literature for high-gravity M7-L7 dwarfs with
likely ages $\ge$500 Myr, we did not observe any apparent difference in the
linear polarimetry intensity between the young and old samples that could be
ascribed to differing atmospheric gravities. Polarimetric variability with peak
to peak amplitudes up to 1.5 $\%$ is detected on scales of about a rotation in
two out of four targets that were monitored over several hours. Long-term
polarimetric variability is also detected in nearly all dwarfs of the sample
with data spanning months to years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08055</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Fauche</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gebhardt</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukharev</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallee</keyname><forenames>Renaud A. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic opals: observation of a collective molecular exciton mode
  beyond the strong coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>submitted to Scientific Reports</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Achieving and controlling strong light-matter interactions in many-body
systems is of paramount importance both for fundamental understanding and
potential applications. In this paper we demonstrate both experimentally and
theoretically how to manipulate strong coupling between the Bragg-plasmon mode
supported by a organo-metallic array and molecular excitons in the form of
J-aggregates dispersed on the hybrid structure. We observe experimentally the
transition from a conventional strong coupling regime exhibiting the usual
upper and lower polaritonic branches to a more complex regime, where a third
nondispersive mode is seen, as the concentration of J-aggregates is increased.
The numerical simulations confirm the presence of the third resonance. We
attribute its physical nature to collective molecule-molecule interactions
leading to the collective electromagnetic response. A simple analytical model
is proposed to explain the physics of the third mode. The nonlinear dependence
on molecular parameters followed from the model are confirmed in a set of
rigorous numerical studies. It is shown that at the energy of the collective
mode molecules oscillate completely out of phase with the incident radiation
acting as an effective thin metal layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08058</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Papadopoulos</keyname><forenames>Lia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blinder</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronellenfitsch</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimm</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katifori</keyname><forenames>Eleni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinfeld</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassett</keyname><forenames>Danielle S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Embedding of biological distribution networks with differing
  environmental constraints</title><categories>q-bio.QM cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, plus supplement</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Distribution networks -- from vasculature to urban transportation systems --
are prevalent in both the natural and consumer worlds. These systems are
intrinsically physical in composition and are embedded into real space,
properties that lead to constraints on their topological organization. In this
study, we compare and contrast two types of biological distribution networks:
mycelial fungi and the vasculature system on the surface of rodent brains. Both
systems are alike in that they must route resources efficiently, but they are
also inherently distinct in terms of their growth mechanisms, and in that fungi
are not attached to a larger organism and must often function in unregulated
and varied environments. We begin by uncovering a common organizational
principle -- Rentian scaling -- that manifests as hierarchical network layout
in both physical and topological space. Simulated models of distribution
networks optimized for transport in the presence of fluctuations are also shown
to exhibit this feature in their embedding, with similar scaling exponents.
However, we also find clear differences in how the fungi and vasculature
balance tradeoffs in material cost, efficiency, and robustness. While the
vasculature appear well optimized for low cost, but relatively high efficiency,
the fungi tend to form more expensive but in turn more robust networks. These
differences may be driven by the distinct functions that each system must
perform, and the different habitats in which they reside. As a whole, this work
demonstrates that distribution networks contain a set of common, emergent
design features, as well as tailored optimizations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08059</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bassett</keyname><forenames>Danielle S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khambhati</keyname><forenames>Ankit N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grafton</keyname><forenames>Scott T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emerging Frontiers of Neuroengineering: A Network Science of Brain
  Connectivity</title><categories>q-bio.NC physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures. Manuscript accepted to the journal &quot;Annual
  Review of Biomedical Engineering&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neuroengineering is faced with unique challenges in repairing or replacing
complex neural systems that are composed of many interacting parts. These
interactions form intricate patterns over large spatiotemporal scales, and
produce emergent behaviors that are difficult to predict from individual
elements. Network science provides a particularly appropriate framework in
which to study and intervene in such systems, by treating neural elements
(cells, volumes) as nodes in a graph and neural interactions (synapses, white
matter tracts) as edges in that graph. Here, we review the emerging discipline
of network neuroscience, which uses and develops tools from graph theory to
better understand and manipulate neural systems, from micro- to macroscales. We
present examples of how human brain imaging data is being modeled with network
analysis and underscore potential pitfalls. We then highlight current
computational and theoretical frontiers, and emphasize their utility in
informing diagnosis and monitoring, brain-machine interfaces, and brain
stimulation. A flexible and rapidly evolving enterprise, network neuroscience
provides a set of powerful approaches and fundamental insights critical to the
neuroengineer's toolkit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08065</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Caorsi</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cecotti</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Homological S-Duality in 4d N=2 QFTs</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>102 pages, 12 figure, 6 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $S$-duality group $\mathbb{S}(\mathcal{F})$ of a 4d $\mathcal{N}=2$
supersymmetric theory $\mathcal{F}$ is identified with the group of triangle
auto-equivalences of its cluster category $\mathscr{C}(\mathcal{F})$ modulo the
subgroup acting trivially on the physical quantities. $\mathbb{S}(\mathcal{F})$
is a discrete group commensurable to a subgroup of the Siegel modular group
$Sp(2g,\mathbb{Z})$ ($g$ being the dimension of the Coulomb branch). This
identification reduces the determination of the $S$-duality group of a given
$\mathcal{N}=2$ theory to a problem in homological algebra. In this paper we
describe the techniques which make the computation straightforward for a large
class of $\mathcal{N}=2$ QFTs. The group $\mathbb{S}(\mathcal{F})$ is naturally
presented as a generalized braid group.
  The $S$-duality groups are often larger than expected. In some models the
enhancement of $S$-duality is quite spectacular. For instance, a QFT with a
huge $S$-duality group is the Lagrangian SCFT with gauge group $SO(8)\times
SO(5)^3\times SO(3)^6$ and half-hypermultiplets in the bi- and tri-spinor
representations.
  We focus on four families of examples: the $\mathcal{N}=2$ SCFTs of the form
$(G,G^\prime)$, $D_p(G)$, and $E_r^{(1,1)}(G)$, as well as the
asymptotically-free theories $(G,\widehat{H})$ (which contain $\mathcal{N}=2$
SQCD as a special case). For the $E_r^{(1,1)}(G)$ models we confirm the
presence of the $PSL(2,\mathbb{Z})$ $S$-duality group predicted by Del Zotto,
Vafa and Xie, but for most models in this class $S$-duality gets enhanced to a
much larger group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08078</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Wislicki</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>The KLOE-2 Experiment at DAPHNE</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, XIII International Conference on Heavy Quarks
  and Leptons, 22-27 May, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present recent results obtained by the KLOE-2 Collaboration at the DAPHNE
e+e- collider. The first class of results concerns search for dark forces at
the scale of 1 GeV in associated production of gamma and the U boson, in search
for the Higgsstrahlung and in possible decays of phi into eta and U. The second
is in neutral kaon physics, on testing the CPT and Lorentz invariance, and on
search for quantum decoherence effects in entangled pairs of kaons. The third
class of results concerns precision measurements in hadronic physics at low
energy where transition form factors of phi to pseudoscalar mesons pi0 and eta
are determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08081</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Hassani-Gangaraj</keyname><forenames>Mostafa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veysset</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuh</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersonic Impact of Metallic Micro-particles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding material behavior under high velocity impact is the key to
addressing a variety of fundamental questions in areas ranging from asteroid
strikes and geological cratering to impact-induced phase transformations,
spallation, wear, and ballistic penetration. Recently, adhesion has emerged in
this spectrum since it has been found that micrometer-sized metallic particles
can bond to metallic substrates under supersonic-impact conditions. However,
the mechanistic aspects of impact-induced adhesion are still unresolved. Here
we study supersonic impact of individual metallic microparticles on substrates
with micro-scale and nanosecond-level resolution. This permits the first direct
observation of a material-dependent threshold velocity, above which the
particle undergoes impact-induced material ejection and adheres to the
substrate. Our finite element simulations reveal that prevailing theories of
impact-induced shear localization and melting cannot account for the material
ejection. Rather, it originates from the propagation of a pressure wave induced
upon impact. The experiments and simulations together establish that the
critical adhesion velocity for supersonic microparticles is proportional to the
bulk speed of sound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08084</id><created>2016-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Petkova</keyname><forenames>Mariela D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tka&#x10d;ik</keyname><forenames>Ga&#x161;per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bialek</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieschaus</keyname><forenames>Eric F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregor</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal decoding of information from a genetic network</title><categories>q-bio.MN physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gene expression levels carry information about signals that have functional
significance for the organism. Using the gap gene network in the fruit fly
embryo as an example, we show how this information can be decoded, building a
dictionary that translates expression levels into a map of implied positions.
The optimal decoder makes use of graded variations in absolute expression
level, resulting in positional estimates that are precise to ~1% of the
embryo's length. We test this optimal decoder by analyzing gap gene expression
in embryos lacking some of the primary maternal inputs to the network. The
resulting maps are distorted, and these distortions predict, with no free
parameters, the positions of expression stripes for the pair-rule genes in the
mutant embryos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
