<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:44:50Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-04" from="2016-12-04" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08040</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2016-11-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hinton</keyname><forenames>Samuel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazin</keyname><forenames>Eyal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Tamara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blake</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brough</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colless</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couch</keyname><forenames>Warrick J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drinkwater</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazebrook</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurek</keyname><forenames>Russel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkinson</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimbblet</keyname><forenames>Kevin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>Gregory B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pracy</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring the 2D Baryon Acoustic Oscillation signal of galaxies in
  WiggleZ: Cosmological constraints</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 18 figures. Published version of results that appear in
  Hinton's PhD thesis, arXiv:1604.01830</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2725</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from the 2D anisotropic Baryon Acoustic Oscillation (BAO)
signal present in the final dataset from the WiggleZ Dark Energy Survey. We
analyse the WiggleZ data in two ways: firstly using the full shape of the 2D
correlation function and secondly focussing only on the position of the BAO
peak in the reconstructed data set. When fitting for the full shape of the 2D
correlation function we use a multipole expansion to compare with theory. When
we use the reconstructed data we marginalise over the shape and just measure
the position of the BAO peak, analysing the data in wedges separating the
signal along the line of sight from that parallel to the line of sight. We
verify our method with mock data and find the results to be free of bias or
systematic offsets. We also redo the pre-reconstruction angle averaged (1D)
WiggleZ BAO analysis with an improved covariance and present an updated result.
The final results are presented in the form of $\Omega_c h^2$, $H(z)$, and
$D_A(z)$ for three redshift bins with effective redshifts $z = 0.44$, $0.60$,
and $0.73$. Within these bins and methodologies, we recover constraints between
5% and 22% error. Our cosmological constraints are consistent with Flat
$\Lambda$CDM cosmology and agree with results from the Baryon Oscillation
Spectroscopic Survey (BOSS).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08692</id><created>2016-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gebauer</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Morrel H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Car</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>A well-scaling natural orbital theory</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1615729113. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1309.3929</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United
  States of America, vol. 113, no. 46, pp. 12913-12918 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1615729113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an energy functional for ground-state electronic structure
calculations. Its variables are the natural spin-orbitals of singlet many-body
wave functions and their joint occupation probabilities deriving from
controlled approximations to the two-particle density matrix that yield
algebraic scaling in general, and Hartree-Fock scaling in its seniority-zero
version. Results from the latter version for small molecular systems are
compared with those of highly accurate quantum-chemical computations. The
energies lie above full configuration interaction calculations, close to doubly
occupied configuration interaction calculations. Their accuracy is considerably
greater than that obtained from current density-functional theory
approximations and from current functionals of the one-particle density matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08838</id><created>2016-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Was</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tau lepton production and decays: perspective of multi-dimensional
  distributions and Monte Carlo methods</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented on the 14th International Workshop on Tau Lepton Physics,
  19-23 September, 2016, IHEP, Beijing, China. arXiv admin note: text overlap
  with arXiv:1412.2937</comments><report-no>IFJPAN-IV-2016-28</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Status of tau lepton decay Monte Carlo generator TAUOLA, its main
applications and recent developments are reviewed. It is underlined, that in
recent efforts on development of new hadronic currents, the multi-dimensional
nature of distributions of the experimental data must be taken with a great
care: lesson from comparison and fits to the BaBar and Belle data is recalled.
It was found, that as in the past at a time of comparisons with CLEO and ALEPH
data, proper fitting, to as detailed as possible representation of the
experimental data, is essential for appropriate developments of models of tau
decay dynamic.
  This multi-dimensional nature of distributions is also important for
observables where tau leptons are used to constrain experimental data. In later
part of the presentation,use of the TAUOLA program for phenomenology of W,Z,H
decays at LHC is addressed, in particular in the context of the Higgs boson
parity measurements. Some new results, relevant for QED lepton pair emission
are mentioned as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09397</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Tiko</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the CMS collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Measurement of top quark polarisation in t-channel single top quark
  production</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>presented at 9th International Workshop on Top Quark Physics Olomouc,
  Czech Republic, September 19&#xc3;&#x83;&#xc2;&#xa2;&#xc3;&#x82;&#xc2;&#x80;&#xc3;&#x82;&#xc2;&#x93;23, 2016</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  A first measurement of the top quark spin asymmetry, sensitive to the top
quark polarisation, in $t$-channel single top quark production is presented. It
is based on a sample of pp collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV
corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 19.7 $\mathrm{fb^{-1}}$. A
high-purity sample of $t$-channel single top quark events with an isolated muon
is selected. Signal and background components are estimated using a fit to
data. A differential cross section measurement, corrected for detector effects,
of an angular observable sensitive to the top quark polarisation is performed.
The differential distribution is used to extract a top quark spin asymmetry of
$0.26 \pm 0.03 \textrm{(stat)} \pm 0.10 \textrm{(syst)}$, which is compatible
with a p-value of $4.6\%$ with the standard model prediction of 0.44.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09888</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09888</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Jamal</keyname><forenames>Wasifa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Saptarshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maharatna</keyname><forenames>Koushik</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence of Millisecond-order Stable States in Time-Varying Phase
  Synchronization Measure in EEG Signals</title><categories>physics.med-ph q-bio.NC stat.AP</categories><comments>4 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), 2013 35th
  Annual International Conference of the IEEE, pp. 2539-2542, July 2013, Osaka,
  Japan</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/EMBC.2013.6610057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we have developed a new measure of understanding the temporal
evolution of phase synchronization for EEG signals using cross-electrode
information. From this measure it is found that there exists a small number of
well-defined phase-synchronized states, each of which is stable for few
milliseconds during the execution of a face perception task. We termed these
quasi-stable states as synchrostates. We used k-means clustering algorithms to
estimate the optimal number of synchrostates from 100 trials of EEG signals
over 128 channels. Our results show that these synchrostates exist consistently
in all the different trials. It is also found that from the onset of the
stimulus, switching between these synchrostates results in well-behaved
temporal sequence with repeatability which may be indicative of the dynamics of
the cognitive process underlying that task. Therefore these synchrostates and
their temporal switching sequences may be used as a new measure of the
stability of phase synchrony and information exchange between different regions
of a human brain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09891</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Jamal</keyname><forenames>Wasifa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Saptarshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maharatna</keyname><forenames>Koushik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuyucu</keyname><forenames>Doga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sicca</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billeci</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apicella</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muratori</keyname><forenames>Filippo</forenames></author></authors><title>Using Brain Connectivity Measure of EEG Synchrostates for Discriminating
  Typical and Autism Spectrum Disorder</title><categories>physics.med-ph q-bio.NC stat.AP</categories><comments>4 pages, 11 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Neural Engineering (NER), 2013 6th International IEEE/EMBS
  Conference on, pp. 1402-1405, Nov. 2013, San Diego, CA</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/NER.2013.6696205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we utilized the concept of stable phase synchronization
topography - synchrostates - over the scalp derived from EEG recording for
formulating brain connectivity network in Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) and
typically-growing children. A synchronization index is adapted for forming the
edges of the connectivity graph capturing the stability of each of the
synchrostates. Such network is formed for 11 ASD and 12 control group children.
Comparative analyses of these networks using graph theoretic measures show that
children with autism have a different modularity of such networks from typical
children. This result could pave the way to a new modality for possible
identification of ASD from non-invasively recorded EEG data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09893</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Coscia</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hausmann</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neffke</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the Uncharted Export: an Analysis of Tourism-Related Foreign
  Expenditure with International Spend Data</title><categories>q-fin.GN cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tourism is one of the most important economic activities in the world: for
many countries it represents the single largest product in their export basket.
However, it is a product difficult to chart: &quot;exporters&quot; of tourism do not ship
it abroad, but they welcome importers inside the country. Current research uses
social accounting matrices and general equilibrium models, but the standard
industry classifications they use make it hard to identify which domestic
industries cater to foreign visitors. In this paper, we make use of open source
data and of anonymized and aggregated transaction data giving us insights about
the spend behavior of foreigners inside two countries, Colombia and the
Netherlands, to inform our research. With this data, we are able to describe
what constitutes the tourism sector, and to map the most attractive
destinations for visitors. In particular, we find that countries might observe
different geographical tourists' patterns -- concentration versus
decentralization --; we show the importance of distance, a country's reported
wealth and cultural affinity in informing tourism; and we show the potential of
combining open source data and anonymized and aggregated transaction data on
foreign spend patterns in gaining insight as to the evolution of tourism from
one year to another.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09999</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>DaeKil</forenames></author></authors><title>Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger Symmetry in Four Qubit System</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 9 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1305.2012</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Like a three-qubit Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger(GHZ) symmetry we explore a
corresponding symmetry in the four-qubit system, which we call GHZ$_4$
symmetry. While whole GHZ-symmetric states can be represented by two real
parameters, the whole set of the GHZ$_4$-symmetric states is represented by
three real parameters. In the parameter space all GHZ$_4$-symmetric states
reside inside a tetrahedron. We also explore a question where the given SLOCC
class of the GHZ$_4$-symmetric states resides in the tetrahedron. Among nine
SLOCC classes we have examined five SLOCC classes, which results in three
linear hierarchies $L_{abc_2} \subset L_{a_4} \subset L_{a_2b_2} \subset
G_{abcd}$, $L_{a_20_{3\oplus\bar{1}}} \subset G_{abcd}$, and
$L_{0_{3\oplus\bar{1}}0_{3\oplus\bar{1}}} \subset G_{abcd}$ which hold, at
least, in the whole set of the GHZ$_4$-symmetric states. Difficulties arising
in the analysis of the remaining SLOCC classes are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10015</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum transport in coupled resonators enclosed synthetic magnetic flux</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 370, 1 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.03.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum transport properties are instrumental to understanding quantum
coherent transport processes. Potential applications of quantum transport are
widespread, in areas ranging from quantum information science to quantum
engineering, and not restricted to quantum state transfer, control and
manipulation. Here, we study light transport in a ring array of coupled
resonators enclosed synthetic magnetic flux. The ring configuration, with an
arbitrary number of resonators embedded, forms an two-arm Aharonov-Bohm
interferometer. The influence of magnetic flux on light transport is
investigated. Tuning the magnetic flux can lead to resonant transmission, while
half-integer magnetic flux quantum leads to completely destructive interference
and transmission zeros in an interferometer with two equal arms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10039</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Bao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark state population determines magnetic sensitivity in radical pair
  magnetoreception model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6:22417,2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  What is the real role of the quantum coherence and entanglement in the
radical pair (RP) compass, and what determines the singlet yield have not been
fully understood. In this paper, we find that the dark states of the
two-electron Zeeman energy operator (TEZE) play an important role in the RP
compass. We respectively calculate the singlet yields for two initial states in
this dark state basis: the coherent state and the same state just removing the
dark state coherence. For the later there is neither dark state coherence nor
entanglement in the whole dynamical process. Surprisingly we find that in both
cases the singlet yields are the same, and based on this result, we believe
that the dark state population determines the singlet yield completely, and the
dark state coherence and entanglement have little contribution to it. Finally,
we also find that the dark state population as well as the singlet yield
anisotropy is fragile to the vertical magnetic noise. However, the orientation
is robust and is even enhanced by the parallel magnetic noise because the dark
states expand a decoherence-free subspace. The dark state population as well as
the orientation is more robust to the hyperfine coupling noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10127</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Karimunnesa</keyname><forenames>Syeda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmmad</keyname><forenames>Bashir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basith</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Strontium substitution on the structural and magnetic
  properties of La1.8Sr0.2MMnO6 (M = Ni, Co) layered manganites</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12</comments><journal-ref>Phase Transitions, November, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/01411594.2016.1260723</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sr substituted perovskites La1.8Sr0.2MMnO6 (M = Ni, Co) were synthesized
using solid state reaction technique to present a systematic study on their
morphological, structural and magnetic properties. The average grain size of
the as-prepared La1.8Sr0.2NiMnO6 samples are in the range of 0.2-0.7 {\mu}m and
those for La1.8Sr0.2CoMnO6 manganites are 0.1-2.8 {\mu}m, which is
significantly less than that of unsubstituted La2NiMnO6 (LNMO) and La2CoMnO6
(LCMO) manganites. The XPS analysis enlightened about phase purity, binding
energy and oxygen vacancy of La1.8Sr0.2MMnO6 manganites. The Sr substituted
LNMO has revealed a sharp ferromagnetic to paramagnetic phase transition at 160
K which is about 120 K less than that of parent LNMO. The Sr substituted LCMO
exhibited such a transition at 220 K which is 8 K less than that of parent
LCMO. The temperature dependent magnetization measurements suggest that the
effect of Sr on the transition temperature in LNMO is more significant than
that of LCMO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10312</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Gracia-L&#xe1;zaro</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flor&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Luis M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>Yamir</forenames></author></authors><title>Cognitive hierarchy theory and two-person games</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.GT</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures. Submitted for publication</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The outcome of many social and economic interactions, such as stock-market
transactions, is strongly determined by the predictions that agents make about
the behavior of other individuals. Cognitive Hierarchy Theory provides a
framework to model the consequences of forecasting accuracy that has proven to
fit data from certain types of game theory experiments, such as Keynesian
Beauty Contests and Entry Games. Here, we focus on symmetric
two-players-two-actions games and establish an algorithm to find the players'
strategies according to the Cognitive Hierarchy Approach. We show that the
Snowdrift Game exhibits a pattern of behavior whose complexity grows as the
cognitive levels of players increases. In addition to finding the solutions up
to the third cognitive level, we demonstrate, in this theoretical frame, two
new properties of snowdrift games: i) any snowdrift game can be characterized
by only a parameter -- its class, ii) they are anti-symmetric with respect to
the diagonal of the pay-off's space. Finally, we propose a model based on an
evolutionary dynamics that captures the main features of the Cognitive
Hierarchy Theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10345</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ekanga</keyname><forenames>Tr&#xe9;sor</forenames></author></authors><title>Anderson localization for weakly interacting multi-particle models in
  the continuum</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR math.SP</categories><comments>25 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1201.2339</comments><msc-class>47B80, 47A75 (Primary), 35P10 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the weakly interacting one-dimensional multi-particle Anderson model in
the continuum space of configurations, we prove the spectral exponential and
the strong dynamical localization. The results require the interaction
amplitude to be sufficiently small. The general strategy uses the multi-scale
analysis bounds. Actually, we show that the multi-scale analysis bounds of the
single particle model remain stable when passing to multi-particle systems,
provided that the inter-particle interaction is sufficiently small. The common
probability distribution of the i.i.d. random external potential in the
Anderson model, is only needed to be log-H\&quot;older continuous.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00199</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Tantalo</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lubicz</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sachrajda</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanfilippo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simula</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic corrections to leptonic decay rates of charged
  pseudoscalar mesons: finite-volume effects</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Carrasco et al. we have recently proposed a method to calculate $O(e^2)$
electromagnetic corrections to leptonic decay widths of pseudoscalar mesons.
The method is based on the observation that the infrared divergent
contributions (that appear at intermediate stages of the calculation and that
cancel in physical quantities thanks to the Bloch-Nordsieck mechanism) are
universal, i.e. depend on the charge and the mass of the meson but not on its
internal structure. In this talk we perform a detailed analysis of the
finite-volume effects associated with our method. In particular we show that
also the leading $1/L$ finite-volume effects are universal and perform an
analytical calculation of the finite-volume leptonic decay rate for a
point-like meson.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00326</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Lobo</keyname><forenames>Iarley P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmisano</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric interpretation of Planck-scale-deformed co-products</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages, Contribution to the proceedings of the 9th Alexander
  Friedmann International Seminar, St. Petersburg, Russia, June 21-27, 2015</comments><doi>10.1142/S2010194516601265</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For theories formulated with a maximally symmetric momentum space we propose
a general characterization for the description of interactions in terms of the
isometry group of the momentum space. The well known cases of
$\kappa$-Poincar\'e-inspired and (2+1)-dimensional gravity-inspired composition
laws both satisfy our condition. Future applications might include the proposal
of a class of models based on momenta spaces with anti-de Sitter geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
