<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:44:25Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-02" from="2016-12-02" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1106.5942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1106.5942</id><created>2011-06-29</created><updated>2014-02-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heunen</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizations of categories of commutative C*-subalgebras</title><categories>math.OA math.CT quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><msc-class>46L35, 18F99, 06B75, 81P10</msc-class><journal-ref>Communications in Mathematical Physics 331(1):215-238, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-014-2088-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim to characterize the category of injective *-homomorphisms between
commutative C*-subalgebras of a given C*-algebra A. We reduce this problem to
finding a weakly terminal commutative subalgebra of A, and solve the latter for
various C*-algebras, including all commutative ones and all type I von Neumann
algebras. This addresses a natural generalization of the Mackey-Piron
programme: which lattices are those of closed subspaces of Hilbert space? We
also discuss the way this categorified generalization differs from the original
question.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1202.4028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1202.4028</id><created>2012-02-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Dyckovsky</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olmschenk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of photon-mediated entanglement between distinguishable matter
  qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 85, 052322 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.85.052322</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically evaluate establishing remote entanglement between
distinguishable matter qubits through interference and detection of two emitted
photons. The fidelity of the entanglement operation is analyzed as a function
of the temporal and frequency mode-matching between the photons emitted from
each quantum memory. With a general analysis, we define limits on the absolute
magnitudes of temporal and frequency mode-mismatches in order to maintain
entanglement fidelities greater than 99% with two-photon detection efficiencies
greater than 90%. We apply our analysis to several selected systems of quantum
memories. Results indicate that high fidelities may be achieved in each system
using current experimental techniques, while maintaining acceptable rates of
entanglement. Thus, it might be possible to use two-photon-mediated
entanglement operations between distinguishable quantum memories to establish a
network for quantum communication and distributed quantum computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1202.4879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1202.4879</id><created>2012-02-22</created><updated>2013-02-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>K&#xf6;hn</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebert</keyname><forenames>Ute</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular distribution of Bremsstrahlung photons and of positrons for
  calculations of terrestrial gamma-ray flashes and positron beams</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>75 pages, 19 figures, 1 table, 1 source code</comments><journal-ref>Atmospheric Research, 2014, vol. 135-136, pp. 432-465</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.atmosres.2013.03.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within thunderstorms electrons can gain energies of up to hundred(s) of MeV.
These electrons can create X-rays and gamma-rays as Bremsstrahlung when they
collide with air molecules. Here we calculate the distribution of angles
between incident electrons and emitted photons as a function of electron and
photon energy. We derive these doubly differential cross-sections by
integrating analytically over the triply differential cross-sections derived by
Bethe and Heitler; this is appropriate for light atoms like nitrogen and oxygen
(Z=7,8) if the energy of incident and emitted electron is larger than 1 keV. We
compare our results with the approximations and cross section used by other
authors. We also discuss some simplifying limit cases, and we derive some
simple approximation for the most probable scattering angle. We also provide
cross sections for the production of electron positron pairs from energetic
photons when they interact with air molecules. This process is related to the
Bremsstrahlung process by some physical symmetry. Therefore the results above
can be transferred to predictions on the angles between incident photon and
emitted positron, again as a function of photon and positron energy. We present
the distribution of angles and again a simple approximation for the most
probable scattering angle. Our results are given as analytical expressions as
well as in the form of a C++ code that can be directly be implemented into
Monte Carlo codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.2909</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.2909</id><created>2013-01-14</created><updated>2015-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chru&#x15b;ciel</keyname><forenames>Piotr T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>James D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minguzzi</keyname><forenames>Ettore</forenames></author></authors><title>On differentiability of volume time functions</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure; minor corrections, the differentiability proof
  expanded</comments><report-no>Preprint UWThPh-2013-1</report-no><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincar\'e 17 (2016), 2801-2824</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-015-0448-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show differentiability of a class of Geroch's volume functions on globally
hyperbolic manifolds. Furthermore, we prove that every volume function
satisfies a local anti-Lipschitz condition over causal curves, and that locally
Lipschitz time functions which are locally anti-Lipschitz can be uniformly
approximated by smooth time functions with timelike gradient. Finally, we prove
that in stably causal spacetimes Hawking's time function can be uniformly
approximated by smooth time functions with timelike gradient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.5375</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.5375</id><created>2014-06-20</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the $t\bar{t}$ production cross-section using $e\mu$
  events with $b$-tagged jets in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}=7$ and 8 TeV with
  the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>21 pages plus author list + cover pages (34 pages total), 9 figues, 8
  tables, an addendum added to the published version and available as Eur.
  Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 642, http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4501-2.
  All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/TOPQ-2013-04/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2014-124</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C74 (2014) 3109; Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016) 642</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-014-3109-7 10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4501-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inclusive top quark pair ($t\bar{t}$) production cross-section
$\sigma_{t\bar{t}}$ has been measured in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}=7$ TeV
and $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV with the ATLAS experiment at the LHC, using $t\bar{t}$
events with an opposite-charge $e\mu$ pair in the final state. The measurement
was performed with the 2011 7 TeV dataset corresponding to an integrated
luminosity of 4.6 fb$^{-1}$ and the 2012 8 TeV dataset of 20.3 fb$^{-1}$. The
cross-section was measured to be: $\sigma_{t\bar{t}}=182.9\pm 3.1\pm 4.2\pm 3.6
\pm 3.3$ pb ($\sqrt{s}=7$ TeV) and $\sigma_{t\bar{t}}=242.9\pm 1.7\pm 5.5\pm
5.1\pm 4.2$ pb ($\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV, updated as described in the Addendum), where
the four uncertainties arise from data statistics, experimental and theoretical
systematic effects, the knowledge of the integrated luminosity and of the LHC
beam energy. The results are consistent with recent theoretical QCD
calculations at next-to-next-to-leading order. Fiducial measurements
corresponding to the experimental acceptance of the leptons are also reported,
together with the ratio of cross-sections measured at the two centre-of-mass
energies. The inclusive cross-section results were used to determine the top
quark pole mass via the dependence of the theoretically-predicted cross-section
on $m_t^{\rm pole}$, giving a result of $m_t^{\rm pole}=172.9^{+2.5}_{-2.6}$
GeV. By looking for an excess of $t\bar{t}$ production with respect to the QCD
prediction, the results were also used to place limits on the pair-production
of supersymmetric top squarks $\tilde{t}_1$ with masses close to the top quark
mass decaying via $\tilde{t}_1\rightarrow t\tilde{\chi}^0_1$ to predominantly
right-handed top quarks and a light neutralino $\tilde{\chi}_0^1$, the lightest
supersymmetric particle. Top squarks with masses between the top quark mass and
177 GeV are excluded at the 95% confidence level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04386</id><created>2015-01-18</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling of nuclear modification factors for hadrons and light nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A 52, 354 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16354-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The number of constituent quarks (NCQ-) scaling of hadrons and the number of
constituent nucleons (NCN-) scaling of light nuclei are proposed for nuclear
modification factors ($R_{cp}$) of hadrons and light nuclei, respectively,
according to the experimental investigations in relativistic heavy-ion
collisions. Based on coalescence mechanism the scalings are performed for pions
and protons in quark level, and light nuclei $d (\bar d)$ and $^3$He for
nucleonic level, respectively, formed in Au + Au and Pb + Pb collisions and
nice scaling behaviour emerges. NCQ or NCN scaling law of $R_{cp}$ can be
respectively taken as a probe for quark or nucleon coalescence mechanism for
the formation of hadron or light nuclei in relativistic heavy-ion collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05685</id><created>2015-02-19</created><updated>2015-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Wainer</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivera-Tapia</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Notte-Cuello</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondrashuk</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Clifford Bundle Approach to the Wave Equation of a Spin 1/2 Fermion in
  the de Sitter Manifold</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This version contains a new appendix and improves the presentation of
  section 5</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Applied Clifford Algebras 26 (2016) 253-277</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00006-015-0588-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we give a Clifford bundle motivated approach to the wave
equation of a free spin $1/2$ fermion in the de Sitter manifold, a brane with
topology $M=\mathrm{S0}(4,1)/\mathrm{S0}(3,1)$ living in the bulk spacetime
$\mathbb{R}^{4,1}=(\mathring{M}=\mathbb{R}^{5},\boldsymbol{\mathring{g}})$ and
equipped with a metric field
$\boldsymbol{g:=-i}^{\ast}\boldsymbol{\mathring{g}%}$ with
$\boldsymbol{i}:M\rightarrow\mathring{M}$ being the inclusion map. To obtain
the analog of Dirac equation in Minkowski spacetime in the structure
$\mathring{M}$ we appropriately factorize the two Casimir invariants $C_{1}$
and $C_{2}$ of the Lie algebra of the de Sitter group using the constraint
given in the linearization of $C_{2}$ as input to linearize $C_{1}$. In this
way we obtain an equation that we called \textbf{DHESS1,}which in previous
studies by other authors was simply postulated.$.$Next we derive a wave
equation (called \textbf{DHESS2}) for a free spin $1/2$ fermion in the de
Sitter manifold using a heuristic argument which is an obvious generalization
of a heuristic argument (described in detail in Appendix D) permitting a
derivation of the Dirac equation in Minkowski spacetime and which shows that
such famous equation express nothing more than the fact that the momentum of a
free particle is a constant vector field over timelike \ integral curves of a
given velocity field. It is a remarkable fact that \textbf{DHESS1}and
\textbf{DHESS2}\ coincide. One of the main ingredients in our paper is the use
of the concept of Dirac-Hestenes spinor fields. Appendices B and C recall this
concept and its relation with covariant Dirac spinor fields usualy used by
physicists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02586</id><created>2015-03-06</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shkerin</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sibiryakov</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>On stability of electroweak vacuum during inflation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, dependence of the grav. corrections to the bounce
  action on non-minimal coupling updated, corresponding references added</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-TH-2015-043, INR-TH/2015-008</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 746 (2015) 257-260</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.05.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study Coleman-De Luccia tunneling of the Standard Model Higgs field during
inflation in the case when the electroweak vacuum is metastable. We verify that
the tunneling rate is exponentially suppressed. The main contribution to the
suppression is the same as in flat space-time. We analytically estimate the
corrections due to the expansion of the universe and an effective mass term in
the Higgs potential that can be present at inflation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03996</id><created>2015-04-15</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ertan</keyname><forenames>Unal</forenames></author></authors><title>The inner disk radius in the propeller phase and accretion-propeller
  transition of neutron stars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the critical conditions required for a steady propeller
effect for magnetized neutron stars with optically thick, geometrically thin
accretion disks. We have shown through simple analytical calculations that a
steady-state propeller mechanism cannot be sustained at an inner disk radius
where the viscous and magnetic stresses are balanced. The radius calculated by
equating these stresses is usually found to be close to the conventional Alfven
radius for spherical accretion, r_A. Our results show that: (1) a steady
propeller phase can be established with a maximum inner disk radius that is at
least \sim 15 times smaller than r_A depending on the mass-flow rate of the
disk, rotational period and strength of the magnetic dipole field of the star,
(2) the critical accretion rate corresponding to the accretion-propeller
transition is orders of magnitude lower than the rate estimated by equating r_A
to the co-rotation radius. Our results are consistent with the properties of
the transitional millisecond pulsars which show transitions between the
accretion powered X-ray pulsar and the rotational powered radio pulsar states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06419</id><created>2015-04-24</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xundong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toro</keyname><forenames>Ligia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly Nonlinear Luminescence Induced by Gold Nanoparticles on Glass
  Surfaces with Continuous-Wave Laser Illumination</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on highly nonlinear luminescence being observed from individual
spherical gold nanoparticles immobilized on a glass surface and illuminated by
continuous-wave (CW) lasers with relatively low power. The nonlinear
luminescence shows optical super-resolution beyond the diffraction limit in
three dimensions compared to the scatting of the excitation laser light. The
luminescence intensity from most nanoparticles is proportional to the 5th--7th
power of the excitation laser power and has wide excitation and emission
spectra across the visible wavelength range. Strong nonlinear luminescence is
only observed near the glass surface. High optical nonlinearity excited by low
CW laser power is related to a long-lived dark state of the gold nanoparticles,
where the excitation light is strongly absorbed. This phenomenon has potential
biological applications in super-resolution and deep tissue imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.08227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.08227</id><created>2015-04-07</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schroer</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author></authors><title>Peculiarities of massive vectormesons and their zero mass limits</title><categories>physics.gen-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>34 pages Latex, several additional remarks and citations, improved
  formulations, same as published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 75 (2015) 365</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3497-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive QED, in contrast with its massless counterpart, possesses two
conserved charges; one is a screened (vanishing) Maxwell charge which is
directly associated with the massive vector mesons through the identically
conserved Maxwell current. A somewhat peculiar situation arises for couplings
of Hermitian matter fields to massive vector potentials; in that case the only
current is the screened Maxwell current and the coupling disappears in the
massless limit. In case of selfinteracting massive vector mesons the situation
becomes even more peculiar in that the usually renormalizability guaranteeing
validity of the first order power-counting criterion breaks down in second
order and requires the compensatory presence of additional Hermitian H-fields.
Some aspect of these observation have already been noticed in the BRST gauge
theoretic formulation, but here we use a new setting based on string-local
vector mesons which is required by Hilbert space positivity. The coupling to
H-fields induces Mexican hat like selfinteractions; they are not imposed and
bear no relation with spontaneous symmetry breaking; they are rather
consequences of the foundational causal localization properties realized in a
Hilbert space setting. In case of selfinteracting massive vectormesons their
presence is required in order to maintain the first order power-counting
restriction of renormalizability also in second order. The presentation of the
new Hilbert space setting for vector mesons which replaces gauge theory and
extends on-shell unitarity to its off-shell counterpart is the main motivation
for this work. The new Hilbert space setting also shows that the second order
Lie-algebra structure of selfinteracting vector mesons is a consequence of the
principles of QFT and promises a deeper understanding of the origin of
confinement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07010</id><created>2015-05-26</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gopal</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Sourabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Arpita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Jit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Chiranjib</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological delocalization and tuning of surface channel separation in
  Bi2Se2Te Topological Insulator Thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Revised Version, with further experimental data included</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The surface states of a 3D topological insulator (TI) exhibit topological
protection against backscattering. However, the contribution of bulk electrons
to the transport data is an impediment to the topological protection of
surface. We report the tuning of the chemical potential in the bulk of Bi2Se2Te
TI thin films, pinning it near the center of the bulk band gap, thereby
suppressing the bulk carriers. The temperature dependent resistance of these
films shows activated behavior down to 50K, followed by a metallic transition
at lower temperatures, a hallmark of the robustness of TI surface states.
Manifestation of topological protection and surface dominated transport is
explained by 2D weak antilocalization phenomenon. We further explore the effect
of surface to bulk coupling in TI in this work, which is captured by the number
of effective conducting surface channels that participate in the transport. The
presence of a single conducting channel indicates a strong surface to bulk
coupling which is detrimental to purely topological transport. We demonstrate
the decoupling of topological surface states on opposite surfaces of thin
films, thereby suppressing the bulk transport. Our findings provide a deeper
understanding of surface to bulk coupling along with topological transport
behavior and their respective tunability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03792</id><created>2015-07-14</created><updated>2015-09-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baudis</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kish</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piastra</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmogenic activation of xenon and copper</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C75 (2015) no.10, 485</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3711-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rare event search experiments using liquid xenon as target and detection
medium require ultra-low background levels to fully exploit their physics
potential. Cosmic ray induced activation of the detector components and, even
more importantly, of the xenon itself during production, transportation and
storage at the Earth's surface, might result in the production of radioactive
isotopes with long half-lives, with a possible impact on the expected
background. We present the first dedicated study on the cosmogenic activation
of xenon after 345 days of exposure to cosmic rays at the Jungfraujoch research
station at 3470m above sea level, complemented by a study of copper which has
been activated simultaneously. We have directly observed the production of 7Be,
101Rh, 125Sb, 126I and 127Xe in xenon, out of which only 125Sb could
potentially lead to background for a multi-ton scale dark matter search. The
production rates for five out of eight studied radioactive isotopes in copper
are in agreement with the only existing dedicated activation measurement, while
we observe lower rates for the remaining ones. The specific saturation
activities for both samples are also compared to predictions obtained with
commonly used software packages, where we observe some underpredictions,
especially for xenon activation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08785</id><created>2015-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhdanov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seideman</keyname><forenames>Tamar</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of control constraints in quantum optimal control</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92 (2015) 052109</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.052109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problems of optimizing the value of an arbitrary observable of the
two-level system at both a fixed time and the shortest possible time is
theoretically explored. Complete identification and classification along with
comprehensive analysis of globally optimal control policies and traps (i.e.
policies which are locally but not globally optimal) is presented. The central
question addressed is whether the control landscape remains trap-free if
control constraints of the inequality type are imposed. The answer is
astonishingly controversial, namely, although formally it is always negative,
in practice it is positive provided that the control time is fixed and chosen
long enough.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04016</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Mukesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Xifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>Rashidul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornell</keyname><forenames>Alan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Uta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mellado</keyname><forenames>Bruce</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing anomalous couplings using di-Higgs production in electron-proton
  collisions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><report-no>WITS-MITP 019</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 764 (2017) 247-253</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A proposed high energy Future Circular Hadron-Electron Collider would provide
sufficient energy in a clean environment to probe di-Higgs production. Using
this channel we show that the azimuthal angle correlation between the missing
transverse energy and the forward jet is a very good probe for the non-standard
$hhh$ and $hhWW$ couplings. We give the exclusion limits on these couplings as
a function of integrated luminosity at a $95$\% C.L. using the fiducial cross
sections. With appropriate error fitting methodology we find that the Higgs
boson self coupling could be measured to be $g^{(1)}_{hhh} =
1.00^{+0.24(0.14)}_{-0.17(0.12)}$ of its expected Standard Model value at
$\sqrt s = 3.5(5.0)$ TeV for an ultimate 10 ab$^{-1}$ of integrated luminosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04611</id><created>2015-09-15</created><updated>2015-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wen-Du</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Wu-Sheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering theory without large-distance asymptotics in arbitrary
  dimensions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 465202</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/46/465202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In conventional scattering theory, by large-distance asymptotics, at the cost
of losing the information of the distance between target and observer, one
imposes a large-distance asymptotics to achieve a scattering wave function
which can be represented explicitly by a scattering phase shift. In this paper,
without large-distance asymptotics, we establish an arbitrary-dimensional
scattering theory. Arbitrary-dimensional scattering wave functions, scattering
boundary conditions, cross sections, and phase shifts are given without
large-distance asymptotics. The importance of an arbitrary-dimensional
scattering theory is that the dimensional renormalization procedure in quantum
field theory needs an arbitrary-dimensional result. Moreover, we give a
discussion of one- and two-dimensional scatterings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08158</id><created>2015-09-27</created><updated>2016-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clifton</keyname><forenames>Sara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>Rosemary I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abrams</keyname><forenames>Daniel M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Handicap principle implies emergence of dimorphic mating displays</title><categories>q-bio.PE math.DS nlin.AO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, supplementary information included</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society B 283, 1970: November 30 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspb.2016.1970</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Species spanning the animal kingdom have evolved extravagant and costly
ornaments to attract mating partners. Zahavi's handicap principle offers an
elegant explanation for this: ornaments signal individual quality, and must be
costly to ensure honest signalling, making mate selection more efficient. Here
we incorporate the assumptions of the handicap principle into a mathematical
model and show that they are sufficient to explain the heretofore puzzling
observation of bimodally distributed ornament sizes in a variety of species.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07431</id><created>2015-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Pivoluska</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plesch</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>An explicit classical strategy for winning a $\mathrm{CHSH}_{q}$ game</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 025013 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/2/025013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A $\mathrm{CHSH}_{q}$ game is a generalization of the standard two player
$\mathrm{CHSH}$ game, having $q$ different input and output options. In
contrast to the binary game, the best classical and quantum winning strategies
are not known exactly. In this paper we provide a constructive classical
strategy for winning a $\mathrm{CHSH}_{q}$ game, with $q$ being a prime. Our
construction achieves a winning probability better than
$\frac{1}{22}q^{-\frac{2}{3}}$, which is in contrast with the previously known
constructive strategies achieving only the winning probability of $O(q^{-1})$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01434</id><created>2015-12-04</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Pin</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic incoherent transport in Einstein-Maxwell-dilaton Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 106015 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.106015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent progress in the holographic approach makes it more transparent that
each conductivity can be decomposed into the coherent contribution due to
momentum relaxation and the incoherent contribution due to intrinsic current
relaxation. In this paper we investigate this decomposition in the framework of
Einstein-Maxwell-dilaton theory. We derive the perturbation equations, which
are decoupled for a large class of background solutions, and then obtain the
analytic results of conductivity with the slow momentum relaxation in low
frequency approximation, which is consistent with the known results from memory
matrix techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03095</id><created>2015-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Ulhoa</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Quantization of the Charge-Mass Ratio</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2017) 49: 3</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2170-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper deals with the problem of describing fundamental particles. The
Einstein-Rosen approach was revisited to explain que charge-mass ratio
quantization. Such a result is obtained once a quantization prescription is
applied to the expression of gravitational energy defined in the realm of
teleparallel gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06782</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dhuria</keyname><forenames>Mansi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Gaurav</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbativity, vacuum stability and inflation in the light of 750 GeV
  diphoton excess</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures. Journal version (to appear in Phy. Rev. D)</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D94 (2016) no.5, 055009</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.055009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent observation of the 750 GeV diphoton excess at 13 TeV LHC has
motivated many scenarios of physics beyond the Standard Model. In this work, we
begin by showing that many models which explain the observed excess tend to get
strongly coupled well below the Planck scale. We then study a simple scenario
involving colored vector-like fermions with exotic charges, which is expected
to stay weakly coupled till the Planck scale. We find the conditions under
which this happens, derive the Renormalization Group equations for such models
and solve them to show that perturbativity till Planck scale can be maintained
for a very reasonable choice of parameters. Finally, we discuss issues related
to vacuum stability and the possibility of inflation in the scenarios we study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01055</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haldar</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Jibitesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Subenoy</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comparative Study of Different Entropies in Fractal Universe</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Revised throughly</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we make an attempt to extend the idea of generalized Hawking temperature
and modified Bekenstein entropy at the event horizon in a fractal universe. The
modified Hawking temperature and Bekenstein entropy are considered in the
governing Friedmann equations, which is modified in the background of a fractal
universe. The validity of the Generalized second law of thermodynamics\,(GSLT)
and Thermodynamic Equilibrium\,(TE) have been examined and compared graphically
in a fractal universe filled with a perfect fluid having the constant equation
of state in three different generalized Bekenstein system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03997</id><created>2016-01-15</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janke</keyname><forenames>Wolfhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>Desmond A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solutions to plaquette Ising models with free and periodic
  boundaries</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>v5 - The title is changed to better reflect the contents and the
  exposition is streamlined. Version accepted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics B, Volume 914, January 2017, Pages 388-404</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.11.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An anisotropic limit of the 3d plaquette Ising model, in which the plaquette
couplings in one direction were set to zero, was solved for free boundary
conditions by Suzuki (Phys. Rev. Lett. 28 (1972) 507), who later dubbed it the
fuki-nuke, or &quot;no-ceiling&quot;, model. Defining new spin variables as the product
of nearest-neighbour spins transforms the Hamiltonian into that of a stack of
(standard) 2d Ising models and reveals the planar nature of the magnetic order,
which is also present in the fully isotropic 3d plaquette model. More recently,
the solution of the fuki-nuke model was discussed for periodic boundary
conditions, which require a different approach to defining the product spin
transformation, by Castelnovo et al. (Phys. Rev. B 81 (2010) 184303).
  We clarify the exact relation between partition functions with free and
periodic boundary conditions expressed in terms of original and product spin
variables for the 2d plaquette and 3d fuki-nuke models, noting that the
differences are already present in the 1d Ising model. In addition, we solve
the 2d plaquette Ising model with helical boundary conditions. The various
exactly solved examples illustrate how correlations can be induced in finite
systems as a consequence of the choice of boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06717</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Wei-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jamiolkowski</keyname><forenames>Megan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>William R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aubry</keyname><forenames>Nadine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massoudi</keyname><forenames>Mehrdad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antaki</keyname><forenames>James F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-Constituent Simulation of Thrombus Deposition</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.TO</categories><comments>Submission planned to Biophysical Journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present a spatio-temporal mathematical model for simulating
the formation and growth of a thrombus. Blood is treated as a multi-constituent
mixture comprised of a linear fluid phase and a thrombus (solid) phase. The
transport and reactions of 10 chemical and biological species are incorporated
using a system of coupled convection-reaction-diffusion (CRD) equations to
represent three processes in thrombus formation: initiation, propagation and
stabilization. Computational fluid dynamic (CFD) simulations using the
libraries of OpenFOAM were performed for two illustrative benchmark problems:
in vivo thrombus growth in an injured blood vessel and in vitro thrombus
deposition in micro-channels (1.5mm x 1.6mm x 0.1mm) with small crevices
(125{\mu}m x 75{\mu}m and 125{\mu}m x 137{\mu}m). For both problems, the
simulated thrombus deposition agreed very well with experimental observations,
both spatially and temporally. Based on the success with these two benchmark
problems, which have very different flow conditions and biological
environments, we believe that the current model will provide useful insight
into the genesis of thrombosis in blood-wetted devices, and provide a tool for
the design of less thrombogenic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06891</id><created>2016-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yepes</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Diboson excess and $Z'$-predictions via left-right non-linear Higgs</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 40 (2016) 1650228</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231650228X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The excess events reported by the ATLAS Collaboration in the $WZ$-final
state, and by the CMS Collaboration in the $e^+\!e^- jj$, $Wh$ and $jj$-final
states, may be induced by the decays of a heavy boson $W'$ in the 1.8-2 TeV
mass range, here modelled via the larger local group $SU(2)_L\times
SU(2)_R\times U(1)_{B-L}$ in a non-linear dynamical Higgs scenario. The
$W'$-production cross section at the 13 TeV LHC is around 700-1200 fb. This
framework also predicts a heavy $Z'$ boson with a mass of 2.5-4 TeV, and some
decay channels testable in the LHC Run II. We determine the cross section times
branching fractions for the dijet, dilepton and top-pair $Z'$-decay channels at
the 13 TeV LHC around 2.3, 7.1, 70.2 fb respectively, for $M_{Z'}= 2.5$ TeV,
while one/two orders of magnitude smaller for the dijet/dilepton and top-pair
modes at $M_{Z'}= 4$ TeV. Non-zero contributions from the effective operators,
and the underlying Higgs sector of the model, will induce sizeable enhancement
in the $W^+W^-$ and $Z h$-final states that could be probed in the future LHC
Run II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07954</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2016-04-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gani</keyname><forenames>Vakhid A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizunova</keyname><forenames>Mariya A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radomskiy</keyname><forenames>Roman V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalar triplet on a domain wall: an exact solution</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.PS</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures; v2: typos corrected, references added, minor
  changes to match version published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 04 (2016) 043</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a model with a real scalar Higgs field and a scalar triplet field
that allows existence of a topological defect -- a domain wall. The wall breaks
the global $O(3)$ symmetry of the model, which gives rise to non-Abelian
orientational degrees of freedom. We found an exact analytic solution that
describes a domain wall with a localized configuration of the triplet field on
it. This solution enables one to calculate contributions to the action from the
orientational and translational degrees of freedom of the triplet field. We
also study the linear stability of the domain wall with the triplet field
switched off. We obtain that degrees of freedom localized on the wall can
appear or do not appear depending on the parameters of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02150</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xc1;valos-Ovando</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastrogiuseppe</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulloa</keyname><forenames>Sergio E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noncollinear exchange interaction in transition metal dichalcogenide
  edges</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages and 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 161404(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.161404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Ruderman-Kittel-Kasuya-Yosida effective exchange interaction
between magnetic impurities embedded on the edges of transition-metal
dichalcogenide flakes, using a three-orbital tight-binding model. Electronic
states lying midgap of the bulk structure have strong one-dimensional (1D)
character, localized on the edges of the crystallite. This results in exchange
interactions with $1/r$ (or slower) decay with distance $r$, similar to other
1D systems. Most interestingly, however, the strong spin-orbit interaction in
these materials results in sizable non-collinear Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya
interactions between impurities, comparable in size to the usual Ising and
in-plane components. Varying the relevant Fermi energy by doping or gating may
allow one to modulate the effective interactions, controlling the possible
helical ground state configurations of multiple impurities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04073</id><created>2016-02-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Juan Jesus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sainz</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimov</keyname><forenames>Andrei B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum tomography via Non-orthogonal basis and weak values</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 91, 062127 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.91.062127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a relation between a bi-orthogonal set of equiseparable bases and the
weak values of the density matrix we derive an explicit formula for its
tomographic reconstruction completely analogous to the standard mutually
unbiased bases expansion. With the simple example of a qubit is evidenced the
relationship between weak values, measured probabilities and the separation
between non-orthogonal bases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07717</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Philippe</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldston</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glaser</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>d'Errico</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>A physical zero-knowledge object-comparison system for nuclear warhead
  verification</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages and 4 figures including methods</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7:12890 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12890</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Zero-knowledge proofs are mathematical cryptographic methods to demonstrate
the validity of a claim while providing no further information beyond the claim
itself. The possibility of using such proofs to process classified and other
sensitive physical data has attracted attention, especially in the field of
nuclear arms control. Here we demonstrate a non-electronic fast neutron
differential radiography technique using superheated emulsion detectors that
can confirm that two objects are identical without revealing their geometry or
composition. Such a technique could form the basis of a verification system
that could confirm the authenticity of nuclear weapons without sharing any
secret design information. More broadly, by demonstrating a physical
zero-knowledge proof that can compare physical properties of objects, this
experiment opens the door to developing other such secure proof-systems for
other applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03519</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takaguchi</keyname><forenames>Taro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Yuichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Cycle and flow trusses in directed networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures. Supplementary Materials can be found in the
  journal reference</comments><journal-ref>Royal Society Open Science, 3, 160270 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsos.160270</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When we represent real-world systems as networks, the directions of links
often convey valuable information. Finding module structures that respect link
directions is one of the most important tasks for analyzing directed networks.
Although many notions of a directed module have been proposed, no consensus has
been reached. This lack of consensus results partly because there might exist
distinct types of modules in a single directed network, whereas most previous
studies focused on an independent criterion for modules. To address this issue,
we propose a generic notion of the so-called truss structures in directed
networks. Our definition of truss is able to extract two distinct types of
trusses, named the cycle truss and the flow truss, from a unified framework. By
applying the method for finding trusses to empirical networks obtained from a
wide range of research fields, we find that most real networks contain both
cycle and flow trusses. In addition, the abundance of (and the overlap between)
the two types of trusses may be useful to characterize module structures in a
wide variety of empirical networks. Our findings shed light on the importance
of simultaneously considering different types of modules in directed networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04362</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Yu-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Dao-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Chih-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Yu-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandvik</keyname><forenames>Anders W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of the random-singlet phase: from the disordered Heisenberg
  chain to an amorphous valence-bond solid</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>15 pages; v2 new material on log corrections added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 174442 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.174442</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a strong-disorder renormalization group (SDRG) method and ground-state
quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) simulations to study S=1/2 spin chains with random
couplings, calculating disorder-averaged spin and dimer correlations. The QMC
simulations demonstrate logarithmic corrections to the power-law decaying
correlations obtained with the SDRG scheme. The same asymptotic forms apply
both for systems with standard Heisenberg exchange and for certain multi-spin
couplings leading to spontaneous dimerization in the clean system. We show that
the logarithmic corrections arise in the valence-bond (singlet pair) basis from
a contribution that can not be generated by the SDRG scheme. In the model with
multi-spin couplings, where the clean system dimerizes spontaneously, random
singlets form between spinons localized at domain walls in the presence of
disorder. This amorphous valence-bond solid is asymptotically a random-singlet
state and only differs from the random-exchange Heisenberg chain in its
short-distance properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04884</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bringmann</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ihle</keyname><forenames>Haavard Tveit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kersten</keyname><forenames>Joern</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walia</keyname><forenames>Parampreet</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppressing structure formation at dwarf galaxy scales and below: late
  kinetic decoupling as a compelling alternative to warm dark matter</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>23 pages revtex4, 11 figures. Extended discussion and model
  classification. Matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 103529 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.103529</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Warm dark matter cosmologies have been widely studied as an alternative to
the cold dark matter paradigm, the characteristic feature being a suppression
of structure formation on small cosmological scales. A very similar situation
occurs if standard cold dark matter particles are kept in local thermal
equilibrium with a, possibly dark, relativistic species until the universe has
cooled down to keV temperatures. We perform a systematic phenomenological study
of this possibility, and classify all minimal models containing dark matter and
an arbitrary radiation component that allow such a late kinetic decoupling. We
recover explicit cases recently discussed in the literature and identify new
classes of examples that are very interesting from a model-building point of
view. In some of these models dark matter is inevitably self-interacting, which
is remarkable in view of recent observational support for this possibility.
Hence, dark matter models featuring late kinetic decoupling have the potential
not only to alleviate the missing satellites problem but also to address other
problems of the cosmological concordance model on small scales, in particular
the cusp-core and too-big-too-fail problems, in some cases without invoking any
additional input.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07344</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Snelson</keyname><forenames>Stanley</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic stability for odd perturbations of the the stationary kink in
  the variable-speed $\phi^4$ model</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>22 pages, minor errors corrected</comments><msc-class>35L71</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the $\phi^4$ model in one space dimension with propagation speeds
that are small deviations from a constant function. In the constant-speed case,
a stationary solution called the kink is known explicitly, and the recent work
of Kowalczyk, Martel, and Mu\~noz established the asymptotic stability of the
kink with respect to odd perturbations in the natural energy space. We show
that a stationary kink solution exists also for our class of non-constant
propagation speeds, and extend the asymptotic stability result by taking a
perturbative approach to the method of Kowalczyk, Martel, and Mu\~noz. This
requires an understanding of the spectrum of the linearization around the
variable-speed kink.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08190</id><created>2016-03-27</created><updated>2016-10-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Minguzzi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The boundary of the chronology violating set</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Latex2e, 22 pages, 3 figures. v2: added proof that compactly
  generated horizons are compactly constructed</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 225004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/22/225004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A sufficiently general definition for the future and past boundaries of the
chronology violating region is given. In comparison to previous studies, this
work does not assume that the complement of the chronology violating set is
globally hyperbolic. The boundary of the chronology violating set is studied
and several propositions are obtained which confirm the reasonability of the
definition. Some singularity theorems related to chronology violation are
considered. Among the other results we prove that compactly generated horizons
are compactly constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07964</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>L&#xfc;tf&#xfc;o&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erdogan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic Properties of a Nucleon under the Generalized Symmetric
  Woods-Saxon Potential in Flourine 17 Isotope</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 Table and 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>ANADOLU UNIVERSITY JOURNAL OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY A - Applied
  Sciences and Engineering, 17 (2016), 708-716</journal-ref><doi>10.18038/aubtda.266151</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exact analytical solution of the Schr\&quot;odinger equation for a generalized
symmetrical Woods-Saxon potential are examined for a nucleon in Fluorine 17
nucleus for bound and quasi-bound states in one dimension. The wave functions
imply that the nucleon is completely confined within the nucleus, i.e., no
decay probability for bound states, while tunneling probabilities arise for the
quasi-bound state. We have calculated the temperature dependent Helmholtz free
energies, the internal energies, the entropies and the specific heat capacities
of the system. It is shown that, when the quasi-bound state is included, the
internal energy and entropy increase, while the Helmholtz energy decreases at
high temperatures. Very high excitation temperatures imply that the nucleus
does not tend to release a nucleon. The calculated quasi bound state energy is
in reasonable agreement with the experimental data on the cumulative fission
energy issued by IAEA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00500</id><created>2016-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>R&#xe5;sander</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moram</keyname><forenames>Michelle A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure of the high and low pressure polymorphs of
  MgSiN$_{2}$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/2053-1591/3/8/085902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed density functional calculations on the group II-IV nitride
MgSiN$_{2}$. At a pressure of about 20~GPa the ground state wurtzite derived
MgSiN$_{2}$ structure (LP-MgSiN$_{2}$) transforms into a rock-salt derived
structure (HP-MgSiN$_{2}$) in agreement with previous theoretical and
experimental studies. Both phases are wide band gap semiconductors with
indirect band gaps at equilibrium of 5.58 eV (LP-MgSiN$_{2}$) and 5.87 eV
(HP-MgSiN$_{2}$), respectively. As the pressure increases, the band gaps become
larger for both phases, however, the band gap in LP-MgSiN$_{2}$ increases
faster than the gap in HP-MgSiN$_{2}$ and with a high enough pressure the band
gap in LP-MgSiN$_{2}$ becomes larger than the band gap in HP-MgSiN$_{2}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03025</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2016-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinari</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Mayor</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parisi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yllanes</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature chaos is a non-local effect</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures. Version accepted for publication in JSTAT</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 123301</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/12/123301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Temperature chaos plays a role in important effects, like for example memory
and rejuvenation, in spin glasses, colloids, polymers. We numerically
investigate temperature chaos in spin glasses, exploiting its recent
characterization as a rare-event driven phenomenon. The peculiarities of the
transformation from periodic to anti-periodic boundary conditions in spin
glasses allow us to conclude that temperature chaos is non-local: no bounded
region of the system causes it. We precise the statistical relationship between
temperature chaos and the free-energy changes upon varying boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04758</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ashoorioon</keyname><forenames>Amjad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casadio</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koivisto</keyname><forenames>Tomi</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic non-Gaussianity from Rotational Symmetry Breaking Excited
  Initial States</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>v1: 13 pages, 3 figures, double column, v2: some refs added; v3:
  Matched the JCAP version</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2016-35</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 12 (2016) 002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/12/002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If the initial quantum state of the primordial perturbations broke rotational
invariance, that would be seen as a statistical anisotropy in the angular
correlations of the cosmic microwave background radiation (CMBR) temperature
fluctuations. This can be described by a general parameterisation of the
initial conditions that takes into account the possible direction-dependence of
both the amplitude and the phase of particle creation during inflation. The
leading effect in the CMBR two-point function is typically a quadrupole
modulation, whose coefficient is analytically constrained here to be $|B|
\lesssim 0.06$. The CMBR three-point function then acquires enhanced
non-gaussianity, especially for the local configurations. In the large
occupation number limit, a distinctive prediction is a modulation of the
non-gaussianity around a mean value depending on the angle that short and long
wavelength modes make with the preferred direction. The maximal variations with
respect to the mean value occur for the configurations which are coplanar with
the preferred direction and the amplitude of the non-gaussianity increases
(decreases) for the short wavelength modes aligned with (perpendicular to) the
preferred direction. For a high scale model of inflation with maximally pumped
up isotropic occupation and $\epsilon\simeq 0.01$ the difference between these
two configurations is about $0.27$, which could be detectable in the future.
For purely anisotropic particle creation, the non-Gaussianity can be larger and
its anisotropic feature very sharp. The non-gaussianity can then reach $f_{NL}
\sim 30$ in the preferred direction while disappearing from the correlations in
the orthogonal plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05145</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Liming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ting-gui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Ning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Chenwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>Jianwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Hongyan</forenames></author></authors><title>Long Fading Mid-Infrared Emission in Transient Coronal Line Emitters:
  Dust Echo of Tidal Disruption Flare</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal, 2016, Volume 832, 188</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/2/188</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sporadic accretion following the tidal disruption of a star by a
super-massive black hole (TDE) leads to a bright UV and soft X-ray flare in the
galactic nucleus. The gas and dust surrounding the black hole responses to such
a flare with an echo in emission lines and infrared emission. In this paper, we
report the detection of long fading mid-IR emission lasting up to 14 years
after the flare in four TDE candidates with transient coronal lines using the
WISE public data release. We estimate that the reprocessed mid-IR luminosities
are in the range between $4\times 10^{42}$ and $2\times 10^{43}$ erg~s$^{-1}$
and dust temperature in the range of 570-800K when WISE first detected these
sources three to five years after the flare. Both luminosity and dust
temperature decreases with time. We interpret the mid-IR emission as the
infrared echo of the tidal disruption flare. We estimate the UV luminosity at
the peak flare to be 1 to 30 times $10^{44}$ erg s$^{-1}$ and for warm dust
masses to be in the range of 0.05-1.3 Msun within a few parsecs. Our results
suggest that the mid-infrared echo is a general signature of TDE in the
gas-rich environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06444</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2016-10-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baldassi</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgs</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chayes</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ingrosso</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucibello</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saglietti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zecchina</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Unreasonable Effectiveness of Learning Neural Networks: From Accessible
  States and Robust Ensembles to Basic Algorithmic Schemes</title><categories>stat.ML cond-mat.dis-nn cs.LG</categories><comments>31 pages (14 main text, 18 appendix), 12 figures (6 main text, 6
  appendix)</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 113(48):E7655-E7662, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1608103113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In artificial neural networks, learning from data is a computationally
demanding task in which a large number of connection weights are iteratively
tuned through stochastic-gradient-based heuristic processes over a
cost-function. It is not well understood how learning occurs in these systems,
in particular how they avoid getting trapped in configurations with poor
computational performance. Here we study the difficult case of networks with
discrete weights, where the optimization landscape is very rough even for
simple architectures, and provide theoretical and numerical evidence of the
existence of rare - but extremely dense and accessible - regions of
configurations in the network weight space. We define a novel measure, which we
call the &quot;robust ensemble&quot; (RE), which suppresses trapping by isolated
configurations and amplifies the role of these dense regions. We analytically
compute the RE in some exactly solvable models, and also provide a general
algorithmic scheme which is straightforward to implement: define a
cost-function given by a sum of a finite number of replicas of the original
cost-function, with a constraint centering the replicas around a driving
assignment. To illustrate this, we derive several powerful new algorithms,
ranging from Markov Chains to message passing to gradient descent processes,
where the algorithms target the robust dense states, resulting in substantial
improvements in performance. The weak dependence on the number of precision
bits of the weights leads us to conjecture that very similar reasoning applies
to more conventional neural networks. Analogous algorithmic schemes can also be
applied to other optimization problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07714</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hong-Kun</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay of correlations for billiards with flat points II: cusps effect</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>3 fihures</comments><msc-class>37D50, 37A25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we continue to study billiards with flat points, by
constructing a spec family of dispersing billiards with cusps. All boundaries
of the table have positive curvature except that the curvature vanishes at the
vertex of a cusp, i.e. there is a pair of boundaries intersection at the flat
point tangentially. We study the mixing rates of this one-parameter family of
billiards with parameter $\beta\in (2,\infty)$, and show that the correlation
functions of the collision map decay polynomially with order
$\cO(n^{-\frac{1}{\beta-1}})$ as $n\to\infty$. In particular, this solves an
open question raised by Chernov and Markarian \cite{CM05}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02893</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yuxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiribella</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashi</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal compression for identically prepared qubit states</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math-ph math.IT math.MP</categories><comments>5+ 12 pages, 3 figures. Published version.A few typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 090502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.090502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish the ultimate limits to the compression of sequences of
identically prepared qubits. The limits are determined by Holevo's information
quantity and are attained through use of the optimal universal cloning machine,
which finds here a novel application to quantum Shannon theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03960</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-09-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Itsik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharon</keyname><forenames>Nati</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retzker</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuous dynamical decoupling utilizing time-dependent detuning</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Fortschr. Phys., 64, 1 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/prop.201600071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Resilience to noise and to decoherence processes is an important ingredient
for the implementation of quantum information processing, and quantum
technologies. To this end, techniques such as pulsed and continuous dynamical
decoupling have been proposed to reduce noise effects. In this paper, we
suggest a new approach to implementing continuous dynamical decoupling
techniques, that uses an extra control parameter; namely, the ability to shape
the time dependence of the detuning. This approach reduces the complexity of
the experimental setup, such that we are only left with noise originating from
the frequency of the driving field, which is much more robust than the
amplitude (Rabi frequency) noise. As an example, we show that our technique can
be utilized for improved sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04566</id><created>2016-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bredtmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patchkovskii</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>iSURF: A family of infinite-time surface flux methods</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 245001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/24/245001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The computation and analysis of photoelectron spectra (PES) is a fundamental
technique in atomic and molecular physics to study the structural and dynamical
properties of a target system, and to gain insight into the process of its
ionization. Since the first numerical solutions of the time-dependent
Schr\&quot;odinger equation, numerous methods have been developed to extract PES
from the calculated wave functions. However, most of these methods have severe
limitations or are computationally very demanding. Here we present a new family
of methods, based on the ideas of the so-called analytical Volkov continuation,
or time-dependent surface flux ([Ermolaev, A. M. et al. Phys. Rev. A 60, 4831
(1999), Ermolaev, A. M. et al. Phys. Rev. A 62, 015401 (2000), Tao L. and
Scrinzi A. New Journal of Physics 14, 013021 (2012)]), that allows one to
obtain fully-converged PES at the end of the laser pulse using either Volkov
states or the exact scattering-states, and that has been implemented in the
Time Dependent Schr\&quot;odinger Equation (TDSE) solver ([Patchkovskii S. and
Muller H. G., Computer Physics Communications 199, 153 (2016)]).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04847</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wlaz&#x142;owski</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekizawa</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magierski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bulgac</keyname><forenames>Aurel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forbes</keyname><forenames>Michael McNeil</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex pinning and dynamics in the neutron star crust</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR cond-mat.supr-con nucl-th</categories><comments>supplemental materials included</comments><report-no>NT@UW-16-06</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 232701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.232701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of the interaction between superfluid vortices and the neutron
star crust, conjectured by Anderson and Itoh in 1975 to be at the heart vortex
creep and the cause of glitches, has been a long-standing question in
astrophysics. Using a qualitatively new approach, we follow the dynamics as
superfluid vortices move in response to the presence of &quot;nuclei&quot; (nuclear
defects in the crust). The resulting motion is perpendicular to the force,
similar to the motion of a spinning top when pushed. We show that nuclei repel
vortices in the neutron star crust, and characterize the force as a function of
the vortex-nucleus separation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05647</id><created>2016-06-17</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Chantal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Fangqiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlesinger</keyname><forenames>Kimberly J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>Izzeddin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>Jean M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective Decision Dynamics in Group Evacuation: Behavioral Experiment
  and Machine Learning Models</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.NE cs.SI</categories><comments>formerly part 1 of a 2-part series, now presented individually</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Identifying factors that affect human decision making and quantifying their
influence remain essential and challenging tasks for the design and
implementation of social and technological communication systems. We report
results of a behavioral experiment involving decision making in the face of an
impending natural disaster. In a controlled laboratory setting, we characterize
individual and group evacuation decision making influenced by several key
factors, including the likelihood of the disaster, available shelter capacity,
group size, and group decision protocol. Our results show that success in
individual decision making is not a strong predictor of group performance. We
use an artificial neural network trained on the collective behavior of subjects
to predict individual and group outcomes. Overall model accuracy increases with
the inclusion of a subject-specific performance parameter based on laboratory
trials that captures individual differences. In parallel, we demonstrate that
the social media activity of individual subjects, specifically their Facebook
use, can be used to generate an alternative individual personality profile that
leads to comparable model accuracy. Quantitative characterization and
prediction of collective decision making is crucial for the development of
effective policies to guide the action of populations in the face of threat or
uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05851</id><created>2016-06-19</created><updated>2016-08-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Ka Hei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mok</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fung</keyname><forenames>Kin Hung</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Light Scattering by Topological ${\mathcal{PT}}$-symmetric
  Particle Arrays</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6 38049 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep38049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Robust topological edge modes may evolve into complex-frequency modes when a
physical system becomes non-Hermitian. We show that, while having negligible
forward optical extinction cross section, a conjugate pair of such complex
topological edge modes in a non-Hermitian $\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric system can
give rise to an anomalous sideway scattering when they are simultaneously
excited by a plane wave. We propose a realization of such scattering state in a
linear array of subwavelength resonators coated with gain media. The prediction
is based on an analytical two-band model and verified by rigorous numerical
simulation using multiple-multipole scattering theory. The result suggests an
extreme situation where leakage of classical information is unnoticeable to the
transmitter and the receiver when such a $\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric unit is
inserted into the communication channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06733</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carena</keyname><forenames>Marcela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Peisi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ismail</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Low</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>Nausheen R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Carlos E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Second Peak in Diphoton (or Diboson) Resonances</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures. v2: added discussion with updated figures,
  modified title and benchmark, conclusions unchanged, to appear in PRD</comments><report-no>EFI-16-14, NSF-KITP-16-089, WSU-HEP-1602</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 115001 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many new physics models contain a neutral scalar resonance that can be
predominantly produced via gluon fusion through loops. In such a case, there
could be important effects of additional particles, that in turn may hadronize
before decaying and form bound states. This interesting possibility may lead to
novel signatures with double peaks that can be searched for at the LHC. We
study the phenomenology of double peak searches in diboson final states from
loop induced production and decay of a new neutral spin-0 resonance at the LHC.
The loop-induced couplings should be mediated by particles carrying color and
electroweak charge that after forming bound states will induce a second peak in
the diboson invariant mass spectrum near twice their mass. A second peak could
be present via loop-induced couplings into $gg$ (dijet), $\gamma\gamma$ and
$Z\gamma$ final states as well as in the $WW$ and $ZZ$ channels for the case of
a pseudo-scalar resonance or for scalars with suppressed tree-level coupling to
gauge bosons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07001</id><created>2016-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Aalbers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agostini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alfonsi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaro</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amsler</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aprile</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arazi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arneodo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrow</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baudis</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benabderrahmane</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beskers</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breskin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breur</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruenner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budnik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buetikofer</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calven</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>J. M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cichon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coderre</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colijn</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conrad</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cussonneau</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Decowski</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diglio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drexlin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchovni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erdal</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eurin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferella</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fieguth</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulgione</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosso</keyname><forenames>A. Gallo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Gangi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Giovanni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galloway</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garbini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glueck</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grignon</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasterok</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannen</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogenbirk</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howlett</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hils</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaminsky</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilminster</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kish</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krauss</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landsman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>F. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindemann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>J. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Undagoitia</keyname><forenames>T. Marrodan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masbou</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massoli</keyname><forenames>F. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayani</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messina</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micheneau</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molinario</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morteau</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murra</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naganoma</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newstead</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberlack</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakarha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelssers</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Perio</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persiani</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piastra</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piro</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plante</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupp</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>J. M. F. Dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sartorelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheibelhut</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavina</keyname><forenames>L. Scotto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selvi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shagin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simgen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sissol</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Sivers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thers</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thurn</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiseni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trotta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tunnell</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valerius</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vargas</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinheimer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wester</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wulf</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuber</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>DARWIN: towards the ultimate dark matter detector</title><categories>astro-ph.IM hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>36 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1611 (2016) no.11, 017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/11/017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  DARk matter WImp search with liquid xenoN (DARWIN) will be an experiment for
the direct detection of dark matter using a multi-ton liquid xenon time
projection chamber at its core. Its primary goal will be to explore the
experimentally accessible parameter space for Weakly Interacting Massive
Particles (WIMPs) in a wide mass-range, until neutrino interactions with the
target become an irreducible background. The prompt scintillation light and the
charge signals induced by particle interactions in the xenon will be observed
by VUV sensitive, ultra-low background photosensors. Besides its excellent
sensitivity to WIMPs above a mass of 5 GeV/c2, such a detector with its large
mass, low-energy threshold and ultra-low background level will also be
sensitive to other rare interactions. It will search for solar axions, galactic
axion-like particles and the neutrinoless double-beta decay of 136-Xe, as well
as measure the low-energy solar neutrino flux with &lt;1% precision, observe
coherent neutrino-nucleus interactions, and detect galactic supernovae. We
present the concept of the DARWIN detector and discuss its physics reach, the
main sources of backgrounds and the ongoing detector design and R&amp;D efforts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07665</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-10-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Minguzzi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The conformal transformation of the night sky</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages. v2: a minimal change in the Introduction</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 235009</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/23/235009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a simple differential geometric proof of the conformal transformation
of the night sky under change of observer. The proof does not rely on the four
dimensionality of spacetime or on spinor methods. Furthermore, it really shows
that the result does not depend on Lorentz transformations. This approach, by
giving a transparent covariant expression to the conformal factor, shows that
in most situations it is possible to define a thermal sky metric independent of
the observer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08774</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kammermeier</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wenk</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schliemann</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Control of Spin Helix Symmetry in Semiconductor Quantum Wells by Crystal
  Orientation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 236801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.236801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possibility of spin-preserving symmetries due to the
interplay of Rashba and Dresselhaus spin-orbit coupling in n-doped zinc-blende
semiconductor quantum wells of general crystal orientation. It is shown that a
conserved spin operator can be realized if and only if at least two
growth-direction Miller indices agree in modulus. The according spin-orbit
field has in general both in-plane and out-of-plane components and is always
perpendicular to the shift vector of the corresponding persistent spin helix.
We also analyze higher-order effects arising from the Dresselhaus term, and the
impact of our results on weak (anti)localization corrections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01884</id><created>2016-07-07</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Muthukrishna</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames><affiliation>School of Mathematics and Physics, University of Queensland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Parkinson</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>School of Mathematics and Physics, University of Queensland</affiliation></author></authors><title>A cosmographic analysis of the transition to acceleration using SN-Ia
  and BAO</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>21 pages, 10 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics, Issue 11, article
  id. 052, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/11/052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the distance-redshift relation using a cosmographic methodology,
and show how the cosmographic parameters can be used to determine the redshift
of transition from deceleration to acceleration. Such a transition at a low
redshift occupies only a small region of the available parameter space, and the
prior assumption of an early period of deceleration can significantly change
the posterior constraints. We use available type Ia Supernovae (SN-Ia) and
Baryon Acoustic Oscillation (BAO) data sets to determine the cosmographic
deceleration $q_0$, jerk $j_0$, snap $s_0$ and lerk $l_0$ parameters. The
parameters are consistent with the $\Lambda$CDM model for a flat universe
within 2-sigma. We derive constraints on the redshift of transition from
deceleration to acceleration for the different expansions, and find $z_{\rm
acc} &gt; 0.14$ at 95% confidence in the most conservative case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03449</id><created>2016-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Lun-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Dong-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fu-Chun</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory for Spin Selective Andreev Reflection in Vortex Core of
  Topological Superconductor: Majorana Zero Modes on Spherical Surface and
  Application to Spin Polarized Scanning Tunneling Microscope Probe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 14 figures, 1 table. Comments are welcome!</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 224501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.224501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Majorana zero modes (MZMs) have been predicted to exist in the topological
insulator (TI)/superconductor (SC) heterostructure. Recent spin polarized
scanning tunneling microscope (STM) experiment$^{1}$ has observed
spin-polarization dependence of the zero bias differential tunneling
conductance at the center of vortex core, which may be attributed to the spin
selective Andreev reflection, a novel property of the MZMs theoretically
predicted in 1-dimensional nanowire$^{2}$. Here we consider a helical electron
system described by a Rashba spin orbit coupling Hamiltonian on a spherical
surface with a s-wave superconducting pairing due to proximity effect. We
examine in-gap excitations of a pair of vortices with one at the north pole and
the other at the south pole. While the MZM is not a spin eigenstate, the spin
wavefunction of the MZM at the center of the vortex core, r = 0, is parallel to
the magnetic field, and the local Andreev reflection of the MZM is spin
selective, namely occurs only when the STM tip has the spin polarization
parallel to the magnetic field, similar to the case in 1-dimensional nanowire2.
The total local differential tunneling conductance consists of the normal term
proportional to the local density of states and an additional term arising from
the Andreev reflection. We also discuss the finite size effect, for which the
MZM at the north pole is hybridized with the MZM at the south pole. We apply
our theory to examine the recently reported spin-polarized STM experiments and
show good agreement with the experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07764</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sainz</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimov</keyname><forenames>Andrei B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Error estimation in the direct state tomography</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>EPL 116, 10002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/116/10002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that reformulating the Direct State Tomography (DST) protocol in
terms of projections into a set of non-orthogonal bases one can perform an
accuracy analysis of DST in a similar way as in the standard projection-based
reconstruction schemes. i.e. in terms of the Hilbert-Schmidt distance between
estimated and true states. This allows us to determine the estimation error for
any measurement strength, including the weak measurement case, and to obtain an
explicit analytic form for the average minimum square errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08126</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roldan-Vargas</keyname><forenames>Sandalo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovigatti</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciortino</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Connectivity, Dynamics, and Structure in a Tetrahedral Network Liquid</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>19 pages, 17 panels and 29 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a detailed computational study by Brownian Dynamics simulations of
the structure and dynamics of a liquid of patchy particles which develops an
amorphous tetrahedral network upon decreasing temperature. The highly
directional particle interactions allows us to investigate the system
connectivity by discriminating the total set of particles into different
populations according to a penta-modal distribution of bonds per particle. With
this methodology we show how the particle bonding process is not randomly
independent but it manifests clear bond correlations at low temperatures. We
further explore the dynamics of the system in real space and establish a clear
relation between particle mobility and particle connectivity. In particular, we
provide evidence of anomalous diffusion at low temperatures and reveal how the
dynamics is affected by the short-time hopping motion of the weakly bounded
particles. Finally we widely investigate the dynamics and structure of the
system in Fourier space and identify two quantitatively similar length scales,
one dynamic and the other one static, which increase upon cooling the system
and reach distances of the order of few particle diameters. We summarize our
findings in a qualitative picture where the low temperature regime of the
viscoelastic liquid is understood in terms of an evolving network of long time
metastable cooperative domains of particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03120</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Christ</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonnenschein</keyname><forenames>Bernard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author></authors><title>Tristable and multiple bistable activity in complex random binary
  networks of two-state units</title><categories>physics.soc-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>The final publication is available at Springer via http://dx.doi.org/
  10.1140/epjb/e2016-70474-x</comments><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70474-x</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We study complex networks of stochastic two-state units. Our aim is to model
discrete stochastic excitable dynamics with a rest and an excited state. Both
states are assumed to possess different waiting time distributions. The rest
state is treated as an activation process with an exponentially distributed
life time, whereas the latter in the excited state shall have a constant mean
which may originate from any distribution. The activation rate of any single
unit is determined by its neighbors according to a random complex network
structure. In order to treat this problem in an analytical way, we use a
heterogeneous mean-field approximation yielding a set of equations general
valid for uncorrelated random networks. Based on this derivation we focus on
random binary networks where the network is solely comprised of nodes with
either of two degrees. The ratio between the two degrees is shown to be a
crucial parameter. Dependent on the composition of the network the steady
states show the usual transition from disorder to homogeneous ordered
bistability as well as new scenarios that include inhomogeneous ordered and
disordered bistability as well as tristability. The various steady states
differ in their spiking activity expressed by a state dependent spiking rate.
Numerical simulations agree with analytic results of the heterogeneous
mean-field approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03291</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Hui-Yiing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scherrer</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reviving Quintessence with an Exponential Potential</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, reference and discussion added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine a quintessence model with a modified exponential potential given
by $V(\phi) = V_0(1+e^{-\lambda \phi})$. Unlike quintessence with a standard
exponential potential, our model can yield an acceptable accelerated expansion
at late times, while producing a distinct &quot;early dark energy&quot; signature at high
redshift. We determine the evolution of the equation of state parameter,
$w_\phi$, and the density parameter, $\Omega_\phi$, as a function of the scale
factor. The strongest constraints on the model come from cosmic microwave
background observations rather than supernova data. The former give the limit
$\lambda &gt; 13$. This model predicts a value of the effective neutrino number
during Big Bang nucleosynthesis larger than the standard model value. It also
provides a partial solution to the coincidence problem, in that the ratio of
the quintessence energy density is always within a few orders of magnitude of
the background radiation or matter density from the early universe up to the
present, but it does not explain why the accelerated expansion is beginning
near the present day, suggesting that these two different ways of
characterizing the coincidence problem are not entirely equivalent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03806</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03806</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2016-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ori</keyname><forenames>Amos</forenames></author></authors><title>Versatile method for renormalized stress-energy computation in
  black-hole spacetimes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures. V2: Added two important references (Refs. [18]
  and [19]), which already showed ANEC violations previously, although for
  different fields. Title was consequently changed, and also various
  modifications were made in the text. Overall, the paper's content is
  unchanged. V3: Typo corrected. V4: Updated to match the version in PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 231101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.231101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report here on a new method for calculating the renormalized stress-energy
tensor (RSET) in black-hole (BH) spacetimes, which should also be applicable to
dynamical BHs and to spinning BHs. This new method only requires the spacetime
to admit a single symmetry. So far we developed three variants of the method,
aimed for stationary, spherically symmetric, or axially symmetric BHs. We used
this method to calculate the RSET of a minimally-coupled massless scalar field
in Schwarzschild and Reissner-Nordstrom backgrounds, for several quantum
states. We present here the results for the RSET in the Schwarzschild case in
Unruh state (the state describing BH evaporation). The RSET is type I at weak
field, and becomes type IV at $r\lesssim2.78M$. Then we use the RSET results to
explore violation of the weak and null Energy conditions. We find that both
conditions are violated all the way from $r\simeq4.9M$ to the horizon. We also
find that the averaged weak energy condition is violated by a class of
(unstable) circular timelike geodesics. Most remarkably, the circular null
geodesic at $r=3M$ violates the averaged null energy condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04388</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martizzi</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrusa</keyname><forenames>Harrison</forenames></author></authors><title>Mass modeling of galaxy clusters: quantifying hydrostatic bias and
  contribution from non-thermal pressure</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables, submitted to MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galaxy cluster mass determinations achieved using X-ray and
Sunyaev-Zel'dovich data combined with the assumption of hydrostatic equilibrium
are generally biased. The bias exists for two main reasons: non-thermal
pressure forces are expected to contribute to the overall pressure balance and
deviations from spherical symmetry and hydrostatic equilibrium can be present.
In this paper, we use a sample of zoom-in hydrodynamical simulations of galaxy
clusters to measure the magnitude of hydrostatic bias and the non-thermal
contribution to the total pressure. We propose a new empirical model for
non-thermal pressure based on our simulations that can be applied to
observations. We show that our model can be successfully applied to remove most
of the bias related to neglection of non-thermal pressure, which is usually not
included in hydrostatic cluster mass profile reconstructions. The use of this
model may significantly improve the calibration of cluster scaling relations
that are a key tool for cluster cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06971</id><created>2016-08-24</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Samanta</keyname><forenames>Himadri S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuravlev</keyname><forenames>Pavel I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinczewski</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hori</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Shaon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thirumalai</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Protein Collapse is Encoded in the Folded State Architecture</title><categories>q-bio.BM cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Natural protein sequences that self-assemble to form globular structures are
compact with high packing densities in the folded states. It is known that
proteins unfold upon addition of denaturants, adopting random coil structures.
The dependence of the radii of gyration on protein size in the folded and
unfolded states obeys the same scaling laws as synthetic polymers. Thus, one
might surmise that the mechanism of collapse in proteins and polymers ought to
be similar. However, because the number of amino acids in single domain
proteins is not significantly greater than about two hundred, it has not been
resolved if the unfolded states of proteins are compact under conditions that
favor the folded states - a problem at the heart of how proteins fold. By
adopting a theory used to derive polymer-scaling laws, we find that the
propensity for the unfolded state of a protein to be compact is universal and
is encoded in the contact map of the folded state. Remarkably, analysis of over
2000 proteins shows that proteins rich in $\beta$-sheets have greater tendency
to be compact than $\alpha$-helical proteins. The theory provides insights into
the reasons for the small size of single domain proteins and the physical basis
for the origin of multi-domain proteins. Application to non-coding RNA
molecules show that they have evolved to collapse sharing similarities to
$\beta$-sheet proteins. An implication of our theory is that the evolution of
natural foldable sequences is guided by the requirement that for efficient
folding they should populate minimum energy compact states under folding
conditions. This concept also supports the compaction selection hypothesis used
to rationalize the unusually condensed states of viral RNA molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07557</id><created>2016-08-26</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Saeed</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xfc;reci</keyname><forenames>Hakan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Hermitian coupled-mode theory for incoherently pumped
  exciton-polariton condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures; updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 053856 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.053856</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The generalized Gross-Pitaevskii equation (gGPE) is an effective
phenomenological description for the dynamics of incoherently pumped
exciton-polariton condensates. However, a brute force numerical simulation of
the gGPE provides little physical insight into condensate formation under
arbitrary pumping configurations, and is demanding in terms of computational
resources. We introduce in this paper a modal description of polariton
condensation under incoherent pumping of arbitrary spatial profile, based on
eigenmodes of the non-Hermitian generator of the linearized dynamics. A
pump-dependent basis is then introduced to formulate a temporal coupled-mode
theory that captures condensate dynamics in the presence of all nonlinear
interactions. Simulations using a single set of modes for a given pumping and
trapping configuration agree very well with a full integration of the gGPE in
diverse dynamical regimes, supporting the validity of this modal description,
while also providing a speedup in simulation times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02148</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2016-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drlica-Wagner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bechtol</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allam</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruendl</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nidever</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>K. A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wechsler</keyname><forenames>R. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cioni</keyname><forenames>M. R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conn</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Y. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>N. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neilsen</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>No&#xeb;l</keyname><forenames>N. E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pieres</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stringfellow</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Marel</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanny</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Ultra-Faint Galaxy Candidate Discovered in Early Data from the
  Magellanic Satellites Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, 1 table; updated to match published version</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-353-AE</report-no><journal-ref>ApJ 833, L5 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/833/1/L5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new ultra-faint stellar system found in Dark Energy Camera data
from the first observing run of the Magellanic Satellites Survey (MagLiteS).
MagLiteS J0644-5953 (Pictor II or Pic II) is a low surface brightness ({\mu} =
28.5 mag arcsec$^{-2}$ within its half-light radius) resolved overdensity of
old and metal-poor stars located at a heliocentric distance of 45 kpc. The
physical size (r$_{1/2}$ = 46 pc) and low luminosity (Mv = -3.2 mag) of this
satellite are consistent with the locus of spectroscopically confirmed
ultra-faint galaxies. MagLiteS J0644-5953 (Pic II) is located 11.3 kpc from the
Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC), and comparisons with simulation results in the
literature suggest that this satellite was likely accreted with the LMC. The
close proximity of MagLiteS J0644-5953 (Pic II) to the LMC also makes it the
most likely ultra-faint galaxy candidate to still be gravitationally bound to
the LMC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02344</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaul</keyname><forenames>Romesh K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sengupta</keyname><forenames>Sandipan</forenames></author></authors><title>New solutions in pure gravity with degenerate tetrads</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, Journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 104047 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.104047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In first order formulation of pure gravity, we find a new class of solutions
to the equations of motion represented by degenerate four-geometries. These
configurations are described by non- invertible tetrads with two zero
eigenvalues and admit non-vanishing torsion. The homogeneous ones among these
infinitely many degenerate solutions admit a geometric classification provided
by the three fundamental geometries that a closed two-surface can accomodate,
namely, E^2 , S^2 and H^2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02555</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berlin</keyname><forenames>Asher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hooper</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krnjaic</keyname><forenames>Gordan</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Dark Matter From A Highly Decoupled Sector</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>28 pages (1 in the Appendix), 9 figures; added references and updated
  to published version</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-318-A</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 095019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.095019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has recently been shown that if the dark matter is in thermal equilibrium
with a sector that is highly decoupled from the Standard Model, it can
freeze-out with an acceptable relic abundance, even if the dark matter is as
heavy as ~1-100 PeV. In such scenarios, both the dark and visible sectors are
populated after inflation, but with independent temperatures. The lightest
particle in the dark sector will be generically long-lived, and can come to
dominate the energy density of the universe. Upon decaying, these particles can
significantly reheat the visible sector, diluting the abundance of dark matter
and thus allowing for dark matter particles that are much heavier than
conventional WIMPs. In this paper, we present a systematic and pedagogical
treatment of the cosmological history in this class of models, emphasizing the
simplest scenarios in which a dark matter candidate annihilates into hidden
sector particles which then decay into visible matter through the vector,
Higgs, or lepton portals. In each case, we find ample parameter space in which
very heavy dark matter particles can provide an acceptable thermal relic
abundance. We also discuss possible extensions of models featuring these
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03218</id><created>2016-09-11</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Giovannini</keyname><forenames>Umberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;bener</keyname><forenames>Hannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author></authors><title>Monitoring in real time the photon-dressing and undressing of
  quasiparticles from first principles time-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical pumping of solids creates a non-equilibrium electronic structure
where electrons and photons combine to form quasiparticles of dressed
electronic states. The resulting shift of electronic levels is known as the
optical Stark effect, visible as a red shift in the optical spectrum. Here we
show that in a pump-probe setup we can uniquely define a non-equilibrium
quasiparticle bandstructure that can be directly measurable with photo-electron
spectroscopy. The dynamical photon-dressing (and undressing) of the many-body
electronic states can be monitored by pump-probe time and angular resolved
photoelectron spectroscopy (tr-ARPES) as the photon-dressed bandstructure
evolves in time depending on the pump-probe pulse overlap. The computed
tr-ARPES spectrum agrees perfectly with the quasi-energy spectrum of Floquet
theory at maximum overlap and goes to the the equilibrium bandstructure as the
pump-probe overlap goes to zero. Additionally, we show how this time-dependent
non-equilibrium quasiparticle structure can be understood to be the
bandstructure underlying the optical Stark effect. The extension to
spin-resolved PES can be used to predict asymmetric dichroic response linked to
the valley selective optical excitations in monolayer transition metal
dichalcogenides (TMDs).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04287</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sanchez-Soares</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greer</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A semimetal nanowire rectifier: balancing quantum confinement and
  surface electronegativity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b03612</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For semimetal nanowires with diameters smaller than a few tens of nanometers,
a semimetal-to-semiconductor transition is observed as the emergence of an
energy band gap resulting from quantum confinement. Quantum confinement in a
semimetal results in either lifting of the degeneracy of the conduction and
valence bands in a zero gap semimetal, or shifting of bands with a negative
energy overlap to form conduction and valence bands. For semimetal nanowires
with diameters below 10 nanometer, the magnitude of the band gap can become
significantly larger than the thermal energy at room temperature resulting in a
new class of semiconductors relevant for nanoelectronics with critical
dimensions on the order of a few atomic lengths. The smaller a nanowire's
diameter, the larger its surface-to-volume ratio thus leading to an increasing
impact of surface chemistry on its electronic structure. Energy level shifts to
states in the vicinity of the Fermi level due to the electronegativity of
surface terminating species are shown to be comparable in magnitude to quantum
confinement effects at nanowire diameters of a few nanometer; these two effects
can be used to counteract one another leading to semimetallic behavior for
nanowire cross sections at which the quantum confinement effect would otherwise
dominate. Abruptly changing the surface terminating species along the length of
a nanowire leads to an abrupt change in the surface electronegativity. This can
result in the formation of a semimetal-semiconductor junction within a
monomaterial nanowire, without the need for impurity doping nor requiring the
formation of a heterojunction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05912</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grishin</keyname><forenames>Evgeni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perets</keyname><forenames>Hagai B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenati</keyname><forenames>Yossef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michaely</keyname><forenames>Erez</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Hill-Stability Criteria for Hierarchical Three-Body Systems
  at Arbitrary Inclinations</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3096</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental aspect of the three-body problem is its stability. Most
stability studies have focused on the co-planar three-body problem, deriving
analytic criteria for the dynamical stability of such pro/retrograde systems.
Numerical studies of inclined systems phenomenologically mapped their stability
regions, but neither complement it by theoretical framework, nor provided
satisfactory fit for their dependence on mutual inclinations. Here we present a
novel approach to study the stability of hierarchical three-body systems at
arbitrary inclinations, which accounts not only for the instantaneous stability
of such systems, but also for the secular stability and evolution through
Lidov-Kozai cycles and evection. We generalize the Hill-stability criteria to
arbitrarily inclined triple systems, explain the existence of quasi-stable
regimes and characterize the inclination dependence of their stability. We
complement the analytic treatment with an extensive numerical study, to test
our analytic results. We find excellent correspondence up to high inclinations
$(\sim120^{\circ}$), beyond which the agreement is marginal. At such high
inclinations the stability radius is larger, the ratio between the outer and
inner periods becomes comparable, and our secular averaging approach is no
longer strictly valid. We therefore combine our analytic results with
polynomial fits to the numerical results to obtain a generalized stability
formula for triple systems at arbitrary inclinations. Besides providing a
generalized secular-based physical explanation for the stability of non
co-planar systems, our results have direct implications for any triple systems,
and in particular binary planets and moon/satellite systems; we briefly discuss
the latter as a test case for our models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00994</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Skripnikov</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Combined 4-component and relativistic pseudopotential study of ThO for
  the electron electric dipole moment search</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 214301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4968229</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A precise theoretical study of the electronic structure of heavy atom
diatomic molecules is of key importance to interpret the experiments in the
search for violation of time-reversal (T) and spatial-parity (P) symmetries of
fundamental interactions it terms of the electron electric dipole moment, eEDM,
and dimensionless constant, $k_{T,P}$, characterizing the strength of the
T,P-odd pseudoscalar$-$scalar electron$-$nucleus neutral current interaction.
ACME collaboration has recently obtained and improved limits on these
quantities using a beam of ThO molecules in the $H^3\Delta_1$ state [Science
343, 269 (2014)]. We apply the combined direct 4-component and two-step
relativistic pseudopotential/restoration approaches to a benchmark calculation
of the effective electric field, Eeff, parameter of the T,P-odd
pseudoscalar$-$scalar interaction, $W_{T,P}$, and HFS constant in $^3\Delta_1$
state of the ThO molecule. The first two parameters are required to interpret
the experimental data in terms of the eEDM and $k_{T,P}$ constant. We have
investigated the electron correlation for all of the 98 electrons of ThO
simultaneously up to the level of the coupled cluster with single, double and
noniterative triple amplitudes theory. Contributions from iterative triple and
noniterative quadruple cluster amplitudes for the valence electrons have been
also treated. The obtained values are Eeff=79.9 GV/cm, $W_{T,P}$=113.1 kHz. The
theoretical uncertainty of these values we estimate as about two times smaller
than that of our previous study [JCP, 142, 024301 (2015)]. It was found that
the correlation of the inner- and outer- core electrons contributes 9% to the
effective electric field. The values of the molecule frame dipole moment of the
$^3\Delta_1$ state and the $H^3\Delta_1\to X^1\Sigma^+$ transition energy of
ThO calculated within the same methods are in a very good agreement with the
experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02241</id><created>2016-10-07</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kubo</keyname><forenames>Jisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Masatoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Scale genesis and gravitational wave in a classically scale invariant
  extension of the standard model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 6 figures; references added; typos corrected; published in
  JCAP</comments><report-no>KANAZAWA-16-11, KUNS-2643</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP12 (2016) 001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/12/001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assume that the origin of the electroweak (EW) scale is a gauge-invariant
scalar-bilinear condensation in a strongly interacting non-abelian gauge
sector, which is connected to the standard model via a Higgs portal coupling.
The dynamical scale genesis appears as a phase transition at finite
temperature, and it can produce a gravitational wave (GW) background in the
early Universe. We find that the critical temperature of the scale phase
transition lies above that of the EW phase transition and below few $O(100)$
GeV and it is strongly first-order. We calculate the spectrum of the GW
background and find the scale phase transition is strong enough that the GW
background can be observed by DECIGO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03747</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Melnikov</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tancredi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wever</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-loop $gg \to Hg$ amplitude mediated by a nearly massless quark</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 4 figures, analytical results attached as ancillary files,
  v2 minor typos corrected, published on JHEP</comments><report-no>TTP16-041</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analytically compute the two-loop scattering amplitude $gg \to Hg$
assuming that the mass of the quark, that mediates the ggH interaction, is
vanishingly small. Our computation provides an important ingredient required to
improve the theoretical description of the top-bottom interference effect in
Higgs boson production in gluon fusion, and to elucidate its impact on the
Higgs boson transverse momentum distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04682</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2016-11-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hees</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>Quentin G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgoin</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bars</keyname><forenames>H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne Pihan-Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerlin</keyname><forenames>Christine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poncin-Lafitte</keyname><forenames>Christophe Le</forenames></author></authors><title>Tests of Lorentz symmetry in the gravitational sector</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>40 pages, 2 figures, version accepted for publication in Universe</comments><journal-ref>Universe 2016, 2(4), 30</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/universe2040030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lorentz symmetry is one of the pillars of both General Relativity and the
Standard Model of particle physics. Motivated by ideas about quantum gravity,
unification theories and violations of CPT symmetry, a significant effort has
been put the last decades into testing Lorentz symmetry. This review focuses on
Lorentz symmetry tests performed in the gravitational sector. We briefly review
the basics of the pure gravitational sector of the Standard-Model Extension
(SME) framework, a formalism developed in order to systematically parametrize
hypothetical violations of the Lorentz invariance. Furthermore, we discuss the
latest constraints obtained within this formalism including analyses of the
following measurements: atomic gravimetry, Lunar Laser Ranging, Very Long
Baseline Interferometry, planetary ephemerides, Gravity Probe B, binary
pulsars, high energy cosmic rays,... In addition, we propose a combined
analysis of all these results. We also discuss possible improvements on current
analyses and present some sensitivity analyses for future observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05576</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiktenko</keyname><forenames>E. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Man'ko</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Information processing using three-qubit and qubit-qutrit encodings of
  noncomposite quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Russ. Laser Res. 37, 581 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10946-016-9610-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study quantum information properties of a seven-level system realized by a
particle in an one-dimensional square-well trap. Features of encodings of
seven-level systems in a form of three-qubit or qubit-qutrit systems are
discussed. We use the three-qubit encoding of the system in order to
investigate subadditivity and strong subadditivity conditions for the thermal
state of the particle. The qubit-qutrit encoding is employed to suggest a
single qudit algorithm for calculation of parity of a bit string. Obtained
results indicate on the potential resource of multilevel systems for
realization of quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05665</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ciret</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorza</keyname><forenames>Simon-Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of ultra broadband coherent supercontinuum in tapered and
  dispersion managed silicon nanophotonic waveguides</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tapered and dispersion managed (DM) silicon nanophotonic waveguides are
investigated for the generation of optimal ultra broadband supercontinuum (SC).
DM waveguides are structures showing a longitudinally dependent group velocity
dispersion that results from the variation of the waveguide width with the
propagation distance. For the generation of optimal SC, a genetic algorithm has
been used to find the best dispersion map. This allows for the generation of
highly coherent supercontinuums that span over 1.14 octaves from 1300 nm to
2860 nm and 1.25 octaves from 1200 nm to 2870 nm at -20 dB level for the
tapered and DM waveguides respectively, for a 2 $\mu$m, 200 fs and 6.4 pJ input
pulse. The comparison of these two structures with the usually considered
optimal fixed width waveguide shows that the SC is broader and flatter in the
more elaborated DM waveguide, while the high coherence is ensured by the
varying dispersion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07506</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lodato</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merbis</keyname><forenames>Wout</forenames></author></authors><title>Super-BMS$_3$ algebras from $\mathcal{N}=2$ flat supergravities</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, v2 version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>TUW-16-21</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1611 (2016) 150</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider two possible flat space limits of three dimensional $\mathcal{N}
= (1,1)$ AdS supergravity. They differ by how the supercharges are scaled with
the AdS radius $\ell$: the first limit (democratic) leads to the usual
super-Poincare theory, while a novel `twisted' theory of supergravity stems
from the second (despotic) limit. We then propose boundary conditions such that
the asymptotic symmetry algebras at null infinity correspond to supersymmetric
extensions of the BMS algebras previously derived in connection to non- and
ultra-relativistic limits of the $\mathcal{N}=(1,1)$ Virasoro algebra in two
dimensions. Finally, we study the supersymmetric energy bounds and find the
explicit form of the asymptotic and global Killing spinors of supersymmetric
solutions in both flat space supergravity theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08409</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Frolov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynov</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonance contribution of scalar color octet to $t \bar{t}$ production
  at the LHC in the minimal four color quark-lepton symmetry model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in Modern Physics
  Letters A</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 39 (2016) 1650224</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316502242</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The scalar color octet contribution to the resonance $t\bar{t}$-pair
production at the LHC is calculated and analysed with account of the one loop
effective two gluon vertex. It is shown that this contribution from the scalar
color octet $F_2$ predicted by the minimal model with the four color
quark-lepton symmetry is for $\sqrt{s}=13$ TeV of about a few percents for $750
&lt; m_{F_2} &lt; 1800$ GeV and can exceed 10% for $400 &lt; m_{F_2} &lt; 750$ GeV. It is
also pointed out that the search for the scalar octet $F_2$ as the resonance in
the dijet mass spectra seems to be difficult because of the smallness of its
one loop effective two gluon interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08966</id><created>2016-10-26</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rjabchikov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>The Ancient Astronomy of Easter Island: Aldebaran and the Pleiades</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>Archaeoastronomy; 28 pages, 35 figures, 3 tables, 1 photo; a few
  misprints have been corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is a good cause to assert that the Easter Islanders constantly watched
Aldebaran and the Pleiades in the past. The Russian scholar Irina K. Fedorova
and the American scholar Georgia Lee were the first who contributed
significantly to the archaeoastronomical studies of these celestial bodies. I
have decoded the Mataveri calendar completely. The ceremonial platform Hekii 2
was oriented on Aldebaran and nearby stars. The disappearance of the Pleiades
during the dawn period in the north at the end of August could be an important
mark before the arrival of sooty terns and before the elections of the next
bird-man. The calculated dates of several solar eclipses have been used for
composing the chronology of Easter Island from 1771 till 1867 A.D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00191</id><created>2016-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Khatami</keyname><forenames>Maryam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Katrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ejtehadi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Reza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stark</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author></authors><title>Active Brownian particles and run-and-tumble particles separate inside a
  maze</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>submitted to Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 37670 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep37670</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A diverse range of natural and artificial self-propelled particles are known
and are used nowadays. Among them, active Brownian particles (ABPs) and
run-and-tumble particles (RTPs) are two important classes. We numerically study
non-interacting ABPs and RTPs strongly confined to different maze geometries in
two dimensions. We demonstrate that by means of geometrical confinement alone,
ABPs are separable from RTPs. By investigating Matryoshka-like mazes with
nested shells, we show that a circular maze has the best filtration efficiency.
Results on the mean first-passage time reveal that ABPs escape faster from the
center of the maze, while RTPs reach the center from the rim more easily.
According to our simulations and a rate theory, which we developed, ABPs in
steady state accumulate in the outermost region of the Matryoshka-like mazes,
while RTPs occupy all locations within the maze with nearly equal probability.
These results suggest a novel technique for separating different types of
self-propelled particles by designing appropriate confining geometries without
using chemical or biological agents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00428</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2016-11-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Landim</keyname><forenames>Ricardo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>Elcio</forenames></author></authors><title>Metastable dark energy</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures, references added. Accepted for publication in
  PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 764 (2017) 271-276</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We build a model of metastable dark energy, in which the observed vacuum
energy is the value of the scalar potential at the false vacuum. The scalar
potential is given by a sum of even self-interactions up to order six. The
deviation from the Minkowski vacuum is due to a term suppressed by the Planck
scale. The decay time of the metastable vacuum can easily accommodate a mean
life time compatible with the age of the universe. The metastable dark energy
is also embedded into a model with $SU(2)_R$ symmetry. The dark energy doublet
and the dark matter doublet naturally interact with each other. A three-body
decay of the dark energy particle into (cold and warm) dark matter can be as
long as large fraction of the age of the universe, if the mediator is massive
enough, the lower bound being at intermediate energy level some orders below
the grand unification scale. Such a decay shows a different form of interaction
between dark matter and dark energy, and the model opens a new window to
investigate the dark sector from the point-of-view of particle physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02107</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klauder</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author></authors><title>When Canonical Quantization Fails, Here is How to Fix It</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>7 pages, treats quantum contact transformations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following Dirac, the rules of canonical quantization include classical and
quantum contact transformations of classical and quantum phase space variables.
While arbitrary classical canonical coordinate transformations exist that is
not the case for some analogous quantum canonical coordinate transformations.
This failure is due to the rigid connection of quantum variables arising by
promoting the corresponding classical variable from a $c$-number to a
$q$-number. A different relationship of $c$-numbers and $q$-numbers in the
procedures of Enhanced Quantization shows the compatibility of all quantum
operators with all classical canonical coordinate transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02244</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Orlov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiota</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takasaki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pfaffian structures and certain solutions to BKP hierarchies II.
  Multiple integrals</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a useful and rather simple classes of BKP tau functions which
which we shall shall call &quot;easy tau functions&quot;. We consider the &quot;large BKP
hiearchy&quot; related to $O(2\infty +1)$ which was introduced in \cite{KvdLbispec}
(which is closely related to the DKP $O(2\infty) $hierarchy introduced in
\cite{JM}). Actually &quot;easy tau functions&quot; of the small BKP was already
considered in \cite{HLO}, here we are more interested in the large BKP and also
the mixed small-large BKP tau functions \cite{KvdLbispec}. Tau functions under
consideration are equal to sums over partitions and to multi-integrals. In this
way they may be appliciable in models of random partitions and models of random
matrices. Here in the part II we consider multi-intergals and series of $N$-ply
integrals in $N$. Relations to matrix models is explained. This paper may be
viewed as a developement of the the paper by J.van de Leur \cite{L1} related to
orthogonal and symplectic ensembles of random matrices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02843</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mrenca-Kolasinska</keyname><forenames>Alina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szafran</keyname><forenames>Bartlomiej</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz force effects for graphene Aharonov-Bohm interferometers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.195315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate magnetic deflection of currents that flow across the
Aharonov-Bohm interferom- eters defined in graphene. We consider devices
induced by closed n-p junctions in nanoribbons as well as etched quantum rings.
The deflection effects on conductance are strictly correlated with the
properties of the ring-localized quasibound states. The energy of these states,
their lifetime and the periodicity of the conductance oscillations are
determined by orientation of the current circulating within the interferometer.
Formation of high harmonics of conductance at high magnetic field and the role
of intervalley scattering are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02969</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fauvarque</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neichel</keyname><forenames>Benoit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fusco</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauvage</keyname><forenames>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Girault</keyname><forenames>Orion</forenames></author></authors><title>General formalism for Fourier based Wave Front Sensing</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><journal-ref>Optica, Vol. 3, No. 12, December 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.001440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce in this article a general formalism for Fourier based wave front
sensing. To do so, we consider the filtering mask as a free parameter. Such an
approach allows to unify sensors like the Pyramid Wave Front Sensor (PWFS) and
the Zernike Wave Front Sensor (ZWFS). In particular, we take the opportunity to
generalize this two sensors in terms of sensors' class where optical quantities
as, for instance, the apex angle for the PWFS or the depth of the Zernike mask
for the ZWFS become free parameters. In order to compare all the generated
sensors of this two classes thanks to common performance criteria, we firstly
define a general phase-linear quantity that we call meta-intensity. Analytical
developments allow then to split the perfectly phase-linear behavior of a WFS
from the non-linear contributions making robust and analytic definitions of the
sensitivity and the linearity range possible. Moreover, we define a new
quantity called the SD factor which characterizes the trade-off between these
two antagonist quantities. These developments are generalized for modulation
device and polychromatic light. A non-exhaustive study is finally led on the
two classes allowing to retrieve the usual results and also make explicit the
influence of the optical parameters introduced above.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03863</id><created>2016-11-11</created><updated>2016-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zaragoza-Cardiel</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beckman</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Font</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosado</keyname><forenames>Margarita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camps-Fari&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>Artemi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borlaff</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinematics of the ionized and molecular gas in nearby luminous infrared
  interacting galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS. 16 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2963</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have observed three luminous infrared galaxy systems (LIRGS) which are
pairs of interacting galaxies, with the Galaxy H$\alpha$ Fabry-Perot system
(GH$\alpha$FaS) mounted on the 4.2m William Herschel Telescope at the Roque de
los Muchachos Observatory, and combined the observations with the Atacama Large
Millimeter Array (ALMA) observations of these systems in CO emission to compare
the physical properties of the star formation regions and the molecular gas
clouds, and specifically the internal kinematics of the star forming regions.
We identified 88 star forming regions in the H$\alpha$ emission data-cubes, and
27 molecular cloud complexes in the CO emission data-cubes. The surface
densities of the star formation rate and the molecular gas are significantly
higher in these systems than in non-interacting galaxies and the Galaxy, and
are closer to the surface densities of the star formation rate and the
molecular gas of extreme star forming galaxies at higher redshifts. The large
values of the velocity dispersion also show the enhanced gas surface density.
The HII regions are situated on the ${\rm{SFR}}-\sigma_v$ envelope, and so are
also in virial equilibrium. Since the virial parameter decreases with the
surface densities of both the star formation rate and the molecular gas, we
claim that the clouds presented here are gravitationally dominated rather than
being in equilibrium with the external pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06691</id><created>2016-11-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Turek</keyname><forenames>Ilja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudrnovsky</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drchal</keyname><forenames>Vaclav</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence and stiffness of spin waves in diluted ferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, accepted in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 174447 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.174447</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results of a numerical analysis of magnon spectra in supercells
simulating two-dimensional and bulk random diluted ferromagnets with
long-ranged pair exchange interactions. We show that low-energy spectral
regions for these strongly disordered systems contain a coherent component
leading to interference phenomena manifested by a pronounced sensitivity of the
lowest excitation energies to the adopted boundary conditions. The dependence
of configuration averages of these excitation energies on the supercell size
can be used for an efficient determination of the spin-wave stiffness D. The
developed formalism is applied to the ferromagnetic Mn-doped GaAs semiconductor
with optional incorporation of phosphorus; the obtained concentration trends of
D are found in reasonable agreement with recent experiments. Moreover, a
relation of the spin stiffness to the Curie temperature Tc has been studied for
Mn-doped GaAs and GaN semiconductors. It is found that the ratio Tc/D exhibits
qualitatively the same dependence on Mn concentration in both systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07359</id><created>2016-11-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Hailong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pengjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>Pujia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Loren N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kastner</keyname><forenames>Marc A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing \nu = 5/2 fractional quantum Hall states in confined geometry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>PNAS 113 (44), 12386-12390 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1614543113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some theories predict that the filling factor 5/2 fractional quantum Hall
state can exhibit non-Abelian statistics, which makes it a candidate for
fault-tolerant topological quantum computation. Although the non-Abelian
Pfaffian state and its particle-hole conjugate, the anti-Pfaffian state, are
the most plausible wave functions for the 5/2 state, there are a number of
alternatives with either Abelian or non-Abelian statistics. Recent experiments
suggest that the tunneling exponents are more consistent with an Abelian state
rather than a non-Abelian state. Here, we present edge-current-tunneling
experiments in geometrically confined quantum point contacts, which indicate
that Abelian and non-Abelian states compete at filling factor 5/2. Our results
are consistent with a transition from an Abelian state to a non-Abelian state
in a single quantum point contact when the confinement is tuned. Our
observation suggests that there is an intrinsic non-Abelian 5/2 ground state,
but that the appropriate confinement is necessary to maintain it. This
observation is important not only for understanding the physics of the 5/2
state, but also for the design of future topological quantum computation
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09767</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2016-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schlesinger</keyname><forenames>Kimberly J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Chantal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Imtiaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlson</keyname><forenames>Jean M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective Decision Dynamics in Group Evacuation: Modeling Tradeoffs and
  Optimal Behavior</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantifying uncertainties in collective human behavior and decision making is
crucial for ensuring public health and safety, enabling effective disaster
response, informing the design of transportation and communication networks,
and guiding the development of new technologies. However, modeling and
predicting such behavior is notoriously difficult, due to the influence of a
variety of complex factors such as the availability and uncertainty of
information, the interaction and influence of social groups and networks, the
degree of risk or time pressure involved in a situation, and differences in
individual personalities and preferences. Here, we develop a stochastic model
of human decision making to describe the empirical behavior of subjects in a
controlled experiment simulating a natural disaster scenario. We compare the
observed behavior to that of statistically optimal Bayesian decision makers,
quantifying the extent to which human decisions are optimal and identifying the
conditions in which sub-optimal decisions are made. Finally, we investigate how
human evacuation strategies change when decisions are made in groups under a
variety of different rules, and whether these group strategy adjustments are
optimal or beneficial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09883</id><created>2016-11-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Karbstein</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author></authors><title>The quantum vacuum in electromagnetic fields: From the Heisenberg-Euler
  effective action to vacuum birefringence</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures; Lectures given at the Helmholtz International
  Summer School (HISS) - Dubna International Advanced School of Theoretical
  Physics (DIAS-TH): &quot;Quantum Field Theory at the Limits: from Strong Fields to
  Heavy Quarks&quot;, July 2016</comments><doi>10.3204/DESY-PROC-2016-04</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The focus of these lectures is on the quantum vacuum subjected to classical
electromagnetic fields. To this end we explicitly derive the renowned
Heisenberg-Euler effective action in constant electromagnetic fields in a
rather pedagogical and easy to conceive way. As an application, we use it to
study vacuum birefringence constituting one of the most promising optical
signatures of quantum vacuum nonlinearity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09936</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Consiglio</keyname><forenames>S. Michelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Jean L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>David S.</forenames></author></authors><title>ALMA Reveals Potential Localized Dust Enrichment from Massive Star
  Clusters in II Zw 40</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 833, Issue 1, article
  id. L6, 6pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/833/1/L6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present subarcsecond images of submillimeter CO and continuum emission
from a local galaxy forming massive star clusters: the blue compact dwarf
galaxy II Zw 40. At $\sim$0.4&quot; resolution (20 pc), the CO(3-2), CO(1-0), 3mm
and 870${\mu}$m continuum maps illustrate star formation on the scales of
individual molecular clouds. Dust contributes about a third of the 870${\mu}$m
continuum emission, with free-free accounting for the rest. On these scales,
there is not a good correspondence between gas, dust, and free-free emission.
Dust continuum is enhanced toward the star-forming region as compared to the CO
emission. We suggest that an unexpectedly low and spatially variable
gas-to-dust ratio is the result of massive clusters of the starburst.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00003</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Schroer</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author></authors><title>Rudolf Haag's legacy of Local Quantum Physics and reminiscences about a
  cherished teacher and friend</title><categories>math-ph math.MP physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>54 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After some personal recollectioms about Rudolf Haag and his thoughts which
led him to &quot;Local Quantum Physics&quot;, the present work recalls his ideas about
scattering theory, the relation between local observables and localized fields
and his contributions to the physical aspects of modular operator theory which
paved the way for an intrisic understanding of quantum causal localization in
which fields &quot;coordinatize&quot; the local algebras. The paper ends with the
presentation of string-local fields whose construction and use in a new
renormalization theory for higher spin fields is part of an ongoing
reformulation of gauge theory in the conceptual setting of Haag's LQP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00023</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Neuberger</keyname><forenames>Herbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Resolving-Power Quantization</title><categories>hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting with a general discussion, a program is sketched for a quantization
based on dilations. This resolving-power quantization is simplest for scalar
field theories. The hope is to find a way to relax the requirement of locality
so that the necessity to fine tune mass parameters is eliminated while
universality is still preserved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00027</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zerf</keyname><forenames>Nikolai</forenames></author></authors><title>Irreducible tensor basis and general Fierz relations for Bhabha
  scattering like amplitudes</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 13 figures and 5 tables</comments><report-no>ALBERTA-THY-10-16</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct an irreducible s- and t-channel tensor basis for Bhabha
scattering like amplitudes based on the properties of the underlying Lorentz
symmetry in four space-time dimensions. In the given basis the calculation of
amplitude contractions like the amplitude square reduces to the contraction of
their corresponding coefficient tensors. Further the basis retains the full
amplitude information and thus can be applied in off-shell cases. The general
Fierz transformations which relate the s- and t-channel basis with each other
are obtained. As an example for application we use the basis to calculate the
tree-level Bhabha scattering amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00028</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Khitun</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Guanxiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balandin</keyname><forenames>Alexander A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Dimensional Oscillatory Neural Network Based on Charge-Density-Wave
  Devices Operating at Room Temperature</title><categories>cs.ET cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an oscillatory neural network implemented with two-dimensional
tantalum disulfide devices operating in the change density wave regime at room
temperature. An elementary cell of the network consists of two 1T-TaS2 devices
connected in series. Such a cell has constant output and oscillatory states.
All cells have the same bias voltage. There is constant current flowing through
the cell in the constant output mode. The oscillations occur at a certain bias
voltage due to the electrical-field driven metal-to-insulator transition owing
to the changes in the charge density wave phase in the 1T-TaS2 channel. Two
1T-TaS2 devices oscillate out-of-phase where one of the devices is in the
insulator phase while the other one is in the metallic state. The
nearest-neighbor cells are coupled via graphene transistors. The cells are
resistively coupled if the graphene transistor is in the On state while they
are capacitively coupled if the transistor is in the Off state. The operation
of the oscillatory neural network is simulated numerically for the 30x30 node
network. The results of our numerical modeling show the formation of artificial
vortexes and cellular-automata type data processing. The two-dimensional
1T-TaS2 devices, utilized in the network, offer a unique combination of
properties such as scalability, high operational frequency, fast
synchronization speed, and radiation hardness, which makes them promising for
both consumer electronic and defense applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00034</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Donnell</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient quantum tomography II</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS</categories><comments>35 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following [OW16], we continue our analysis of: (1) &quot;Quantum tomography&quot;,
i.e., learning a quantum state, i.e., the quantum generalization of learning a
discrete probability distribution; (2) The distribution of Young diagrams
output by the RSK algorithm on random words. Regarding (2), we introduce two
powerful new tools: (i) A precise upper bound on the expected length of the
longest union of $k$ disjoint increasing subsequences in a random length-$n$
word with letter distribution $\alpha_1 \geq \alpha_2 \geq \cdots \geq
\alpha_d$; (ii) A new majorization property of the RSK algorithm that allows
one to analyze the Young diagram formed by the lower rows $\lambda_k,
\lambda_{k+1}, \dots$ of its output.
  These tools allow us to prove several new theorems concerning the
distribution of random Young diagrams in the nonasymptotic regime, giving
concrete error bounds that are optimal, or nearly so, in all parameters. As one
example, we give a fundamentally new proof of the fact that the expected length
of the longest increasing sequence in a random length-$n$ permutation is
bounded by $2\sqrt{n}$. This is the $k = 1$, $\alpha_i \equiv \frac1d$, $d \to
\infty$ special case of a much more general result we prove: the expected
length of the $k$th Young diagram row produced by an $\alpha$-random word is
$\alpha_k n \pm 2\sqrt{\alpha_kd n}$.
  From our new analyses of random Young diagrams we derive several new results
in quantum tomography, including: (i) Learning the eigenvalues of an unknown
state to $\epsilon$-accuracy in Hellinger-squared, chi-squared, or KL distance,
using $n = O(d^2/\epsilon)$ copies; (ii) Learning the optimal rank-$k$
approximation of an unknown state to $\epsilon$-fidelity (Hellinger-squared
distance) using $n = \widetilde{O}(kd/\epsilon)$ copies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00037</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemat-Nasser</keyname><forenames>Sia</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional Phononic Crystals with Acoustic-Band Negative Refraction</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>in Proceedings of the ASME 2016 Conference on Smart Materials,
  Adaptive Structures and Intelligent Systems, Stowe, VT (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A two-dimensional phononic crystal (PC) can exhibit longitudinal-mode
negative energy refraction on its lowest (acoustical) frequency pass band. The
effective elastodynamic properties of a typical PC are calculated and it is
observed that the components of the effective density tensor can achieve
negative values at certain low frequencies on the acoustical branches for the
longitudinal-mode pass-band, and that negative refraction may be accompanied by
either positive or negative effective density. Furthermore, such a PC has a
high anisotropy ratio at certain low frequencies, offering potential for
application to acoustic cloaking where effective material anisotropy is
essential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00039</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A</forenames></author></authors><title>Use of Feedback to Maximize Photon Count Rate in XRF Spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effective bandwidth of an energy dispersive x-ray fluorescence
spectroscopy system is limited by the timing of incident photons. When multiple
photons strike the detector within the processing time of the detector photon
pile-up occurs and the signal received by the detector during this interval
must be ignored. In conventional ED-XRF systems the probability of a photon
being incident upon the detector is uniform over time, and thus pile-up follows
Poisson statistics. In this paper we present a mathematical treatment of the
relationship between photon timing statistics and the count rate of an XRF
system. We show that it is possible to increase the maximum count rates by
applying feedback from the detector to the x-ray source to alter the timing
statistics of photon emission. Monte-Carlo simulations, show that this
technique can increase the maximum count rate of an XRF spectroscopy system by
a factor of 2.94 under certain circumstances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00041</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xe4;ntysaari</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schenke</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints for proton structure fluctuations from exclusive scattering</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures. Talk given by H.M. at the 8th International
  Conference on Hard and Electromagnetic Probes of High-Energy Nuclear
  Collisions (Hard Probes 2016), 22-27 September 2016, Wuhan, China</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We constrain the average density profile of the proton and the amount of
event-by-event fluctuations by simultaneously calculating the coherent and
incoherent exclusive diffractive vector meson production cross section in deep
inelastic scattering. Working within the Color Glass Condensate picture, we
find that the gluonic density of the proton must have large geometric
fluctuations in order to describe the experimentally measured large incoherent
cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00046</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>van der Meeren</keyname><forenames>Christer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oksavik</keyname><forenames>Kjellmar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorentzen</keyname><forenames>Dag A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paxton</keyname><forenames>Larry J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clausen</keyname><forenames>Lasse B. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scintillation and irregularities from the nightside part of a
  Sun-aligned polar cap arc</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><proxy>Kavitha &#xc3;&#x83;&#xc2;&#x98;stgaard</proxy><doi>10.1002/2016JA022708</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the presence of irregularities and scintillation in
relation to the nightside part of a long-lived, Sun-aligned transpolar arc on
15 January 2015. The arc was observed in DMSP UV and particle data and lasted
at least 3 h between 1700 and 2000 UT. The arc was more intense than the main
oval during this time. From all-sky imagers on Svalbard we were able to study
the evolution of the arc, which drifted slowly westward toward the dusk cell.
The intensity of the arc as observed from ground was 10-17 kR in 557.7 nm and
2-3.5 kR in 630.0 nm, i.e., significant emissions in both green and red
emission lines. We have used high-resolution raw data from global navigation
satellite systems (GNSS) receivers and backscatter from Super Dual Auroral
Radar Network (SuperDARN) radars to study irregularities and scintillation in
relation to the polar cap arc. Even though the literature has suggested that
polar cap arcs are potential sources for irregularities, our results indicate
only very weak irregularities. This may be due to the background density in the
northward IMF polar cap being too low for significant irregularities to be
created.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00076</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Haldane</keyname><forenames>F. D. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ground State Properties of Antiferromagnetic Chains with Unrestricted
  Spin: Integer Spin Chains as Realisations of the O(3) Non-Linear Sigma Model</title><categories>cond-mat.other cond-mat.str-el</categories><report-no>SP-81/95</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A continuum limit treatment of planar spin chains with arbitrary S is
presented. The difference between integer and half-integer spins is emphasised.
While isotropic half-integer spin chains are gapless,and have power-law decay
of correlations at T = 0 with exponent eta = 1, integer spin systems have a
singlet ground state with a gap for S=1 excitations and exponential decay of
correlations. The easy-plane to easy-axis transition is described.
  Note: this is a verbatim transcription of ILL preprint SP-81/95, which is
cited in a number of places, but was rejected for publication in 1981, and
remained unpublished in this original form, which gives somewhat different
arguments for the central result as compared to the later paper finally
published in Phys. Lett. 93A, 464 (1983); many thanks to Jeno Solyom for
preserving this historical document.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00079</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Finkelstein</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author></authors><title>My Century of Physics</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A short autobiography written for a centennial party.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00080</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Shastry</keyname><forenames>Tejas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balla</keyname><forenames>Itamar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeron</keyname><forenames>Hadallia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amsterdam</keyname><forenames>Samuel H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marks</keyname><forenames>Tobin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hersam</keyname><forenames>Mark C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mutual Photoluminescence Quenching and Photovoltaic Effect in Large-Area
  Single-Layer MoS2-Polymer Heterojunctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano, 2016, 10 (11), pp 10573-10579</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b06592</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) have recently
attracted attention due to their superlative optical and electronic properties.
In particular, their extraordinary optical absorption and semiconducting band
gap have enabled demonstrations of photovoltaic response from heterostructures
composed of TMDCs and other organic or inorganic materials. However, these
early studies were limited to devices at the micrometer scale and/or failed to
exploit the unique optical absorption properties of single-layer TMDCs. Here we
present an experimental realization of a large-area type-II photovoltaic
heterojunction using single-layer molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) as the primary
absorber, by coupling it to the organic {\pi}-donor polymer PTB7. This
TMDC-polymer heterojunction exhibits photoluminescence intensity that is
tunable as a function of the thickness of the polymer layer, ultimately
enabling complete quenching of the TMDC photoluminescence. The strong optical
absorption in the TMDC-polymer heterojunction produces an internal quantum
efficiency exceeding 40% for an overall cell thickness of less than 20 nm,
resulting in exceptional current density per absorbing thickness in comparison
to other organic and inorganic solar cells. Furthermore, this work provides new
insight into the recombination processes in type-II TMDC-polymer
heterojunctions and thus provides quantitative guidance to ongoing efforts to
realize efficient TMDC-based solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00103</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Review on Hadron Spectroscopy</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures. Plenary review talk on 34th International
  Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I review some of the lattice results on spectroscopy and resonances in the
past years. For the conventional hadron spectrum computations, focus has been
put on the isospin breaking effects, QED effects, and simulations near the
physical pion mass point. I then go through several single-channel scattering
studies within L\&quot;uscher formalism, a method that has matured over the past few
years. The topics cover light mesons and also the charmed mesons, with the
latter case intimately related to the recently discovered exotic $XYZ$
particles. Other possible related formalisms that are available on the market
are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00120</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Zhiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lipo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Shijun</forenames></author></authors><title>On the origin of intrinsic randomness of Rayleigh-Benard turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>http://engine.scichina.com/doi/10.1007/s11433-016-0401-5</comments><journal-ref>Science China Physics, Mechanics &amp; Astronomy 60, 014712 (2017 )</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11433-016-0401-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is of broad interest to understand how the evolution of non-equilibrium
systems can be triggered and the role played by external perturbations. A
famous example is the origin of randomness in the laminar-turbulence
transition, which is raised in the pipe flow experiment by Reynolds as a
century old unresolved problem. Although there exist different hypotheses, it
is widely believed that the randomness is &quot;intrinsic&quot;, which, however, remains
as an open question to be verified. Simulating the modeled Rayleigh-Benard
convection system by means of the so-called clean numerical simulation (CNS)
with negligible numerical noises that are smaller even than thermal
fluctuation, we verify that turbulence can be self-excited from the inherent
thermal fluctuation, without any external disturbances, i.e. out of nothing.
This reveals a relationship between microscopic physical uncertainty and
macroscopic randomness. It is found that in physics the system nonlinearity
functions as a channel for randomness information, and energy as well, to
transport microscopic uncertainty toward large scales. Such scenario can
generally be helpful to understand the various relevant phenomena. In
methodology, compared with direct numerical simulation (DNS), CNS opens a new
direction to investigate turbulent flows with largely improved accuracy and
reliability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00162</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Curr&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manganaro</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear wave interaction problems in three dimensional case</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><msc-class>35L50, 35C05, 35L72, 37K05, 37K10</msc-class><doi>10.1088/1361-6544/30/1/207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three dimensional nonlinear wave interactions have been analytically
described. The procedure under interest can be applied to three dimensional
quasilinear systems of first order, whose hydrodynamic reductions are
homogeneous semi-Hamiltonian hydrodynamic type systems (i.e. possess a diagonal
form and infinitely many conservation laws). The interaction of N waves was
studied. In particular we prove that they behave like simple waves and they
distort after the collision region. The amount of the distortion can be
analytically computed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00171</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanyal</keyname><forenames>Shankha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Archi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guhathakurata</keyname><forenames>Tarit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sengupta</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Dipak</forenames></author></authors><title>A Non Linear Multifractal Study to Illustrate the Evolution of Tagore
  Songs Over a Century</title><categories>cs.SD nlin.CD</categories><comments>6 PAGES, 5 FIGURES, Presented in International Symposium on Frontiers
  of Research in Speech and Music (FRSM)2016 held in North Orissa University,
  11-12 November 2016. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1601.07709</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The works of Rabindranath Tagore have been sung by various artistes over
generations spanning over almost 100 years. there are few songs which were
popular in the early years and have been able to retain their popularity over
the years while some others have faded away. In this study we look to find cues
for the singing style of these songs which have kept them alive for all these
years. For this we took 3 min clip of four Tagore songs which have been sung by
five generation of artistes over 100 years and analyze them with the help of
latest nonlinear techniques Multifractal Detrended Fluctuation Analysis
(MFDFA). The multifractal spectral width is a manifestation of the inherent
complexity of the signal and may prove to be an important parameter to identify
the singing style of particular generation of singers and how this style varies
over different generations. The results are discussed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00172</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanyal</keyname><forenames>Shankha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Archi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guhathakurata</keyname><forenames>Tarit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sengupta</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Dipak</forenames></author></authors><title>A Non Linear Approach towards Automated Emotion Analysis in Hindustani
  Music</title><categories>cs.SD nlin.CD</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures; Presented in International Symposium on Frontiers
  of Research in Speech and Music (FRSM)2016 held in North Orissa University,
  11-12 November 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In North Indian Classical Music, raga forms the basic structure over which
individual improvisations is performed by an artist based on his/her
creativity. The Alap is the opening section of a typical Hindustani Music (HM)
performance, where the raga is introduced and the paths of its development are
revealed using all the notes used in that particular raga and allowed
transitions between them with proper distribution over time. In India,
corresponding to each raga, several emotional flavors are listed, namely erotic
love, pathetic, devotional, comic, horrific, repugnant, heroic, fantastic,
furious, peaceful. The detection of emotional cues from Hindustani Classical
music is a demanding task due to the inherent ambiguity present in the
different ragas, which makes it difficult to identify any particular emotion
from a certain raga. In this study we took the help of a high resolution
mathematical microscope (MFDFA or Multifractal Detrended Fluctuation Analysis)
to procure information about the inherent complexities and time series
fluctuations that constitute an acoustic signal. With the help of this
technique, 3 min alap portion of six conventional ragas of Hindustani classical
music namely, Darbari Kanada, Yaman, Mian ki Malhar, Durga, Jay Jayanti and
Hamswadhani played in three different musical instruments were analyzed. The
results are discussed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00173</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Minato</keyname><forenames>Futoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Proton-neutron random phase approximation studied by the
  Lipkin-Meshkov-Glick model in the SU(2) $\times$ SU(2)</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, Proceedings of the XXIII Nuclear Physics
  Workshop, &quot;Marie &amp; Pierre Curie,&quot; Kazimierz Dolny, Poland, Sep. 27-Oct. 2
  (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the proton-neutron RPA with an extended Lipikin-Meshkov-Glick model.
We pay attention to the effect of correlated ground state and the case in which
neutron and proton numbers are different. The effect of the correlated ground
state are tested on the basis of quasi-boson approximation. We obtain the
result that RPA excitation energies and transition strengths are in a good
agreement with the exact solution up to a certain strength of the
particle-particle interaction. However, the transition strength becomes worse
if we consider the case in which neutron and proton numbers are different even
at a weak particle-particle interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00189</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsushita</keyname><forenames>Yu-ichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshiyama</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanisms of initial oxidation of 4H-SiC (0001) and (000$\bar{1}$)
  surfaces unraveled by first-principles calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>28 pages, and 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed electronic state calculations to clarify the initial stage
of the oxidation of the Si- and C-faces in 4H-SiC based on the
density-functional theory. We investigate how each Si and C atomic site is
oxidized on C- and Si-face, and explore most probable reaction pathways,
corresponding energy barriers, and possible defects generated during the
oxidation. We have found that carbon annihilation process is different between
on Si- and on C-face, and this difference causes different defects in
interface; In C-face case, (1), carbon atoms are dissociated directly from the
substrate as CO molecules. (2), after CO dissociation, 3-fold coordinated
oxygen atoms (called Y-lid) are observed at the interface. (3), high density of
C-dangling bonds can remain at the interface. In Si-face case, (1), C atoms
inevitably form carbon nano clusters (composed of a few atoms) in interface to
reduce the number of dangling bonds there. Moreover, we have found that the
carbon nano clusters are composed of not only single but also double chemical
bonds. (2), We have observed that CO molecules are dissociated from the carbon
nano clusters in MD simulations. Furthermore, we have investigated whether
H$_2$ and NO molecules react with the defects found in this study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00205</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Algazin</keyname><forenames>Oleg D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction by similarity method of the fundamental solution of the
  Dirichlet problem for Keldysh type equation in the half-space</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><msc-class>2010: 35Q99, 35J25, 35J70</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For elliptic in the half-space and parabolic degenerating on the boundary
equation of Keldysh type we construct by similarity method the self-similar
solution, which is the approximation to the identity in the class of integrable
functions. This solution is the fundamental solution of the Dirichlet problem,
i.e. the solution of the Dirichlet problem with the Dirac delta-function in the
boundary condition. Solution of the Dirichlet problem with an arbitrary
function in the boundary condition can be written as the convolution of the
function with the fundamental solution of the Dirichlet problem, if a
convolution exists. For a bounded and piecewise continuous boundary function
convolution exists and is written in the form of an integral, which gives the
classical solution of the Dirichlet problem, and is a generalization of the
Poisson integral for the Laplace equation. If the boundary function is a
generalized function, the convolution is a generalized solution of the
Dirichlet problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00213</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kozyrev</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teretenkov</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volovich</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Flows in nonequilibrium quantum systems and quantum photosynthesis</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A three level quantum system interacting with nonequilibrium environment is
investigated. The stationary state of the system is found (both for
non-coherent and coherent environment) and relaxation and decoherence to the
stationary state is described. The stationary state of the system will be
non-equilibrium and will generate flows. We describe the dependence of the
flows on the state of the environment.
  We also discuss application of this model to the problem of quantum
photosynthesis, in particular, to description of flows of excitons and
generation of excitonic coherences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00216</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Skalozub</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minaiev</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>On magnetization of quark-gluon plasma at the LHC experiment energies</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 Table, 15 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large scale chromomagnetic, B_3, B_8, and usual magnetic,H, fields have to be
generated in QCD after the deconfinement phase transition (DPT) at temperatures
T larger than deconfinement temperature T_d. The two former fields are created
spontaneously due to asymptotic freedom of gluon intaractions. Whereas H is
produced due to either the feature of quarks to possess both electric and color
charges or a vacuum polarization in this case. At the polarization, the vacuum
quark loops mix the external fields. As a result, B_3, B_8 become the sources
generating H. The latter field appears at $T$ much lower than the electroweak
phase transition temperature T_ew. This mechanism should exhibit itself at the
LHC experiments on heavy ion collisions. It operates at the one-loop diagram
level for an effective potential. The created fields are temperature dependent
and occupying the macroscopic volume of quark-gluon plasma. The magnetization
influences different processes and may serve as a signal for the DPT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00221</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Banisch</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olbrich</keyname><forenames>Eckehard</forenames></author></authors><title>The Coconut Model with Heterogeneous Strategies and Learning</title><categories>q-fin.EC cs.LG nlin.AO</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Journal of Artificial Societies and
  Social Simulation (JASSS)</comments><msc-class>91-08, 68T05, 60J10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we develop an agent-based version of the Diamond search
equilibrium model - also called Coconut Model. In this model, agents are faced
with production decisions that have to be evaluated based on their expectations
about the future utility of the produced entity which in turn depends on the
global production level via a trading mechanism. While the original dynamical
systems formulation assumes an infinite number of homogeneously adapting agents
obeying strong rationality conditions, the agent-based setting allows to
discuss the effects of heterogeneous and adaptive expectations and enables the
analysis of non-equilibrium trajectories. Starting from a baseline
implementation that matches the asymptotic behavior of the original model, we
show how agent heterogeneity can be accounted for in the aggregate dynamical
equations. We then show that when agents adapt their strategies by a simple
temporal difference learning scheme, the system converges to one of the fixed
points of the original system. Systematic simulations reveal that this is the
only stable equilibrium solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00223</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kulyk</keyname><forenames>Kostiantyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zettergren</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatchell</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borysenko</keyname><forenames>Mykola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palianytsia</keyname><forenames>Borys</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larsson</keyname><forenames>Mats</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulik</keyname><forenames>Tetiana</forenames></author></authors><title>Dimethylsilanone generation from pyrolysis of polysiloxanes filled with
  nanosized silica and ceria/silica</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 9 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>ChemPlusChem 81, 1003-1013 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/cplu.201600229</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) is a widely used organosilicon polymer often
employed in formulations with fine oxide particles for various high temperature
applications. Although PDMS is considered to be thermally stable and chemically
inert, it is not always clear how the oxide filler influences its
thermoresistance, decomposition chemistry and what reactive products are formed
in the underlying thermal reactions. In this work we use temperature programmed
desorption mass spectrometry (TPD MS) to study the pyrolysis of PDMS and its
composites with nanosized silica and ceria/silica. Our results suggest that the
elusive organosilicon compound - dimethylsilanone is generated from PDMS over a
broad temperature range (in some cases starting at 70${\deg}$C). The presence
of nano-oxides catalyzed this process. Ions characteristic of the fragmentation
of dimethylsilanone under electron ionization were assigned with the aid of DFT
structure calculations. Possible reaction mechanisms for generating
dimethylsilanone were discussed in the context of the calculated kinetic
parameters. Observed accompanying products of PDMS pyrolysis, such as
tetramethylcyclodisiloxane and hexamethylcyclotrisiloxane, indicate that
multiple channels are involved in the dimethylsilanone release.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00225</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Pandey-Pommier</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edge</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guiderdoni</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narasimha</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagchi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-thermal emission and dynamical state of massive galaxy clusters from
  CLASH sample</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, Soci\'et\'e Fran\c{c}aise d'Astronomie et d'Astrophysique
  meeting, Lyon-France, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive galaxy clusters are the most violent large scale structures
undergoing merger events in the Universe. Based upon their morphological
properties in X-rays, they are classified as un-relaxed and relaxed clusters
and often host (a fraction of them) different types of non-thermal radio
emitting components, viz., haloes, mini-haloes, relics and phoenix within their
Intra Cluster Medium (ICM). The radio haloes show steep (alpha = -1.2) and
ultra steep (alpha &lt; -1.5) spectral properties at low radio frequencies, giving
important insights on the merger (pre or post) state of the cluster. Ultra
steep spectrum radio halo emissions are rare and expected to be the dominating
population to be discovered via LOFAR and SKA in the future. Further, the
distribution of matter (morphological information), alignment of hot X-ray
emitting gas from the ICM with the total mass (dark + baryonic matter) and the
bright cluster galaxy (BCG) is generally used to study the dynamical state of
the cluster. We present here a multi wavelength study on 14 massive clusters
from the CLASH survey and show the correlation between the state of their
merger in X-ray and spectral properties (1.4 GHz - 150 MHz) at radio
wavelengths. Using the optical data we also discuss about the gas-mass
alignment, in order to understand the interplay between dark and baryonic
matter in massive galaxy clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00229</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Kyu Been</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Teyoun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Hyung Seon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Young-Kuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ersfeld</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaroszynski</keyname><forenames>Dino A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hur</keyname><forenames>Min Sup</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasma Dipole Oscillation Excited by Trapped Electrons Leading to Bursts
  of Coherent Radiation</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasma dipole oscillation (PDO) depicted as harmonic motion of a spatially
localized block of electrons has, until now, been hypothetical. In practice,
the plasma oscillation occurs always as a part of a plasma wave. Studies on
radiation burst from plasmas have focused only on coupling of the plasma wave
and electromagnetic wave. Here we show that a very-high-field PDO can be
generated by the electrons trapped in a moving train of potential wells. The
electrons riding on the potential train coherently construct a local dipole
moment by charge separation. The subsequent PDO is found to persist stably
until its energy is emitted entirely via coherent radiation. In our novel
method, the moving potentials are provided by two slightly-detuned laser pulses
colliding in a non-magnetized plasma. The radiated energy reaches several
millijoules in the terahertz spectral region. The proposed method provides a
way of realizing the PDO as a new radiation source in the laboratory. PDO as a
mechanism of astrophysical radio-bursts is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00241</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Raymond E.</forenames></author></authors><title>A biology journal that can teach physicists a lesson in peer review</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DL q-bio.CB</categories><comments>3 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physics Today 69(12), 10 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/PT.3.3378</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  This is a Commentary in $Physics~Today$ on the novel review process developed
by the biology journal $eLife$, with the suggestion that it be adopted by
physics journals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00244</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Todorovic</keyname><forenames>Natasa</forenames></author></authors><title>The Precise and Powerful Chaos of the 5:2 Mean Motion Resonance with
  Jupiter</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, published in Monthly Notices of the Royal
  Astronomical Society</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work reexamines the dynamics of the 5:2 mean motion resonance with
Jupiter located in the Outer Belt at $a\sim 2.82$ AU. First, we compute
dynamical maps revealing the precise structure of chaos inside the resonance.
Being interested to verify the chaotic structures as sources of natural
transportation routes, we additionally integrate 1000 massless particles
initially placed along them and follow their orbital histories up to 5 Myr. As
many as 99.5\% of our test particles became Near-Earth Objects, 23.4\% migrated
to semi-major axis below 1 AU and more than 57\% entered the Hill sphere of
Earth. We have also observed a borderline defined by the $q \simeq 2.6$ AU
perihelion distance along which particles escape from the Solar System.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00264</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Titov</keyname><forenames>Alexander I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampfer</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosaka</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takabe</keyname><forenames>Hideaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear quantum dynamics in strong and short electromagnetic fields</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Lecture given at Helmholtz - DIAS International Summer School Quantum
  Field Theory at the Limits: from Strong Fields to Heavy Quarks, July 18-30,
  2016, Dubna, Russia. 10 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our contribution we give a brief overview of two widely discussed quantum
processes: electron-positron pairs production off a probe photon propagating
through a polarized short-pulsed electromagnetic (e.m.) (e.g.\ laser) wave
field or generalized Breit-Wheeler process and a single a photon emission off
an electron interacting with the laser pules, so-called non-linear Compton
scattering. We show that at small and moderate laser field intensities the
shape and duration of the pulse are very important for the probability of
considered processes. However, at high intensities the multi-photon
interactions of the fermions with laser field are decisive and completely
determined all aspects of subthreshold electron-positron pairs and photon
production
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00275</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Galiazzo</keyname><forenames>Mattia Alvise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Hungaria region as possible source of Trojans and satellites in the
  inner solar-system</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 445, 3999, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stu2016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Hungaria Family (the closest region of the Main Belt to Mars) is an
important source of Planet-Crossing-Asteroids and even impactors of terrestrial
planets. We present the possibility that asteroids coming from the Hungaria
Family get captured into co-orbital motion with the terrestrial planets in the
inner solar system. Therefore we carried out long term numerical integrations
(up to 100 Myr) to analyze the migrations from their original location - the
Hungaria family region- into the inner solar system. During the integration
time we observed whether or not the Hungarias get captured into a co-orbital
motion with the terrestrial planets. Our results show that 5.5% of 200
Hungarias, selected as a sample of the whole group, escape from the Hungaria
region and the probability from that to become co-orbital objects (Trojans,
satellites or horseshoes) turns out to be about 3.3%: 1.8% for Mars and 1.5%
for the Earth. In addition, we distinguished in which classes of co-orbital
motion the asteroids get captured and for how long they stay there in stable
motion. Most of the escaped Hungarias become Quasi-satellites and the ones
captured as Trojans favor the L_5 lagrangian point. This work highlights that
the Hungaria region is a source of Mars and also Earth co-orbital objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00285</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bahrampour</keyname><forenames>Bardiya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wellegehausen</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Smekal</keyname><forenames>Lorenz</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Local effective SU(2) Polyakov-loop models from inverse Monte-Carlo
  methods</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures; Proceedings of the 34th International Symposium
  on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), 24-30 July 2016, University of
  Southampton, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strong-coupling expansion of the lattice gauge action leads to
Polyakov-loop models that effectively describe gluodynamics at low
temperatures, and together with the hopping expansion of the fermion
determinant provides insight into the QCD phase diagram at finite density and
low temperatures, although for rather heavy quarks. At higher temperatures the
strong-coupling expansion breaks down and it is expected that the interactions
between Polyakov loops become non-local. Here, we therefore test how well pure
SU(2) gluodynamics can be mapped onto different non-local Polyakov models with
inverse Monte-Carlo methods. We take into account Polyakov loops in higher
representations and gradually add interaction terms at larger distances. We are
particularly interested in extrapolating the range of non-local terms in
sufficiently large volumes and higher representations. We study the
characteristic fall-off in strength of the non-local couplings with the
interaction distance, and its dependence on the gauge coupling in order to
compare our results to existing proposals for non-local effective actions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00287</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of scalar dissipation in terms of vorticity geometry in
  isotropic turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Turbulence, Taylor \&amp; Francis, 2012, 13, pp.N41</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/14685248.2012.718440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mechanisms promoting scalar dissipation through scalar gradient
production are scrutinized in terms of vorticity alignment with respect to
strain principal axes. For that purpose, a stochastic Lagrangian model for the
velocity gradient tensor and the scalar gradient vector is used. The model
results show that the major part of scalar dissipation occurs for stretched
vorticity, namely when the vorticity vector aligns with the extensional and
intermediate strain eigenvectors. More specifically, it appears that the mean
scalar dissipation is well represented by the sample defined by alignment with
the extensional strain, while the most intense scalar dissipation is promoted
by the set of events for which vorticity aligns with the intermediate strain.
This difference is explained by rather subtle mechanisms involving the
statistics of both the strain intensities and the scalar gradient alignment
resulting from these special alignments of vorticity. The analysis allowing for
the local flow structure confirms the latter scenario for both the strain-and
rotation-dominated events. However, despite the prevailing role of strain in
promoting scalar dissipation, the difference in the level of scalar dissipation
when vorticity aligns with either the extensional or the intermediate strain
mostly arises from rotation-dominated events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00288</id><created>2016-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xfc;zen</keyname><forenames>Mehmet</forenames></author></authors><title>A testable prediction from entropic gravity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I have shown conceptually that quantum state has a direct relationship to
gravitational constant due to entropic force posed by Verlinde's argument and
part of the Newton-Schr\&quot;odinger equation (N-S) in the context of gravity
induced collapse of the wavefunction via Di\'osi-Penrose proposal. This direct
relationship can be used to measure gravitational constant using
state-of-the-art mater-wave interferometry to test the entropic gravity
argument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00292</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kniazev</keyname><forenames>A. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gvaramadze</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berdnikov</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>SALT spectroscopy of evolved massive stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, in Stars: from collapse to collapse. Proceedings
  of the International Conference held in Nizhnij Arkhyz, Karachai-Cherkessian
  Republic, Special Astrophysical Observatory, October 3-7, 2016, ASP Conf.
  Ser. 2017 (in press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Long-slit spectroscopy with the Southern African Large Telescope (SALT) of
central stars of mid-infrared nebulae detected with the Spitzer Space Telescope
and Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer (WISE) led to the discovery of numerous
candidate luminous blue variables (cLBVs) and other rare evolved massive stars.
With the recent advent of the SALT fibre-fed high-resolution echelle
spectrograph (HRS), a new perspective for the study of these interesting
objects is appeared. Using the HRS we obtained spectra of a dozen newly
identified massive stars. Some results on the recently identified cLBV Hen
3-729 are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00294</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Simaciu</keyname><forenames>Ion</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumitrescu</keyname><forenames>Gheorghe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borsos</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradac</keyname><forenames>Mariana</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactions in an acoustic world</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present paper aims to complete an earlier paper where the acoustic world
was introduced. This is accomplished by analyzing the interactions which occur
between the inhomogeneities of the acoustic medium, which are induced by the
acoustic vibrations traveling in the medium. When a wave packet travels in a
medium, the medium becomes inhomogeneous. The spherical wave packet behaves
like an acoustic spherical lens for the acoustic plane waves. According to the
principle of causality, there is an interaction between the wave and plane wave
packet. In specific conditions the wave packet behaves as an acoustic black
hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00297</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Lind&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Fredrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cederquist</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zettergren</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction and charge transfer between dielectric spheres: exact and
  approximate analytical solutions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics 145, 194307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4967701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present exact analytical solutions for charge transfer reactions between
two arbitrarily charged hard dielectric spheres. These solutions, and the
corresponding exact ones for sphere-sphere interaction energies, include sums
that describe polarization effects to infinite orders in the inverse of the
distance between the sphere centers. In addition, we show that these exact
solutions may be approximated by much simpler analytical expressions that are
useful for many practical applications. This is exemplified through
calculations of Langevin type cross sections for forming a compound system of
two colliding spheres and through calculations of electron transfer cross
sections. We find that it is important to account for dielectric properties and
finite sphere sizes in such calculations, which for example may be useful for
describing the evolution, growth, and dynamics of nanometer sized dielectric
objects such as molecular clusters or dust grains in different environments
including astrophysical ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00298</id><created>2016-11-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gera</keyname><forenames>Prerna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salac</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Variation of Soft Matter Interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Submitted to Communications in Mathematical Physics</comments><msc-class>74K15, 74G65, 49S05, 53Z99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The variation of energies associated with soft matter interfaces where
surface inhomogeneities are present. These energies include the total bending
and splay energy, the variable surface tension energy, a coupling energy
between the total curvature and an underlying surface concentration field, the
energy due to an external field, and a phase segregation energy. When
considering these energies the variation of material properties such a bending
rigidity are taken into account, which results in more general variation
expressions. These variations can be used to determine the equilibrium
interface and concentration configuration or to determine the driving forces
for non-equilibrium situations. While the focus of this work are energies
associated with multicomponent vesicles, it can easily be extended to any soft
matter interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00299</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonnarel</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames><affiliation>CADC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dowler</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames><affiliation>CADC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Noddle</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames><affiliation>IFA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tody</keyname><forenames>Douglas</forenames><affiliation>NRAO</affiliation></author></authors><title>IVOA Data Access Layer: Goals, Achievements and Current Trends</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>in ADASS XXV, Oct 2015, Sydney, Australia. 25, ADASS conference
  series</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The IVOA Data Access Layer (DAL) working group was created in 2002 to define
protocols to homogenize data discovery, data description, data retrieval, and
data access processes. We describe its history and status today, and look at
current trends for future development of the DAL protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00304</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Saadat</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pourhassan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>FRW Bulk Viscous Cosmology with Modified Chaplygin Gas in Flat Space</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>published by Astrophysics and Space Science see
  http://inspirehep.net/record/1215969</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.Space Sci. 343 (2013) 783-786</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-012-1268-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study FRW bulk viscous cosmology in presence of modified
Chaplygin gas. We write modified Friedmann equations due to bulk viscosity and
Chaplygin gas and obtain time-dependent energy density for the special case of
flat space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00307</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>McLeod</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balan</keyname><forenames>Sreekumar T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>Filipe B.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Joint Analysis for Cosmology and Photometric Redshift Calculation
  Using Cross Correlations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 Pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2989</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method of calibrating the properties of photometric redshift
bins as part of a larger Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) analysis for the
inference of cosmological parameters. The redshift bins are characterised by
their mean and variance, which are varied as free parameters and marginalised
over when obtaining the cosmological parameters. We demonstrate that the
likelihood function for cross-correlations in an angular power spectrum
framework tightly constrains the properties of bins such that they may be well
determined, reducing their influence on cosmological parameters and avoiding
the bias from poorly estimated redshift distributions. We demonstrate that even
with only three photometric and three spectroscopic bins, we can recover
accurate estimates of the mean redshift of a bin to within $\Delta\mu \approx
3-4 \times10^{-3}$ and the width of the bin to $\Delta\sigma \approx
1\times10^{-3}$ for galaxies near $z = 1$. This indicates that we may be able
to bring down the photometric redshift errors to a level which is in line with
the requirements for the next generation of cosmological experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00311</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Luke Kristopher</forenames></author></authors><title>1D Classical Density Functional Theory of a Tethered Polymer Layer</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple application of classical density functional theory is derived and
applied to a system of polymers grafted to a plane. The system is assumed to
have symmetry in directions parallel to the grafting plane hence it being a
'1-dimensional' problem. A quick introduction to using propagators in the
theory of chains in the presence of external fields and a numerical algorithm
for solving the modified diffusion (or Fokker-Planck) equation are presented.
Density profiles are found for hard-sphere chains which agree with results in
the literature (see Murat,.., Milner,.., Muhukumar and others) and align with
physical expectations of brush formation due to excluded volume. The linear
scaling $h \approx (\sigma)^{1/3} N$, of brush height with polymerisation $N$,
is reproduced here.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00331</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Harbour</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dharma-wardana</keyname><forenames>M. W. Chandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klug</keyname><forenames>Dennis D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Laurent J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pair potentials for warm dense matter and their application to x-ray
  Thomson scattering in aluminum and beryllium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94, 053211 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.053211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrafast laser experiments yield increasingly reliable data on warm dense
matter, but their interpretation requires theoretical models. We employ an
efficient density functional neutral-pseudoatom hypernetted-chain (NPA-HNC)
model with accuracy comparable to ab initio simulations and which provides
first-principles pseudopotentials and pair-potentials for warm-dense matter. It
avoids the use of (i) ad hoc core-repulsion models and (ii) &quot;Yukawa screening&quot;,
and (iii) need not assume ionelectron thermal equilibrium. Computations of the
x-Ray Thomson scattering (XRTS) spectra of aluminum and beryllium are compared
with recent experiments and with density-functional-theory molecular-dynamics
(DFT-MD) simulations. The NPA-HNC structure factors, compressibilities, phonons
and conductivities agree closely with DFT-MD results, while Yukawa screening
gives misleading results. The analysis of the XRTS data for two of the
experiments, using two-temperature quasi-equilibrium models, is supported by
calculations of their temperature relaxation times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00358</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Felice</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author></authors><title>A Study of a Nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger Equation for Optical Fibers</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>PhD. Thesis - Ciclo XXIII, Settore disciplinare MAT/07 Fisica
  Matematica, Universit\`a degli Studi di Firenze (2012)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non linear fiber optics concerns with the non linear optical phenomena
occurring inside optical fibers. The propagation of light in single-mode fibers
is governed by the one-dimensional nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation (NLS) in
the presence of attenuation, dispersion, and non linear effects. In this NLS
the role of space and time is exchanged with respect to the standard NLS as
introduced in the almost entire mathematical literature. Such an exchange is
far from being only formal as it enters in the interpretation of basic ideas as
well-posedness and stability, as well as in the phenomenological meaning of the
predictions formulated by such model. In this dissertation, the physical bases
of the optical fibers are provided, and a derivation of the NLS from the
Maxwell's equations is reviewed. Furthermore, problems of local nature (local
existence of solutions, uniqueness) and problems of global nature (global
existence) are studied by the Kato's method based on a fixed point argument and
Strichartz's estimates. Moreover, tools usually employed to study global
problems connected with finite-time blow up of solutions, are here used to show
a closeness result between the NLS for optical fibers and an integrable NLS.
Integrability is pursued by means of the Painlev\'e analysis that allows to
describe quite a large class of integrable equations like the transformed
equation from the standard NLS. Among these functions, one can be described as
a standard NLS with an additional linear harmonic oscillator term. This
equation is showed to be close in $L^2$-norm to the NLS for single-mode fibers.
Finally, the dissertation focuses on two kinds of stationary solutions: the
so-called time-homogenous, that is given by a stationary wave oscillating in
space, and the soliton-like solution. Results are obtained about stability
properties of them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00363</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherukara</keyname><forenames>Mathew J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narayanan</keyname><forenames>Badri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benmore</keyname><forenames>Chris J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sankaranarayanan</keyname><forenames>Subramanian KRS</forenames></author></authors><title>Ice grains grow by dissolution, ripening and grain boundary migration</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the exponential growth in computing resources and the availability of
a myriad of different theoretical water models, an accurate, yet
computationally efficient molecular level description of mesoscopic grain
growth remains a grand challenge. The underlying phase transitions and
dynamical processes in deeply supercooled systems are often rendered
inaccessible due to limitations imposed by system sizes and timescales, which
is further compounded by their sluggish kinetics. Here, we introduce a
machine-learned, bond-order-based potential model (BOP) that more accurately
describes the anomalous behavior, as well as structural and thermodynamical
properties of both liquid water and ice, with at least two orders of magnitude
cheaper computational cost than existing atomistic water models. In a
significant departure from conventional force-field fitting, we use a
multilevel evolutionary strategy that trains the BOP model against not just
energetics but temperature dependent properties inferred from on-the-fly
molecular dynamics simulations as well. We use the BOP model to probe the
homogeneous ice nucleation and growth process by performing molecular dynamics
on multi-million molecule systems for up to microsecond time scales. These
massively parallel, long-time simulations naturally capture the competition
between cubic, hexagonal, and stacking disordered ice phases during nucleation
and early stages of growth leading to the formation of nanometer sized grains.
Subsequently, we elucidate the hitherto elusive mechanism of grain coarsening
of the crystallized mixed ice phases, which occur through grain dissolution and
Ostwald ripening followed by grain boundary migration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00371</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Guzman</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robledo</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic description of fission in nobelium isotopes with the
  Gogny-D1M energy density functional</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 348</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16348-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Constrained mean-field calculations, based on the Gogny-D1M energy density
functional, have been carried out to describe fission in the isotopes
$^{250-260}$No. The even-even isotopes have been considered within the standard
Hartree-Fock-Bogoliobov (HFB) framework while for the odd-mass ones the Equal
Filling Approximation (HFB-EFA) has been employed. Ground state quantum numbers
and deformations, pairing energies, one-neutron separation energies, inner and
outer barrier heights as well as fission isomer excitation energies are given.
Fission paths, collective masses and zero-point quantum vibrational and
rotational corrections are used to compute the systematic of the spontaneous
fission half-lives t$_\mathrm{SF}$ both for even-even and odd-mass nuclei.
Though there exists a strong variance of the predicted fission rates with
respect to the details involved in their computation, it is shown that both the
specialization energy and the pairing quenching effects, taken into account
within the self-consistent HFB-EFA blocking procedure, lead to larger
t$_\mathrm{SF}$ values in odd-mass nuclei as compared with their even-even
neighbors. Alpha decay lifetimes have also been computed using a
parametrization of the Viola-Seaborg formula. The high quality of the Gogny-D1M
functional regarding nuclear masses leads to a very good reproduction of
$Q_{\alpha}$ values and consequently of lifetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00387</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Emonts</keyname><forenames>B. H. C.</forenames><affiliation>Centro de Astrobiologia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lehnert</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames><affiliation>IAP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Villar-Martin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Centro de Astrobiologia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames><affiliation>CASS-ATNF</affiliation><affiliation>Western Sydney Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ekers</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames><affiliation>CASS-ATNF</affiliation></author><author><keyname>van Moorsel</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames><affiliation>NRAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dannerbauer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>, IAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pentericci</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>INAF</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Miley</keyname><forenames>G. K.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Leiden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Allison</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames><affiliation>CASS-ATNF</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sadler</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Sydney</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Guillard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>IAP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Carilli</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames><affiliation>NRAO</affiliation><affiliation>Cavendish Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Manchester</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rottgering</keyname><forenames>H. J. A.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Leiden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>De Breuck</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>ESO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Seymour</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>Curtin Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gullberg</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>Durham Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ceverino</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Heidelberg</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jagannathan</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>NRAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vernet</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>ESO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Indermuehle</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames><affiliation>CASS-ATNF</affiliation></author></authors><title>Molecular Gas in the Halo Fuels the Growth of a Massive Cluster Galaxy
  at High Redshift</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in Science on 2 Dec 2016 (accepted 21 Oct 2016), 20 pages,
  5 figures, 3 tables. Contains minor copy-editing differences with published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Science, Vol. 354, Issue 6316, pp. 1128-1130 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aag0512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The largest galaxies in the Universe reside in galaxy clusters. Using
sensitive observations of carbon-monoxide, we show that the Spiderweb Galaxy -a
massive galaxy in a distant protocluster- is forming from a large reservoir of
molecular gas. Most of this molecular gas lies between the protocluster
galaxies and has low velocity dispersion, indicating that it is part of an
enriched inter-galactic medium. This may constitute the reservoir of gas that
fuels the widespread star formation seen in earlier ultraviolet observations of
the Spiderweb Galaxy. Our results support the notion that giant galaxies in
clusters formed from extended regions of recycled gas at high redshift.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00392</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Effects in Dislocation Theory II: Shear Banding and Yielding
  Transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermodynamic dislocation theory presented in preceding papers is used
here to describe shear-banding instabilities. Central ingredients of the theory
are a thermodynamically defined effective configurational temperature, and a
formula for the plastic deformation rate determined by thermally activated
depinning of entangled dislocations. An important feature of this paper is an
interpretation of yielding transitions in polycrystalline solids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00398</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Burton</keyname><forenames>B. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cockayne</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopman</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dogan</keyname><forenames>Gunay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hood</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author></authors><title>The Polar Nano Regions $\rightleftharpoons$ Relaxor Transition in
  $Pb_{1-X}(Sc_{1/2}Nb_{1/2})O_{3-X}$; $X$ = bulk concentration of nearest
  neighbor [Pb-O] divacancies</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In previous work, molecular dynamics simulations based on a
first-principles-derived effective Hamiltonian for
$Pb_{1-X}(Sc_{1/2}Nb_{1/2})O_{3-X}$~ (PSN), with nearest-neighbor Pb-O
divacancy pairs, was used to calculate $X_{\rm [Pb-O]}$~vs.~T, phase diagrams
for PSN with: ideal rock-salt type chemical order; nanoscale chemical
short-range order; and random chemical disorder. Here, we show that the phase
diagrams should include additional regions in which a glassy relaxor-phase (or
state) is predicted. With respect to phase diagram topology, these results
strongly support the analogy between relaxors and magnetic spin-glass-systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00415</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Gozzi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khelifi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic expansions of the largest eigenvalues</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we provide a rigorous derivation of asymptotic formula for the
largest eigenvalues using the convergence estimation of the eigenvalues of a
sequence of self-adjoint compact operators of perturbations resulting from the
presence of small inhomogeneities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0104266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0104266</id><created>2001-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lensky</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gani</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudryavtsev</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On U(1)-charged domain walls</title><categories>hep-th nlin.PS</categories><comments>16 pages, LaTeX, 4 PostScript figures</comments><report-no>ITEP-05/01</report-no><journal-ref>J. Exp. Theor. Phys. 93, 677 (2001); [Russian version: Zh. Eksp.
  Teor. Fiz. 120, 778 (2001)]</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/1.1420436</doi><abstract>  A classical field system of two interacting fields -- a real Higgs field and
a complex scalar field -- is considered. It is shown that in such field system
a non-trivial solution exists, which is U(1) charged topological kink. Some
questions of stability of the obtained solution are discussed. An improved
variational procedure for searching of topological U(1) charged solutions is
given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
