<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:57:13Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-10-27" from="2017-10-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.6521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.6521</id><created>2010-11-30</created><updated>2012-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Arghya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharjee</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing order parameters and a tricritical point with a difference</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Physica B, 407, 18, 3722-3726, 2012</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2012.05.050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a mean-field, phenomenological Ginzburg-Landau free energy
functional with two competing order parameters for a two-component,
spin-polarized Fermi gas. This free energy supports a tricritical point which
is different from the conventional one and this change offers a correct
understanding of the experimental phase diagram of imbalanced Fermi systems
(Shin et al, Nature, 2008). The specific heat also happens to be different than
in standard theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1302.2919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1302.2919</id><created>2013-02-12</created><updated>2013-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boyle</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular velocity of gravitational radiation from precessing binaries and
  the corotating frame</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted by PRD; added a few clarifications</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 87, 104006 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.87.104006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper defines an angular velocity for time-dependent functions on the
sphere, and applies it to gravitational waveforms from compact binaries.
Because it is geometrically meaningful and has a clear physical motivation, the
angular velocity is uniquely useful in helping to solve an important---and
largely ignored---problem in models of compact binaries: the inverse problem of
deducing the physical parameters of a system from the gravitational waves
alone. It is also used to define the corotating frame of the waveform. When
decomposed in this frame, the waveform has no rotational dynamics and is
therefore as slowly evolving as possible. The resulting simplifications lead to
straightforward methods for accurately comparing waveforms and constructing
hybrids. As formulated in this paper, the methods can be applied robustly to
both precessing and nonprecessing waveforms, providing a clear, comprehensive,
and consistent framework for waveform analysis. Explicit implementations of all
these methods are provided in accompanying computer code.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08450</id><created>2015-03-29</created><updated>2015-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gan</keyname><forenames>Yanbiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Aiguo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Guangcai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Succi</keyname><forenames>Sauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Boltzmann modeling of multiphase flows: hydrodynamic and
  thermodynamic non-equilibrium effects</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2015, 11, 5336</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c5sm01125f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A discrete Boltzmann model (DBM) is developed to investigate the hydrodynamic
and thermodynamic non-equilibrium (TNE) effects in phase separation processes.
The interparticle force drives changes and the gradient force, induced by
gradients of macroscopic quantities, opposes them. In this paper, we
investigate the interplay between them by providing detailed inspection of
various non-equilibrium observables. Based on the TNE features, we define a TNE
strength which roughly estimates the deviation amplitude from the thermodynamic
equilibrium. The time evolution of the TNE intensity provides a convenient and
efficient physical criterion to discriminate the stages of the spinodal
decomposition and domain growth. Via the DBM simulation and this criterion, we
quantitatively study the effects of latent heat and surface tension on phase
separation. It is found that, the TNE strength attains its maximum at the end
of the spinodal decomposition stage, and it decreases when the latent heat
increases from zero. The surface tension effects are threefold, to prolong the
duration of the spinodal decomposition stage, decrease the maximum TNE
intensity, and accelerate the speed of the domain growth stage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01818</id><created>2015-05-05</created><updated>2016-01-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yasseri</keyname><forenames>Taha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bright</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Wikipedia traffic data and electoral prediction: towards theoretically
  informed models</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>submitted to EPJ Data Science. Additional File 1 available at
  https://drive.google.com/open?id=0BxaGC-YCTO6SWkJhRXlrMVRYVlE</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Data Science, 5: 22 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjds/s13688-016-0083-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This aim of this article is to explore the potential use of Wikipedia page
view data for predicting electoral results. Responding to previous critiques of
work using socially generated data to predict elections, which have argued that
these predictions take place without any understanding of the mechanism which
enables them, we first develop a theoretical model which highlights why people
might seek information online at election time, and how this activity might
relate to overall electoral outcomes, focussing especially on how different
types of parties such as new and established parties might generate different
information seeking patterns. We test this model on a novel dataset drawn from
a variety of countries in the 2009 and 2014 European Parliament elections. We
show that while Wikipedia offers little insight into absolute vote outcomes, it
offers a good information about changes in both overall turnout at elections
and in vote share for particular parties. These results are used to enhance
existing theories about the drivers of aggregate patterns in online information
seeking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01465</id><created>2015-07-06</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Csat&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</forenames></author></authors><title>Distance-based accessibility indices</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><msc-class>15A06, 91D30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper attempts to develop a suitable accessibility index for networks
where each link has a value such that a smaller number is preferred like
distance, cost, or travel time. A measure called distance sum is characterized
by three independent properties: anonymity, an appropriately chosen
independence axiom, and dominance preservation, which requires that a node not
far to any other is at least as accessible.
  We argue for the need of eliminating the independence property in certain
applications. Therefore generalized distance sum, a family of accessibility
indices, will be suggested. It is linear, considers the accessibility of
vertices besides their distances and depends on a parameter in order to control
its deviation from distance sum. Generalized distance sum is anonymous and
satisfies dominance preservation if its parameter meets a sufficient condition.
Two detailed examples demonstrate its ability to reflect the vulnerability of
accessibility to link disruptions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09421</id><created>2016-03-30</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Nittis</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomi</keyname><forenames>Kiyonori</forenames></author></authors><title>The cohomological nature of the Fu-Kane-Mele invariant</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.mes-hall math.MP</categories><comments>v2: 51 pages, 3 main tables. New title and abstract. Typos fixed.
  Version accepted for publication in J. Geometry Phys.. Keywords:
  &quot;Quaternionic&quot; vector bundle, FKMM-invariant, Fu-Kane-Mele index,
  Bloch-bundle, Topological insulators</comments><msc-class>57R22 (Primary), 55N25, 53C80, 19L64 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we generalize the definition of the FKMM-invariant introduced
in [DG2] for the case of &quot;Quaternionic&quot; vector bundles over involutive base
spaces endowed with free involution or with a non-finite fixed-point set. In
[DG2] it has already be shown how the FKMM-invariant provides a cohomological
description of the Fu-Kane-Mele index used to classify topological insulators
in class AII. It follows that the FKMM-invariant described in this paper
provides a cohomological generalization of the Fu-Kane-Mele index which is
applicable to the classification of protected phases for other type of
topological quantum systems (TQS) which are not necesarily related to models
for topological insulators (e.g. the two-dimensional models of adiabatically
perturbed systems discussed in [GR]). As a byproduct we provide the complete
classification of &quot;Quaternionic&quot; vector bundles over a big class of low
dimensional involutive spheres and tori.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03942</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grigoriev</keyname><forenames>Pavel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziman</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author></authors><title>Slow quantum oscillations without fine-grained Fermi Surface
  Reconstruction in Cuprate Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters 106, 371 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364017180023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Fourier transform of the observed magnetic quantum oscillations (MQO) in
YBa$_{2}$Cu$_{3}$O$_{6+\delta }$ high-temperature superconductors has a
prominent low-frequency peak with two smaller neighbouring peaks. The
separation and positions of these three peaks are almost independent of doping.
This pattern has been explained previously by rather special, exquisitely
detailed, Fermi-surface reconstruction. We propose that these MQO have a
different origin, and their frequencies are related to the bilayer and
inter-bilayer electron hopping rather than directly to the areas of tiny
Fermi-surface pockets. Such so-called &quot;slow oscillations&quot; explain more
naturally many features of the observed oscillations and allow us to estimate
the inter-layer transfer integrals and in-plane Fermi momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03637</id><created>2016-07-13</created><updated>2017-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Horsman</keyname><forenames>Dominic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heunen</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pusey</keyname><forenames>Matthew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrett</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spekkens</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Can a quantum state over time resemble a quantum state at a single time?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 3 figures. Published version</comments><journal-ref>Proc. R. Soc. A 473 (2205), p. 20170395 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspa.2017.0395</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Standard quantum theory represents a composite system at a given time by a
joint state, but it does not prescribe a joint state for a composite of systems
at different times. If a more even-handed treatment of space and time is
possible, then such a joint state should be definable, and one might expect it
to satisfy the following five conditions: that it is a Hermitian operator on
the tensor product of the single-time Hilbert spaces; that it represents
probabilistic mixing appropriately; that it has the appropriate classical
limit; that it has the appropriate single-time marginals; that composing over
multiple time-steps is associative. We show that no construction satisfies all
these requirements. If an even-handed treatment of space and time is possible,
therefore, one or more axioms must be dropped. In particular, if Hermiticity is
dropped, then we show that the construction is fixed uniquely up to an ordering
convention.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05577</id><created>2016-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palumbo</keyname><forenames>Giandomenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>C. Morais</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal QED in two-dimensional topological insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>(5+4) pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 14175 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-14635-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been shown recently that local four-fermion interactions on the edges
of two-dimensional time-reversal-invariant topological insulators give rise to
a new non-Fermi-liquid phase, called helical Luttinger liquid (HLL). In this
work, we provide a first-principle derivation of this non-Fermi-liquid phase
based on the gauge-theory approach. Firstly, we derive a gauge theory for the
edge states by simply assuming that the interactions between the Dirac fermions
at the edge are mediated by a quantum dynamical electromagnetic field. Here,
the massless Dirac fermions are confined to live on the one-dimensional
boundary, while the (virtual) photons of the U(1) gauge field are free to
propagate in all the three spatial dimensions that represent the physical space
where the topological insulator is embedded. We then determine the effective
1+1-dimensional conformal field theory (CFT) given by the conformal quantum
electrodynamics (CQED). By integrating out the gauge field in the corresponding
partition function, we show that the CQED gives rise to a 1+1-dimensional
Thirring model. The bosonized Thirring Hamiltonian describes exactly a HLL with
a parameter K and a renormalized Fermi velocity that depend on the value of the
fine-structure constant $\alpha$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07036</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tianyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daiber</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Jarvist M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Sander A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnett</keyname><forenames>Erik C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ehrler</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author></authors><title>Indirect to direct bandgap transition in methylammonium lead halide
  perovskite</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Energy and Environmental Science 10, 509 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6ee03474h</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Methylammonium lead iodide perovskites are considered direct bandgap
semiconductors. Here we show that in fact they present a weakly indirect
bandgap 60 meV below the direct bandgap transition. This is a consequence of
spin-orbit coupling resulting in Rashba-splitting of the conduction band. The
indirect nature of the bandgap explains the apparent contradiction of strong
absorption and long charge carrier lifetime. Under hydrostatic pressure from
ambient to 325 MPa, Rashba splitting is reduced due to a pressure induced
ordering of the crystal structure. The nature of the bandgap becomes
increasingly more direct, resulting in five times faster charge carrier
recombination, and a doubling of the radiative efficiency. At hydrostatic
pressures above 325 MPa, MAPI undergoes a reversible phase transition resulting
in a purely direct bandgap semiconductor. The pressure-induced changes suggest
epitaxial and synthetic routes to higher efficiency optoelectronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08012</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghodsi</keyname><forenames>Hoda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baghram</keyname><forenames>Shant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habibi</keyname><forenames>Farhang</forenames></author></authors><title>Supernovae anisotropy power spectrum</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, final version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 10(2017)017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/10/017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We contribute another anisotropy study to this field of research using Type
Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). In this work, we utilise the power spectrum calculation
method and apply it to both the current SNe Ia data and simulation. Using the
Union2.1 data set at all redshifts, we compare the spectrum of the residuals of
the observed distance moduli to that expected from an isotropic universe
affected by the Union2.1 observational uncertainties at low multipoles. Through
this comparison we find a dipolar anisotropy with tension of less that
$2\sigma$ towards $l =171^\circ \pm 21^\circ$ and $b=-26^\circ \pm 28^\circ$
which is mainly induced by anisotropic spatial distribution of the SNe with $z
&gt; 0.2$ rather than being a cosmic effect. Furthermore, we find a tension of
$\sim 4\sigma$ at $\ell=4$ between the two spectra. Our simulations are
constructed with the characteristics of the upcoming surveys like the Large
Synoptic Survey Telescope (LSST), which shall bring us the largest SNe Ia
collection to date. We make predictions for the amplitude of a possible dipolar
anisotropy that would be detectable by future SNe Ia surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01392</id><created>2016-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Baczyk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konieczka</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakatsukasa</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satula</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Mirror and triplet displacement energies within nuclear DFT: numerical
  stability</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>talk presented at the Zakopane Conference on Nuclear Physics,
  Zakopane, Poland, August 28 - September 4, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Acta Phys. Pol. B48 (2017) 259</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolB.48.259</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Isospin-symmetry-violating class II and III contact terms are introduced into
the Skyrme energy density functional to account for charge dependence of the
strong nuclear interaction. The two new coupling constants are adjusted to
available experimental data on triplet and mirror displacement energies,
respectively. We present preliminary results of the fit, focusing on its
numerical stability with respect to the basis size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07133</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07133</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tews</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lattimer</keyname><forenames>James M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohnishi</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolomeitsev</keyname><forenames>Evgeni E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry Parameter Constraints From A Lower Bound On The Neutron-Matter
  Energy</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>27 pages, 13 figures, published version</comments><report-no>YITP-16-121, INT-PUB-16-045</report-no><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 848, 105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa8db9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the existence of a lower bound on the energy of pure neutron
matter (PNM) on the basis of unitary-gas considerations. We discuss its
justification from experimental studies of cold atoms as well as from
theoretical studies of neutron matter. We demonstrate that this bound results
in limits to the density-dependent symmetry energy, which is the difference
between the energies of symmetric nuclear matter and PNM. In particular, this
bound leads to a lower limit to the volume symmetry energy parameter $S_0$. In
addition, for assumed values of $S_0$ above this minimum, this bound implies
both upper and lower limits to the symmetry energy slope parameter $L$, which
describes the lowest-order density dependence of the symmetry energy. A lower
bound on the neutron-matter incompressibility is also obtained. These bounds
are found to be consistent with both recent calculations of the energies of PNM
and constraints from nuclear experiments. Our results are significant because
several equations of state that are currently used in astrophysical simulations
of supernovae and neutron star mergers, as well as in nuclear physics
simulations of heavy-ion collisions, have symmetry energy parameters that
violate these bounds. Furthermore, below the nuclear saturation density, the
bound on neutron-matter energies leads to a lower limit to the
density-dependent symmetry energy, which leads to upper limits to the nuclear
surface symmetry parameter and the neutron-star crust-core boundary. We also
obtain a lower limit to the neutron-skin thicknesses of neutron-rich nuclei.
Above the nuclear saturation density, the bound on neutron-matter energies also
leads to an upper limit to the symmetry energy, with implications for
neutron-star cooling via the direct Urca process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07654</id><created>2016-11-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Davanco</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapienza</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chen-Zhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Jose Vinicius De Miranda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Varun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirin</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Sae Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author></authors><title>A heterogeneous III-V/silicon integration platform for on-chip quantum
  photonic circuits with single quantum dot devices</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 8:889 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-00987-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photonic integration is an enabling technology for photonic quantum science,
offering greater scalability, stability, and functionality than traditional
bulk optics. Here, we describe a scalable, heterogeneous III-V/silicon
integration platform to produce Si$_3$N$_4$ photonic circuits incorporating
GaAs-based nanophotonic devices containing self-assembled InAs/GaAs quantum
dots. We demonstrate pure singlephoton emission from individual quantum dots in
GaAs waveguides and cavities - where strong control of spontaneous emission
rate is observed - directly launched into Si$_3$N$_4$ waveguides with &gt; 90 %
efficiency through evanescent coupling. To date, InAs/GaAs quantum dots
constitute the most promising solidstate triggered single-photon sources,
offering bright, pure and indistinguishable emission that can be electrically
and optically controlled. Si$_3$N$_4$ waveguides offer low-loss propagation,
tailorable dispersion and high Kerr nonlinearities, desirable for linear and
nonlinear optical signal processing down to the quantum level. We combine these
two in an integration platform that will enable a new class of scalable,
efficient and versatile integrated quantum photonic devices
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09311</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-02-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bennaceur</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Idini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kortelainen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raimondi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlocal energy density functionals for pairing and beyond-mean-field
  calculations</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>24 LaTeX pages, 9 figures, 4 tables, and supplemental material,
  version accepted for publication in Journal of Physics G</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 (2017) 045106</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa5fd7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose to use two-body regularized finite-range pseudopotential to
generate nuclear energy density functional (EDF) in both particle-hole and
particle-particle channels, which makes it free from self-interaction and
self-pairing, and also free from singularities when used beyond mean field. We
derive a sequence of pseudopotentials regularized up to next-to-leading order
(NLO) and next-to-next-to-leading order (N2LO), which fairly well describe
infinite-nuclear-matter properties and finite open-shell paired and/or deformed
nuclei. Since pure two-body pseudopotentials cannot generate sufficiently large
effective mass, the obtained solutions constitute a preliminary step towards
future implementations, which will include, e.g., EDF terms generated by
three-body pseudopotentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00378</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Idini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennaceur</keyname><forenames>Karim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau parameters for energy density functionals generated by local
  finite-range pseudopotentials</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 (2017) 064004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa691e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Landau theory of Fermi liquids, the particle-hole interaction near the
Fermi energy in different spin-isospin channels is probed in terms of an
expansion over the Legendre polynomials. This provides a useful and efficient
way to constrain properties of nuclear energy density functionals in symmetric
nuclear matter and finite nuclei. In this study, we present general expressions
for Landau parameters corresponding to a two-body central local regularized
pseudopotential. We also show results obtained for two recently adjusted NLO
and N$^2$LO parametrizations. Such pseudopotentials will be used to determine
mean-field and beyond-mean-field properties of paired nuclei across the entire
nuclear chart.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01785</id><created>2016-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>McNeill</keyname><forenames>Graham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bright</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hale</keyname><forenames>Scott A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating Local Commuting Patterns From Geolocated Twitter Data</title><categories>cs.CY cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Graham McNeill, Jonathan Bright and Scott A Hale (2017) Estimating
  local commuting patterns from geolocated Twitter data, EPJ Data Science
  20176:24</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjds/s13688-017-0120-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The emergence of large stores of transactional data generated by increasing
use of digital devices presents a huge opportunity for policymakers to improve
their knowledge of the local environment and thus make more informed and better
decisions. A research frontier is hence emerging which involves exploring the
type of measures that can be drawn from data stores such as mobile phone logs,
Internet searches and contributions to social media platforms, and the extent
to which these measures are accurate reflections of the wider population. This
paper contributes to this research frontier, by exploring the extent to which
local commuting patterns can be estimated from data drawn from Twitter. It
makes three contributions in particular. First, it shows that simple heuristics
drawn from geolocated Twitter data offer a good proxy for local commuting
patterns; one which outperforms the major existing method for estimating these
patterns (the radiation model). Second, it investigates sources of error in the
proxy measure, showing that the model performs better on short trips with
higher volumes of commuters; it also looks at demographic biases but finds
that, surprisingly, measurements are not significantly affected by the fact
that the demographic makeup of Twitter users differs significantly from the
population as a whole. Finally, it looks at potential ways of going beyond
simple heuristics by incorporating temporal information into models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04414</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bellorin</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Restuccia</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Einstein's quadrupole formula from the kinetic-conformal Horava theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>v2: 26 pages, one section added. Changes in presentation and more
  references added. Title changed</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics D 26 (2017) 1750174</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817501747</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the radiative and nonradiative linearized variables in a gravity
theory within the familiy of the nonprojectable Horava theories, the Horava
theory at the kinetic-conformal point. There is no extra mode in this
formulation, the theory shares the same number of degrees of freedom with
general relativity. The large-distance effective action, which is the one we
consider, can be given in a generally-covariant form under asymptotically flat
boundary conditions, the Einstein-aether theory under the condition of
hypersurface orthogonality on the aether vector. In the linearized theory we
find that only the transverse-traceless tensorial modes obey a sourced wave
equation, as in general relativity. The rest of variables are nonradiative. The
result is gauge-independent at the level of the linearized theory. For the case
of a weak source, we find that the leading mode in the far zone is exactly
Einstein's quadrupole formula of general relativity, if some coupling constants
are properly identified. There are no monopoles nor dipoles in this
formulation, in distinction to the nonprojectable Horava theory outside the
kinetic-conformal point. We also discuss some constraints on the theory arising
from the observational bounds on Lorentz-violating theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06186</id><created>2016-11-26</created><updated>2017-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moosavi</keyname><forenames>Vahid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isacchini</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author></authors><title>A Markovian Model of the Evolving World Input-Output Network</title><categories>q-fin.EC cs.SI physics.soc-ph q-fin.GN</categories><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0186746</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The initial theoretical connections between Leontief input-output models and
Markov chains were established back in 1950s. However, considering the wide
variety of mathematical properties of Markov chains, there has not been a full
investigation of evolving world economic networks with Markov chain formalism.
Using the recently available world input-output database, we modeled the
evolution of the world economic network from 1995 to 2011 through analysis of a
series of finite Markov chains. We assessed different aspects of this evolving
system via different properties of the Markov chains such as mixing time,
Kemeny constant, steady state probabilities and perturbation analysis of the
transition matrices. First, we showed how the time series of mixing times and
Kemeny constants could be used as an aggregate index of globalization. Next, we
focused on the steady state probabilities as a measure of structural power of
the economies that are comparable to GDP shares of economies as the traditional
index of economies. Further, we introduced two measures of systemic risk,
called systemic influence and systemic fragility, where the former is the ratio
of number of influenced nodes to the total number of nodes, caused by a shock
in the activity of a node and the latter is based on the number of times a
specific economic node is affected by a shock in the activity of any of the
other nodes. Finally, focusing on Kemeny constant as a global indicator of
monetary flow across the network, we showed that there is a paradoxical effect
of a change in activity levels of economic nodes on the overall flow of the
network. While the economic slowdown of the majority of nodes with high
structural power results to a slower average monetary flow over the network,
there are some nodes, where their slowdowns improve the overall quality of the
network in terms of connectivity and the average monetary flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01188</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Spanton</keyname><forenames>Eric M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Mingtang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaitiek&#x117;nas</keyname><forenames>Saulius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krogstrup</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nyg&#xe5;rd</keyname><forenames>Jesper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcus</keyname><forenames>Charles M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moler</keyname><forenames>Kathryn A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Current-phase relations of few-mode InAs nanowire Josephson junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><report-no>NBI QDEV 2017</report-no><journal-ref>Nature Physics (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys4224</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gate-tunable semiconductor nanowires with superconducting leads have great
potential for quantum computation and as model systems for mesoscopic Josephson
junctions. The supercurrent, $I$, versus the phase, $\phi$, across the junction
is called the current-phase relation (CPR). It can reveal not only the
amplitude of the critical current, but also the number of modes and their
transmission. We measured the CPR of many individual InAs nanowire Josephson
junctions, one junction at a time. Both the amplitude and shape of the CPR
varied between junctions, with small critical currents and skewed CPRs
indicating few-mode junctions with high transmissions. In a gate-tunable
junction, we found that the CPR varied with gate voltage: Near the onset of
supercurrent, we observed behavior consistent with resonant tunneling through a
single, highly transmitting mode. The gate dependence is consistent with
modeled subband structure that includes an effective tunneling barrier due to
an abrupt change in the Fermi level at the boundary of the gate-tuned region.
These measurements of skewed, tunable, few-mode CPRs are promising both for
applications that require anharmonic junctions and for Majorana readout
proposals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01198</id><created>2017-01-04</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Dawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Keren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katiyar</keyname><forenames>Hemant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Annie Jihyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Guanru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xin</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>GuiLu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodutch</keyname><forenames>Aharon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baugh</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Bei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laflamme</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing quantum control by bootstrapping a quantum processor of 12
  qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>The published version in npj Quantum Information</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 3, 45 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0045-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate and efficient control of quantum systems is one of the central
challenges for quantum information processing. Current state-of-the-art
experiments rarely go beyond 10 qubits and in most cases demonstrate only
limited control. Here we demonstrate control of a 12-qubit system, and show
that the system can be employed as a quantum processor to optimize its own
control sequence by using measurement-based feedback control (MQFC). The final
product is a control sequence for a complex 12-qubit task: preparation of a
12-coherent state. The control sequence is about 10% more accurate than the one
generated by the standard (classical) technique, showing that MQFC can correct
for unknown imperfections. Apart from demonstrating a high level of control
over a relatively large system, our results show that even at the 12-qubit
level, a quantum processor can be a useful lab instrument. As an extension of
our work, we propose a method for combining the MQFC technique with a twirling
protocol, to optimize the control sequence that produces a desired Clifford
gate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01381</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shapira</keyname><forenames>Dekel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Doron</forenames></author></authors><title>The lognormal-like statistics of a stochastic squeeze process</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 042152 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.042152</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the full statistics of a stochastic squeeze process. The model's
two parameters are the bare stretching rate~$w$, and the angular diffusion
coefficient~$D$. We carry out an exact analysis to determine the drift and the
diffusion coefficient of $\log(r)$, where $r$ is the radial coordinate. The
results go beyond the heuristic lognormal description that is implied by the
central limit theorem. Contrary to the common &quot;Quantum Zeno&quot; approximation, the
radial diffusion is not simply $D_r = (1/8)w^2/D$, but has a non-monotonic
dependence on $w/D$. Furthermore, the calculation of the radial moments is
dominated by the far non-Gaussian tails of the $\log(r)$ distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02770</id><created>2017-01-10</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chow</keyname><forenames>Colin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Hongyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Aaron M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaibley</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koehler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandrus</keyname><forenames>David G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merlin</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Wang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon-assisted oscillatory exciton dynamics in monolayer MoSe2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published in npj 2D Materials and Applications.
  https://www.nature.com/articles/s41699-017-0035-1</comments><journal-ref>Chow et al., npj 2D Materials and Applications 1, 33 (2017)
  (https://www.nature.com/articles/s41699-017-0035-1)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41699-017-0035-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In monolayer semiconductor transition metal dichalcogenides, the
exciton-phonon interaction is expected to strongly affect the photocarrier
dynamics. Here, we report on an unusual oscillatory enhancement of the neutral
exciton photoluminescence with the excitation laser frequency in monolayer
MoSe2. The frequency of oscillation matches that of the M-point longitudinal
acoustic phonon, LA(M). Oscillatory behavior is also observed in the
steady-state emission linewidth and in timeresolved photoluminescence
excitation data, which reveals variation with excitation energy in the exciton
lifetime. These results clearly expose the key role played by phonons in the
exciton formation and relaxation dynamics of two-dimensional van der Waals
semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05477</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-09-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yllanes</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchetti</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>How many dissenters does it take to disorder a flock?</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures. Version accepted for publication in New Journal
  of Physics</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 (2017) 103026</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa8ed7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the effect of introducing a small number of non-aligning agents
in a well-formed flock. To this end, we modify a minimal model of active
Brownian particles with purely repulsive (excluded volume) forces to introduce
an alignment interaction that will be experienced by all the particles except
for a small minority of &quot;dissenters&quot;. We find that even a very small fraction
of dissenters disrupts the flocking state. Strikingly, these motile dissenters
are much more effective than an equal number of static obstacles in breaking up
the flock. For the studied system sizes we obtain clear evidence of scale
invariance at the flocking-disorder transition point and the system can be
effectively described with a finite-size scaling formalism. We develop a
continuum model for the system which reveals that dissenters act like annealed
noise on aligners, with a noise strength that grows with the persistence of the
dissenters' dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06324</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hiti</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cindro</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gori&#x161;ek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hemperek</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>University of Bonn, Physikalisches Institut</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kishishita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>University of Bonn, Physikalisches Institut</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kramberger</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>University of Bonn, Physikalisches Institut</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mandi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Miku&#x17e;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation><affiliation>University of Ljubljana, Faculty of Mathematics and Physics</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wermes</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>University of Bonn, Physikalisches Institut</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zavrtanik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Jo&#x17e;ef Stefan Institute</affiliation></author></authors><title>Charge collection properties in an irradiated pixel sensor built in a
  thick-film HV-SOI process</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/12/10/P10020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigation of HV-CMOS sensors for use as a tracking detector in the ATLAS
experiment at the upgraded LHC (HL-LHC) has recently been an active field of
research. A potential candidate for a pixel detector built in
Silicon-On-Insulator (SOI) technology has already been characterized in terms
of radiation hardness to TID (Total Ionizing Dose) and charge collection after
a moderate neutron irradiation. In this article we present results of an
extensive irradiation hardness study with neutrons up to a fluence of 1x10e16
neq/cm2. Charge collection in a passive pixelated structure was measured by
Edge Transient Current Technique (E-TCT). The evolution of the effective space
charge concentration was found to be compliant with the acceptor removal model,
with the minimum of the space charge concentration being reached after 5x10e14
neq/cm2. An investigation of the in-pixel uniformity of the detector response
revealed parasitic charge collection by the epitaxial silicon layer
characteristic for the SOI design. The results were backed by a numerical
simulation of charge collection in an equivalent detector layout.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06811</id><created>2017-02-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Elouard</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernardes</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>A. R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auff&#xe8;ves</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing quantum fluctuation theorems in engineered reservoirs</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics, Volume 19, Issue 10, article id. 103011
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa7fa2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fluctuation Theorems are central in stochastic thermodynamics, as they allow
for quantifying the irreversibility of single trajectories. Although they have
been experimentally checked in the classical regime, a practical demonstration
in the framework of quantum open systems is still to come. Here we propose a
realistic platform to probe fluctuation theorems in the quantum regime. It is
based on an effective two-level system coupled to an engineered reservoir, that
enables the detection of the photons emitted and absorbed by the system. When
the system is coherently driven, a measurable quantum component in the entropy
production is evidenced. We quantify the error due to photon detection
inefficiency, and show that the missing information can be efficiently
corrected, based solely on the detected events. Our findings provide new
insights into how the quantum character of a physical system impacts its
thermodynamic evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08363</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valencio</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebogi</keyname><forenames>Celso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baptista</keyname><forenames>Murilo S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Methods for removal of unwanted signals from gravity time-series:
  comparison using linear techniques complemented with analysis of system
  dynamics</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>This preprint includes the Supplementary Materials</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The presence of undesirable dominating signals in geophysical experimental
data is a challenge in many subfields. One remarkable example is surface
gravimetry, where frequencies from Earth tides correspond to time-series
fluctuations up to a thousand times larger than the phenomena of major
interest, such as hydrological gravity effects or co-seismic gravity changes.
This work discusses general methods for removal of unwanted dominating signals
by applying them to 8 long-period gravity time-series of the International
Geodynamics and Earth Tides Service, equivalent to the acquisition from 8
instruments in 5 locations representative of the network. We compare three
different conceptual approaches for tide removal: frequency filtering, physical
modelling and data-based modelling. Each approach reveals a different
limitation to be considered depending on the intended application. Vestiges of
tides remain in the residues for the modelling procedures, whereas the signal
was distorted in different ways by the filtering and data-based procedures. The
linear techniques employed were power spectral density, spectrogram,
cross-correlation and classical harmonics decomposition, while the system
dynamics was analysed by state-space reconstruction and estimation of the
largest Lyapunov exponent. Although the tides could not be completely
eliminated, they were sufficiently reduced to allow observation of geophysical
events of interest above the $10 \text{ nm s}^{-2}$ level, exemplified by a
hydrology-related event of $60 \text{ nm s}^{-2}$. The implementations adopted
for each conceptual approach are general, so that their principles could be
applied to other kinds of data affected by undesired signals composed mainly by
periodic or quasi-periodic components.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01575</id><created>2017-03-05</created><updated>2017-08-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xinjuan</forenames><affiliation>ZJUT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames><affiliation>SJTU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames><affiliation>SHAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengjie</forenames><affiliation>SJTU</affiliation></author></authors><title>Weak lensing power spectrum reconstruction by counting galaxies.-- I:
  the ABS method</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>v1: 13 pages, 10 figures. v2: minor revisions. ApJ in press</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 845, 174 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7ed4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an Analytical method of Blind Separation (ABS) of cosmic
magnification from the intrinsic fluctuations of galaxy number density in the
observed galaxy number density distribution. The ABS method utilizes the
different dependences of the signal (cosmic magnification) and contamination
(galaxy intrinsic clustering) on galaxy flux, to separate the two. It works
directly on the measured cross galaxy angular power spectra between different
flux bins. It determines/reconstructs the lensing power spectrum analytically,
without assumptions of galaxy intrinsic clustering and cosmology. It is
unbiased in the limit of infinite number of galaxies. In reality the lensing
reconstruction accuracy depends on survey configurations, galaxy biases, and
other complexities, due to finite number of galaxies and the resulting shot
noise fluctuations in the cross galaxy power spectra. We estimate its
performance (systematic and statistical errors) in various cases. We find that,
stage IV dark energy surveys such as SKA and LSST are capable of reconstructing
the lensing power spectrum at $z\simeq 1$ and $\ell\la 5000$ accurately. This
lensing reconstruction only requires counting galaxies, and is therefore highly
complementary to the cosmic shear measurement by the same surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02167</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sodemann</keyname><forenames>Inti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropy Driven Transition from Moore-Read State to Quantum Hall
  Stripes</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 201116(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.201116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nature of the quantum Hall liquid in a half-filled second
Landau level ($n=1$) as a function of band mass anisotropy using numerical
exact diagonalization (ED) and density matrix renormalization group (DMRG)
methods. We find increasing the mass anisotropy induces a quantum phase
transition from the Moore-Read state to a charge density wave state. By
analyzing the energy spectrum, guiding center structure factors and by adding
weak pinning potentials, we show that this charge density wave is a
uni-directional quantum Hall stripe, which has a periodicity of a few magnetic
lengths and survives in the thermodynamic limit. We find smooth profiles for
the guiding center occupation function that reveal the strong coupling nature
of the array of chiral Luttinger liquids residing at the stripe edges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02464</id><created>2017-03-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Brandner</keyname><forenames>Kay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seifert</keyname><forenames>Udo</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Coherence-Induced Power Losses of Quantum Heat Engines in
  Linear Response</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>7+4 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 170602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.170602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a universal scheme to divide the power output of a periodically
driven quantum heat engine into a classical contribution and one stemming
solely from quantum coherence. Specializing to Lindblad-dynamics and small
driving amplitudes, we derive general upper bounds on both, the coherent and
the total power. These constraints imply that, in the linear-response regime,
coherence inevitably leads to power losses. To illustrate our general analysis,
we explicitly work out the experimentally relevant example of a single-qubit
engine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05294</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iaria</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambino</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Salvo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burderi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matranga</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riggio</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanna</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'A&#xec;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A possible solution of the puzzling variation of the orbital period of
  MXB 1659-298</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2529</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  MXB 1659-298 is a transient neutron star Low-Mass X-ray binary system that
shows eclipses with a periodicity of 7.1 hr. The source went to outburst in
August 2015 after 14 years of quiescence. We investigate the orbital properties
of this source with a baseline of 40 years obtained combining the eight eclipse
arrival times present in literature with 51 eclipse arrival times collected
during the last two outbursts. A quadratic ephemeris does not fit the delays
associated with the eclipse arrival times and the addition of a sinusoidal term
with a period of $2.31 \pm 0.02$ yr is required. We infer a binary orbital
period of $P=7.1161099(3)$ hr and an orbital period derivative of
$\dot{P}=-8.5(1.2) \times 10^{-12}$ s s$^{-1}$. We show that the large orbital
period derivative can be explained with a highly non conservative mass transfer
scenario in which more than 98\% of the mass provided by the companion star
leaves the binary system. We predict an orbital period derivative value of
$\dot{P}=-6(3) \times 10^{-12}$ s s$^{-1}$ and constrain the companion star
mass between $\sim$0.3 and $ 0.9 \pm 0.3$ M$_{\odot}$. Assuming that the
companion star is in thermal equilibrium the periodic modulation can be due to
either a gravitational quadrupole coupling due to variations of the oblateness
of the companion star or with the presence of a third body of mass M$_3 &gt;21 $
Jovian masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08988</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaebel</keyname><forenames>Sebastian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veitch</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>How would GW150914 look with future GW detector networks?</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1700020</report-no><journal-ref>S M Gaebel and J Veitch 2017 Class. Quantum Grav. 34 174003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa82d9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first detected gravitational wave signal, GW150914, was produced by the
coalescence of a stellar-mass binary black hole. Along with the subsequent
detection of GW151226, GW170104 and the candidate event LVT151012, this gives
us evidence for a population of black hole binaries with component masses in
the tens of solar masses. As detector sensitivity improves, this type of source
is expected to make a large contribution to the overall number of detections,
but has received little attention compared to binary neutron star systems in
studies of projected network performance. We simulate the observation of a
system like GW150914 with different proposed network configurations, and study
the precision of parameter estimates, particularly source location, orientation
and masses. We find that the improvements to low frequency sensitivity that are
expected with continued commissioning will improve the precision of chirp mass
estimates by an order of magnitude, whereas the improvements in sky location
and orientation are driven by the expanded network configuration. This
demonstrates that both sensitivity and number of detectors will be important
factors in the scientific potential of second generation detector networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09948</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-08-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bozic</keyname><forenames>Anze Losdorfer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podgornik</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author></authors><title>pH dependence of charge multipole moments in proteins</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.BM</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures; 12 pages and 12 figures of Supporting Material;
  accepted for publication in Biophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>Biophys. J. 113, 1454-1465 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.bpj.2017.08.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electrostatic interactions play a fundamental role in the structure and
function of proteins. Due to ionizable amino acid residues present on the
solvent-exposed surfaces of proteins, the protein charge is not constant but
varies with the changes in the environment -- most notably, the pH of the
surrounding solution. We study the effects of pH on the charge of four globular
proteins by expanding their surface charge distributions in terms of
multipoles. The detailed representation of the charges on the proteins is in
this way replaced by the magnitudes and orientations of the multipole moments
of varying order. Focusing on the three lowest-order multipoles -- the total
charge, dipole, and quadrupole moment -- we show that the value of pH
influences not only their magnitudes, but more notably and importantly also the
spatial orientation of their principal axes. Our findings imply important
consequences for the study of protein-protein interactions and the assembly of
both proteinaceous shells and patchy colloids with dissociable charge groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01323</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maitra</keyname><forenames>Arpita</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement Device Independent Quantum Dialogue</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Information Processing 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Very recently, the experimental demonstration of Quantum Secure Direct
Communication (QSDC) with state-of-the-art atomic quantum memory has been
reported (Phys. Rev. Lett., 2017). Quantum Dialogue (QD) falls under QSDC where
the secrete messages are communicated simultaneously between two legitimate
parties. The successful experimental demonstration of QSDC opens up the
possibilities for practical implementation of QD protocols. Thus, it is
necessary to analyze the practical security issues of QD protocols for future
implementation. Since the very first proposal for QD by Nguyen (Phys. Lett. A,
2004) a large number of variants and extensions have been presented till date.
However, all of those leak half of the secret bits to the adversary through
classical communications of the measurement results. In this direction,
motivated by the idea of Lo et al. (Phys. Rev. Lett., 2012), we propose a
Measurement Device Independent Quantum Dialogue (MDI-QD) scheme which is
resistant to such information leakage as well as side channel attacks. In the
proposed protocol, Alice and Bob, two legitimate parties, are allowed to
prepare the states only. The states are measured by an untrusted third party
(UTP) who may himself behave as an adversary. We show that our protocol is
secure under this adversarial model. The current protocol does not require any
quantum memory and thus it is inherently robust against memory attacks. Such
robustness might not be guaranteed in the QSDC protocol with quantum memory
(Phys. Rev. Lett., 2017).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02057</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-09-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsuura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizukami</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugimura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maejima</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machida</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanuki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yajima</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiroi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yip</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Y. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosoi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukasa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasahara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>J. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goh</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uwatoko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibauchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximizing Tc by tuning nematicity and magnetism in FeSe1-xSx
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures. A revised version will appear in Nature
  Communications</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 1143 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-01277-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental issue concerning iron-based superconductivity is the roles of
electronic nematicity and magnetism in realising high transition temperature
($T_{\rm c}$). To address this issue, FeSe is a key material, as it exhibits a
unique pressure phase diagram involving nonmagnetic nematic and
pressure-induced antiferromagnetic ordered phases. However, as these two phases
in FeSe overlap with each other, the effects of two orders on superconductivity
remain perplexing. Here we construct the three-dimensional electronic phase
diagram, temperature ($T$) against pressure ($P$) and isovalent S-substitution
($x$), for FeSe$_{1-x}$S$_{x}$, in which we achieve a complete separation of
nematic and antiferromagnetic phases. In between, an extended nonmagnetic
tetragonal phase emerges, where we find a striking enhancement of $T_{\rm c}$.
The completed phase diagram uncovers two superconducting domes with similarly
high $T_{\rm c}$ on both ends of the dome-shaped antiferromagnetic phase. The
$T_{\rm c}(P,x)$ variation implies that nematic fluctuations unless
accompanying magnetism are not relevant for high-$T_{\rm c}$ superconductivity
in this system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02330</id><created>2017-04-07</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhardwaj</keyname><forenames>Lakshya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tachikawa</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author></authors><title>On finite symmetries and their gauging in two dimensions</title><categories>hep-th math.CT</categories><comments>73 pages, v2: correct treatment of pivotal structure leading to the
  resolution of a contradiction between non-trivial anomaly and unitarity</comments><report-no>IPMU-17-0049</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well-known that if we gauge a $\mathbb{Z}_n$ symmetry in two
dimensions, a dual $\mathbb{Z}_n$ symmetry appears, such that re-gauging this
dual $\mathbb{Z}_n$ symmetry leads back to the original theory. We describe how
this can be generalized to non-Abelian groups, by enlarging the concept of
symmetries from those defined by groups to those defined by unitary fusion
categories. We will see that this generalization is also useful when studying
what happens when a non-anomalous subgroup of an anomalous finite group is
gauged: for example, the gauged theory can have non-Abelian group symmetry even
when the original symmetry is an Abelian group. We then discuss the
axiomatization of two-dimensional topological quantum field theories whose
symmetry is given by a category. We see explicitly that the gauged version is a
topological quantum field theory with a new symmetry given by a dual category.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02692</id><created>2017-04-09</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asaka</keyname><forenames>Takehiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eijima</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minogawa</keyname><forenames>Kosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshii</keyname><forenames>Tomoya</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial condition for baryogenesis via neutrino oscillation</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>24 pages, 35 figures, v2; correspond to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 083010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.083010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a baryogenesis scenario via the oscillation of right-handed
neutrinos with Majorana masses of the order of GeV, which are also responsible
for neutrino masses by the seesaw mechanism. We study how the initial condition
alters the prediction of the present baryon asymmetry by this mechanism. It is
usually assumed that the abundance of right-handed neutrinos is zero after the
reheating of the inflationary universe and they are produced in scattering
processes by the renomalizable Yukawa interaction. However, the
higher-dimensional operator with right-handed neutrinos may provide an
additional production which is most effective at the reheating epoch. It is
shown that such an initial abundance of right-handed neutrinos can
significantly modify the prediction when the strong washout of the asymmetry is
absent. This leads to the parameter space of the model for the successful
baryogenesis being enlarged.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06208</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bosman</keyname><forenames>Sal J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gely</keyname><forenames>Mario F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Vibhor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bothner</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>Gary A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-mode ultra-strong coupling in circuit quantum electrodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 3, Article number: 46 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0046-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the introduction of superconducting circuits into the field of quantum
optics, many novel experimental demonstrations of the quantum physics of an
artificial atom coupled to a single-mode light field have been realized.
Engineering such quantum systems offers the opportunity to explore extreme
regimes of light-matter interaction that are inaccessible with natural systems.
For instance the coupling strength $g$ can be increased until it is comparable
with the atomic or mode frequency $\omega_{a,m}$ and the atom can be coupled to
multiple modes which has always challenged our understanding of light-matter
interaction. Here, we experimentally realize the first Transmon qubit in the
ultra-strong coupling regime, reaching coupling ratios of $g/\omega_{m}=0.19$
and we measure multi-mode interactions through a hybridization of the qubit up
to the fifth mode of the resonator. This is enabled by a qubit with 88% of its
capacitance formed by a vacuum-gap capacitance with the center conductor of a
coplanar waveguide resonator. In addition to potential applications in quantum
information technologies due to its small size and localization of electric
fields in vacuum, this new architecture offers the potential to further explore
the novel regime of multi-mode ultra-strong coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06526</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaillac</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pullumbi</keyname><forenames>Pluton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beyer</keyname><forenames>Kevin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapman</keyname><forenames>Karena W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keen</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>Thomas D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coudert</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois-Xavier</forenames></author></authors><title>Liquid Metal-Organic Frameworks</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nature Materials, 2017, 16, 1149-1154</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4998</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metal--organic frameworks (MOFs) are a family of chemically diverse
materials, with applications in a wide range of fields covering engineering,
physics, chemistry, biology and medicine. Research so far has focused almost
entirely on crystalline structures, yet a clear trend has emerged shifting the
emphasis onto disordered states of MOFs, including &quot;defective by design&quot;
crystals, as well as amorphous phases such as glasses and gels. Here we
introduce a MOF liquid, a strongly associated liquid obtained by melting a
zeolitic imidazolate framework (ZIF), with retention of chemical configuration,
coordinative bonding modes, and porosity of the parent crystalline framework.
We combine in-situ variable temperature X-ray, ex-situ neutron pair
distribution function experiments, and first principles molecular dynamics
simulations to study the melting phenomenon and the nature of the liquid
obtained, focusing on structural characterization at the molecular scale,
dynamics of the species, and thermodynamics of the solid--liquid transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07830</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lochner</keyname><forenames>Michelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassett</keyname><forenames>Bruce A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lablanche</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Yves</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>Shankar</forenames></author></authors><title>zBEAMS: A unified solution for supernova cosmology with redshift
  uncertainties</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Matches published version, 18 pages, 6 figures, Code available:
  https://github.com/MichelleLochner/zBEAMS</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 10, (2017) 036</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/10/036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supernova cosmology without spectra will be an important component of future
surveys such as LSST. This lack of supernova spectra results in uncertainty in
the redshifts which, if ignored, leads to significantly biased estimates of
cosmological parameters. Here we present a hierarchical Bayesian formalism --
zBEAMS -- that addresses this problem by marginalising over the unknown or
uncertain supernova redshifts to produce unbiased cosmological estimates that
are competitive with supernova data with spectroscopically confirmed redshifts.
zBEAMS provides a unified treatment of both photometric redshifts and host
galaxy misidentification (occurring due to chance galaxy alignments or faint
hosts), effectively correcting the inevitable contamination in the Hubble
diagram. Like its predecessor BEAMS, our formalism also takes care of non-Ia
supernova contamination by marginalising over the unknown supernova type. We
illustrate this technique with simulations of supernovae with photometric
redshifts and host galaxy misidentification. A novel feature of the photometric
redshift case is the important role played by the redshift distribution of the
supernovae.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07983</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Performance of the ATLAS Track Reconstruction Algorithms in Dense
  Environments in LHC Run 2</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>44 pages in total, author list starting page 28, 17 figures, 1 table,
  submitted to EPJC, All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/PERF-2015-08/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2017-045</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 673</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5225-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the increase in energy of the Large Hadron Collider to a centre-of-mass
energy of 13 TeV for Run 2, events with dense environments, such as in the
cores of high-energy jets, became a focus for new physics searches as well as
measurements of the Standard Model. These environments are characterized by
charged-particle separations of the order of the tracking detectors sensor
granularity. Basic track quantities are compared between 3.2 fb$^{-1}$ of data
collected by the ATLAS experiment and simulation of proton-proton collisions
producing high-transverse-momentum jets at a centre-of-mass energy of 13 TeV.
The impact of charged-particle separations and multiplicities on the track
reconstruction performance is discussed. The efficiency in the cores of jets
with transverse momenta between 200 GeV and 1600 GeV is quantified using a
novel, data-driven, method. The method uses the energy loss, dE/dx, to identify
pixel clusters originating from two charged particles. Of the charged particles
creating these clusters, the measured fraction that fail to be reconstructed is
$0.061 \pm 0.006 \textrm{(stat.)} \pm 0.014 \textrm{(syst.)}$ and $0.093 \pm
0.017 \textrm{(stat.)}\pm 0.021 \textrm{(syst.)}$ for jet transverse momenta of
200-400 GeV and 1400-1600 GeV, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08460</id><created>2017-04-27</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mre&#x144;ca-Kolasi&#x144;ska</keyname><forenames>Alina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szafran</keyname><forenames>Bart&#x142;omiej</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging backscattering in graphene quantum point contacts</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 165310 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.165310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study graphene quantum point contacts (QPC) and imaging of the
backscattering of the Fermi level wave function by potential introduced by a
scanning probe. We consider both etched single-layer QPCs as well as the ones
formed by bilayer patches deposited at the sides of the monolayer conducting
channel using an atomistic tight binding approach. A computational method is
developed to effectively simulate an infinite graphene plane outside the QPC
using a computational box of a finite size. We demonstrate that in spite of the
Klein phenomenon interference due to the backscattering at a circular n-p
junction induced by the probe potential is visible in spatial maps of
conductance as functions of the probe position.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00348</id><created>2017-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wierzbowski</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigger</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straubinger</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kremser</keyname><forenames>Malte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurstbauer</keyname><forenames>Ursula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holleitner</keyname><forenames>Alexander W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaniber</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finley</keyname><forenames>Jonathan J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct exciton emission from atomically thin transition metal
  dichalcogenide heterostructures near the lifetime limit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-09739-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the reduction of the inhomogeneous linewidth of the free
excitons in atomically thin transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs)
MoSe$_{2}$, WSe$_{2}$ and MoS$_{2}$ by encapsulation within few nanometer thick
hBN. Encapsulation is shown to result in a significant reduction of the 10K
excitonic linewidths down to $\sim3.5 \text{ meV}$ for n-MoSe$_{2}$, $\sim5.0
\text{ meV}$ for p-WSe$_{2}$ and $\sim4.8 \text{ meV}$ for n-MoS$_{2}$.
Evidence is obtained that the hBN environment effectively lowers the Fermi
level since the relative spectral weight shifts towards the neutral exciton
emission in n-doped TMDCs and towards charged exciton emission in p-doped
TMDCs. Moreover, we find that fully encapsulated MoS$_{2}$ shows resolvable
exciton and trion emission even after high power density excitation in contrast
to non-encapsulated materials. Our findings suggest that encapsulation of
mechanically exfoliated few-monolayer TMDCs within nanometer thick hBN
dramatically enhances optical quality, producing ultra-narrow linewidths that
approach the homogeneous limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02286</id><created>2017-05-05</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>Matthew D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haghighirad</keyname><forenames>Amir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhodes</keyname><forenames>Luke C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoesch</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Timur K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic anisotropies revealed by detwinned ARPES measurements of FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 103021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa8a04</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report high resolution ARPES measurements of detwinned FeSe single
crystals. The application of a mechanical strain is used to promote the volume
fraction of one of the orthorhombic domains in the sample, which we estimate to
be 80$\%$ detwinned. While the full structure of the electron pockets
consisting of two crossed ellipses may be observed in the tetragonal phase at
temperatures above 90~K, we find that remarkably, only one peanut-shaped
electron pocket oriented along the longer $a$ axis contributes to the ARPES
measurement at low temperatures in the nematic phase, with the expected pocket
along $b$ being not observed. Thus the low temperature Fermi surface of FeSe as
experimentally determined by ARPES consists of one elliptical hole pocket and
one orthogonally-oriented peanut-shaped electron pocket. Our measurements
clarify the long-standing controversies over the interpretation of ARPES
measurements of FeSe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03958</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leon</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Eternal inflation and the quantum birth of cosmic structure</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages plus references. Replaced to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 705</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5288-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the eternal inflation scenario of the slow-roll/chaotic type with
the additional element of an objective collapse of the wave function. The
incorporation of this new agent to the traditional inflationary setting might
represent a possible solution to the quantum measurement problem during
inflation, a subject that has not reached a consensus among the community.
Specifically, it could provide an explanation for the generation of the
primordial anisotropies and inhomogeneities, starting from a perfectly
symmetric background and invoking symmetric dynamics. We adopt the continuous
spontaneous localization model, in the context of inflation, as the dynamical
reduction mechanism that generates the primordial inhomogeneities. Furthermore,
when enforcing the objective reduction mechanism, the condition for eternal
inflation can be bypassed. In particular, the collapse mechanism incites the
wave function, corresponding to the inflaton, to localize itself around the
zero mode of the field. Then the zero mode will evolve essentially unperturbed,
driving inflation to an end in any region of the Universe where inflation
occurred. Also, our approach achieves a primordial spectrum with an amplitude
and shape consistent with the one that best fits the observational data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06290</id><created>2017-05-17</created><updated>2017-05-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandkishore</keyname><forenames>Rahul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sondhi</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Many body localization with long range interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>Expanded discussion of higher dimensions, updated references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 041021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many body localization (MBL) has emerged as a powerful paradigm for
understanding non-equilibrium quantum dynamics. Folklore based on perturbative
arguments holds that MBL only arises in systems with short range interactions.
Here we advance non-perturbative arguments indicating that MBL can arise in
systems with long range (Coulomb) interactions. In particular, we show using
bosonization that MBL can arise in one dimensional systems with ~ r
interactions, a problem that exhibits charge confinement. We also argue that
(through the Anderson-Higgs mechanism) MBL can arise in two dimensional systems
with log r interactions, and speculate that our arguments may even extend to
three dimensional systems with 1/r interactions. Our arguments are `asymptotic'
(i.e. valid up to rare region corrections), yet they open the door to
investigation of MBL physics in a wide array of long range interacting systems
where such physics was previously believed not to arise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09143</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knolle</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moessner</keyname><forenames>Roderich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovrizhin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Absence of Ergodicity without Quenched Disorder: from Quantum
  Disentangled Liquids to Many-Body Localization</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 176601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.176601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the time evolution after a quantum quench in a family of models
whose degrees of freedom are fermions coupled to spins, where quenched disorder
appears neither in the Hamiltonian parameters nor in the initial state.
Focussing on the behaviour of entanglement, both spatial and between
subsystems, we show that the model supports a state exhibiting combined
area/volume law entanglement, being characteristic of the quantum disentangled
liquid. This behaviour appears for one set of variables, which is related via a
duality mapping to another set, where this structure is absent. Upon adding
density interactions between the fermions, we identify an exact mapping to an
XXZ spin-chain in a random binary magnetic field, thereby establishing the
existence of many-body localization with its logarithmic entanglement growth in
a fully disorder-free system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09631</id><created>2017-05-26</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yubing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faessler</keyname><forenames>Amand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutsche</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Qifang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyubovitskij</keyname><forenames>Valery E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Selected strong decays of $\eta(2225)$ and $\phi(2170)$ as $\Lambda
  \bar\Lambda$ bound states</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 074027 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.074027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strong decays of the two resonances $\eta(2225)$ and $\phi(2170)$ are
discussed for selected decay channels. The two resonances are considered as the
$\Lambda \bar{\Lambda}$ bound states in the molecular scenario. The
phenomenological hadronic molecular approach is employed for the calculation of
respective decay modes using effective Lagrangians. Our results show that the
decay modes $\eta(2225)\to K^*K$ and $\phi(2175) \to KK$ dominate over the
partial decay widths of $\eta(2275)\to VV (\phi\phi, \omega\omega, K^*K^*)$ and
$\phi(2175)\to VS (\omega\sigma, K^*K^*_0(800), \phi f_0(980))$ due to phase
space and couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10859</id><created>2017-05-30</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Corrections for a constant radial magnetic field in the g-2 and
  electric-dipole-moment experiments with muons in storage rings</title><categories>physics.acc-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 695 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5229-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the corrections for constant radial magnetic field in muon g--2
and electric-dipole-moment experiments in storage rings. While the correction
is negligible for the current generation of g--2 experiments, it affects the
upcoming muon electric-dipole-moment experiment at Fermilab.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02065</id><created>2017-06-07</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author></authors><title>General description of spin motion in storage rings in presence of
  oscillating horizontal fields</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters 118, 61003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/61003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The general theoretical description of the influence of oscillating
horizontal magnetic and quasimagnetic fields on the spin evolution in storage
rings is presented. Previous results are generalized to the case when both of
the horizontal components of the oscillating field are nonzero and the vector
of this field circumscribes an ellipse. General equations describing a behavior
of all components of the polarization vector are derived and the case of an
arbitrary initial polarization is considered. The derivation is fulfilled in
the case when the oscillation frequency is nonresonant. The general spin
evolution in storage rings conditioned by vertical betatron oscillations is
calculated as an example.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09429</id><created>2017-06-28</created><updated>2017-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luitz</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lev</keyname><forenames>Yevgeny Bar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarides</keyname><forenames>Achilleas</forenames></author></authors><title>Absence of dynamical localization in interacting driven systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.other cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Scipost resubmission. 14 pages, 4 figures. Changes to the figures.
  Corrects a few typos</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 029 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.4.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a numerically exact method we study the stability of dynamical
localization to the addition of interactions in a periodically driven isolated
quantum system which conserves only the total number of particles. We find that
while even infinitesimally small interactions destroy dynamical localization,
for weak interactions density transport is significantly suppressed and is
asymptotically diffusive, with a diffusion coefficient proportional to the
interaction strength. For systems tuned away from the dynamical localization
point, even slightly, transport is dramatically enhanced and within the largest
accessible systems sizes a diffusive regime is only pronounced for sufficiently
small detunings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01230</id><created>2017-07-05</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Francis</forenames></author></authors><title>A class of non-holomorphic modular forms I</title><categories>math.NT hep-th</categories><comments>Based on a talk given at Zagier's 65th birthday conference `modular
  forms are everywhere'. What was formerly the appendix has now turned into
  arXiv:1710.07912</comments><msc-class>11F11, 11F67</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This introductory paper studies a class of real analytic functions on the
upper half plane satisfying a certain modular transformation property. They are
not eigenfunctions of the Laplacian and are quite distinct from Maass forms.
These functions are modular equivariant versions of real and imaginary parts of
iterated integrals of holomorphic modular forms, and are modular analogues of
single-valued polylogarithms. The coefficients of these functions in a suitable
power series expansion are periods. They are related both to mixed motives
(iterated extensions of pure motives of classical modular forms), as well as
the modular graph functions arising in genus one string perturbation theory. In
an appendix, we use weakly holomorphic modular forms to write down modular
primitives of cusp forms. Their coefficients involve the full period matrix
(periods and quasi-periods) of cusp forms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03557</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoodian</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magarill</keyname><forenames>L. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Entin</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Edge absorption and pure spin current in 2D topological insulator in the
  Volkov-Pankratov model</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29 (2017) 435303</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa8849</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The light absorption due to the transitions between the edge and
two-dimensional (2D) states of a 2D topological insulator (TI) is considered in
the Volkov-Pankratov model. It is shown that the transitions are allowed only
for the in-plane electric field orthogonal to the edge of the TI. It is found
that the absorption is accompanied by the pure spin photocurrent along the TI
edge. The possibility of the spin current measurement using polarized
luminescence from 2D TI quantum dots is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04140</id><created>2017-07-13</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rios</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polls</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dickhoff</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pairing and short-range correlations in nuclear systems</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>Final version, as published in journal after refereeing</comments><journal-ref>J Low Temp Phys (2017) 189: 234</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-017-1818-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structure and density dependence of the pairing gap in infinite matter is
relevant for astrophysical phenomena and provides a starting point for the
discussion of pairing properties in nuclear structure. Short-range correlations
can significantly deplete the available single-particle strength around the
Fermi surface and thus provide a reduction mechanism of the pairing gap. Here,
we study this effect in the singlet and triplet channels of both neutron matter
and symmetric nuclear matter. Our calculations use phase-shift equivalent
interactions and chiral two-body and three-body interactions as a starting
point. We find an unambiguous reduction of the gap in all channels with very
small dependence on the NN force in the singlet neutron matter and the triplet
nuclear matter channel. In the latter channel, short range correlations alone
provide a 50% reduction of the pairing gap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06054</id><created>2017-07-19</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Yanqi</forenames></author></authors><title>A rigidity property of superpositions involving determinantal processes</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main result of this paper states that if $(N, \Pi)$ is a pair of
independent point processes on a common ground space with $N$ Poisson and $\Pi$
determinantal induced by a locally trace class (not necessarily self-adjoint)
correlation kernel, then their independent superposition $N + \Pi$ determines
uniquely the distributions of $N$ and $\Pi$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09218</id><created>2017-07-28</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cubero</keyname><forenames>Axel Cort&#xe9;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuricht</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum quench in the attractive regime of the sine-Gordon model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 103106</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa8c2e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of the sine-Gordon model after a quantum quench into
the attractive regime, where the spectrum consists of solitons, antisolitons
and breathers. In particular, we analyse the time-dependent expectation value
of the vertex operator, $\exp\left({\rm i}\beta\Phi/2\right)$, starting from an
initial state in the &quot;squeezed state form&quot; corresponding to integrable boundary
conditions. Using an expansion in terms of exact form factors, we compute
analytically the leading contributions to this expectation value at late times.
We show that form factors containing breathers only contribute to the late-time
dynamics if the initial state exhibits zero-momentum breather states. The
leading terms at late times exponentially decay, and we compute the different
decay rates. In addition, the late-time contributions from the zero-momentum
breathers display oscillatory behaviour, with the oscillation frequency given
by the breather mass renormalised by interaction effects. Using our result, we
compute the low-energy contributions to the power spectrum of the vertex
operator. The oscillatory terms in the expectation value are shown to produce
smooth peaks in the power spectrum located near the values of the bare breather
masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.00499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.00499</id><created>2017-08-01</created><updated>2017-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ruo Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skelton</keyname><forenames>Jonathan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>E. Lora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Jarvist M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous Octahedral Tilting in the Cubic Inorganic Caesium Halide
  Perovskites CsSnX$_3$ and CsPbX$_3$ (X = F, Cl, Br, I)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 8, 4720-4726 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b02423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The local crystal structures of many perovskite-structured materials deviate
from the average space group symmetry. We demonstrate, from lattice-dynamics
calculations based on quantum chemical force constants, that all the
caesium-lead and caesium-tin halide perovskites exhibit vibrational
instabilities associated with octahedral titling in their high-temperature
cubic phase. Anharmonic double-well potentials are found for zone-boundary
phonon modes in all compounds with barriers ranging from 108 to 512 meV. The
well depth is correlated with the tolerance factor and the chemistry of the
composition, but is not proportional to the imaginary harmonic phonon
frequency. We provide quantitative insights into the thermodynamic driving
forces and distinguish between dynamic and static disorder based on the
potential-energy landscape. A positive band gap deformation (spectral
blueshift) accompanies the structural distortion, with implications for
understanding the performance of these materials in applications areas
including solar cells and light-emitting diodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02464</id><created>2017-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Knopf</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal control of a Vlasov-Poisson plasma by an external magnetic field
  - The basics for variational calculus</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.OC</categories><msc-class>49J20, 35Q83</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the three dimensional Vlasov-Poisson system that is equipped with
an external magnetic field to describe a plasma. The aim of various concrete
applications is to control a plasma in a desired fashion. This can be modeled
by an optimal control problem. For that reason the basics for calculus of
variations will be introduced in this paper. We have to find a suitable class
of fields that are admissible for this procedure as they provide unique global
solutions of the Vlasov-Poisson system. Then we can define a field-state
operator that maps any admissible field onto its corresponding distribution
function. We will show that this field-state operator is Lipschitz continuous
and (weakly) compact. Last we will consider a model problem with a tracking
type cost functional and we will show that this optimal control problem has at
least one globally optimal solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02753</id><created>2017-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Knopf</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal control of a Vlasov-Poisson plasma by an external magnetic field
  - Analysis of a tracking type optimal control problem</title><categories>math.OC math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><msc-class>49J20, 35Q83</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the paper &quot;Optimal control of a Vlasov-Poisson plasma by an external
magnetic field - The basics for variational calculus&quot; [arXiv:1708.02464] we
have already introduced a set of admissible magnetic fields and we have proved
that each of those fields induces a unique strong solution of the
Vlasov-Poisson system. We have also established that the field-state operator
that maps any admissible field onto its corresponding solution is continuous
and weakly compact. In this paper we will show that this operator is also
Fr\'echet differentiable and we will continue to analyze the optimal control
problem that was introduced in [arXiv:1708.02464]. More precisely, we will
establish necessary and sufficient conditions for local optimality and we will
show that an optimal solution is unique under certain conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03939</id><created>2017-08-13</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Anuradha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arun</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sathyaprakash</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of binary black hole detections on the merger rates of
  double neutron stars and neutron star-black holes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, no figures, 4 tables, v2: matches published version</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1700209</report-no><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, 849:L14 (5pp), 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa9271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the inferred merger rate and chirp masses of binary black holes
(BBHs) detected by advanced LIGO (aLIGO) can be used to constrain the rate of
double neutron star (DNS) and neutron star - black hole (NSBH) mergers in the
universe. We explicitly demonstrate this by considering a set of publicly
available population synthesis models of \citet{Dominik:2012kk} and show that
if all the BBH mergers, GW150914, LVT151012, GW151226, and GW170104, observed
by aLIGO arise from isolated binary evolution, the predicted DNS merger rate
may be constrained to be $2.3-471.0$~\rate~ and that of NSBH mergers will be
constrained to $0.2-48.5$~\rate. The DNS merger rates are not constrained much
but the NSBH rates are tightened by a factor of $\sim 4$ as compared to their
previous rates. Note that these constrained DNS and NSBH rates are extremely
model dependent and are compared to the unconstrained values $2.3-472.5$ \rate~
and $0.2-218$ \rate, respectively, using the same models of
\citet{Dominik:2012kk}. These rate estimates may have implications for short
Gamma Ray Burst progenitor models assuming they are powered (solely) by DNS or
NSBH mergers. While these results are based on a set of open access population
synthesis models which may not necessarily be the representative ones, the
proposed method is very general and can be applied to any number of models
thereby yielding more realistic constraints on the DNS and NSBH merger rates
from the inferred BBH merger rate and chirp mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04008</id><created>2017-08-14</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Shoichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum limit of hyperon vector coupling $f_1(0)$ from 2+1 flavor
  domain wall QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 20 figures; v2: version published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 074509 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.074509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the hyperon vector couplings $f_1(0)$ for $\Sigma^{-}\rightarrow
nl^-\bar{\nu_l}$ and $\Xi^0\rightarrow\Sigma^{+}l^-\bar{\nu_l}$ semileptonic
decays in the continuum limit with (2+1)-flavors of dynamical domain-wall
fermions, using the Iwasaki gauge action at two different lattice spacings of
$a$=0.114(2) and 0.086(2) fm. A theoretical estimation of flavor SU(3)-breaking
effect on the vector coupling is required to extract $V_{us}$ from the
experimental rate of hyperon beta decays. We obtain the vector couplings
$f_1(0)$ for $\Sigma\rightarrow N$ and $\Xi\rightarrow \Sigma$ beta-decays with
an accuracy of less than one percent. We then find that lattice results of
$f_1(0)$ combined with the best estimate of $|V_{us}|$ with imposing
Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa (CKM) unitarity are slightly deviated from the
experimental result of $|V_{us}f_1(0)|$ for the $\Sigma\rightarrow N$
beta-decay. This discrepancy can be attributed to an assumption made in the
experimental analysis on $|V_{us}f_1(0)|$, where the induced second-class form
factor $g_2$ is set to be zero regardless of broken SU(3) symmetry. We report
on this matter and then estimate the possible value of $g_2(0)$, which is
evaluated from the experimental decay rate with our lattice result of $f_1(0)$
under the first-row CKM-unitarity condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05138</id><created>2017-08-17</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yue-Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>On Thermal Gravitational Contribution to Particle Production and Dark
  Matter</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures and 2 tables, published version</comments><report-no>UT-17-27</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 774C (2017) 676-681</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the particle production from thermal gravitational
annihilation in the very early universe, which is an important contribution for
particles that might not be in thermal equilibrium or/and only have
gravitational interaction, such as dark matter (DM). For particles with spin 0,
1/2 and 1 we calculate the relevant cross sections through gravitational
annihilation and give the analytic formulas with full mass-dependent terms. We
find that DM with mass between TeV and $10^{16}$GeV could have the relic
abundance that fits the observation, with small dependence on its spin. We also
discuss the effects of gravitational annihilation from inflatons.
Interestingly, contributions from inflatons could be dominant and have the same
power dependence on Hubble parameter of inflation as that from vacuum
fluctuation. Also, fermion production from inflatons, in comparison to boson,
is suppressed by its mass due to helicity selection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05147</id><created>2017-08-17</created><updated>2017-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Misumi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>New class of flat-band models on tetragonal and hexagonal lattices:
  Gapped versus crossing flat bands</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con hep-lat</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures; typos corrected, references added, version to
  appear in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 155137 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.155137</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new class of tight-binding models where a flat band is either
gapped from or crossing right through a dispersive band on two-band (i.e., two
sites/unit cell) tetragonal and honeycomb lattices. By imposing a condition on
the hopping parameters for generic models with up to third-neighbor hoppings,
we first obtain models having a rigorously flat band isolated from a dispersive
band with a gap, which accommodate both rank-reducing and non-rank-reducing of
the Hamiltonian. The class of models include Tasaki's flat-band models, but the
present model has a nonzero flat-band energy, whose gap from the dispersive
band is controllable as well. We then modify the models by appropriately
changing the second- or third-neighbor hoppings, leading to a new class of
two-dimensional lattices where a (slightly warped) flat band pierces a
dispersive one. As with the known flat-band models, the connectivity condition
is satisfied in the present models, so that we have unusual, unorthogonalizable
Wannier orbitals. We have also shown that the present flat-band model can be
extended to three (or higher) dimensions. Implications on possible high-$T_{C}$
superconductivity are discussed when a repulsive electron-electron interaction
is introduced, where the flat band is envisaged to be utilized as intermediate
states in pair scattering processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.06906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.06906</id><created>2017-08-23</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paturej</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreer</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hierarchical excluded volume screening in solutions of bottlebrush
  polymers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>24 pages and 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7SM01968H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polymer bottlebrushes provide intriguing features being relevant both in
nature and in synthetic systems. While their presence in the articular
cartilage optimizes synovial joint lubrication, bottlebrushes offer pathways
for fascinating applications, such as within super- soft elastomers or for drug
delivery. However, the current theoretical understanding lacks completeness,
primarily due to the complicated interplay of many length scales. Herein, we
develop an analytical model that demonstrates how structural properties of
bottlebrushes depend on the concentration, ranging from dilute solutions to
highly concentrated melts. The validity of our model is supported by data from
extensive molecular dynamics simulation. We demonstrate that the hierarchical
structure of bottlebrushes dictates a sequence of conformational changes as the
solution concentration increases. The effect is mediated by screening
ofexcluded volume interactions atsubsequent structural parts ofthe
bottlebrushes. Our findings provide important insights that should enable
improved customization of novel materials based on the architectural design of
polymer bottlebrushes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.09530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.09530</id><created>2017-08-30</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baumgardt</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sollima</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>The Global Mass Functions of 35 Galactic globular clusters: II. Clues on
  the Initial Mass Function and Black Hole Retention Fraction</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, MNRAS, 472, 744</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we compare the mass function slopes of Galactic globular
clusters recently determined by Sollima &amp; Baumgardt (2017) with a set of
dedicated N-body simulations of star clusters containing between 65,000 to
200,000 stars. We study clusters starting with a range of initial mass
functions (IMFs), black hole retention fractions and orbital parameters in the
parent galaxy. We find that the present-day mass functions of globular clusters
agree well with those expected for star clusters starting with Kroupa or
Chabrier IMFs, and are incompatible with clusters starting with single
power-law mass functions for the low-mass stars. The amount of mass segregation
seen in the globular clusters studied by Sollima &amp; Baumgardt (2017) can be
fully explained by two-body relaxation driven mass segregation from initially
unsegregated star clusters. Based on the present-day global mass functions, we
expect that a typical globular cluster in our sample has lost about 75% of its
mass since formation, while the most evolved clusters have already lost more
than 90% of their initial mass and should dissolve within the next 1 to 2 Gyr.
Most clusters studied by Sollima &amp; Baumgardt also show a large difference
between their central and global MF slopes, implying that the majority of
Galactic globular clusters is either near or already past core collapse. The
strong mass segregation seen in most clusters also implies that only a small
fraction of all black holes formed in globular clusters still reside in them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.00746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.00746</id><created>2017-09-03</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Luis C.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Optimal Strategy for Accurate Bulge-to-disk Decomposition of Disk
  Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>30 pages, 14 figures, published in ApJ; minor typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J.845:114-139,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7da4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of two-dimensional (2D) bulge-to-disk decomposition
techniques has shown their advantages over traditional one-dimensional (1D)
techniques, especially for galaxies with non-axisymmetric features. However,
the full potential of 2D techniques has yet to be fully exploited. Secondary
morphological features in nearby disk galaxies, such as bars, lenses, rings,
disk breaks, and spiral arms, are seldom accounted for in 2D image
decompositions, even though some image-fitting codes, such as GALFIT, are
capable of handling them. We present detailed, 2D multi-model and
multi-component decomposition of high-quality $R$-band images of a
representative sample of nearby disk galaxies selected from the Carnegie-Irvine
Galaxy Survey, using the latest version of GALFIT. The sample consists of five
barred and five unbarred galaxies, spanning Hubble types from S0 to Sc.
Traditional 1D decomposition is also presented for comparison. In detailed case
studies of the 10 galaxies, we successfully model the secondary morphological
features. Through a comparison of best-fit parameters obtained from different
input surface brightness models, we identify morphological features that
significantly impact bulge measurements. We show that nuclear and inner
lenses/rings and disk breaks must be properly taken into account to obtain
accurate bulge parameters, whereas outer lenses/rings and spiral arms have a
negligible effect. We provide an optimal strategy to measure bulge parameters
of typical disk galaxies, as well as prescriptions to estimate realistic
uncertainties of them, which will benefit subsequent decomposition of a larger
galaxy sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.01520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.01520</id><created>2017-09-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chi-Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of the Drude peak and of zero sound in probe brane holography</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B774, 569 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At zero temperature, the charge current operator appears to be conserved,
within linear response, in certain holographic probe brane models of strange
metals. At small but finite temperature, we analytically show that the weak
non-conservation of this current leads to both a collective &quot;zero sound&quot; mode
and a Drude peak in the electrical conductivity. This simultaneously resolves
two outstanding puzzles about probe brane theories. The nonlinear dynamics of
the current operator itself appears qualitatively different.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.02132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.02132</id><created>2017-09-07</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lucha</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sazdjian</keyname><forenames>Hagop</forenames></author></authors><title>Exotic states and their properties from large-$N_{\rm c}$ QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, talk presented at &quot;The European Physical Society
  Conference on High Energy Physics - EPS-HEP 2017&quot; (5 - 12 July 2017, Venice,
  Italy)</comments><report-no>HEPHY-PUB 989/17 (2017)</report-no><journal-ref>PoS EPS-HEP2017 (2017) 390</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The analysis of two-ordinary-meson scattering amplitudes in the limit of a
large number $N_{\rm c}$ of the colour degrees of freedom of quantum
chromodynamics, with suitably decreasing strong coupling and all quarks
transforming according to the gauge group's fundamental representation, enables
us to establish a set of rigorous consistency conditions for the emergence of a
tetraquark (i.e., a bound state of two quarks and two antiquarks) as a pole in
these amplitudes. For genuinely flavour-exotic tetraquarks, these constraints
require the existence of two tetraquark states distinguishable by their
preferred couplings to two ordinary mesons, whereas, for cryptoexotic
tetraquarks, our constraints may be satisfied by a single tetraquark state,
which then, however, may mix with ordinary mesons. For elucidation of the
tetraquark features, the consideration of the subleading contributions proves
to be mandatory: for both variants of tetraquarks, their decay widths fall off
like $1/N_{\rm c}^2$ for large $N_{\rm c}.$
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.03873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.03873</id><created>2017-09-08</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>The isolated electron: De Broglie's &quot;hidden&quot; thermodynamics, SU(2)
  Quantum Yang-Mills theory, and a strongly perturbed BPS monopole</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pp, 3 figs, v2: mistake in estimating the core-size of monopole
  rectified and typos eliminated</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 2017, 19(11), 575</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19110575</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on a recent numerical simulation of the temporal evolution of a
spherically perturbed BPS monopole, SU(2) Yang-Mills thermodynamics, Louis de
Broglie's deliberations on the disparate Lorentz transformations of the
frequency of an internal &quot;clock&quot; on one hand and the associated quantum energy
on the other hand, and postulating that the electron is represented by a
figure-eight shaped, self-intersecting center vortex loop in SU(2) Quantum
Yang-Mills theory we estimate the spatial radius $R_0$ of this
self-intersection region in terms of the electron's Compton wave length
$\lambda_C$. This region, which is immersed into the confining phase,
constitutes a blob of deconfining phase of temperature $T_0$ mildly above the
critical temperature $T_c$ carrying a frequently perturbed BPS monopole (with a
magnetic-electric dual interpretation of its charge w.r.t. U(1)$\subset$SU(2)).
We also establish a quantitative relation between rest mass $m_0$ of the
electron and SU(2) Yang-Mills scale $\Lambda$, which in turn is defined via
$T_c$. Surprisingly, $R_0$ turns out to be comparable to the Bohr radius while
the core size of the monopole matches $\lambda_C$, and the correction to the
mass of the electron due to Coulomb energy is about 2\,\%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05255</id><created>2017-09-15</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wallace</keyname><forenames>Colin S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chambers</keyname><forenames>Timothy G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prather</keyname><forenames>Edward E.</forenames></author></authors><title>An item response theory evaluation of the Light and Spectroscopy Concept
  Inventory national data set</title><categories>physics.ed-ph astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 60 figures, submitted to Physical Review: Physics Education
  Research, revised in response to referee comments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents the first item response theory (IRT) analysis of the
national data set on introductory, general education, college-level astronomy
teaching using the Light and Spectroscopy Concept Inventory (LSCI). We used the
difference between students' pre- and post-instruction IRT-estimated abilities
as a measure of learning gain. This analysis provides deeper insights than
prior publications into both the LSCI as an instrument and into the
effectiveness of teaching and learning in introductory astronomy courses. Our
IRT analysis supports the classical test theory findings of prior studies using
the LSCI with this population. In particular, we found that students in classes
that used active learning strategies at least 25\% of the time had average
IRT-estimated learning gains that were approximately 1 logit larger than
students in classes that spent less time on active learning strategies. We also
found that instructors who want their classes to achieve an improvement in
abilities of average $\Delta \theta = 1$ logit must spend at least 25\% of
class time on active learning strategies. However, our analysis also powerfully
illustrates the lack of insight into student learning that is revealed by
looking at a single measure of learning gain, such as average $\Delta \theta$.
Educators and researchers should also examine the distributions of students'
abilities pre- and post-instruction in order to understand how many students
actually achieved an improvement in their abilities and whether or not a
majority of students have moved to post-abilities significantly greater than
the national average.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05777</id><created>2017-09-18</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weingarten</keyname><forenames>Don</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden Variable Theory of a Single World from Many-Worlds Quantum
  Mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures, additions to sections V and VI</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method for finding an initial state vector which by ordinary
Hamiltonian time evolution follows a single branch of many-worlds quantum
mechanics. The resulting deterministic system appears to exhibit random
behavior as a result of the successive emergence over time of information
present in the initial state but not previously observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.06453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.06453</id><created>2017-09-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Plata</keyname><forenames>Carlos A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prados</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Kovacs-like memory effect in athermal systems: linear response analysis</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures; submitted to the special issue of the journal
  Entropy on &quot;Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics of Small Systems&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 19, 539 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19100539</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the emergence of Kovacs-like memory effects in athermal systems
within the linear response regime. This is done by starting from both the
master equation for the probability distribution and the equations for the
physically relevant moments. The general results are applied to a general class
of models with conserved momentum and non-conserved energy. Our theoretical
predictions, obtained within the first Sonine approximation, show an excellent
agreement with the numerical results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08569</id><created>2017-09-25</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dowker</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>a-F interpolation with boundary</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages. Added extensive section on boundary value problems and the
  D to N map. Connections to work by Barvinsky and others made</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A recent derivation of the interpolation between the free energy and
conformal anomaly for free fields on spheres is generalised to hemispheres with
Neumann (N) and Dirichlet (D) conditions at the rim for GJMS scalar fields. It
is shown that the N minus D interpolation is minus a quarter of that for a
higher derivative fermion on the spherical rim. In particular, since, for
ordinary bosons k=1, the related fermion is irregular propagating according to
a second order (pseudo) operator. (2k is the derivative order in the equation
of motion.)
  It is suggested that the relation has a role to play in the Type--B AdS/CFT
mismatch. The DN boundary value problem is enlarged upon in the context of
Branson and Gover's construction of the D to N operator. Contact is made with a
result of Park and Wojciechowski which is then related to a duality relation of
Barvinsky and Nesterov.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08884</id><created>2017-09-26</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Selli</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Valentin</keyname><forenames>Cristiana</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling Realistic TiO2 Nanospheres: a Benchmark Study of SCC-DFTB
  against Hybrid DFT</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4994165</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  TiO2 nanoparticles (NPs) are nowadays considered fundamental building blocks
for many technological applications. Morphology is found to play a key role
with spherical NPs presenting higher binding properties and chemical activity.
From the experimental point of view, the characterization of these nano-objects
is extremely complex, opening a large room for computational investigations. In
this work, TiO2 spherical NPs of different size (from 300 to 4000 atoms) have
been studied with a two-scale computational approach. Global optimization to
obtain stable and equilibrated NSs was performed with a self-consistent charge
density functional tight-binding (SCC-DFTB) simulated annealing process,
causing a considerable atomic rearrangement within the nanospheres. Those
SCC-DFTB relaxed structures have been then optimized at DFT(B3LYP) level of
theory. We present a systematic and comparative SCC-DFTB vs DFT(B3LYP) study of
the structural properties, with particular emphasis on the surface-to-bulk
sites ratio, coordination distribution of surface sites and surface energy.
From the electronic point of view, we compare HOMO-LUMO and Kohn-Sham gaps,
total and projected density of states. Overall, the comparisons between DFTB
and hybrid DFT show that DFTB provides a rather accurate geometrical and
electronic description of these nanospheres of realistic size (up to a diameter
of 4.4 nm) at an extremely reduced computational cost. This opens for new
challenges in simulations of very large systems and more extended molecular
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00767</id><created>2017-10-02</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Broussard</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrow</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chance</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crow</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeBeer-Schmitt</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo-Uribarri</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallmeier</keyname><forenames>F. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heilbronn</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iverson</keyname><forenames>E. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamyshkov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pentill&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruggles</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybolt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snow</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Townsend</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varriano</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vavra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Search for Mirror Neutrons at HFIR</title><categories>hep-ex nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures. Talk presented at the APS Division of Particles
  and Fields Meeting (DPF 2017), July 31-August 4, 2017, Fermilab. C170731</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theory of mirror matter predicts a hidden sector made up of a copy of the
Standard Model particles and interactions but with opposite parity. If mirror
matter interacts with ordinary matter, there could be experimentally accessible
implications in the form of neutral particle oscillations. Direct searches for
neutron oscillations into mirror neutrons in a controlled magnetic field have
previously been performed using ultracold neutrons in storage/disappearance
measurements, with some inconclusive results consistent with characteristic
oscillation time of $\tau$$\sim$10~s. Here we describe a proposed disappearance
and regeneration experiment in which the neutron oscillates to and from a
mirror neutron state. An experiment performed using the existing General
Purpose-Small Angle Neutron Scattering instrument at the High Flux Isotope
Reactor at Oak Ridge National Laboratory could have the sensitivity to exclude
up to $\tau$$&lt;$15~s in 1 week of beamtime and at low cost.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.01005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.01005</id><created>2017-10-03</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on hydrodynamics from many-body quantum chaos</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 + 19 pages, 1+0 figures. v2: revised presentation of key results,
  added small calculations on SYK chains</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Is the hydrodynamics of an interacting many-body system fundamentally limited
by basic principles of quantum mechanics? Starting with the conjecture that
viscosity is at least as large as entropy density (as measured in fundamental
units), there has been a long search for a precise answer to this question. In
this work, we identify a simple relationship between hydrodynamics and
many-body quantum chaos in a broad class of experimentally realizable systems.
Consistency with the quantum butterfly effect leads to upper bounds on the
speed of sound and diffusion constants of hydrodynamics. These bounds link two
very different theories of quantum many-body dynamics, clarify the relationship
between classical hydrodynamics and quantum information loss, and provide a
simple way to constrain theories of thermalization and quantum chaos in
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.02646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.02646</id><created>2017-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zarei</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Hossein</forenames></author></authors><title>A strong-weak coupling duality between two perturbed quantum many-body
  systems: CSS codes and Ising-like systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, submitted to PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 165146 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.165146</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphs and recently hypergraphs have been known as an important tool for
considering different properties of quantum many-body systems. In this paper,
we study a mapping between an important class of quantum systems namely quantum
Calderbank-Shor-Steane (CSS) codes and Ising-like systems by using hypergraphs.
We show that the Hamiltonian corresponding to a CSS code on a hypergraph $H$
which is perturbed by a uniform magnetic field is mapped to Hamiltonian of a
Ising-like system on dual hypergraph $\tilde{H}$ in a transverse field.
Interestingly, we show that a strong regime of couplings in one of the systems
is mapped to a weak regime of couplings in another one. We also give some
applications for such a mapping where we study robustness of different
topological CSS codes against a uniform magnetic field including Kitaev's toric
codes defined on graphs and color codes in different dimensions. We show that a
perturbed Kitaev's toric code on an arbitrary graph is mapped to an Ising model
in a transverse field on the same graph and a perturbed color code on a D-colex
is mapped to a Ising-like model on a D-simplicial lattice in a transverse
field. In particular, we use these results to explicitly compare the robustness
of TC on different graphs in different dimensions. Interestingly, our results
show that the robustness of such topological codes defined on graphs decreases
with increasing dimension. Furthermore, we also use the duality mapping for
some self-dual models where we exactly derive the point of phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03415</id><created>2017-10-10</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sussman</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author></authors><title>Rademacher Series for $\eta$-Quotients</title><categories>math.NT math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>11F30 (Primary), 30E20, 41A30, 11P82, 05A17 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply Rademacher's method in order to compute the Fourier coefficients of
a large class of $\eta$-quotients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03682</id><created>2017-10-01</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Avetissian</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghazaryan</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedrakian</keyname><forenames>Kh. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avchyan</keyname><forenames>B. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic quantum theory of nonlinear absorption of strong
  electromagnetic radiation in doped graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1703.06854</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microscopic quantum theory of nonlinear stimulated scattering of 2D Dirac
particles in doped graphene on Coulomb field of impurity ions at the presence
of an external strong coherent electromagnetic radiation is developed. We
consider high Fermi energies and low frequencies (actually terahertz radiation)
to exclude the valence electrons excitations. The Liouville-von Neumann
equation for the density matrix is solved analytically, taking into account the
interaction of electrons with the scattering potential in the Born
approximation. With the help of this solution, the nonlinear
inverse-bremsstrahlung absorption rate for a grand canonical ensemble of 2D
Dirac fermions is calculated. It is shown that one can achieve the efficient
absorption coefficient by this mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03853</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03853</id><created>2017-10-10</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Komatsu</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author></authors><title>Lectures on Three-point Functions in N=4 Supersymmetric Yang-Mills
  Theory</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>58 pages. v2 An appendix added. Typos corrected. References added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a pedagogical review on the integrability-based approach to the
three-point function in N=4 supersymmetric Yang-Mills theory. We first discuss
the computation of the structure constant at weak coupling and show that the
result can be recast as a sum over partitions of the rapidities of the magnons.
We then introduce a non-perturbative framework, called the &quot;hexagon approach&quot;,
and explain how one can use the symmetries (i.e. superconformal and gauge
symmetries) and integrability to determine the structure constants. This
article is based on the lectures given in Les Houches Summer School
&quot;Integrability: From statistical systems to gauge theory&quot; in June 2016.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04193</id><created>2017-10-11</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alexeev</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mixon</keyname><forenames>Dustin G.</forenames></author></authors><title>An impossibility theorem for gerrymandering</title><categories>math.CO math.MG physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The U.S. Supreme Court is currently deliberating over whether a proposed
mathematical formula should be used to detect unconstitutional partisan
gerrymandering. We show that in some cases, this formula will only flag
bizarrely shaped districts as potentially constitutional.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.05083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.05083</id><created>2017-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glass</keyname><forenames>H. F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suard</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutton</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relieving the frustration through Mn$^{3+}$ substitution in Holmium
  Gallium Garnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures, 4 supplementary figures, accepted for
  publication in Physical Review B as a Rapid Communication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 140412 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.140412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a study on the impact of Mn$^{3+}$ substitution in the
geometrically frustrated Ising garnet Ho$_3$Ga$_5$O$_{12}$ using bulk magnetic
measurements and low temperature powder neutron diffraction. We find that the
transition temperature, $T_N$ = 5.8 K, for Ho$_3$MnGa$_4$O$_{12}$ is raised by
almost 20 when compared to Ho$_3$Ga$_5$O$_{12}$. Powder neutron diffraction on
Ho$_3$Mn$_x$Ga$_{5-x}$O$_{12}$ ($x$ = 0.5, 1) below $T_N$ shows the formation
of a long range ordered ordered state with $\mathbf{k}$ = (0,0,0). Ho$^{3+}$
spins are aligned antiferromagnetically along the six crystallographic axes
with no resultant moment while the Mn$^{3+}$ spins are oriented along the body
diagonals, such that there is a net moment along [111]. The magnetic structure
can be visualised as ten-membered rings of corner-sharing triangles of
Ho$^{3+}$ spins with the Mn$^{3+}$ spins ferromagnetically coupled to each
individual Ho$^{3+}$ spin in the triangle. Substitution of Mn$^{3+}$ completely
relieves the magnetic frustration with $f = \theta_{CW}/T_N \approx 1.1$ for
Ho$_3$MnGa$_4$O$_{12}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.07236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.07236</id><created>2017-10-19</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Derr</keyname><forenames>Tyler</forenames><affiliation>Michigan State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chenxing</forenames><affiliation>Michigan State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Suhang</forenames><affiliation>Arizona State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Jiliang</forenames><affiliation>Michigan State University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Signed Node Relevance Measurements</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we perform the initial and comprehensive study on the problem
of measuring node relevance on signed social networks. We design numerous
relevance measurements for signed social networks from both local and global
perspectives and investigate the connection between signed relevance
measurements, balance theory and signed network properties. Experimental
results are conducted to study the effects of signed relevance measurements
with four real-world datasets on signed network analysis tasks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08148</id><created>2017-10-23</created><updated>2017-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Dai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Dexin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jianxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lao</keyname><forenames>Chenglong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiangkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Sifen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Longgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hanbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xingfan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Ming Li Chuanxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qilong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Zhiyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>In situ high resolution real-time quantum efficiency imaging for
  photocathodes</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aspects of the preparation process and performance degradation are two major
problems of photocathodes. The lack of a means for dynamic quantum efficiency
measurements results in the inability to observe the inhomogeneity of the
cathode surface by fine structural analysis and in real time.Here we present a
simple and scalable technique for in situ real-time quantum efficiency
diagnosis. An incoherent light source provides uniform illumination on the
cathode surface, and solenoid magnets are used as lens for focusing and imaging
the emitted electron beam on a downstream scintillator screen, which converts
the quantum efficiency information into fluorescence intensity distribution.
The microscopic discontinuity and the dynamic changes of the quantum efficiency
of a gallium arsenide photocathode are observed at a resolution of a few
microns. An unexpected uneven decrease of the quantum efficiency is also
recorded. The work demonstrates a new observation method for photoemission
materials research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09376</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Muselli</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Double Differential High Energy Resummation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study a general framework to perform leading log high energy
resummation with complete dependence from the rapidity and the transverse
momentum of the studied system. As an application, high energy resummed
expression for the Higgs boson production in the effective field theory
framework will be derived. Explicit result for this process will be
cross-checked against fixed order evaluations up to NNLO. Consistency with
known high energy resummation for single differential rapidity or transverse
momentum distribution, as well as for inclusive cross section, will also be
shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09395</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>De Palma</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author></authors><title>Gaussian optimizers and other topics in quantum information</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>PhD thesis defended on 12 Sep 2016, supervisor: Prof. Vittorio
  Giovannetti</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main topic of this thesis is the proof of two fundamental entropic
inequalities for quantum Gaussian channels. Quantum Gaussian channels model the
propagation of electromagnetic waves through optical fibers and free space in
the quantum regime, and provide the mathematical model to determine the maximum
rates achievable by quantum communication devices for communication and quantum
key distribution. The first inequality proven in this thesis is the quantum
Entropy Power Inequality, which provides a lower bound to the output entropy of
the beam-splitter or of the squeezing in terms of the entropies of the two
inputs. The second inequality states that Gaussian states minimize the output
entropy of the one-mode quantum Gaussian attenuator among all the input states
with a given entropy, and was a longstanding conjecture in quantum
communication theory. The generalization of this inequality to the multimode
attenuator would determine its triple trade-off region and its capacity region
for broadcast communication to two receivers. The thesis contains further
results in Gaussian quantum information, quantum statistical mechanics and
relativistic quantum information. The most important of these results concerns
the Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis (ETH). The ETH is an assumption in
quantum statistical mechanics stating that the eigenstates of the Hamiltonian
of a system+bath compound look as thermal states if we can access only the
system. We prove that the ETH must hold if the system thermalizes for any
initial product state of the system+bath compound with a well-defined
temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09396</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Schwieger</keyname><forenames>Kay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Noncommutative Coverings of Quantum Tori</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><msc-class>46L85, 14F35 (primary), 55R10, 14A20 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a framework for coverings of noncommutative spaces. Moreover, we
study noncommutative coverings of irrational quantum tori and characterize all
such coverings that are connected in a reasonable sense.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09400</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Movassagh</keyname><forenames>Ramis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edelman</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenvalue approximation of sums of Hermitian matrices from eigenvector
  localization/delocalization</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>19 pages and 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a technique for calculating and understanding the eigenvalue
distribution of sums of random matrices from the known distribution of the
summands. The exact problem is formidably hard. One extreme approximation to
the true density amounts to classical probability, in which the matrices are
assumed to commute; the other extreme is related to free probability, in which
the eigenvectors are assumed to be in generic positions and sufficiently large.
In practice, free probability theory can give a good approximation of the
density.
  We develop a technique based on eigenvector localization/delocalization that
works very well for important problems of interest where free probability is
not sufficient, but certain uniformity properties apply. The
localization/delocalization property appears in a convex combination parameter
that notably, is independent of any eigenvalue properties and yields accurate
eigenvalue density approximations.
  We demonstrate this technique on a number of examples as well as discuss a
more general technique when the uniformity properties fail to apply.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09421</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Datar</keyname><forenames>Adwait V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fyta</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marconi</keyname><forenames>Umberto Marini Bettolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchionna</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrokinetic Lattice Boltzmann solver coupled to Molecular Dynamics:
  application to polymer translocation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Datar, Adwait V., et al. &quot;Electrokinetic Lattice Boltzmann Solver
  Coupled to Molecular Dynamics: Application to Polymer Translocation.&quot;
  Langmuir: the ACS journal of surfaces and colloids (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a theoretical and computational approach to deal with systems that
involve a disparate range of spatio-temporal scales, such as those comprised of
colloidal particles or polymers moving in a fluidic molecular environment. Our
approach is based on a multiscale modeling that combines the slow dynamics of
the large particles with the fast dynamics of the solvent into a unique
framework. The former is numerically solved via Molecular Dynamics and the
latter via a multi-component Lattice Boltzmann. The two techniques are coupled
together to allow for a seamless exchange of information between the
descriptions. Being based on a kinetic multi-component description of the fluid
species, the scheme is flexible in modeling charge flow within complex
geometries and ranging from large to vanishing salt concentration. The details
of the scheme are presented and the method is applied to the problem of
translocation of a charged polymer through a nanopores. In the end, we discuss
the advantages and complexities of the approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09440</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Giri</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Sean W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanford</keyname><forenames>William A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Antonio R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merril</keyname><forenames>Devin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Liza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oviedo</keyname><forenames>Ron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richards</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olson</keyname><forenames>David H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaskins</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeAngelis</keyname><forenames>Freddy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henry</keyname><forenames>Asegun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Patrick E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Small-mass atomic defects enhance vibrational thermal transport at
  disordered interfaces with ultrahigh thermal boundary conductance</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The role of interfacial nonidealities and disorder on thermal transport
across interfaces is traditionally assumed to add resistance to heat transfer,
decreasing the thermal boundary conductance (TBC).$^1$ However, recent
computational works have suggested that interfacial defects can enhance this
thermal boundary conductance through emergence of unique vibrations that are
intrinsic to the material interface and defect atoms,$^{2-6}$ a finding that
contradicts traditional theory and conventional understanding. By manipulating
the local heat flux of atomic vibrations that comprise these interfacial modes,
in principle, the TBC can be increased. In this work, we provide evidence that
interfacial defects can enhance the TBC across interfaces through the emergence
of unique high frequency vibrational modes that arise from atomic mass defects
at the interface with relatively small masses. We demonstrate ultrahigh TBC at
amorphous SiOC:H/SiC:H interfaces, approaching 1 GW m$^{-2}$ K$^{-1}$, that is
further increased through the introduction of nitrogen defects. The fact that
disordered interfaces can exhibit such high conductances, which can be further
increased with additional defects offers a unique direction in controlling
interfacial thermal transport that becomes important in manipulating heat
transfer across materials with high densities of interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09445</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Alam</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Sandipan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Filtering with Poly-T Wrapped Single Wall Carbon Nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nanoscale, 2017, 9, 5155-5163</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6NR09395G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin filtering is an essential operation in spintronics that allows creation
and detection of spin polarized carriers. Transition metal ferromagnets are
used as spin filters in most cases, though their spin filtering efficiency is
only around ~50%, thereby limiting the efficiency of spintronic devices.
Recently, chiral systems such as DNA have been shown to exhibit efficient spin
filtering, a phenomenon often dubbed as &quot;chirality induced spin selectivity&quot;
(CISS). In this work, we consider single wall carbon nanotubes helically
wrapped with single stranded poly-T DNA. By magnetoresistance measurements we
show that this system exhibits significant spin polarization of ~80%, which
could be attributed to the Rashba spin-orbit interaction induced by the
inversion asymmetric helical potential of the DNA. Observed spin polarization
is larger than that reported before for d(GT)15 strands. Such systems allow
tailoring spin polarization by chemical means and also allow extremely
localized creation and detection of spin polarization without any magnetic
element and could lead to extreme miniaturization and compact integration of
spintronic devices and circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09446</id><created>2017-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kozak</keyname><forenames>Aleksander</forenames><affiliation>Wroc&#x142;aw U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Scalar-tensor gravity in the Palatini approach</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>73 pages, Master thesis, Wroc{\l}aw University. arXiv admin note:
  text overlap with arXiv:gr-qc/0403063 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main objective of this thesis is to discuss scalar-tensor theories in the
Palatini approach. Both scalar-tensor theories and Palatini formalism are means
of alternating classical theory of gravity, general relativity, in order to
account for phenomena being seemingly unexplainable on the ground of the
Einstein theory or to serve as toy models used to test limitations of the
theory in question. In the literature, both Palatini approach and scalar-tensor
theories have been widely discussed, but there are very few - if none - authors
writing about a merge of these two ideas. The present paper is a result of an
insufficient attention given to the topic of scalar-tensor theories in Palatini
formalism.
  In the course of the thesis action functional for scalar-tensor theories of
gravity will be introduced. This action functional differs significantly from
the action defined in case of scalar-tensor theories in metric approach. We aim
at analysing the theory using the language of invariants, allowing us to write
down all equations in a frame-independent manner. We discover that invariants
defined for the metric case do not always have their counterparts in Palatini
formalism. Also, two frames most frequently used in the literature are
discussed: Einstein and Jordan frame. Possible applications of the theory
developed in the first part of the thesis are presented. We show the
equivalence between $f(R)$ and scalar-tensor theories of gravity and exploit
this fact by analysing the former using methods developed for scalar-tensor
theories. We conclude the thesis with calculating the Friedmann equations for
an empty universe of vanishing spatial curvature and preparing set-up for
analysing inflationary behaviour.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09455</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Couture</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author></authors><title>Ninth Planet or Wandering Star ?</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>12 pages and 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the gravitational effects of two celestrial bodies on a typical
object of the Kuyper Belt. The first body is a kuyperian object itself with
fairly large eccentricity and perihelion but with a large mass, about 16 times
the mass of the Earth. The second body is a star whose mass is 30% - 50% of the
mass of the sun that passes by our solar system at a speed between 25 km/sec
and 100 km/sec and at a distance of closest approach between 0.05 and 0.5 light
year. As a measure of the perturbations caused by these bodies on the light
kuyperian object, we analyse its eccentricity. We find that the effects due to
the passage of the wandering star are permanent in the sense that the
eccentricity of the kuyperian object remains anomalous long after the passage
of the star. The same is true of the heavy kuyperian object: it can perturb
greatly the orbit of the lighter kuyperian object, which leads to a permanent,
anomalous eccentricity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09456</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fournier</keyname><forenames>Dani&#xe8;le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marangolo</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eddrief</keyname><forenames>Mahmoud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolesnikov</keyname><forenames>Nikolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fretigny</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Straightforward measurement of thermal properties of anisotropic
  materials: the case of Bi2Se3 single crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that by a simple two-steps measurement protocol one can extract the
thermal properties of anisotropic insulator materials. We focus on Bi2Se3
single crystal, a layered crystal with individual sheets held together by Van
der Waals force, presenting strong heat diffusion anisotropy. Since the shape
of the sample does not allow experiments in the perpendicular direction the
challenge is to measure the in plane and out of plane thermal properties by in
plane measurements. The optical properties of Bi2Se3 being known (opaque sample
for the pump and probe beams), thermoreflectance microscopy experiments can be
done on the bare substrate. In this case, the lateral heat diffusion is
governed by the in plane thermal diffusivity. A 100 nm gold layer is then
deposited on the sample. In this second experiment it is straightforward to
demonstrate that the perpendicular thermal properties of the layer rule the
lateral diffusivity. The good agreement of theoretical curves obtained by
thermal models with experimental data permit us to evaluate the thermal
conductivity coefficients of bulk Bi2Se3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09468</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Davenport</keyname><forenames>James R. A</forenames></author></authors><title>Infrared Flares from M Dwarfs: a Hinderance to Future Transiting
  Exoplanet Studies</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>2 pages, 1 figure. Accepted to Research Notes of the American
  Astronomical Society</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many current and future exoplanet missions are pushing to infrared (IR)
wavelengths where the flux contrast between the planet and star is more
favorable (Deming et al. 2009), and the impact of stellar magnetic activity is
decreased. Indeed, a recent analysis of starspots and faculae found these forms
of stellar activity do not substantially impact the transit signatures or
science potential for FGKM stars with JWST (Zellem et al. 2017). However, this
is not true in the case of flares, which I demonstrate can be a hinderance to
transit studies in this note.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09488</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Avila</keyname><forenames>Karina E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>Horacio E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vollmayr-Lee</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zippelius</keyname><forenames>Annette</forenames></author></authors><title>Slow and Long-ranged Dynamical Heterogeneities in Dissipative Fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>14 pages, 25 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2016,12, 5461-5474</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM00784H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A two-dimensional bidisperse granular fluid is shown to exhibit pronounced
long-ranged dynamical heterogeneities as dynamical arrest is approached. Here
we focus on the most direct approach to study these heterogeneities: we
identify clusters of slow particles and determine their size, $N_c$, and their
radius of gyration, $R_G$. We show that $N_c\propto R_G^{d_f}$, providing
direct evidence that the most immobile particles arrange in fractal objects
with a fractal dimension, $d_f$, that is observed to increase with packing
fraction $\phi$. The cluster size distribution obeys scaling, approaching an
algebraic decay in the limit of structural arrest, i.e., $\phi\to\phi_c$.
Alternatively, dynamical heterogeneities are analyzed via the four-point
structure factor $S_4(q,t)$ and the dynamical susceptibility $\chi_4(t)$.
$S_4(q,t)$ is shown to obey scaling in the full range of packing fractions,
$0.6\leq\phi\leq 0.805$, and to become increasingly long-ranged as
$\phi\to\phi_c$. Finite size scaling of $\chi_4(t)$ provides a consistency
check for the previously analyzed divergences of $\chi_4(t)\propto
(\phi-\phi_c)^{-\gamma_{\chi}}$ and the correlation length $\xi\propto
(\phi-\phi_c)^{-\gamma_{\xi}}$. We check the robustness of our results with
respect to our definition of mobility. The divergences and the scaling for
$\phi\to\phi_c$ suggest a non-equilibrium glass transition which seems
qualitatively independent of the coefficient of restitution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09500</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shusen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yinan</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Runyao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ying</keyname><forenames>Mingsheng</forenames></author></authors><title>$Q|SI\rangle$: A Quantum Programming Environment</title><categories>quant-ph cs.PL</categories><comments>30 pages, software available at http://www.qcompiler.com</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes a quantum programming environment, named $Q|SI\rangle$.
It is a platform embedded in the .Net language that supports quantum
programming using a quantum extension of the $\mathbf{while}$-language. The
framework of the platform includes a compiler of the quantum
$\mathbf{while}$-language and a suite of tools for simulating quantum
computation, optimizing quantum circuits, and analyzing and verifying quantum
programs. Throughout the paper, using $Q|SI\rangle$ to simulate quantum
behaviors on classical platforms with a combination of components is
demonstrated. The scalable framework allows the user to program customized
functions on the platform. The compiler works as the core of $Q|SI\rangle$
bridging the gap from quantum hardware to quantum software. The built-in
decomposition algorithms enable the universal quantum computation on the
present quantum hardware.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09509</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Hanakata</keyname><forenames>Paul Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodin</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Harold S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>David K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>A. H. Castro</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional Square Buckled Rashba Lead Chalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 96, 161401(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.161401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the lead sulphide (PbS) monolayer as a 2D semiconductor with a
large Rashba-like spin-orbit effect controlled by the out-of-plane buckling.
The buckled PbS conduction band is found to possess Rashba-like dispersion and
spin texture at the $M$ and $\Gamma$ points, with large effective Rashba
parameters of $\lambda\sim5~$eV$\AA~$ and $\lambda\sim1~$eV$~\AA$,
respectively. Using a tight-binding formalism, we show that the Rashba effect
originates from the very large spin-orbit interaction and the hopping term that
mixes the in-plane and out-of-plane $p$ orbitals of Pb and S atoms. The latter,
which depends on the buckling angle, can be controlled by applying strain to
vary the spin texture as well as the Rashba parameter at $\Gamma$ and $M$. Our
density functional theory results together with tight-binding formalism provide
a unifying framework for designing Rashba monolayers and for manipulating their
spin properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09520</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiaojie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiantao</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable absorbing boundary conditions for molecular dynamics in general
  domains</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new type of absorbing boundary conditions for molecular dynamics
simulations are presented. The exact boundary conditions for crystalline solids
with harmonic approximation are expressed as a dynamic Dirichlet- to-Neumann
(DtN) map. It connects the displacement of the atoms at the boundary to the
traction on these atoms. The DtN map is valid for a domain with general
geometry. To avoid evaluating the time convo- lution of the dynamic DtN map, we
approximate the associated kernel function by rational functions in the Laplace
domain. The parameters in the approximations are determined by interpolations.
The explicit forms of the zeroth, first, and second order approximations will
be presented. The stability of the molecular dynamics model, supplemented with
these absorbing boundary conditions is established. Two numerical simulations
are performed to demonstrate the effectiveness of the methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09525</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaskins</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, University of Virginia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kotsonis</keyname><forenames>George</forenames><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, North Carolina State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Giri</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, University of Virginia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shelton</keyname><forenames>Christopher T.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, North Carolina State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sachet</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, North Carolina State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames><affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Foley</keyname><forenames>Brian M.</forenames><affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zeyu</forenames><affiliation>Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering, Notre Dame</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ju</keyname><forenames>Shenghong</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Tokyo</affiliation><affiliation>Center for Materials Research by Information Integration, National Institute for Materials Science</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Junichiro</keyname><affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Tokyo</affiliation><affiliation>Center for Materials Research by Information Integration, National Institute for Materials Science</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goorsky</keyname><forenames>Mark S.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, University of California</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Graham</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames><affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation><affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Tengfei</forenames><affiliation>Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering, Notre Dame</affiliation><affiliation>Center for Sustainable Energy of Notre Dame</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Henry</keyname><forenames>Asegun</forenames><affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation><affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation><affiliation>Heat Lab, Georgia Institute of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Maria</keyname><forenames>Jon-Paul</forenames><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, North Carolina State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Patrick E.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, University of Virginia</affiliation><affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, University of Virginia</affiliation><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Virginia</affiliation></author></authors><title>Thermal boundary conductance across epitaxial ZnO/GaN interfaces:
  Assessment of phonon gas models and atomistic Green's function approaches for
  predicting interfacial phonon transport</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present experimental measurements of the thermal boundary conductance
(TBC) from $77 - 500$ K across isolated heteroepitaxially grown ZnO films on
GaN substrates. These data provide an assessment of the assumptions that drive
the phonon gas model-based diffuse mismatch models (DMM) and atomistic Green's
function (AGF) formalisms for predicting TBC. Our measurements, when compared
to previous experimental data, suggest that the TBC can be influenced by long
wavelength, zone center modes in a material on one side of the interface as
opposed to the &quot;vibrational mismatch&quot; concept assumed in the DMM; this
disagreement is pronounced at high temperatures. At room temperature, we
measure the ZnO/GaN TBC as $490\lbrack +150, -110\rbrack$ MW m$^{-2}$ K$^{-1}$.
The disagreement among the DMM and AGF and the experimental data these elevated
temperatures suggests a non-negligible contribution from additional modes
contributing to TBC that not accounted for in the fundamental assumptions of
these harmonic formalisms, such as inelastic scattering. Given the high quality
of these ZnO/GaN interface, these results provide an invaluable critical and
quantitive assessment of the accuracy of assumptions in the current state of
the art of computational approaches for predicting the phonon TBC across
interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09527</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>SDSS J090152.05+624342.6: A New &quot;Overlapping-Trough&quot; FeLoBAL Quasar At
  Z$\sim2$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, proceedings of the conference &quot;QUASARS at all
  cosmic epochs&quot;, accepted for publication on Frontiers in Astronomy and Space
  Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We here report an identification of SDSS J090152.04+624342.6 as a new
&quot;overlapping-trough&quot; iron low-ionization broad absorption line quasar at
redshift of $z\sim2.1$. No strong variation of the broad absorption lines can
be revealed through the two spectra taken by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey with
a time interval of $\sim6$yr. Further optical and infrared spectroscopic study
on this object is suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09534</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jiangrong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jiangxing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Baochang</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice Boltzmann modeling of wall-bounded ternary fluid flows</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>32 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a wetting boundary scheme used to describe the interactions
among ternary fluids and solid is proposed in the framework of the lattice
Boltzmann method. This scheme for three-phase fluids can preserve the reduction
consistency property with the diphasic situation such that it could give
physically relevant results. Combining this wetting boundary scheme and the
lattice Boltzmann (LB) ternary fluid model based on the multicomponent
phase-field theory, we simulated several ternary fluid flow problems involving
solid substrate, including the spreading of binary drops on the substrate, the
spreading of a compound drop on the substrate, and the shear of a compound
liquid drop on the substrate. The numerical results are found to be good
agreement with the analytical solutions or some available results. Finally, as
an application, we use the LB model coupled with the present wetting boundary
scheme to numerically investigate the impact of a compound drop on a solid
circular cylinder. It is found that the dynamics of a compound drop can be
remarkably influenced by the wettability of the solid surface and the
dimensionless Weber number.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09548</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Vishal</keyname><forenames>Gajjar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the nulling, drifting, and their interactions in PSRs J1741-0840 and
  J1840-0840</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>16 pages, 14 figures, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report detailed investigation of nulling and drifting behavior of two
pulsars PSRs J1741-0840 and J1840-0840 observed from the Giant Meterwave Radio
Telescope at 625 MHz. PSR J1741-840 was found to show nulling fraction (NF) of
around 30(5)% while PSR J1840-0840 was shown to have NF of around 50(6)%. We
measured drifting behavior from different profile components in PSR J1840-0840
for the first time with the leading component showing drifting with 13.5(0.7)
periods while the weak trailing component showed drifting of around 18(1)
periods. Large nulling do hamper accuracy of these quantities derived using
standard Fourier techniques. A more accurate comparison was drawn from
driftband slopes, measured after sub-pulse modeling. These measurements
revealed interesting sporadic and irregular drifting behavior in both pulsars.
We conclude that the previously reported different drifting periodicities in
the trailing component of PSR J1741-0840 is likely due to the spread in these
driftband slopes. We also find that both components of PSR J1840-0840 show
similar driftband slopes within the uncertainties. Unique nulling-drifting
interaction is identified in PSR J1840-0840 where, in most occasions, the
pulsar tends to start nulling after what appears to be an end of a driftband.
Similarly, when the pulsar switches back to an emission phase, in most
occasions it starts at the beginning of a new driftband in both components.
Such behaviors have not been detected in any other pulsars to our knowledge. We
also found that PSR J1741-0840 seems to have no memory of its previous burst
phase while PSR J1840-0840 clearly exhibits memory of its previous state even
after longer nulls for both components. We discuss possible explanations for
these intriguing nulling-drifting interactions seen in both pulsars based on
various pulsar nulling models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09558</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsarev</keyname><forenames>Sergey P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanenko</keyname><forenames>Vitaly A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On weakly commutative triples of partial differential operators</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>13 pages of text</comments><msc-class>35Q53, 37K10, 12E15</msc-class><journal-ref>published in: Siberian Electronic Mathematical Reports, Volume 14
  (2017), p.~1050-1063 http://semr.math.nsc.ru</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate algebraic properties of weakly commutative triples, appearing
in the theory of integrable nonlinear partial differential equations. Algebraic
technique of skew fields of formal pseudodifferential operators as well as skew
Ore fields of fractions are applied to this problem, relating weakly
commutative triples to commuting elements of skew Ore field of formal fractions
of ordinary differential operators. A version of Burchnall-Chaundy theorem for
weakly commutative triples is proved by algebraic means avoiding analytical
complications typical for its proofs known in the theory of integrable
equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09563</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Tamisra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>Constantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lessnich</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Silica Surfaces on the Structure and Dynamics of Room
  Temperature Ionic Liquids: A Molecular Dynamics Simulation Study</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Room temperature ionic liquids (ILs) at solid surfaces have been recognized
for their significant interfacial properties in electrochemical and electronic
devices. To ascertain the interface effects, we investigate dynamical and
structural properties of two ILs in nanoscale confinement at various
temperatures. Specifically, we perform all-atom molecular dynamics simulations
for ILs composed of 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium cations and hexafluorophosphate
([Bmim][PF6]) or tetrafluoroborate ([Bmim][BF4]) anions sandwiched between
amorphous silica slabs. Density profiles of the ionic species across the slit
reveal that [PF6] and [BF4] anions tend to stay closer to the slab wall than
[Bmim] cations resulting in a bi-layered arrangement in the interfacial region.
For the cations, we observe a preferred orientation at the surface with the
methyl groups pointing towards the wall and the butyl tails projected inwards.
Mean square displacements and incoherent scattering function reveal slowed and
heterogeneous dynamics of all ionic species in the slit pore. In particular,
spatially resolved analyses show that the structural relaxation times increase
by about two orders of magnitude when approaching the silica surfaces, an
effect to be considered when designing applications. The altered structural and
dynamical features of the confined ILs can be related to an existence of
preferred sites for the anions on the amorphous silica surfaces. Detailed
analyses of relations between the broadly distributed site and surface
properties show that particularly stable anion sites result when triangular
arrangements of silanol groups enable multiple hydrogen bonds with the various
fluorine atoms of a given anion, elucidating an important trapping mechanism at
the silica surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09573</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ludwig</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishop</keyname><forenames>Shawn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egli</keyname><forenames>Ramon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernenko</keyname><forenames>Valentyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deneva</keyname><forenames>Boyana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faestermann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Famulok</keyname><forenames>Nicolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fimiani</keyname><forenames>Leticia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Guzman</keyname><forenames>Jose Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hain</keyname><forenames>Karin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korschinek</keyname><forenames>Gunther</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanzlik</keyname><forenames>Marianne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merchel</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rugel</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Time resolved 2 million year old supernova activity discovered in
  Earth's microfossil record</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Figures from the Supplementary Information are not included due to
  file size restrictions. Download the, now open access, original article for
  those details (see doi)</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academies of Science, vol. 113 (2016)
  pg. 9232-9237</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1601040113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive stars, which terminate their evolution as core collapse supernovae,
are theoretically predicted to eject more than 1E-5 solar masses of the
radioisotope 60Fe. If such an event occurs sufficiently close to our solar
system, traces of the supernova debris could be deposited on Earth. Herein, we
report a time resolved 60Fe signal residing, at least partially, in a biogenic
reservoir. Using accelerator mass spectrometry, this signal was found through
the direct detection of live 60Fe atoms contained within secondary iron oxides,
among which are magnetofossils, the fossilized chains of magnetite crystals
produced by magnetotactic bacteria. The magnetofossils were chemically
extracted from two Pacific Ocean sediment drill cores. Our results show that
the 60Fe signal onset occurs around 2.6 Ma to 2.8 Ma, near the lower
Pleistocene boundary, terminates around 1.7 Ma, and peaks at about 2.2 Ma.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09581</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Babar</keyname><forenames>Gulmina Zaman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babar</keyname><forenames>Adil Zaman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Yen-Kheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Periodic orbits around a spherically symmetric naked singularity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D, 96 084052 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.084052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The motion of time-like test particles in the Fisher/Janis-Newman-Winicour
(F/JNW) spacetime is studied with the Hamiltonian formulation of the geodesic
equations. The spacetime is characterised by its mass parameter $r_g$ and
scalar field parameter $\nu$. The innermost bound and stable circular orbits
are calculated and the effective potential is analysed. Consistent with
numerical results in earlier literature, for $\nu&lt;1/2$, particles with non-zero
angular momentum encounter an infinite potential barrier, preventing them from
reaching the naked singularity at $r=r_g$. Periodic orbits in the spacetime are
also obtained. Compared to the periodic orbits around the Schwarzschild black
hole, it is found that typically lower energies are required for the same
orbits in the F/JNW spacetime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09596</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Zakharov</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pismen</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Active textiles with Janus fibres</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe reshaping of active textiles actuated by bending of Janus fibres
comprising both active and passive components. A great variety of shapes,
determined by minimising the overall energy of the fabric, can be produced by
varying bending directions determined by the orientation of Janus fibres. Under
certain conditions, alternative equilibrium states, one absolutely stable and
the other metastable coexist, and their relative energy may flip its sign as
system parameters, such as the extension upon actuation, change. A snap-through
reshaping in a specially structured textile reproduces the Venus flytrap
effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09604</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kiefer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halbwachs</keyname><forenames>J. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebreton</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soubiran</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arenou</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pourbaix</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Famaey</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillout</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ibata</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazeh</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Masses of the components of SB2 binaries observed with Gaia. IV.
  Accurate SB2 orbits for 14 binaries, and masses of 3 binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, 8 tables</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2794</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The orbital motion of non-contact double-lined spectroscopic binaries (SB2),
with periods of a few tens of days to several years, holds unique accurate
informations on individual stellar masses, that only long-term monitoring can
unlock. The combination of radial velocity measurements from high-resolution
spectrographs and astrometric measurements from high-precision interferometers
allows the derivation of SB2 components masses down to the percent precision.
Since 2010, we observed a large sample of SB2 with the SOPHIE spectrograph at
the Observatoire de Haute-Provence, aiming at the derivation of orbital
elements with sufficient accuracy to obtain masses of components with relative
errors as low as 1$\%$ when the astrometric measurements of the Gaia satellite
will be taken into account. In this paper we present the results from six years
of observations of 14 SB2 systems with periods ranging from 33 to 4185 days.
Using the TODMOR algorithm we computed radial velocities from the spectra, and
then derived the orbital elements of these binary systems. The minimum masses
of the 28 stellar components are then obtained with a sample average accuracy
of 1.0$\pm$0.2$\,\%$. Combining the radial velocities with existing
interferometric measurements, we derived the masses of the primary and
secondary components of HIP 61100, HIP 95995 and HIP 101382 with relative
errors for components (A,B) of respectively (2.0, 1.7)$\,\%$, (3.7, 3.7)$\,\%$,
and (0.2, 0.1)$\,\%$. Using the Cesam2k stellar evolution code, we could
constrain the initial He-abundance, age and metallicity for HIP 61100 and HIP
95995.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09625</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>Friedrich Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiedler</keyname><forenames>Johnnes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buhmann</keyname><forenames>Stefan Yoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Correct zero-point energy-momentum of the electromagnetic field in media
  for studying the Casimir force</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the long-standing controversy regarding the correct description of
the electromagnetic energy-momentum tensor in media and its consequences for
the Casimir force. The latter being due to the zero-point momentum of the
electromagnetic field, competing approaches based on the Abraham or Maxwell
stress tensor lead to different predictions. We consider the test scenario of
two colloidal spherical particles submerged in a dielectric medium and use
three criteria to distinguish the two approaches: we show that the Abraham
stress tensor, and not the Maxwell stress tensor, leads to a Casimir force that
is form-equivalent to Casimir-Polder and van der Waals forces, obeys duality as
a fundamental symmetry and is consistent with microscopic many-body
calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09631</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Vairo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Quarkonium hybrids</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures, presented at &quot;The European Physical Society
  Conference on High Energy Physics - EPS-HEP 2017&quot; (5 - 12 July 2017, Venice,
  Italy)</comments><report-no>TUM-EFT 103/17</report-no><journal-ref>PoS EPS-HEP2017 (2017) 416</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the quarkonium hybrid spectrum from the perspective of
nonrelativistic effective field theories combined with lattice QCD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09634</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Charmonium production in p-Pb collisions with ALICE at the LHC</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, EPS-HEP 2017, European Physical Society
  conference on High Energy Physics, Venice, Italy, 5-12 July 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The suppression of quarkonium production with respect to pp collisions is one
of the most distinctive signatures of the formation of quark-gluon plasma
(QGP), a hot nuclear medium created in ultrarelativistic heavy-ion collisions.
However, the suppression of heavy quarkonium production with respect to pp
collisions can also take place in p-A collisions, where QGP is not expected to
be created and only cold nuclear matter (CNM) effects, such as nuclear
absorption, parton shadowing and parton energy loss in initial and final states
occur. The study of p-A collisions is therefore important to disentangle the
effects of QGP from the CNM ones, and to provide essential input to understand
the nucleus-nucleus collisions.
  The ALICE Collaboration at the LHC has studied inclusive J/$\psi$ production,
in the dimuon decay channel, at forward rapidity (2.03 $&lt;$ $y_{\rm cms}$ $&lt;$
3.53) and backward rapidity ($-$4.46 $&lt;$ $y_{\rm cms}$ $&lt;$ $-$2.96) in p-Pb
collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}} = 8.16$ TeV with the Muon Spectrometer. In
this contribution, we present the measurement of the nuclear modification
factor of inclusive J/$\psi$ as a function of the centrality and we show the
comparison of this result with the one at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}} = 5.02$ TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09637</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Tikhonov</keyname><forenames>Aleksey M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermotropic Phase Transition in an Adsorbed Melissic Acid Film at the
  n-Hexane - Water Interface</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP Lett. 105, 775 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S002136401712013X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A reversible thermotropic phase transition in an adsorption melissic acid
film at the interface between n-hexane and an aqueous solution of potassium
hydroxide (pH=10) is investigated by X-ray reflectometry and diffuse scattering
using synchrotron radiation. The experimental data indicate that the interface
&quot;freezing&quot; transition is accompanied not only by the crystallization of the
Gibbs monolayer but also by the formation of a planar smectic structure in the
~300-Angstrom-thick adsorption film; this structure is formed by
~50-Angstrom-thick layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09641</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rath</keyname><forenames>Pranati K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samal</keyname><forenames>Pramoda Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing isotropy of cosmos with WMAP and PLANCK data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 Pages, 0 Figures, 4 Tables; Published in 2015; Accepted version
  added to arXiv now</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A (2015) 30, 1550131</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231550131X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, there have been a large number of studies which support
violation of statistical isotropy. Meanwhile, there are some studies which also
found inconsistency. We use the power tensor method defined earlier in the
literature to study the new CMBR data. The orientation of these three
orthogonal vectors, as well as the power associated with each vector, contains
information about possible violation of statistical isotropy. This information
is encoded in two entropy measures, the power-entropy and alignment- entropy.
We apply this method to WMAP 9-year and PLANCK data. Here, we also revisit the
statistics to test high-l anomaly reported in our earlier paper and find that
the high degree of isotropy seen in earlier WMAP 5-year data is absent in the
revised WMAP 9-year data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09643</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Feldman</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-implicit direct forcing immersed boundary method for incompressible
  viscous thermal flow problems: a Schur complement approach</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An extended immersed boundary method utilizing a semi-implicit direct forcing
approach for the simulation of confined incompressible viscous thermal flow
problems is presented. The method utilizes a Schur complement approach to
enforce the kinematic constraints of no-slip and the corresponding thermal
boundary conditions for immersed surfaces. The developed methodology can be
straightforwardly adapted to any existing incompressible time marching solver
based on a segregated pressure-velocity coupling. The method accurately meets
the thermal and the no-slip boundary conditions on the surfaces of immersed
bodies for the entire range of Rayleigh numbers $10^3\leqslant
Ra\leqslant10^6$. Strategies for further increasing the computational
efficiency of the developed approach are discussed. The method has been
extensively verified by applying it for the simulation of a number of
representative fully 3D confined natural convection steady and periodic flows.
Complex dynamic phenomena typical of this kind of flow including vortical
structures and convection cells and instability characteristics, were simulated
and visualized and the results were found to compare favorably with results
known from literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09659</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhukov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pogosov</keyname><forenames>W. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lozovik</keyname><forenames>Yu. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling dynamics of entangled physical systems with superconducting
  quantum computer</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We implement several quantum algorithms in real five-qubit superconducting
quantum processor IBMqx4 to perform quantum computation of the dynamics of
spin-1/2 particles interacting directly and indirectly through the boson field.
Particularly, we focus on effects arising due to the presence of entanglement
in the initial state of the system. The dynamics is implemented in a digital
way using Trotter expansion of evolution operator. Our results demonstrate that
dynamics in our modeling based on real device is governed by quantum
interference effects being highly sensitive to phase parameters of the initial
state. We also discuss limitations of our approach due to the device
imperfection as well as possible scaling towards larger systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09661</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Arakelyan</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merino</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shabelski</keyname><forenames>Yu. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuvaev</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inelastic shadowing of secondary pi+-, K+-, p, and bar(p) produced in
  p+Pb collisions at LHC energy</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the Proceedings of the Low-x Meeting 2017, ed by C.
  Royon et al., Bisceglie, near Bari (Italy), June 13th-18th, 2017 (6 pages and
  1 table)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inclusive spectra of secondaries produced in soft (minimum-bias) p+Pb
collisions at LHC energy are calculated in the frame of the Quark-Gluon String
Model, by including the inelastic screening corrections (percolation effects).
These effects are expected to be quite large at the very high energies, and
they should drive down the spectra in the midrapidity region more than 2 times,
at sqrt(sNN)=5 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09665</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bernal</keyname><forenames>Maria del Mar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tortello</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colonnaa</keyname><forenames>Samuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saracco</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fina</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermally and Electrically Conductive Nanopapers from Reduced Graphene
  Oxide: effect of nanoflakes thermal annealing on the film structure and
  properties</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, we report a different strategy to prepare graphene nanopapers
from direct vacuum filtration. Instead of the conventional method, i.e. thermal
annealing nanopapers at extremely high temperatures prepared from graphene
oxide (GO) or partially reduced GO, we fabricate our graphene nanopapers
directly from suspensions of fully reduced graphene oxide (RGO), obtained after
RGO and thermally annealing at 1700 {\deg}C in vacuum. By using this approach,
we studied the effect of thermal annealing on the physical properties of the
macroscopic graphene-based papers. Indeed, we demonstrated that the enhancement
of the thermal and electrical properties of graphene nanopapers prepared from
annealed RGO is strongly influenced by the absence of oxygen functionalities
and the morphology of the nanoflakes. Hence, our methodology can be considered
as a valid alternative to the classical approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09683</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Baglio</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiland</keyname><forenames>Cedric</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of heavy sterile neutrinos on the triple Higgs coupling</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6+1 pages, 3 figures, proceedings of EPS-HEP 2017, the European
  Physical Society conference on High Energy Physics, 5-12 July 2017, Venice,
  Italy</comments><report-no>IPPP/17/77</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New physics beyond the Standard Model is required to give mass to the light
neutrinos. One of the simplest ideas is to introduce new heavy, gauge singlet
fermions that play the role of right-handed neutrinos in a seesaw mechanism.
They could have large Yukawa couplings to the Higgs boson, affecting the Higgs
couplings and in particular the triple Higgs coupling $\lambda_{HHH}^{}$, the
measure of which is one of the major goals of the LHC and of future colliders.
We present a study of the impact of these heavy neutrinos on $\lambda_{HHH}^{}$
at the one-loop level, first in a simplified 3+1 model with one heavy Dirac
neutrino and then in the inverse seesaw model. Taking into account all possible
experimental constraints, we find that sizeable deviations of the order of 35%
are possible, large enough to be detected at future colliders, making the
triple Higgs coupling a new, viable observable to constrain neutrino mass
models. The effects are generic and are expected in any new physics model
including TeV-scale fermions with large Yukawa couplings to the Higgs boson,
such as those using the neutrino portal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09684</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Phan Th&#xe0;nh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Napi&#xf3;rkowski</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author></authors><title>Norm approximation for many-body quantum dynamics: focusing case in low
  dimensions</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math.AP math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the norm approximation to the Schr\&quot;odinger dynamics of $N$ bosons
in $\mathbb{R}^d$ ($d=1,2$) with an interaction potential of the form
$N^{d\beta-1}w(N^{\beta}(x-y))$. Here we are interested in the focusing case
$w\le 0$. Assuming that there is complete Bose-Einstein condensation in the
initial state, we show that in the large $N$ limit, the evolution of the
condensate is effectively described by a nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation and
the evolution of the fluctuations around the condensate is governed by a
quadratic Hamiltonian, resulting from Bogoliubov approximation. Our result
holds true for all $\beta&gt;0$ when $d=1$ and for all $0&lt;\beta&lt;1$ when $d=2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09690</id><created>2017-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triloki</keyname></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray diffraction line profile analysis of KBr thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, the microcrystalline characteristics of KBr thin films
have been investigated by evaluating the breadth of diffraction peak. The
Williamson-Hall, the Size-Strain Plot and the single line Voigt methods are
employed to deconvolute the finite crystallite size and microstrain
contribution from the broaden X-ray profile. The texture coefficient and
dislocation density have been determined along each diffraction peak. Other
relevant physical parameters such as stress, Young's modulus and energy density
are also estimated using Uniform Stress-Deformation and Uniform Deformation
Energy Density approximation of Williamson-Hall method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09703</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Azadi</keyname><forenames>Sam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Ranber</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hne</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Quantum Effects Induce Metallization of Dense Solid Molecular
  Hydrogen</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Journal of Computational Chemistry. arXiv
  admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1608.00754</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an accurate computational study of the electronic structure and
lattice dynamics of solid molecular hydrogen at high pressure. The band-gap
energies of the $C2/c$, $Pc$, and $P6_3/m$ structures at pressures of 250, 300,
and 350 GPa are calculated using the diffusion quantum Monte Carlo (DMC)
method. The atomic configurations are obtained from ab-initio path-integral
molecular dynamics (PIMD) simulations at 300 K and 300 GPa to investigate the
impact of zero-point energy and temperature-induced motion of the protons
including anharmonic effects. We find that finite temperature and nuclear
quantum effects reduce the band-gaps substantially, leading to metallization of
the $C2/c$ and $Pc$ phases via band overlap; the effect on the band-gap of the
$P6_3/m$ structure is less pronounced. Our combined DMC-PIMD simulations
predict that there are no excitonic or quasiparticle energy gaps for the $C2/c$
and $Pc$ phases at 300 GPa and 300 K. Our results also indicate a strong
correlation between the band-gap energy and vibron modes. This strong coupling
induces a band-gap reduction of more than 2.46 eV in high-pressure solid
molecular hydrogen. Comparing our DMC-PIMD with experimental results available,
we conclude that none of the structures proposed is a good candidate for phases
III and IV of solid hydrogen.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09709</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Kashyap</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Surajit</forenames></author></authors><title>PULSEDYN - A dynamical simulation tool for studying strongly nonlinear
  chains</title><categories>physics.comp-ph nlin.PS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce PULSEDYN, a particle dynamics program in $C++$, to solve
many-body nonlinear systems in one dimension. PULSEDYN is designed to make
computing accessible to non-specialists in the field of nonlinear dynamics of
many-body systems and to ensure transparency and easy benchmarking of numerical
results for an integrable model (Toda chain) and three non-integrable models
(Fermi-Pasta-Ulam-Tsingou, Morse and Lennard-Jones). To achieve the latter, we
have made our code open source and free to distribute. We examine (i) soliton
propagation and two-soliton collision in the Toda system, (ii) the recurrence
phenomenon in the Fermi-Pasta-Ulam-Tsingou system and the decay of a single
localized nonlinear excitation in the same system through quasi-equilibrium to
an equipartitioned state, and SW propagation in chains with (iii) Morse and
(iv) Lennard-Jones potentials. We recover well known results from theory and
other numerical results in the literature. We have obtained these results by
setting up a parameter file interface which allows the code to be used as a
black box. Therefore, we anticipate that the code would prove useful to
students and non-specialists. At the same time, PULSEDYN provides
scientifically accurate simulations thus making the study of rich dynamical
processes broadly accessible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09742</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nyffeler</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Hadronic light-by-light scattering in the muon g-2</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure, contribution to the proceedings of the
  International Workshop on e+e- collisions from Phi to Psi 2017, Mainz,
  Germany</comments><report-no>MITP/17-074</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We briefly review the current status of the hadronic light-by-light
scattering contribution to the anomalous magnetic moment of the muon. Based on
various model calculations in the literature, we obtain the estimate
a_{mu}^{HLbL} = (102 \pm 39) x 10^{-11}. Recent developments including more
model-independent approaches using dispersion relations and lattice QCD, that
could lead to a more reliable estimate, are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09777</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kachakhidze</keyname><forenames>Manana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kachakhidze-Murphy</keyname><forenames>Nino</forenames></author></authors><title>Possibility of using of the measured frequency f instead of {\omega}
  self-generated frequency</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><msc-class>86A15</msc-class><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using f frequency instead of {\omega} frequency for earthquake magnitude
computing is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09778</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Fernandez-Acebal</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plenio</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensing phase-transitions via nitrogen-vacancy centers in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra-thin layers of liquids on a surface behave differently from bulk
liquids due to liquid-surface interactions. Some examples are significant
changes in diffusion properties and the temperature at which the liquid-solid
phase transition takes place. Indeed, molecular dynamics simulations suggest
that thin layers of water on a diamond surface may remain solid even well above
room temperature. However, because of the small volumes that are involved, it
is exceedingly difficult to examine these phenomena experimentally with current
technologies. In this context, shallow NV centers promise a highly sensitive
tool for the investigation of magnetic signals emanating from liquids and
solids that are deposited on the surface of a diamond. Moreover, NV centers are
non-invasive sensors with extraordinary performance even at room-temperature.
To that end, we present here a theoretical work, complemented with numerical
evidence based on bosonization techniques, that predicts the measurable signal
from a single NV center when interacting with large spin baths in different
configurations. We therefore propose single NV centers as sensors capable to
resolve structural water features at the nanoscale and even sensitive to phase
transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09799</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Riesch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jirauschek</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical Method for the Maxwell-Liouville-von Neumann Equations using
  Efficient Matrix Exponential Computations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel method to solve the Maxwell-Liouville-von Neumann (MLN)
equations in an accurate and efficient way without invoking the rotating wave
approximation (RWA). The method is a combination of two established concepts,
namely the operator splitting method as well as the adjoint representation of
the Lie algebra SU(N) (or pseudospin representation). The former concept
ensures the accuracy of the approach, but is computationally expensive. The
latter concept provides an efficient representation of the problem and two
optimization possibilities. We have implemented and verified both optimization
approaches and demonstrate that substantial speedup can be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09800</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Belyaeva</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parnovsky</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Correction of the orbital mass of double galaxies estimation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain a more accurate statistical estimation of the mass of double
galaxies moving in circular orbits, including confidence intervals for
different confidence levels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09817</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Avil&#xe9;s-Casco</keyname><forenames>A. Vaquero</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeTar</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>El-Khadra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kronfeld</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laiho</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Water</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\overline{B}\rightarrow D^\ast\ell\overline{\nu}$ at non-zero recoil</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, Proceedings of the talk presented at the 35th
  International Symposium on Lattice Field Theory (Lattice2017), Granada, Spain</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present preliminary results from our analysis of the form factors for the
$\overline{B}\rightarrow D^\ast\ell\overline{\nu}$ decay at non-zero recoil.
Our analysis includes 15 MILC asqtad ensembles with $N_f=2+1$ flavors of sea
quarks and lattice spacings ranging from $a\approx 0.15$ fm down to $0.045$ fm.
The valence light quarks employ the asqtad action, whereas the heavy quarks are
treated using the Fermilab action. We conclude with a discussion of future
plans and phenomenological implications. When combined with experimental
measurements of the decay rate, our calculation will enable a determination of
the CKM matrix element $|V_{cb}|$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09823</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bodepudi</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Sandipan</forenames></author></authors><title>Angle Dependent Interlayer Magnetoresistance (ILMR) in Multilayer
  Graphene Stacks</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 118, 164303 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4934642</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interlayer magnetoresistance (ILMR) effect is explored in a vertical stack of
weakly coupled multilayer graphene as grown by chemical vapor deposition (CVD).
This effect has been characterized as a function of temperature and tilt angle
of the magnetic field with respect to the interlayer current. To our knowledge,
this is the first experimental report on angle dependent ILMR effect in
graphitic systems. Our data agrees qualitatively with the existing theories of
ILMR in multilayer massless Dirac Fermion systems. However, a sharper change in
ILMR has been observed as the tilt angle of the magnetic field is varied. A
physical explanation of this effect is proposed, which is consistent with our
experimental scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09832</id><created>2017-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Xianran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective chemical potential for non-equilibrium systems and its
  application to molecular beam epitaxy of Bi2Se3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First-principles studies often rely on the assumption of equilibrium, which
can be a poor approximation, e.g., for growth. Here, an effective chemical
potential method for non-equilibrium systems is developed. A salient feature of
the theory is that it maintains the equilibrium limits as the correct limit. In
application to molecular beam epitaxy, rate equations are solved for the
concentrations of small clusters, which serve as feedstock for growth. We find
that the effective chemical potential is determined by the most probable,
rather than by the lowest-energy, cluster. In the case of Bi2Se3, the chemical
potential is found to be highly supersaturated, leading to a high nucleus
concentration in agreement with experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
