<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:57:06Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-10-26" from="2017-10-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0709.1747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0709.1747</id><created>2007-09-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Naraigh</keyname><forenames>Lennon O</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiffeault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounds on the mixing enhancement for a stirred binary fluid</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>20 pages, 16 figures. RevTex4 class</comments><journal-ref>Physica D 237 (21), 2673-2684 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physd.2008.04.012</doi><abstract>  The Cahn-Hilliard equation describes phase separation in binary liquids. Here
we study this equation with spatially-varying sources and stirring, or
advection. We specialize to symmetric mixtures and time-independent sources and
discuss stirring strategies that homogenize the binary fluid. By measuring
fluctuations of the composition away from its mean value, we quantify the
amount of homogenization achievable. We find upper and lower bounds on our
measure of homogenization using only the Cahn-Hilliard equation and the
incompressibility of the advecting flow. We compare these theoretical bounds
with numerical simulations for two model flows: the constant flow, and the
random-phase sine flow. Using the sine flow as an example, we show how our
bounds on composition fluctuations provide a measure of the effectiveness of a
given stirring protocol in homogenizing a phase-separating binary fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.3422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.3422</id><created>2011-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Garriga</keyname><forenames>Jaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shlaer</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilenkin</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Minkowski vacua can be metastable</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1111 (2011) 035</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2011/11/035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the recent suggestion that a Minkowski vacuum is either
absolutely stable, or it has a divergent decay rate and thus fails to have a
locally Minkowski description. The divergence comes from boost integration over
momenta of the vacuum bubbles. We point out that a prototypical example of
false-vacuum decay is pair production in a uniform electric field, so if the
argument leading to the divergence is correct, it should apply to this case as
well. We provide evidence that no catastrophic vacuum instability occurs in a
constant electric field, indicating that the argument cannot be right. Instead,
we argue that the boost integration that leads to the divergence is
unnecessary: when all possible fluctuations of the vacuum bubble are included,
the quantum state of the bubble is invariant under Lorentz boosts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.1468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.1468</id><created>2013-05-07</created><updated>2017-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Assimos</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>T. R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreiro</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaz</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otoya</keyname><forenames>V. J. Vasquez</forenames></author></authors><title>From $SL(5,\mathbb{R})$ Yang-Mills theory to induced gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pp. 3 figures. Title changed. Text with several changes. Latest
  version accepted in the IJMPD</comments><journal-ref>Int.J.Mod.Phys. D26 (2017) no.08, 1750087</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817500870</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From pure Yang-Mills action for the $SL(5,\mathbb{R})$ group in four
Euclidean dimensions we obtain a gravity theory in the first order formalism.
Besides the Einstein-Hilbert term, the effective gravity has a cosmological
constant term, a curvature squared term, a torsion squared term and a matter
sector. To obtain such geometrodynamical theory, asymptotic freedom and the
Gribov parameter (soft BRST symmetry breaking) are crucial. Particularly,
Newton and cosmological constant are related to these parameters and they also
run as functions of the energy scale. One-loop computations are performed and
the results are interpreted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.4534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.4534</id><created>2013-10-16</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Ronde</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Causality and the Modeling of the Measurement Process in Quantum Theory</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we provide a general account of the causal models which attempt
to provide a solution to the famous measurement problem of Quantum Mechanics
(QM). We will argue that --leaving aside instrumentalism which restricts the
physical meaning of QM to the algorithmic prediction of measurement outcomes--
the many interpretations which can be found in the literature can be
distinguished through the way they model the measurement process, either in
terms of the efficient cause or in terms of the final cause. We will discuss
and analyze why both, 'final cause' and 'efficient cause' models, face severe
difficulties to solve the measurement problem. In contradistinction to these
schemes we will present a new model based on the immanent cause which, we will
argue, provides an intuitive understanding of the measurement process in QM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.0873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.0873</id><created>2014-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Lahrz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemeshko</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sengstock</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathey</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting quadrupole interactions in ultracold Fermi gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 89, 043616 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.89.043616</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose to detect quadrupole interactions of neutral ultra-cold atoms via
their induced mean-field shift. We consider a Mott insulator state of
spin-polarized atoms in a two-dimensional optical square lattice. The
quadrupole moments of the atoms are aligned by an external magnetic field. As
the alignment angle is varied, the mean-field shift shows a characteristic
angular dependence, which constitutes the defining signature of the quadrupole
interaction. For the $^{3}P_{2}$ states of Yb and Sr atoms, we find a frequency
shift of the order of tens of Hertz, which can be realistically detected in
experiment with current technology. We compare our results to the mean-field
shift of a spin-polarized quasi-2D Fermi gas in continuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.2944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.2944</id><created>2014-02-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikuta</keyname><forenames>Rikizo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Toshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasui</keyname><forenames>Shuto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miki</keyname><forenames>Shigehito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>Taro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terai</keyname><forenames>Hirotaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>Mikio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koashi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Masahide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>A low-noise frequency down-conversion to the telecommunication band for
  a quantum communication based on NV centers in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 22, 11205 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.22.011205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a low-noise frequency down-conversion of photons at 637 nm to
the telecommunication band at 1587 nm by the difference frequency generation in
a periodically-poled lithium niobate. An internal conversion efficiency of the
converter is estimated to be 0.44 at the maximum which is achieved by a pump
power of 430 mW, whereas a rate of internal background photons caused by the
strong cw pump laser is estimated to be 9 kHz/mW within a bandwidth of about 1
nm. By using the experimental values related to the intrinsic property of the
converter, and using the intensity correlation and the average photon number of
a 637-nm input light pulse, we derive the intensity correlation of a converted
telecom light pulse. Then we discuss feasibility of a single-photon frequency
conversion to the telecommunication band for a long-distance quantum
communication based on NV centers in diamond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.8071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.8071</id><created>2014-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Kyuregyan</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Picosecond switching of high voltage reverse-biased p+-n-n+-structures
  into conductive state by pulsed lighting</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, in Russian</comments><doi>10.1134/S1063782614120124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An analytical theory of high voltage reverse-biased p+-n-n+-structures
picosecond switching into conducting state by pulsed lighting has been
developed and a numerical simulation of this process has been performed.
Combining the results of theory and simulation allowed us to obtain a simple
relation between the parameters of structure, light pulse, external circuit and
main characteristics of the process - the load current pulse amplitude and
duration of switching process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.4781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.4781</id><created>2014-08-20</created><updated>2015-08-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thiffeault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>Distribution of particle displacements due to swimming microorganisms</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math.PR physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>23 pages, 16 figures. RevTeX 4-1 style. Fixed reference</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 92, 023023 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.92.023023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The experiments of Leptos et al. [Phys. Rev. Lett. 103, 198103 (2009)] show
that the displacements of small particles affected by swimming microorganisms
achieve a non-Gaussian distribution, which nevertheless scales diffusively --
the 'diffusive scaling.' We use a simple model where the particles undergo
repeated 'kicks' due to the swimmers to explain the shape of the distribution
as a function of the volume fraction of swimmers. The net displacement is
determined by the inverse Fourier transform of a single-swimmer characteristic
function. The only adjustable parameter is the strength of the stresslet term
in our spherical squirmer model. We give a criterion for convergence to a
Gaussian distribution in terms of moments of the drift function, and show that
the experimentally-observed diffusive scaling is a transient related to the
slow crossover of the fourth moment from a ballistic to a linear regime with
path length. We also present a simple model, with logarithmic drift
function,that can be solved analytically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.01478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.01478</id><created>2015-02-05</created><updated>2016-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spagnolie</keyname><forenames>Saverio E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahl</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukasik</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiffeault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>Microorganism Billiards</title><categories>nlin.CD physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>29 pages, 17 figures. Elsevier style. Final published version</comments><journal-ref>Physica D 341, 33-44 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physd.2016.09.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments and numerical simulations have shown that certain types of
microorganisms &quot;reflect&quot; off of a flat surface at a critical angle of
departure, independent of the angle of incidence. The nature of the reflection
may be active (cell and flagellar contact with the surface) or passive
(hydrodynamic) interactions. We explore the billiard-like motion of a body with
this empirical reflection law inside a regular polygon and show that the
dynamics can settle on a stable periodic orbit or can be chaotic, depending on
the swimmer's departure angle and the domain geometry. The dynamics are often
found to be robust to the introduction of weak random fluctuations. The
Lyapunov exponent of swimmer trajectories can be positive or negative, can have
extremal values, and can have discontinuities depending on the degree of the
polygon. A passive sorting device is proposed that traps swimmers of different
departure angles into separate bins. We also study the external problem of a
microorganism swimming in a patterned environment of square obstacles, where
the departure angle dictates the possibility of trapping or diffusive
trajectories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00942</id><created>2015-03-03</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prodan</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hren</keyname><forenames>Ram Du&#x161;i&#x107;</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Midden</keyname><forenames>Marion</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Midden</keyname><forenames>Herman J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zupani&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>The Equivalence Between Unit-Cell Twinning and Tiling in Icosahedral
  Quasicrystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 12474 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-12669-w</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that tiling in icosahedral quasicrystals can also be properly
described by cyclic twinning at the unit cell level. The twinning operation is
applied on the primitive prolate golden rhombohedra, which can be considered a
result of a distorted face-centered cubic parent structure. The shape of the
rhombohedra is determined by an exact space filling, resembling the forbidden
five-fold rotational symmetry. Stacking of clusters, formed around multiply
twinned rhombic hexecontahedra, keeps the rhombohedra of adjacent clusters in
discrete relationships. Thus periodicities, interrelated as members of a
Fibonacci series, are formed. The intergrown twins form no obvious twin
boundaries and fill the space in combination with the oblate golden
rhombohedra, formed between clusters in contact. Simulated diffraction patterns
of the multiply twinned rhombohedra and the Fourier transform of an extended
model structure are in full accord with the experimental diffraction patterns
and can be indexed by means of three-dimensional crystallography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05090</id><created>2015-08-20</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haldar</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharjee</keyname><forenames>Sudipto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Subenoy</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified first law and some general prescription: a redefinition of
  surface gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5179-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper contains an extensive study of the unified first law (UFL) in the
Friedmann-Robertson-Walker spacetime model. By projecting the UFL along the
Kodama vector the second Friedmann equation can be obtained. Also studying the
UFL on the event horizon it is found that Clausius relation cannot be obtained
from the UFL by projecting it along the tangent to the event horizon as it can
be for the trapping horizon. However, it is shown in the present work that
Clausius relation can be obtained by projecting the UFL along the Kodama vector
on the horizon and the result is found to be true for any horizon. Finally
motivated by the Unruh temperature for the Rindler observer, surface gravity is
redefined and a Clausius relation is obtained from the UFL by projecting it
along a vector analogous to the Kodama vector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01967</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2017-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Ana Cristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salavessa</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirichlet principal eigenvalue comparison theorems in geometry with
  torsion</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>Latex, 31 pages. The results of this paper were partially reported at
  the AMS-EMS-SPM international meeting at Porto, 10-13 June 2015. V3. We add a
  detailed description of the entire spectrum of the H-Laplacian on a geodesic
  ball of a model space. Accepted for publication in the Journal of
  Mathematical Analysis and Applications ( 13/04/2017)</comments><msc-class>35P15, 58C40, 53C07</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications Volume 453,
  Issue 2, 15 September 2017, 700-723</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmaa.2017.04.030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe min-max formulas for the principal eigenvalue of a $V$-drift
Laplacian defined by a vector field $V$ on a geodesic ball of a Riemannian
manifold $N$. Then we derive comparison results for the principal eigenvalue
with the one of a spherically symmetric model space endowed with a radial
vector field, under pointwise comparison of the corresponding radial sectional
and Ricci curvatures, and of the radial component of the vector fields. These
results generalize the known case $V=0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02120</id><created>2015-11-06</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maillet</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vavrek</keyname><forenames>Frantisek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fefferman</keyname><forenames>Andrew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgeois</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collin</keyname><forenames>Eddy</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical decoherence in a nanomechanical resonator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>SI not provided</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 073022 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Decoherence is an essential mechanism that defines the boundary between
classical and quantum behaviours, while imposing technological bounds for
quantum devices. Little is known about quantum coherence of mechanical systems,
as opposed to electromagnetic degrees of freedom. But decoherence can also be
thought of in a purely classical context, as the loss of phase coherence in the
classical phase space. Indeed the bridge between quantum and classical physics
is under intense investigation, using in particular classical nanomechanical
analogues of quantum phenomena. In the present work, by separating pure
dephasing from dissipation, we quantitatively model the classical decoherence
of a mechanical resonator: through the experimental control of frequency
fluctuations, we engineer artificial dephasing. Building on the fruitful
analogy introduced between spins/quantum bits and nanomechanical modes, we
report on the methods available to define pure dephasing in these systems,
while demonstrating the intrinsic almost-ideal properties of silicon-nitride
beams. These experimental and theoretical results, at the boundary between
classical nanomechanics and quantum information fields, are prerequisite in the
understanding of decoherence processes in mechanical devices, both classical
and quantum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07334</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Lopera</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>Mauricio A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Switched latent force models for reverse-engineering transcriptional
  regulation in gene expression data</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><doi>10.1109/TCBB.2017.2764908</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To survive environmental conditions, cells transcribe their response
activities into encoded mRNA sequences in order to produce certain amounts of
protein concentrations. The external conditions are mapped into the cell
through the activation of special proteins called transcription factors (TFs).
Due to the difficult task to measure experimentally TF behaviours, and the
challenges to capture their quick-time dynamics, different types of models
based on differential equations have been proposed. However, those approaches
usually incur in costly procedures, and they present problems to describe
sudden changes in TF regulators. In this paper, we present a switched dynamical
latent force model for reverse-engineering transcriptional regulation in gene
expression data which allows the exact inference over latent TF activities
driving some observed gene expressions through a linear differential equation.
To deal with discontinuities in the dynamics, we introduce an approach that
switches between different TF activities and different dynamical systems. This
creates a versatile representation of transcription networks that can capture
discrete changes and non-linearities We evaluate our model on both simulated
data and real-data (e.g. microaerobic shift in E. coli, yeast respiration),
concluding that our framework allows for the fitting of the expression data
while being able to infer continuous-time TF profiles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00863</id><created>2015-12-02</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Sobhit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Castro</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valencia-Jaime</keyname><forenames>Irais</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Aldo H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction of a controllable Weyl semi-metallic phase in
  inversion-asymmetric BiSb</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 Pages, 4 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 161116(R) 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.161116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experimental realization of long sought Weyl fermions in non-magnetic
crystals has greatly motivated condensed matter physicists to search for
materials supporting Weyl fermions. Weyl fermions appear to be very promising
for future electronics, often referred as Weyltronics. Here, by means of
first-principle calculations, we report a stoichiometric crystal structure of
BiSb with broken space-inversion symmetry. This structure is insulating in bulk
and has non-trivial band topology. We observe a pressure driven Weyl
semi-metallic phase transition in this crystal structure. The obtained Weyl
semi-metallic phase exists in the 4.0 - 6.0 GPa pressure range. We find that a
total 6 pairs of Weyl points, 6 monopoles and 6 antimonopoles, exist in the
Brillouin zone. The Weyl points with opposite chirality are located at
different energy values yielding separate electron and hole Fermi-surfaces.
Additionally, the spin-texture of the bulk BiSb compound appears to be
electrically controllable when the interlink between pressure and an electric
field is exploited. This produces novel manipulable topological transport
properties in this system which are very promising for implementation of this
kind of materials in next-generation Weyltronics and spintronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01198</id><created>2016-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Weston</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waintal</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Realistic Time-Resolved Simulations of Quantum Devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J Comput Electron 15, 1148 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10825-016-0855-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on our recent efforts to perform realistic simulations of large
quantum devices in the time domain. In contrast to d.c. transport where the
calculations are explicitly performed at the Fermi level, the presence of
time-dependent terms in the Hamiltonian makes the system inelastic so that it
is necessary to explicitly enforce the Pauli principle in the simulations. We
illustrate our approach with calculations for a flying qubit interferometer, a
nanoelectronic device that is currently under experimental investigation. Our
calculations illustrate the fact that many degrees of freedom (16,700
tight-binding sites in the scattering region) and long simulation times (80,000
times the inverse Bandwidth of the tight-binding model) can be easily achieved
on a local computer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03799</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2017-03-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsang</keyname><forenames>Mankei</forenames></author></authors><title>Conservative classical and quantum resolution limits for incoherent
  imaging</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures. v2: focused on imaging, cleaned up the math,
  added new analytic and numerical results. v3: restructured and submitted</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Modern Optics 65, 104-110 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2017.1377306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I propose classical and quantum limits to the statistical resolution of two
incoherent optical point sources from the perspective of minimax parameter
estimation. Unlike earlier results based on the Cram\'er-Rao bound, the limits
proposed here, based on the worst-case error criterion and a Bayesian version
of the Cram\'er-Rao bound, are valid for any biased or unbiased estimator and
obey photon-number scalings that are consistent with the behaviors of actual
estimators. These results prove that, from the minimax perspective, the
spatial-mode demultiplexing (SPADE) measurement scheme recently proposed by
Tsang, Nair, and Lu [Phys. Rev. X 6, 031033 (2016)] remains superior to direct
imaging for sufficiently high photon numbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09598</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Jihao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yonghui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Min-Hsiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hanwu</forenames></author></authors><title>On Quantum Tensor Product Codes</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information&amp;Computation, vol. 17, no. 13&amp;14, pp.
  1105-1122, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a general framework for the construction of quantum tensor product
codes (QTPC). In a classical tensor product code (TPC), its parity check matrix
is con- structed via the tensor product of parity check matrices of the two
component codes. We show that by adding some constraints on the component
codes, several classes of dual-containing TPCs can be obtained. By selecting
different types of component codes, the proposed method enables the
construction of a large family of QTPCs and they can provide a wide variety of
quantum error control abilities. In particular, if one of the component codes
is selected as a burst-error-correction code, then QTPCs have quantum
multiple-burst-error-correction abilities, provided these bursts fall in
distinct subblocks. Compared with concatenated quantum codes (CQC), the
component code selections of QTPCs are much more exible than those of CQCs
since only one of the component codes of QTPCs needs to satisfy the
dual-containing restriction. We show that it is possible to construct QTPCs
with parameters better than other classes of quantum error-correction codes
(QECC), e.g., CQCs and quantum BCH codes. Many QTPCs are obtained with
parameters better than previously known quantum codes available in the
literature. Several classes of QTPCs that can correct multiple quantum bursts
of errors are constructed based on reversible cyclic codes and
maximum-distance-separable (MDS) codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07377</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07377</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aranas</keyname><forenames>E. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>P. G. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monteiro</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Split-sideband spectroscopy in slowly modulated optomechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 113021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/11/113021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optomechanical coupling between the motion of a mechanical oscillator and a
cavity represents a new arena for experimental investigation of quantum effects
on the mesoscopic and macroscopic scale.The motional sidebands of the output of
a cavity offer ultra-sensitive probes of the dynamics. We introduce a scheme
whereby these sidebands split asymmetrically and show how they may be used as
experimental diagnostics and signatures of quantum noise limited dynamics. We
show split-sidebands with controllable asymmetry occur by simultaneously
modulating the light-mechanical coupling $g$ and $\omega_M$ - slowly and out
of-phase. Such modulations are generic but already occur in optically trapped
set-ups where the equilibrium point of the oscillator is varied cyclically. We
analyse recently observed, but overlooked, experimental split-sideband
asymmetries; although not yet in the quantum regime, the data suggests that
split sideband structures are easily accessible to future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01465</id><created>2016-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikuta</keyname><forenames>Rikizo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Toshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuki</keyname><forenames>Kenichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miki</keyname><forenames>Shigehito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>Taro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terai</keyname><forenames>Hirotaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koashi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukai</keyname><forenames>Tetsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Heralded single excitation of atomic ensemble via solid-state-based
  telecom photon detection</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optica 3, 1279 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.001279</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Telecom photonic quantum networks with matter quantum systems enable a rich
variety of applications, such as a long distance quantum cryptography and
one-way quantum computing. Preparation of a heralded single excitation (HSE) in
an atomic ensemble by detecting a telecom wavelength photon having a
correlation with the atomic excitation is an important step. Such a system has
been demonstrated with a quantum frequency conversion (QFC) to telecom
wavelength employing a Rb atomic cloud. However the limited wavelength
selection prevents the next step. Here we for the first time demonstrate HSE
with a solid-state-based QFC and a detector for a telecom wavelength that will
have a great advantage of the utility of mature telecom technologies. We
unambiguously show that the demonstrated HSE indicates a non-classical
statistics by the direct measurement of the autocorrelation function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05164</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2016-12-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grafe</keyname><forenames>H. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iakovleva</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vavilova</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spillecke</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alfonsov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sturza</keyname><forenames>M. -I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurmehl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nojiri</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler</keyname><forenames>U. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drechsler</keyname><forenames>S. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chner</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence for a magnetic field-induced unconventional nematic state in
  the frustrated and anisotropic spin-chain cuprate LiCuSbO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>revised version published in Sci. Rep. 7, 6729 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-06525-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern theories of quantum magnetism predict exotic multipolar states in
weakly interacting strongly frustrated spin-1/2 Heisenberg chains with
ferromagnetic nearest neighbor (NN) inchain exchange in high magnetic fields.
Experimentally these states remained elusive so far. Here we report the
evidence for a long-sought magnetic field-induced nematic state arising above a
field of $\sim 13$ T in the edge-sharing chain cuprate LiSbCuO$_4$ $\equiv$
LiCuSbO$_4$. This interpretation is based on the observation of a field induced
spin-gap in the measurements of the $^7$Li NMR spin relaxation rate $T_1^{-1}$
as well as a contrasting field-dependent power-law behavior of $T_1^{-1}$ vs.
$T$ and is further supported by static magnetization and ESR data. An
underlying theoretical microscopic approach favoring a nematic scenario is
based essentially on the NN XYZ exchange anisotropy within a model for
frustrated spin-1/2 chains. It is investigated by the DMRG technique. The
employed exchange parameters are justified qualitatively by electronic
structure calculations for LiCuSbO$_4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07314</id><created>2016-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ikuta</keyname><forenames>Rikizo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nozaki</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koashi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental demonstration of robust entanglement distribution over
  reciprocal noisy channels assisted by a counter-propagating classical
  reference light</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 4819 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-05008-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally demonstrate a proposal [Phys. Rev. A 87, 052325 (2013)] of
a scheme for robust distribution of polarization entangled photon pairs over
collective noisy channels having the reciprocity. Although the scheme employs
the robustness of two qubit decoherence-free subspace, by utilizing the forward
propagation of one half of the entangled photons and the backward propagation
of a classical reference light, it achieves an entanglement-sharing rate
proportional to the transmittance of the quantum channel for the signal photon.
We experimentally observed the efficient sharing rate while keeping a highly
entangled state after the transmission. We also show that the protection method
is applicable to transmission of arbitrary polarization state of a single
photon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01752</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Taotao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Kaixi</forenames></author></authors><title>Reheating mechanism of Curvaton with Nonminimal Derivative Coupling to
  Gravity</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures. corrections are made to match the published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.10, 687</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5275-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we continue our study on the curvaton model with nonminimal
derivative coupling (NDC) to Einstein gravity proposed in our previous work,
focusing on the reheating mechanism. We found that according to whether the
curvaton has dominated the background after the end of inflation, it will have
two different behaviors of evolution, which should be the general property of
curvaton with nonminimal couplings. This will cause diffferent rates of
particle creation, which goes on via the parametric resonance process. The
reheating temperature is estimated for both cases in which reheating completes
before and after curvaton domination, and the constraints are quite loose
compared to that of overproduction of gravitino. Finally we investigated the
evolution of curvature perturbation during reheating. We have shown both
analytically and numerically that the curvature perturbation will not blow up
during the resonance process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00143</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2016-09-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kononov</keyname><forenames>Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rectangular superpolynomials for the figure-eight knot</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.GT math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><report-no>ITEP/TH-21/16</report-no><journal-ref>Theoretical and Mathematical Physics 193 (2017) 1630-1646</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0040577917110058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We rewrite the recently proposed differential expansion formula for HOMFLY
polynomials of the knot $4_1$ in arbitrary rectangular representation $R=[r^s]$
as a sum over all Young sub-diagrams $\lambda$ of $R$ with extraordinary simple
coefficients $D_{\lambda^{tr}}(r)\cdot D_\lambda(s)$ in front of the
$Z$-factors. Somewhat miraculously, these coefficients are made from quantum
dimensions of symmetric representations of the groups $SL(r)$ and $SL(s)$ and
restrict summation to diagrams with no more than $s$ rows and $r$ columns. They
possess a natural $\beta$-deformation to Macdonald dimensions and produces
positive Laurent polynomials, which can be considered as plausible candidates
for the role of the rectangular superpolynomials. Both polynomiality and
positivity are non-evident properties of arising expressions, still they are
true. This extends the previous suggestions for symmetric and antisymmetric
representations (when $s=1$ or $r=1$ respectively) to arbitrary rectangular
representations. As usual for differential expansion, there are additional
gradings. In the only example, available for comparison -- that of the trefoil
knot $3_1$, to which our results for $4_1$ are straightforwardly extended, --
one of them reproduces the &quot;fourth grading&quot; for hyperpolynomials. Factorization
properties are nicely preserved even in the 5-graded case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02159</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vidotto</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrau</keyname><forenames>Aurelien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolliet</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schutten</keyname><forenames>Marrit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weimer</keyname><forenames>Celine</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-gravity phenomenology with primordial black holes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, Proceedings of the 2015 Karl Schwarzschild Meeting on
  Gravitational Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum gravity may allow black holes to tunnel into white holes. If so, the
lifetime of a black hole could be shorter than the one given by Hawking
evaporation, solving the information paradox. More interestingly, this could
open to a new window for quantum-gravity phenomenology, in connection with the
existence of primordial black holes. We discuss in particular the power of the
associated explosion and the possibility to observe an astrophysical signal in
the radio and in the gamma wavelengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01845</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kozitsky</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlovskii</keyname><forenames>Mykhailo</forenames></author></authors><title>A phase transition in a continuum particle system with binary
  Curie-Weiss interactions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><msc-class>82B26, 82B21</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Grand canonical equilibrium states of a continuum system of interacting
particles are studied. The particles are placed in the space $\mathbb{R}^d$
divided into congruent cubic cells. For a region $V\subset \mathbb{R}^d$
consisting of $N\in \mathbb{N}$ cells, every two particles contained in $V$
attract each other with intensity $J_1/N$. The particles contained in the same
cell are subject to binary repulsion with intensity $J_2&gt;J_1$. For fixed values
of the temperature, the interaction intensities and the chemical potential, the
thermodynamic phase is defined as a probability measure on the space of
occupation numbers of cells, determined by a condition typical to Curie-Weiss
theories. There is proved that the half-plane $J_1\times$\textit{ chemical
potential} contains phase coexistence points at which two thermodynamic phases
of the system exist. An equation of state for this system is obtained. Some
illustrating numerical results are also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02652</id><created>2016-10-09</created><updated>2016-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Juyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>In-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joung</keyname><forenames>InSuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jooyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>Bernard R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finding dominant transition pathways via global optimization of action</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, and 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1016/j.bpj.2016.11.1570</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new computational approach, Action-CSA, to sample multiple
reaction pathways with fixed initial and final states through global
optimization of the Onsager-Machlup action using the conformational space
annealing method. This approach successfully samples not only the most dominant
pathway but also many other possible paths without initial guesses on reaction
pathways. Pathway space is efficiently sampled by crossover operations of a set
of paths and preserving the diversity of sampled pathways. The sampling ability
of the approach is assessed by finding pathways for the conformational changes
of alanine dipeptide and hexane. The benchmarks demonstrate that the rank order
and the transition time distribution of multiple pathways identified by the new
approach are in good agreement with those of long molecular dynamics
simulations. We also show that the lowest action folding pathway of the
mini-protein FSD-1 identified by the new approach is consistent with previous
molecular dynamics simulations and experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04719</id><created>2016-10-15</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smiet</keyname><forenames>Christopher Berg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Candelaresi</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouwmeester</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>Ideal Relaxation of the Hopf Fibration</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas 24.7 (2017): 072110</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4990076</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ideal MHD relaxation is the topology-conserving reconfiguration of a magnetic
field into a lower energy state where the net force is zero. This is achieved
by modeling the plasma as perfectly conducting viscous fluid. It is an
important tool for investigating plasma equilibria and is often used to study
the magnetic configurations in fusion devices and astrophysical plasmas. We
study the equilibrium reached by a localized magnetic field through the
topology conserving relaxation of a magnetic field based on the Hopf fibration
in which magnetic field lines are closed circles that are all linked with one
another. Magnetic fields with this topology have recently been shown to occur
in non-ideal numerical simulations. Our results show that any localized field
can only attain equilibrium if there is a finite external pressure, and that
for such a field a Taylor state is unattainable. We find an equilibrium plasma
configuration that is characterized by a lowered pressure in a toroidal region,
with field lines lying on surfaces of constant pressure. Therefore, the field
is in a Grad-Shafranov equilibrium. Localized helical magnetic fields are found
when plasma is ejected from astrophysical bodies and subsequently relaxes
against the background plasma, as well as on earth in plasmoids generated by
e.g.\ a Marshall gun. This work shows under which conditions an equilibrium can
be reached and identifies a toroidal depression as the characteristic feature
of such a configuration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10184</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Sondak</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hawley</keyname><forenames>Cory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>Siyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinsonhaler</keyname><forenames>Rebecca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauga</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiffeault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>Can phoretic particles swim in two dimensions?</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures, RevTeX 4-1 style</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94, 062606 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062606</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Artificial phoretic particles swim using self-generated gradients in chemical
species (self-diffusiophoresis) or charges and currents (self-electrophoresis).
These particles can be used to study the physics of collective motion in active
matter and might have promising applications in bioengineering. In the case of
self-diffusiophoresis, the classical physical model relies on a steady solution
of the diffusion equation, from which chemical gradients, phoretic flows and
ultimately the swimming velocity, may be derived. Motivated by disk-shaped
particles in thin films and under confinement, we examine the extension to two
dimensions. Because the two-dimensional diffusion equation lacks a steady state
with the correct boundary conditions, Laplace transforms must be used to study
the long-time behavior of the problem and determine the swimming velocity. For
fixed chemical fluxes on the particle surface, we find that the swimming
velocity ultimately always decays logarithmically in time. In the case of
finite Peclet numbers, we solve the full advection-diffusion equation
numerically and show that this decay can be avoided by the particle moving to
regions of unconsumed reactant. Finite advection thus regularizes the
two-dimensional phoretic problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04381</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delacr&#xe9;taz</keyname><forenames>Luca V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gout&#xe9;raux</keyname><forenames>Blaise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartnoll</keyname><forenames>Sean A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karlsson</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Bad Metals from Fluctuating Density Waves</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>8+4+5 pages. 3 figures. v2: references added, discussion improved.
  v3: presentation revamped to emphasize main points. v4: minor tweaks to
  presentation and data points for more materials added. v5: minor revised
  version for SciPost</comments><report-no>SITP 16/24, NORDITA-2016-132</report-no><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 025 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.3.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bad metals have a large resistivity without being strongly disordered. In
many bad metals the Drude peak moves away from zero frequency as the
resistivity becomes large at increasing temperatures. We catalogue the position
and width of the `displaced Drude peak' in the observed optical conductivity of
several families of bad metals, showing that $\omega_\text{peak} \sim \Delta
\omega \sim k_BT/\hbar$. This is the same quantum critical timescale that
underpins the $T$-linear dc resistivity of many of these materials. We provide
a unified theoretical description of the optical and dc transport properties of
bad metals in terms of the hydrodynamics of short range quantum critical
fluctuations of incommensurate density wave order. Within hydrodynamics, pinned
translational order is essential to obtain the nonzero frequency peak.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08103</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-04-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meda</keyname><forenames>Alice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Losero</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samantaray</keyname><forenames>Nigam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scafirimuto</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradyumna</keyname><forenames>Siva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avella</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruo-Berchera</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon number correlation for quantum enhanced imaging and sensing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>A Meda et al 2017 J. Opt. 19 094002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8986/aa7b27</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this review we present the potentialities and the achievements of the use
of non-classical photon number correlations in twin beams (TWB) states for many
applications, ranging from imaging to metrology. Photon number correlations in
the quantum regime are easy to be produced and are rather robust against
unavoidable experimental losses, and noise in some cases, if compared to the
entanglement, where loosing one photon can completely compromise the state and
its exploitable advantage. Here, we will focus on quantum enhanced protocols in
which only phase-insensitive intensity measurements (photon number counting)
are performed, which allow probing transmission/absorption properties of a
system, leading for example to innovative target detection schemes in a strong
background. In this framework, one of the advantages is that the sources
experimentally available emit a wide number of pairwise correlated modes, which
can be intercepted and exploited separately, for example by many pixels of a
camera, providing a parallelism, essential in several applications, like wide
field sub-shot-noise imaging and quantum enhanced ghost imaging. Finally,
non-classical correlation enables new possibilities in quantum radiometry, e.g.
the possibility of absolute calibration of a spatial resolving detector from
the on-off- single photon regime to the linear regime, in the same setup.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00924</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Roca-Maza</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Col&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bortignon</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards a self-consistent dynamical nuclear model</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>JPhysG. Accepted paper (https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6471/aa5669).
  Special issue
  (http://iopscience.iop.org/journal/0954-3899/page/Emerging%20Leaders)</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 ( 2017 ) 044001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa5669</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density Functional Theory (DFT) is a powerful and accurate tool exploited in
Nuclear Physics to investigate the ground-state and some collective properties
of nuclei along the whole nuclear chart. Models based on DFT are, however, not
suitable for the description of single-particle dynamics in nuclei. Following
the field theoretical approach by A. Bohr and B. R. Mottelson to describe
nuclear interactions between single-particle and vibrational degrees of
freedom, we have undertaken important steps to build a microscopic dynamic
nuclear model. In connection to that, one important issue that needs to be
better understood is the renormalization of the effective interaction in the
particle-vibration approach. One possible way to renormalize the interaction is
the so called {\it subtraction method}. In this contribution we will implement
the {\it subtraction method} for the first time in our model and study its
consequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06296</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-01-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Motovilov</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shkalikov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unconditional bases of subspaces related to non-self-adjoint
  perturbations of self-adjoint operators</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Eurasian Mathematical Journal 8:1 (2017), 119-127
  (http://mi.mathnet.ru/emj251)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assume that $T$ is a self-adjoint operator on a Hilbert space $\mathcal{H}$
and that the spectrum of $T$ is confined in the union $\bigcup_{j\in
J}\Delta_j$, $J\subseteq\mathbb{Z}$, of segments $\Delta_j=[\alpha_j,
\beta_j]\subset\mathbb{R}$ such that $\alpha_{j+1}&gt;\beta_j$ and $$ \inf_{j}
\left(\alpha_{j+1}-\beta_j\right) = d &gt; 0. $$ If $B$ is a bounded (in general
non-self-adjoint) perturbation of $T$ with $\|B\|=:b&lt;d/2$ then the spectrum of
the perturbed operator $A=T+B$ lies in the union $\bigcup_{j\in J}
U_{b}(\Delta_j)$ of the mutually disjoint closed $b$-neighborhoods
$U_{b}(\Delta_j)$ of the segments $\Delta_j$ in $\mathbb{C}$. Let $Q_j$ be the
Riesz projection onto the invariant subspace of $A$ corresponding to the part
of the spectrum of $A$ lying in $U_{b}\left(\Delta_j\right)$, $j\in J$. Our
main result is as follows: The subspaces $\mathcal{L}_j=Q_j(\mathcal H)$, $j\in
J$, form an unconditional basis in the whole space $\mathcal H$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00222</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beccaria</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tseytlin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On induced action for conformal higher spins in curved background</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>27 pages, v2 typos corrected</comments><report-no>Imperial-TP-AAT-2017-02</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.03.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We continue the investigation of the structure of the action for a tower of
conformal higher spin fields in non-trivial 4d background metric recently
discussed in arXiv:1609.09381. The action is defined as an induced one from
path integral of a conformal scalar field in curved background coupled to
higher spin fields. We analyse in detail the dependence of the quadratic part
of the induced action on the spin 1 and spin 3 fields, determining the presence
of a curvature-dependent mixed spin 1 - spin 3 term. One consequence is that
the pure spin 3 kinetic term cannot be gauge-invariant on its own beyond the
leading term in small curvature expansion. We also compute the non-zero
contribution of the 1-3 mixing term to the conformal anomaly c-coefficient. One
is thus to determine all such mixing terms before addressing the question of
possible vanishing of the total c-coefficient in the conformal higher spin
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03219</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chin</keyname><forenames>Seungbeom</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence number as a discrete quantum resource</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>10 pages, Revtex 4.1; (v3) new analysis on the aspect of coherence
  number as a resource for the Grover algorithm, former title &quot;Conversion of
  Coherence into Entanglement $ k $-concurrence&quot; ; (v4) minor corrections and
  clarifications, 1 figure added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 042336 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.042336</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new discrete coherence monotone named the \emph{coherence
number}, which is a generalization of the coherence rank to mixed states. After
defining the coherence number in a similar manner to the Schmidt number in
entanglement theory, we present a necessary and sufficient condition of the
coherence number for a coherent state to be converted to an entangled state of
nonzero $k$-concurrence (a member of the generalized concurrence family with
$2\le k \le d$). It also turns out that the coherence number is a useful
measure to understand the process of Grover search algorithm of $N$ items. We
show that the coherence number remains $N$ and falls abruptly when the success
probability of the searching process becomes maximal. This phenomenon motivates
us to analyze the depletion pattern of $C_c^{(N)}$ (the last member of the
generalized coherence concurrence, nonzero when the coherence number is $N$),
which turns out to be an optimal resource for the process since it is
completely consumed to finish the searching task.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05475</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-08-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pechersky</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pirogov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;tz</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vladimirov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yambartsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Fluctuations of Radiation in Stochastically Activated Two-Level
  Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math.PR</categories><comments>22 pages, no figures</comments><msc-class>Primary 60J, 60F10, Secondary 60K35</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 455203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa8dba</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the large fluctuations of emitted radiations in the system of $N$
non-interacting two-level atoms. Two methods are used to calculate the
probability of the large fluctuations and the time dependence of the excitation
and emission. The first method is based on the large deviation principle for
Markov processes. The second one uses an analogue of the quantum formalism for
classical probability problems. Particularly we prove that in a large
fluctuation limit approximately a half of the atoms are excited. This fact is
independent on the fraction of the excited atoms in the stationary state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07070</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ziqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation effects and hidden spin-orbit entangled electronic order in
  parent and electron-doped iridates Sr$_2$IrO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures + supplementary material (4 pages with 3 figures),
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 041018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analogs of the high-T$_c$ cuprates have been long sought after in transition
metal oxides. Due to the strong spin-orbit coupling (SOC), the $5d$ perovskite
iridates Sr$_2$IrO$_4$ exhibit a low-energy electronic structure remarkably
similar to the cuprates. Whether a superconducting state exists as in the
cuprates requires understanding the correlated spin-orbit entangled electronic
states. Recent experiments discovered hidden order in the parent and electron
doped iridates, some with striking analogies to the cuprates, including Fermi
surface pockets, Fermi arcs, and pseudogap. Here, we study the correlation and
disorder effects in a five-orbital model derived from the band theory. We find
that the experimental observations are consistent with a $d$-wave spin-orbit
density wave order that breaks the symmetry of a joint two-fold spin-orbital
rotation followed by a lattice translation. There is a Berry phase and a
plaquette spin flux due to spin procession as electrons hop between Ir atoms,
akin to the intersite SOC in quantum spin Hall insulators. The associated
staggered circulating $J_\text{eff}=1/2$ spin current can be probed by advanced
techniques of spin-current detection in spintronics. This electronic order can
emerge spontaneously from the intersite Coulomb interactions between the
spatially extended iridium $5d$ orbitals, turning the metallic state into an
electron doped quasi-2D Dirac semimetal with important implications on the
possible superconducting state suggested by recent experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07634</id><created>2017-02-24</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chertkov</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novitsky</keyname><forenames>Nikolai N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Transients in District Heating Systems</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SY math.OC physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>31 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heat fluxes in a district heating pipeline systems need to be controlled on
the scale from minutes to an hour to adjust to evolving demand. There are two
principal ways to control the heat flux - keep temperature fixed but adjust
velocity of the carrier (typically water) or keep the velocity flow steady but
then adjust temperature at the heat producing source (heat plant). We study the
latter scenario, commonly used for operations in Russia and Nordic countries,
and analyze dynamics of the heat front as it propagates through the system.
Steady velocity flows in the district heating pipelines are typically turbulent
and incompressible. Changes in the heat, on either consumption or production
sides, lead to slow transients which last from tens of minutes to hours. We
classify relevant physical phenomena in a single pipe, e.g. turbulent spread of
the turbulent front. We then explain how to describe dynamics of temperature
and heat flux evolution over a network efficiently and illustrate the network
solution on a simple example involving one producer and one consumer of heat
connected by &quot;hot&quot; and &quot;cold&quot; pipes. We conclude the manuscript motivating
future research directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02863</id><created>2017-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Lahrz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weitenberg</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathey</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Implementing supersymmetric dynamics in ultracold atom systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 043624 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.043624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetric systems derive their properties from conserved supercharges
which form a supersymmetric algebra. These systems naturally factorize into two
subsystems, which, when considered as individual systems, have essentially the
same eigenenergies, and their eigenstates can be mapped onto each other. We
first propose a one-dimensional ultracold atom setup to realize such a pair of
supersymmetric systems. We propose a Mach-Zehnder interference experiment which
we demonstrate for this system, and which can be realized with current
technology. In this interferometer, a single atom wave packet that evolves in a
superposition of the subsystems, gives an interference contrast that is sharply
peaked if the subsystems form a supersymmetric pair. Secondly, we propose a
two-dimensional setup that implements supersymmetric dynamics in a synthetic
gauge field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05758</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halataei</keyname><forenames>Seyyed M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leggett</keyname><forenames>Anthony J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunnel Splitting in Asymmetric Double Well Potentials: An Improved WKB
  Calculation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an improved Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin (WKB) calculation of tunnel
splitting in one dimensional asymmetric double well potentials. We show that
the tunnel splitting in general can have linear dependence on the bias energy,
beside the well-known quadratic dependence. We demonstrate that the linear
correction is greater than previously thought.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08341</id><created>2017-03-24</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nikolic</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interpretation miniatures</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, revised, new references, accepted for publication in Int.
  J. Quantum Inf</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Quantum Inf. 15 (2017) 1740001</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749917400019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most physicists do not have patience for reading long and obscure
interpretation arguments and disputes. Hence, to attract attention of a wider
physics community, in this paper various old and new aspects of quantum
interpretations are explained in a concise and simple (almost trivial) form.
About the &quot;Copenhagen&quot; interpretation, we note that there are several different
versions of it and explain how to make sense of &quot;local non-reality&quot;
interpretation. About the many-world interpretation, we explain that it is
neither local nor non-local, that it cannot explain the Born rule, that it
suffers from the preferred basis problem, and that quantum suicide cannot be
used to test it. About the Bohmian interpretation, we explain that it is
analogous to dark matter, use it to explain that there is no big difference
between non-local correlation and non-local causation, and use some
condensed-matter ideas to outline how non-relativistic Bohmian theory could be
a theory of everything. We also explain how different interpretations can be
used to demystify the delayed choice experiment, to resolve the problem of time
in quantum gravity, and to provide alternatives to quantum non-locality.
Finally, we explain why is life compatible with the 2nd law.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10134</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coined Quantum Walks on Weighted Graphs</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 475301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa8c17</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define a discrete-time, coined quantum walk on weighted graphs that is
inspired by Szegedy's quantum walk. Using this, we prove that many
lackadaisical quantum walks, where each vertex has $l$ integer self-loops, can
be generalized to a quantum walk where each vertex has a single self-loop of
real-valued weight $l$. We apply this real-valued lackadaisical quantum walk to
two problems. First, we analyze it on the line or one-dimensional lattice,
showing that it is exactly equivalent to a continuous deformation of the
three-state Grover walk with faster ballistic dispersion. Second, we generalize
Grover's algorithm, or search on the complete graph, to have a weighted
self-loop at each vertex, yielding an improved success probability when $l &lt; 3
+ 2\sqrt{2} \approx 5.828$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01782</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Englert</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Top quark electroweak couplings at future lepton colliders</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>v1: 11 pages, 11 figures. v2: References added, Fig. 11 updated.
  Matches version published in EPJC</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5095-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a comparative study of the reach of future $e^+e^-$ collider
options for the scale of non-resonant new physics effects in the top quark
sector, phrased in the language of higher-dimensional operators. Our focus is
on the electroweak top quark pair production process $e^+e^- \to Z^*/\gamma \to
t\bar t $, and we study benchmark scenarios at the ILC and CLIC. We find that
both are able to constrain mass scales up to the few TeV range in the most
sensitive cases, improving by orders of magnitude on the forecasted
capabilities of the LHC. We discuss the role played by observables such as
forward-backward asymmetries, and making use of different beam polarisation
settings, and highlight the possibility of lifting a degeneracy in the allowed
parameter space by combining top observables with precision $Z$-pole
measurements from LEP1.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06312</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Mi</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peterfalvi</keyname><forenames>Csaba G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkard</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petta</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>High Resolution Valley Spectroscopy of Si Quantum Dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 176803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.176803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study an accumulation mode Si/SiGe double quantum dot (DQD) containing a
single electron that is dipole coupled to microwave photons in a
superconducting cavity. Measurements of the cavity transmission reveal
dispersive features due to the DQD valley states in Si. The occupation of the
valley states can be increased by raising temperature or applying a finite
source-drain bias across the DQD, resulting in an increased signal. Using
cavity input-output theory and a four-level model of the DQD, it is possible to
efficiently extract valley splittings and the inter- and intra-valley tunnel
couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02483</id><created>2017-05-06</created><updated>2017-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mawrie</keyname><forenames>Alestin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Sonu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Tarun Kanti</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical and thermoelectric transport properties of two-dimensional
  fermionic systems with $k$-cubic spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures. To appear in Journal of Physics: Condensed
  Matter</comments><report-no>29, 46530 (2017)</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter 29, 46530 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa89b9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of $k$-cubic spin-orbit interaction on electrical
and thermoelectric transport properties of two-dimensional fermionic systems.
We obtain exact analytical expressions of the inverse relaxation time (IRT) and
the Drude conductivity for long-range Coulomb and short-range delta scattering
potentials. The IRT reveals that the scattering is completely suppressed along
the three directions $\theta^\prime = (2n+1)\pi/3 $ with $ n=1,2,3$. We also
obtain analytical results of the thermopower and thermal conductivity at low
temperature. The thermoelectric transport coefficients obey the Wiedemann-Franz
law, even in the presence of $k$-cubic Rashba spin-orbit coupling (RSOC) at low
temperature. In the presence of quantizing magnetic field, the signature of the
RSOC is revealed through the appearance of the beating pattern in the
Shubnikov-de Haas (SdH) oscillations of thermopower and thermal conductivity in
low magnetic field regime. The empirical formulae for the SdH oscillation
frequencies accurately describe the locations of the beating nodes. The beating
pattern in magnetothermoelectric measurement can be used to extract the
spin-orbit coupling constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04386</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization of spin torque oscillators through spin Hall
  magnetoresistance</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci nlin.AO</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, published as a conference proceeding of Intermag
  2017</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Trans. Magn. 53, 3400907 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TMAG.2017.2704588</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin torque oscillators placed onto a nonmagnetic heavy metal show
synchronized auto-oscillations due to the coupling originating from spin Hall
magnetoresistance effect. Here, we study a system having two spin torque
oscillators under the effect of the spin Hall torque, and show that switching
the external current direction enables us to control the phase difference of
the synchronization between in-phase and antiphase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04475</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>J. P. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>C. Almeida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreira</keyname><forenames>J. Agostinho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conde</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resistive switching in MoSe$_{2}$/BaTiO$_{3}$ hybrid structures</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Mater. Chem. C, 2017,5, 10353-10359</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7TC03024J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we study the resistive switching (RS) effect that emerges when
ferroelectric BaTiO$_{3}$ (BTO) and few-layers MoSe$_{2}$ are combined in one
single structure. The C-V loops reveal the ferroelectric nature of both
Al/Si/SiO$_{x}$/BTO/Au and Al/Si/SiO$_{x}$/MoSe$_{2}$/BTO/Au structures and the
high quality of the SiO$_{x}$/MoSe$_{2}$ interface in the
Al/Si/SiOx/MoSe$_{2}$/Au structure. Al/Si/SiO$_{x}$/MoSe$_{2}$/BTO/Au hybrid
structures show the electroforming free resistive switching that is explained
on the basis of the modulation of the potential distribution at the
MoSe$_{2}$/BTO interface via ferroelectric polarization flipping. This
structure shows promising resistive switching characteristics with switching
ratio of $\approx{}$10$^{2}$ and a stable memory window, which are highly
required for memory applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09078</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bravo-Bergu&#xf1;o</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mereu</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalcante</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ianni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goretti</keyname><forenames>Augusto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabriele</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Tristan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokley</keyname><forenames>Zachary</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelaar</keyname><forenames>Robert Bruce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calaprice</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>The Borexino Thermal Monitoring and Management System</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A monitoring and management system for the thermal environment inside the
Borexino neutrino detector was developed and installed in order to reduce
uncertainties in temperature determination and limit undesirable thermal
couplings between the environment and Borexino's active sections. This strategy
is bringing improved radioactive background conditions to the physics signal
thanks to the reduced mixing taking place in the liquid scintillator. While
equilibrium has not yet been reached, and fine-tuning is possible, the system
has proven extremely effective at greatly stabilizing the detector while
offering precise insight into its internal thermal conditions and transport.
Numerical simulations have also been used to feed this empirical data into a
global model, providing information into present and future thermal trends.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10191</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-10-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alqahtani</keyname><forenames>Mubarak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nopoush</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryblewski</keyname><forenames>Radoslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strickland</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic hydrodynamic modeling of 2.76 TeV Pb-Pb collisions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>31 pages, 9 figures. v2 - improvements to HBT calculation + typos
  fixed; PRC version. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1703.05808</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 96, 044910 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.96.044910</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare phenomenological results from 3+1d quasiparticle anisotropic
hydrodynamics (aHydroQP) with experimental data collected in LHC 2.76 TeV Pb-Pb
collisions. In particular, we present comparisons of particle spectra, average
transverse momentum, elliptic flow, and HBT radii. The aHydroQP model relies on
the introduction of a single temperature-dependent quasiparticle mass which is
fit to lattice QCD data. By taking moments of the resulting Boltzmann equation,
we obtain the dynamical equations used in the hydrodynamic stage which include
the effects of both shear and bulk viscosities. At freeze-out, we use
anisotropic Cooper-Frye freeze-out performed on a fixed-energy-density
hypersurface to convert to hadrons. To model the production and decays of the
hadrons we use THERMINATOR 2 which is customized to sample from ellipsoidal
momentum-space distribution functions. Using smooth Glauber initial conditions,
we find very good agreement with many heavy-ion collision observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10363</id><created>2017-05-29</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Huong Lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>Katja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sefkow</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Software compensation in Particle Flow reconstruction</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>13 pages, 13 figures, v2 with wording and figure improvements,
  published in EPJ C</comments><report-no>DESY 17-083; MPP-2017-98</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 698 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5298-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The particle flow approach to calorimetry benefits from highly granular
calorimeters and sophisticated software algorithms in order to reconstruct and
identify individual particles in complex event topologies. The high spatial
granularity, together with analogue energy information, can be further
exploited in software compensation. In this approach, the local energy density
is used to discriminate electromagnetic and purely hadronic sub-showers within
hadron showers in the detector to improve the energy resolution for single
particles by correcting for the intrinsic non-compensation of the calorimeter
system. This improvement in the single particle energy resolution also results
in a better overall jet energy resolution by improving the energy measurement
of identified neutral hadrons and improvements in the pattern recognition stage
by a more accurate matching of calorimeter energies to tracker measurements.
This paper describes the software compensation technique and its implementation
in particle flow reconstruction with the Pandora Particle Flow Algorithm
(PandoraPFA). The impact of software compensation on the choice of optimal
transverse granularity for the analogue hadronic calorimeter option of the
International Large Detector (ILD) concept is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00828</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Po</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazar</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Admal</keyname><forenames>Nikhil Chandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghoniem</keyname><forenames>Nasr</forenames></author></authors><title>A non-singular theory of dislocations in anisotropic crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a non-singular theory of three-dimensional dislocation loops in a
particular version of Mindlin's anisotropic gradient elasticity with up to six
length scale parameters. The theory is systematically developed as a
generalization of the classical anisotropic theory in the framework of
linearized incompatible elasticity. The non-singular version of all key
equations of anisotropic dislocation theory are derived as line integrals,
including the Burgers displacement equation with isolated solid angle, the
Peach-Koehler stress equation, the Mura-Willis equation for the elastic
distortion, and the Peach-Koehler force. The expression for the interaction
energy between two dislocation loops as a double line integral is obtained
directly, without the use of a stress function. It is shown that all the
elastic fields are non-singular, and that they converge to their classical
counterparts a few characteristic lengths away from the dislocation core. In
practice, the non-singular fields can be obtained from the classical ones by
replacing the classical (singular) anisotropic Green's tensor with the
non-singular anisotropic Green's tensor derived by \cite{Lazar:2015ja}. The
elastic solution is valid for arbitrary anisotropic media. In addition to the
classical anisotropic elastic constants, the non-singular Green's tensor
depends on a second order symmetric tensor of length scale parameters modeling
a weak non-locality, whose structure depends on the specific class of crystal
symmetry. The anisotropic Helmholtz operator defined by such tensor admits a
Green's function which is used as the spreading function for the Burgers vector
density. As a consequence, the Burgers vector density spreads differently in
different crystal structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03140</id><created>2017-06-09</created><updated>2017-10-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>J. D. Huerta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Lara</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization dynamics in twisted fiber amplifiers: a non-Hermitian
  nonlinear dimer model</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 42, 4402 -- 4405 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.004402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study continuous-wave light propagation through a twisted birefringent
single-mode fiber amplifier with saturable nonlinearity. The corresponding
coupled-mode system is isomorphic to a non-Hermitian nonlinear dimer, and gives
rise to analytic polarization-mode dynamics. It provides an optical simulation
of the semi-classical non-Hermitian Bose-Hubbard model, and suggests its use
for the design of polarization circulators and filters, as well as sources of
polarized light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03709</id><created>2017-06-12</created><updated>2017-09-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blackburn</keyname><forenames>James A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirillo</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gronbech-Jensen</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of low temperature quantum crossover in Josephson
  junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4986757</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evidence for macroscopic quantum tunneling (MQT) in Josephson junctions
at low temperatures has been reassessed. Swept bias escape distributions have
been modeled with an algorithm-based simulation and the results compared with
data from representative published experiments. Signatures expected of a
crossover to MQT are not found in the analyzed data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05511</id><created>2017-06-17</created><updated>2017-09-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Claeys</keyname><forenames>Pieter W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Neck</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Baerdemacker</keyname><forenames>Stijn</forenames></author></authors><title>Inner products in integrable Richardson-Gaudin models</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>21+16 pages, minor revisions compared to the previous version</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 028 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.4.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the inner products of eigenstates in integrable Richardson-Gaudin
models from two different perspectives and derive two classes of Gaudin-like
determinant expressions for such inner products. The requirement that one of
the states is on-shell arises naturally by demanding that a state has a dual
representation. By implicitly combining these different representations, inner
products can be recast as domain wall boundary partition functions. The
structure of all involved matrices in terms of Cauchy matrices is made explicit
and used to show how one of the classes returns the Slavnov determinant
formula. This framework provides a further connection between two different
approaches for integrable models, one in which everything is expressed in terms
of rapidities satisfying Bethe equations, and one in which everything is
expressed in terms of the eigenvalues of conserved charges, satisfying
quadratic equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06483</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-08-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gros</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amano</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atti&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baron</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baudin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernard</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dat&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delbart</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frotin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geerebaert</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giebels</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;tz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotaka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louzir</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magniette</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamiyama</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohkuma</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poilleux</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semeniouk</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sizun</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takemoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yonamine</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance measurement of HARPO: a Time Projection Chamber as a
  gamma-ray telescope and polarimeter</title><categories>astro-ph.IM hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Submitted to Astroparticle Physics</comments><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2017.10.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the performance of a gas time projection chamber (TPC) as a
high-performance gamma-ray telescope and polarimeter in the e$^+$e$^-$ pair
creation regime. We use data collected at a gamma-ray beam of known
polarisation. The TPC provides two orthogonal projections $(x,z)$ and $(y,z)$
of the tracks induced by each conversion in the gas volume. We use a simple
vertex finder in which vertices and pseudo-tracks exiting from them are
identified.
  We study the various contributions to the single-photon angular resolution
using Monte Carlo simulations and compare them with the experimental data and
find that they are in excellent agreement. The distribution of the azimutal
angle of pair conversions shows a bias due to the non-cylindrical-symmetric
structure of the detector. This bias would average out for a long duration
exposure on a space mission, but for this pencil-beam characterisation we have
ensured its accurate simulation by a double systematics control scheme, data
taking with the detector rotated at several angles with respect to the beam
polarisation direction and systematics control with a non-polarised beam.
  We measure, for the first time, the polarisation asymmetry of a linearly
polarised gamma-ray beam in the low energy pair creation regime. This sub-GeV
energy range is critical for cosmic sources as their spectra are power laws
which fall quickly as a function of increasing energy.
  This work could pave the way to extending polarised gamma-ray astronomy
beyond the MeV energy regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09034</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blumenhagen</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traube</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Structure of Quantum L$_\infty$ algebras</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, v2: clarifications, version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>MPP-2017-126</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is believed that any classical gauge symmetry gives rise to an L$_\infty$
algebra. Based on the recently realized relation between classical ${\cal W}$
algebras and L$_\infty$ algebras, we analyze how this generalizes to the
quantum case. Guided by the existence of quantum ${\cal W}$ algebras, we
provide a physically well motivated definition of quantum L$_\infty$ algebras
describing the consistency of global symmetries in quantum field theories. In
this case we are restricted to only two non-trivial graded vector spaces $X_0$
and $X_{-1}$ containing the symmetry variations and the symmetry generators.
This quantum L$_\infty$ algebra structure is explicitly exemplified for the
quantum ${\cal W}_3$ algebra. The natural quantum product between fields is the
normal ordered one so that, due to contractions between quantum fields, the
higher L$_\infty$ relations receive off-diagonal quantum corrections.
Curiously, these are not present in the loop L$_\infty$ algebra of closed
string field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.00323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.00323</id><created>2017-08-01</created><updated>2017-10-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Janderson R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>Vilson R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical forces through the effective refractive index</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 42 (2017) 4371-4374</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.004371</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy-based methods as the Dispersion Relation (DR) and Response Theory
of Optical Forces (RTOF) have been largely applied to obtain the optical forces
in the nano-optomechanical devices, in contrast to the Maxwell Stress Tensor
(MST). In this work, we apply first principles to show explicitly why these
methods must agree with the MST formalism in linear lossless systems. We apply
the RTOF multi-port, to show that the optical force expression on these devices
can be extended to analyze multiple light sources, broadband sources, and
multimode devices, with multiple degrees of freedom. We also show that the DR
method, when expressed as a function of the derivative of the effective index
performed at a fixed wave vector, may be misinterpreted and lead to
overestimated results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03678</id><created>2017-08-14</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Y&#xfc;cel</keyname><forenames>Harun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okumu&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>Nazmi Turan</forenames></author></authors><title>A New Tracking Algorithm for Multiple Colloidal Particles Close to
  Contact</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.soft physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa908e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we propose a new algorithm based on radial symmetry center
method to track colloidal particles close to contact, where the optical images
of the particles start to overlap in digital video microscopy. This overlapping
effect is important to observe the pair interaction potential in colloidal
studies and it appears as additional interaction in the measurement of the
interaction with conventional tracking analysis. The proposed algorithm in this
work is simple, fast and applicable for not only two particles but also three
and more particles without any modification. The algorithm uses gradient
vectors of the particle intensity distribution, which allows us to use a part
of the symmetric intensity distribution in the calculation of the actual
particle position. In this study, simulations are performed to see the
performance of the proposed algorithm for two and three particles, where the
simulation images are generated by using fitted curve to experimental particle
image for different sized particles. As a result, the algorithm yields the
maximum error smaller than 2 nm for 5.53 {\mu}m silica particles in contact
condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04421</id><created>2017-08-15</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walmsley</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Separable and Inseparable Quantum Trajectories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 170401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.170401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamical behavior of interacting systems plays a fundamental role for
determining quantum correlations, such as entanglement. In this Letter, we
describe temporal quantum effects of the inseparable evolution of composite
quantum states by comparing the trajectories to their classically correlated
counterparts. For this reason, we introduce equations of motions describing the
separable propagation of any interacting quantum system, which are derived by
requiring separability for all times. The resulting Schroedinger-type equations
allow for comparing the trajectories in a separable configuration with the
actual behavior of the system and, thereby, identifying inseparable and
time-dependent quantum properties. As an example, we study bipartite discrete-
and continuous-variable interacting systems. The generalization of our
developed technique to multipartite scenarios is also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.04771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.04771</id><created>2017-08-16</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abu-Al-Saud</keyname><forenames>Moataz O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soulaine</keyname><forenames>Cyprien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riaz</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tchelepi</keyname><forenames>Hamdi A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Level-set method for accurate modeling of two-phase immiscible flow with
  moving contact lines</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We developed a sharp interface level-set approach for two-phase immiscible
flow with moving contact lines. The Cox-Voinov model is used to describe the
moving contact line. A piecewise linear interface method is used to construct
the signed distance function and to implement the contact angle boundary
condition. Spurious currents are studied in the case of static and moving fluid
interfaces, which show convergence behavior. Pressure and the surface tension
force are balanced up to machine precision for static parabolic interfaces,
while the velocity error decreases steadily with grid refinement when the
interface is advected in a uniform flow field. The moving contact line problem
is studied and validated through comparison with theory and experiments for an
advancing interface and capillary rise in a tube.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.05222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.05222</id><created>2017-08-17</created><updated>2017-08-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>Saroj Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gov</keyname><forenames>Nir S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonequilibrium mode-coupling theory for dense active systems of
  self-propelled particles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2017, 13, 7609 - 7616</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7SM01648D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physics of active systems of self-propelled particles, in the regime of a
dense liquid state, is an open puzzle of great current interest, both for
statistical physics and because such systems appear in many biological
contexts. We develop a nonequilibrium mode-coupling theory (MCT) for such
systems, where activity is included as a colored noise with the particles
having a self-propulsion foce $f_0$ and persistence time $\tau_p$. Using the
extended MCT and a generalized fluctuation-dissipation theorem, we calculate
the effective temperature $T_{eff}$ of the active fluid. The nonequilibrium
nature of the systems is manifested through a time-dependent $T_{eff}$ that
approaches a constant in the long-time limit, which depends on the activity
parameters $f_0$ and $\tau_p$. We find, phenomenologically, that this long-time
limit is captured by the potential energy of a single, trapped active particle
(STAP). Through a scaling analysis close to the MCT glass transition point, we
show that $\tau_\alpha$, the $\alpha$-relaxation time, behaves as
$\tau_\alpha\sim f_0^{-2\gamma}$, where $\gamma=1.74$ is the MCT exponent for
the passive system. $\tau_\alpha$ may increase or decrease as a function of
$\tau_p$ depending on the type of active force correlations, but the behavior
is always governed by the same value of the exponent $\gamma$. Comparison with
numerical solution of the nonequilibrium MCT as well as simulation results give
excellent agreement with the scaling analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07488</id><created>2017-08-24</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kathirgamaraju</keyname><forenames>Adithan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duran</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Barniol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giannios</keyname><forenames>Dimitrios</forenames></author></authors><title>Off-axis short GRBs from structured jets as counterparts to GW events</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, accepted to MNRAS Letters</comments><report-no>MN-17-2999-L.R1</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx175</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Binary neutron star mergers are considered to be the most favorable sources
that produce electromagnetic (EM) signals associated with gravitational waves
(GWs). These mergers are the likely progenitors of short duration gamma-ray
bursts (GRBs). The brief gamma-ray emission (the &quot;prompt GRB&quot; emission) is
produced by ultra-relativistic jets, as a result, this emission is strongly
beamed over a small solid angle along the jet. It is estimated to be a decade
or more before a short GRB jet within the LIGO volume points along our line of
sight. For this reason, the study of the prompt signal as an EM counterpart to
GW events has been sparse. We argue that for a realistic jet model, one whose
luminosity and Lorentz factor vary smoothly with angle, the prompt signal can
be detected for a significantly broader range of viewing angles. This can lead
to a new type of EM counterpart, an &quot;off-axis&quot; short GRB. Our estimates and
simulations show that it is feasible to detect these signals with the aid of
the temporal coincidence from a LIGO trigger, even if the observer is
substantially misaligned with respect to the jet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07652</id><created>2017-08-25</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goldsborough</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evenbly</keyname><forenames>Glen</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement renormalization for disordered systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 21 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 155136 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.155136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a tensor network method for investigating strongly disordered
systems that is based on an adaptation of entanglement renormalization [G.
Vidal, Phys. Rev. Lett. 99, 220405 (2007)]. This method makes use of the strong
disorder renormalization group to determine the order in which lattice sites
are coarse-grained, which sets the overall structure of the corresponding
tensor network ansatz, before optimization using variational energy
minimization. Benchmark results from the disordered XXZ model demonstrates that
this approach accurately captures ground state entanglement in disordered
systems, even at long distances. This approach leads to a new class of
efficiently contractible tensor network ansatz for 1D systems, which may be
understood as a generalization of the multi-scale entanglement renormalization
ansatz for disordered systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.06003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.06003</id><created>2017-09-18</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Byungdo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redden</keyname><forenames>Corbett</forenames></author></authors><title>A classification of equivariant gerbe connections</title><categories>math.DG hep-th math.AT</categories><comments>31 pages; v2 minor revisions</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let G be a compact Lie group acting on a smooth manifold M. In this paper, we
consider Meinrenken's G-equivariant bundle gerbe connections on M as objects in
a 2-groupoid. We prove this 2-category is equivalent to the 2-groupoid of gerbe
connections on the differential quotient stack associated to M, and isomorphism
classes of G-equivariant gerbe connections are classified by degree three
differential equivariant cohomology. Finally, we consider the existence and
uniqueness of conjugation-equivariant gerbe connections on compact semisimple
Lie groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.07191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.07191</id><created>2017-09-21</created><updated>2017-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Produit</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batsch</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernasconi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britvich</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cadoux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cernuda</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Y. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauvin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hajdas</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kole</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramert</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcinkowski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orsi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rapin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybka</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rutczynska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Socha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabelski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traseira</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>B. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwolinska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Design and construction of the POLAR detector</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.09.053</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The POLAR detector is a space based Gamma Ray Burst (GRB) polarimeter with a
wide field of view, which covers almost half the sky. The instrument uses
Compton scattering of gamma rays on a plastic scintillator hodoscope to measure
the polarization of the incoming photons. The instrument has been successfully
launched on board of the Chinese space laboratory Tiangong~2 on September 15,
2016. The construction of the instrument components is described in this
article. Details are provided on problems encountered during the construction
phase and their solutions. Initial performance of the instrument in orbit is as
expected from ground tests and Monte Carlo simulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08097</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08097</id><created>2017-09-23</created><updated>2017-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Obertas</keyname><forenames>Alysa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caiazzo</keyname><forenames>Ilaria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyl</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richer</keyname><forenames>Harvey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalirai</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>Pier-Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>The Onset of Convective Coupling and Freezing in the White Dwarfs of 47
  Tucanae</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Submitted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using images from the Hubble Space Telescope Advanced Camera for Surveys, we
measure the rate of cooling of white dwarfs in the globular cluster 47 Tucanae
and compare it to modelled cooling curves. We examine the effects of the outer
convective envelope reaching the nearly isothermal degenerate core and the
release of latent heat during core crystallisation on the white dwarf cooling
rates. For white dwarfs typical of 47 Tuc, the onset of these effects occur at
similar times. The latent heat released during crystallisation is a small heat
source. In contrast, the heat reservoir of the degenerate core is substantially
larger. When the convective envelope reaches the nearly isothermal interior of
the white dwarf, the star becomes brighter than it would be in the absence of
this effect. Our modelled cooling curves that include this convective coupling
closely match the observed luminosity function of the white dwarfs in 47 Tuc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00434</id><created>2017-10-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Ben K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pudritz</keyname><forenames>Ralph E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of the RNA World: The Fate of Nucleobases in Warm Little Ponds</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in PNAS, 24 pages, 16 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences USA (2017) vol.
  114, no. 43, pg. 11327-11332</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1710339114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Prior to the origin of simple cellular life, the building blocks of RNA
(nucleotides) had to form and polymerize in favourable environments on the
early Earth. At this time, meteorites and interplanetary dust particles
delivered organics such as nucleobases (the characteristic molecules of
nucleotides) to warm little ponds whose wet-dry cycles promoted rapid
polymerization. We build a comprehensive numerical model for the evolution of
nucleobases in warm little ponds leading to the emergence of the first
nucleotides and RNA. We couple Earth's early evolution with complex prebiotic
chemistry in these environments. We find that RNA polymers must have emerged
very quickly after the deposition of meteorites (&lt; a few years). Their
constituent nucleobases were primarily meteoritic in origin and not from
interplanetary dust particles. Ponds appeared as continents rose out of the
early global ocean but this increasing availability of &quot;targets&quot; for meteorites
was offset by declining meteorite bombardment rates. Moreover, the rapid losses
of nucleobases to pond seepage during wet periods, and to UV photodissociation
during dry periods means that the synthesis of nucleotides and their
polymerization into RNA occurred in just one to a few wet-dry cycles. Under
these conditions, RNA polymers likely appeared prior to 4.17 billion years ago.
  Significance: There are two competing hypotheses for the site at which an RNA
world emerged: hydrothermal vents in the deep ocean and warm little ponds.
Because the former lacks wet and dry cycles, which are well known to promote
polymerization (in this case, of nucleotides into RNA), we construct a
comprehensive model for the origin of RNA in the latter sites. Our model
advances the story and timeline of the RNA world by constraining the source of
biomolecules, the environmental conditions, the timescales of reaction, and the
emergence of first RNA polymers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00988</id><created>2017-10-03</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lindlau</keyname><forenames>Jessica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>Cedric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Funk</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rste</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rg</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colombier</keyname><forenames>L&#xe9;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neumann</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Courtade</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shree</keyname><forenames>Shivangi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marie</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbaszek</keyname><forenames>Bernhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;gele</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying optical signatures of momentum-dark excitons in transition
  metal dichalcogenide monolayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) monolayers (MLs) exhibit rich
photoluminescence spectra associated with interband optical transitions of
direct-gap semiconductors. Upon absorption of photons, direct excitons with
zero center-of-mass momentum are formed by photo-excited electrons in the
conduction band and the respective unoccupied states in the valence band of the
same valley. Different spin configurations of such momentum-direct excitons as
well as their charged counterparts provide a powerful platform for spin-valley
and microcavity physics in two-dimensional materials. The corresponding
spectral signatures, however, are insufficient to explain the main
characteristic peaks observed in the photoluminescence spectra of ML TMDs on
the basis of momentum-\textit{direct} excitons alone. Here, we show that the
notion of momentum-\textit{indirect} excitons is important for the
understanding of the versatile photoluminescence features. Taking into account
phonon-assisted radiative recombination pathways for electrons and holes from
dissimilar valleys, we interpret unidentified peaks in the emission spectra as
acoustic and optical phonon sidebands of momentum-dark excitons. Our approach
will facilitate the interpretation of optical, valley and spin phenomena in
TMDs arising from bright and dark exciton manifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00990</id><created>2017-10-03</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rg</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colombier</keyname><forenames>L&#xe9;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Robin K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindlau</keyname><forenames>Jessica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohite</keyname><forenames>Aditya D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Hisato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunger</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;gele</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavity-control of bright and dark interlayer excitons in van der Waals
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Monolayer (ML) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) integrated in optical
microcavities host exciton-polaritons as a hallmark of the strong light-matter
coupling regime. Analogous concepts for hybrid light-matter systems employing
spatially indirect excitons with a permanent electric dipole moment in
heterobilayer (HBL) crystals promise realizations of exciton-polariton gases
and condensates with immanent dipolar interactions. Here, we identify optical
signatures of spatially indirect momentum-bright and momentum-dark interlayer
excitons in vertical MoSe$_2$-WSe$_2$ heterostructures and implement
cavity-control of both exciton manifolds. Our experiments quantify the strength
of light-matter coupling for both zero and finite momentum excitons residing in
Moir\'{e} superlattices of TMD HBLs and demonstrate that both exciton species
are susceptible to Purcell enhancement in cavity-modified photonic
environments. Our results form the basis for further developments of dipolar
exciton-polariton gases and condensates in hybrid cavity -- van der Waals
heterostructure systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.01914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.01914</id><created>2017-10-05</created><updated>2017-10-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kovalev</keyname><forenames>Anton V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viktorov</keyname><forenames>Evgeny A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Class-A mode-locked lasers: fundamental solutions</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures, accepted in 'Chaos'</comments><journal-ref>Chaos 27, 114318 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993882</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a delay differential equation (DDE) model for mode-locked
operation in class-A semiconductor lasers containing both gain and absorber
sections. The material processes are adiabatically eliminated as these are
considered fast in comparison to the delay time for a long cavity device. We
determine the steady states and analyze their bifurcations using DDE-BIFTOOL
[K. Engelborghs, T. Luzyanina, and D. Roose, ACM Trans. Math. Softw. 28, 1
(2002)]. Multiple forms of coexistence, transformation and hysteretic behavior
of stable steady states and fundamental periodic regimes are discussed in
bifurcation diagrams.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.02529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.02529</id><created>2017-10-06</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tonelli</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames><affiliation>for the LHCb Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>A novel measurement of $B^0_s$ and $D^-_s$ lifetimes using semileptonic
  decays at LHCb</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures. Talk presented at the APS Division of Particles
  and Fields Meeting (DPF 2017), July 31-August 4, 2017, Fermilab. C170731</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I report new, world-leading LHCb results on heavy meson lifetimes. We use a
novel approach that suppresses the shortcomings typically associated with
reconstruction of semileptonic decays, allowing for precise measurements of
lifetimes and other properties in collider experiments. We achieve a 15% and a
$2\times$ improvement over current best determinations of the flavor-specific
$B^0_s$ lifetime and $D^-_s$ lifetime, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.02625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.02625</id><created>2017-10-06</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bohdanowicz</keyname><forenames>Thomas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brand&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>Fernando G. S. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Hamiltonians for Exponentially Long Simulation</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages, typos and errors in transition rules corrected from v1,
  more references and acknowledgements added, more comments are welcome!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a Hamiltonian whose dynamics simulate the dynamics of every
other Hamiltonian up to exponentially long times in the system size. The
Hamiltonian is time-independent, local, one-dimensional, and translation
invariant. As a consequence, we show (under plausible computational complexity
assumptions) that the circuit complexity of the unitary dynamics under this
Hamiltonian grows steadily with time up to an exponential value in system size.
This result makes progress on a recent conjecture by Susskind, in the context
of the AdS/CFT correspondence, that the time evolution of the thermofield
double state of two conformal fields theories with a holographic dual has a
circuit complexity increasing linearly in time, up to exponential time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.02783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.02783</id><created>2017-10-08</created><updated>2017-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Apala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yiwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on Uniaxial Solutions in the Landau-de Gennes Theory</title><categories>math.AP cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study uniaxial solutions of the Euler-Lagrange equations for a Landau-de
Gennes free energy for nematic liquid crystals, with a fourth order bulk
potential, with and without elastic anisotropy. In the elastic isotropic case,
we show that (i) all uniaxial solutions of the Euler-Lagrange equations, with a
director field of certain symmetry, necessarily have the radial-hedgehog
structure modulo an orthogonal transformation, (ii) the &quot;escape into third
dimension&quot; director cannot correspond to a purely uniaxial solution of the
Landau-de Gennes Euler-Lagrange equations and we do not use artificial
assumptions on the scalar order parameter and (iii) there are no non-trivial
uniaxial solutions that have $\mathbf{e}_z$ as an eigenvector. In the elastic
anisotropic case, we prove that all uniaxial solutions of the corresponding
Euler-Lagrange equations, with a certain symmetry, are strictly of the
radial-hedgehog type, i.e. the elastic anisotropic case enforces the
radial-hedgehog structure (or the degree $+1$-vortex structure) more strongly
than the elastic isotropic case and the associated partial differential
equations are technically far more difficult than in the elastic isotropic
case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03067</id><created>2017-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Melikhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author></authors><title>Exotic polyquark states and their properties in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Plenary talk given at the XXIII International Workshop &quot;High Energy
  Physics and Quantum Field Theory&quot; (QFTHEP 2017), June 26-July 3, 2017,
  Yaroslavl, Russia</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 158, 01006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201715801006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate rigorous criteria for selecting diagrams to be taken into
account in the analysis of potential polyquark (tetra or penta) poles in QCD.
The central point of these criteria is the requirement that the Feynman
diagrams for the relevant Green functions contain four-quark (or, respectively,
five-quark in the pentaquark case) intermediate states and the corresponding
cuts. It is shown that some diagrams which &quot;visually&quot; seem to contain the
four-quark cuts, turn out to be free of these singularities and therefore
should not be taken into account when calculating the tetraquark properties. We
then consider large-$N_c$ QCD which in many cases provide qualitatively correct
picture of hadron properties and discuss in detail the tetraquark states. For
the &quot;direct&quot; and the &quot;recombination&quot; four-point Green functions, which may
potentially contain the tetraquark poles, we formulate large-$N_c$ consistency
conditions which strongly restrict the behaviour of the tetraquark-to-ordinary
meson transition amplitudes. In the end, these conditions allow us to obtain
constraints on width of the potential tetraquark states at large $N_c$. We
report that both flavor-exotic and cryptoexotic (i.e., flavor-nonexotic)
tetraquarks, if the corresponding poles exist, have a width of order
$O(1/N_c^2)$, i.e. they should be parametrically narrower compared to the
ordinary $\bar qq$ mesons with a width of order $O(1/N_c)$. Moreover, for
flavor-exotic states, the large-$N_c$ consistency conditions require two narrow
flavor-exotic states, each of these states coupling dominantly to one specific
meson-meson channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03207</id><created>2017-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Manoj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>Swarnajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Raja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puri</keyname><forenames>Sanjay</forenames></author></authors><title>Ordering Kinetics in the Random Bond XY Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>To appear in PRE</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 96, 042127 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.042127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comprehensive Monte Carlo study of domain growth in the
random-bond XY model with non-conserved kinetics. The presence of quenched
disorder slows down domain growth in d = 2; 3. In d = 2, we observe power-law
growth with a disorder-dependent exponent on the time-scales of our simulation.
In d = 3, we see the signature of an asymptotically logarithmic growth regime.
The scaling functions for the real-space correlation function are seen to be
independent of the disorder. However, the same does not apply for the two-time
autocorrelation function, demonstrating the breakdown of superuniversality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.06464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.06464</id><created>2017-10-17</created><updated>2017-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>HanYi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Mukul M.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Variable Compliance Method for Estimating In-Situ Stress and
  Leak-Off from DFIT Data</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that using Carter leak-off is an oversimplification that leads to
significant errors in the interpretation of DFIT data. Most importantly, this
article reveals that previous methods of estimating minimum in-situ stress
often lead to significant over or underestimates. Based on our modeling and
simulation results, we propose a much more accurate and reliable method to
estimate the minimum in-situ stress and fracture pressure dependent leak-off
rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08826</id><created>2017-10-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Schreiner</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasse</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hittle</keyname><forenames>Bradley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Himadri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokoloff</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomko</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author></authors><title>GooFit 2.0</title><categories>cs.MS hep-ex physics.data-an</categories><comments>Submitted to the ACAT 2017 proceedings, 6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The GooFit package provides physicists a simple, familiar syntax for
manipulating probability density functions and performing fits, and is highly
optimized for data analysis on NVIDIA GPUs and multithreaded CPU backends.
GooFit was updated to version 2.0, bringing a host of new features. A
completely revamped and redesigned build system makes GooFit easier to install,
develop with, and run on virtually any system. Unit testing, continuous
integration, and advanced logging options are improving the stability and
reliability of the system. Developing new PDFs now uses standard CUDA
terminology and provides a lower barrier for new users. The system now has
built-in support for multiple graphics cards or nodes using MPI, and is being
tested on a wide range of different systems. GooFit also has significant
improvements in performance on some GPU architectures due to optimized memory
access. Support for time-dependent four-body amplitude analyses has also been
added.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08916</id><created>2017-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Softky</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benford</keyname><forenames>Criscillia</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensory Metrics of Neuromechanical Trust</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO</categories><comments>59 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Softky, W. &amp; Benford C. (2017). &quot;Sensory Metrics of
  Neuromechanical Trust.&quot; Neural Computation 29, 2293-2351</journal-ref><doi>10.1162/NECO_a_00988</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Today digital sources supply an unprecedented component of human sensorimotor
data, the consumption of which is correlated with poorly understood maladies
such as Internet Addiction Disorder and Internet Gaming Disorder. This paper
offers a mathematical understanding of human sensorimotor processing as
multiscale, continuous-time vibratory interaction. We quantify human
informational needs using the signal processing metrics of entropy, noise,
dimensionality, continuity, latency, and bandwidth. Using these metrics, we
define the trust humans experience as a primitive statistical algorithm
processing finely grained sensorimotor data from neuromechanical interaction.
This definition of neuromechanical trust implies that artificial sensorimotor
inputs and interactions that attract low-level attention through frequent
discontinuities and enhanced coherence will decalibrate a brain's
representation of its world over the long term by violating the implicit
statistical contract for which self-calibration evolved. This approach allows
us to model addiction in general as the result of homeostatic regulation gone
awry in novel environments and digital dependency as a sub-case in which the
decalibration caused by digital sensorimotor data spurs yet more consumption of
them. We predict that institutions can use these sensorimotor metrics to
quantify media richness to improve employee well-being; that dyads and
family-size groups will bond and heal best through low-latency, high-resolution
multisensory interaction such as shared meals and reciprocated touch; and that
individuals can improve sensory and sociosensory resolution through deliberate
sensory reintegration practices. We conclude that we humans are the victims of
our own success, our hands so skilled they fill the world with captivating
things, our eyes so innocent they follow eagerly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08917</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Jariwala</keyname><forenames>Deep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoyan</keyname><forenames>Artur R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Joeson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atwater</keyname><forenames>Harry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Van der Waals Materials for Atomically-Thin Photovoltaics: Promise and
  Outlook</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b01103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional (2D) semiconductors provide a unique opportunity for
optoelectronics due to their layered atomic structure, electronic and optical
properties. To date, a majority of the application-oriented research in this
field has been focused on field-effect electronics as well as photodetectors
and light emitting diodes. Here we present a perspective on the use of 2D
semiconductors for photovoltaic applications. We discuss photonic device
designs that enable light trapping in nanometer-thickness absorber layers, and
we also outline schemes for efficient carrier transport and collection. We
further provide theoretical estimates of efficiency indicating that 2D
semiconductors can indeed be competitive with and complementary to conventional
photovoltaics, based on favorable energy bandgap, absorption, external
radiative efficiency, along with recent experimental demonstrations. Photonic
and electronic design of 2D semiconductor photovoltaics represents a new
direction for realizing ultrathin, efficient solar cells with applications
ranging from conventional power generation to portable and ultralight solar
power.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08924</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Wevers</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonker</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hodgkin</keyname><forenames>Simon T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostrzewa-Rutkowska</keyname><forenames>Zuzanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Diana L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rixon</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelemans</keyname><forenames>Gijs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roelens</keyname><forenames>Maroussia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyer</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>Floor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoldas</keyname><forenames>Abdullah</forenames></author></authors><title>The fast transient sky with Gaia</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures and 5 tables; MNRAS in press</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2625</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ESA Gaia satellite scans the whole sky with a temporal sampling ranging
from seconds and hours to months. Each time a source passes within the Gaia
field of view, it moves over 10 CCDs in 45 s and a lightcurve with 4.5 s
sampling (the crossing time per CCD) is registered. Given that the 4.5 s
sampling represents a virtually unexplored parameter space in optical time
domain astronomy, this data set potentially provides a unique opportunity to
open up the fast transient sky. We present a method to start mining the wealth
of information in the per CCD Gaia data. We perform extensive data filtering to
eliminate known on-board and data processing artefacts, and present a
statistical method to identify sources that show transient brightness
variations on ~2 hours timescales. We illustrate that by using the Gaia
photometric CCD measurements, we can detect transient brightness variations
down to an amplitude of 0.3 mag on timescales ranging from 15 seconds to
several hours. We search an area of ~23.5 square degrees on the sky, and find
four strong candidate fast transients. Two candidates are tentatively
classified as flares on M-dwarf stars, while one is probably a flare on a giant
star and one potentially a flare on a solar type star. These classifications
are based on archival data and the timescales involved. We argue that the
method presented here can be added to the existing Gaia Science Alerts
infrastructure for the near real-time public dissemination of fast transient
events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08939</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Valladares</keyname><forenames>Ariel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Isaias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinojosa-Romero</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valladares</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valladares</keyname><forenames>Renela M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in the solid phases of Bi. Is Bi-IV a superconductor?</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures, prepublished manuscript</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first successful theory of superconductivity was the one proposed by
Bardeen, Cooper and Schrieffer in 1957. This breakthrough fostered a remarkable
growth of the field that propitiated progress and questionings, generating
alternative theories to explain specific phenomena. For example, it has been
argued that Bismuth, being a semimetal with a low number of carriers, does not
comply with the basic hypotheses underlying BCS and therefore a different
approach should be considered. Nevertheless, in 2016 based on BCS we put forth
a prediction that Bi at ambient pressure becomes a superconductor at 1.3 mK
[1]. A year later an experimental group corroborated that in fact Bi is a
superconductor with a transition temperature of 0.53 mK [2], a result that
eluded previous work. So, since Bi is superconductive in almost all the
different structures and phases, the question is why Bi-IV has been elusive and
has not been found yet to superconduct? Here we present a study of the
electronic and vibrational properties of Bi-IV and infer its possible
superconductivity using a BCS approach. We predict that if the Bi-IV phase
structure were cooled down to liquid helium temperatures it would also
superconduct at a Tc of 4.25 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08945</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asaba</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tinsman</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk Rotational Symmetry Breaking in Kondo Insulator SmB6</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review X 7, 031054 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.031054</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kondo insulator samarium hexaboride (SmB6) has been intensely studied in
recent years as a potential candidate of a strongly correlated topological
insulator. One of the most exciting phenomena observed in SmB6 is the clear
quantum oscillations appearing in magnetic torque at a low temperature despite
the insulating behavior in resistance. These quantum oscillations show multiple
frequencies and varied effective masses. The origin of quantum oscillation is,
however, still under debate with evidence of both two-dimensional Fermi
surfaces and three-dimensional Fermi surfaces. Here, we carry out
angle-resolved torque magnetometry measurements in a magnetic field up to 45 T
and a temperature range down to 40 mK. With the magnetic field rotated in the
(010) plane, the quantum oscillation frequency of the strongest oscillation
branch shows a four-fold rotational symmetry. However, in the angular
dependence of the amplitude of the same branch, this four-fold symmetry is
broken and, instead, a twofold symmetry shows up, which is consistent with the
prediction of a two-dimensional Lifshitz-Kosevich model. No deviation of
Lifshitz-Kosevich behavior is observed down to 40 mK. Our results suggest the
existence of multiple light-mass surface states in SmB6, with their mobility
significantly depending on the surface disorder level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08958</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Longacre</keyname><forenames>Ron</forenames></author></authors><title>Tubes, Mono Jets, Squeeze Out and CME</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><report-no>BNL 114471_2017</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Glasma Flux Tubes, Mono Jets with squeeze out flow around them plus the
Chiral Magnetic Effect(CME) are physical phenomenon that generate two particle
correlation with respect to the reaction plane in mid-central 20\% to 30\%
Au-Au collision $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$ = 200.0 GeV measured at RHIC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08964</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n-Albo</keyname><forenames>Justo</forenames><affiliation>for the DUNE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Sensitivity of DUNE to long-baseline neutrino oscillation physics</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Proceedings of the European Physical Society conference on High
  Energy Physics (EPS-HEP) 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  DUNE is an international project, currently in its design phase, for neutrino
physics and proton-decay searches. It will consist of two detectors exposed to
a megawatt-scale muon neutrino beam that will be produced at Fermilab
(Illinois, USA). One detector will record particle interactions near the source
of the beam, while a second, much larger, detector comprising four 10-kilotonne
liquid argon TPCs will be installed at a depth of 1.5 km at SURF (South Dakota,
USA), about 1300 kilometres away of the neutrino source. Among the primary
scientific goals of DUNE is the precision measurement of the parameters that
govern neutrino mixing, including those still unknown: the octant in which the
$\theta_{23}$ mixing angle lies, the neutrino mass ordering and the value of
the CP violation phase. This paper discusses the sensitivity of the DUNE
experiment to these parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08968</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Draine</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames><affiliation>Princeton</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hensley</keyname><forenames>Brandon S.</forenames><affiliation>JPL</affiliation></author></authors><title>On the Shapes of Interstellar Grains: Modeling Extinction and
  Polarization by Speroids and Continuous Distributions of Ellipsoids</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>30 pages, 8 figures, submitted to ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although interstellar grains are known to be aspherical, their actual shapes
remain poorly constrained. We assess whether three distributions of ellipsoidal
shapes from the literature, employed principally for their convenient
mathematical properties, are suitable for describing the shapes of interstellar
grains. Randomly-selected shapes from each distribution are shown as
illustrations. The often-used BHCDE distribution includes a very large fraction
of extreme shapes: fully 10% of random draws have axial ratio a_3/a_1 &gt; 19.7,
and 5% have a_3/a_1 &gt; 33. Of the three distributions considered, the CDE2
appears to be most realistic. For each of the three CDEs considered, we derive
shape-averaged cross sections for extinction and polarization. Finally, we
describe a method for &quot;synthesizing&quot; a dielectric function for an assumed shape
or shape distribution if the actual absorption cross sections per grain volume
are known from observations. This synthetic dielectric function predicts the
wavelength dependence of polarization, which can then be compared to
observations to constrain the grain shape.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08992</id><created>2017-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ruiqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hongzhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Jianbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas Eruption Phenomenon Happening from Ga-In Alloy in Electrolyte</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a gas eruption phenomenon caused by electrolysis of liquid Ga-In
alloy in an electrolyte, especially NaOH solution. A volcanic eruption-like
blowout of gas occurred from the orifice on the alloy surface. In addition to
gas plume, large gas bubbles were also generated and the total gas yield
increased as In ratio was increased. It is found that destructiveness of the
passivation layer on the Ga-In alloy is critical to gas generation. The
mechanism of gas eruption can be ascribed to a galvanic interaction happens
owing to passivation film and alloy with different activity connected as
electrode in electrolyte. Further investigation demonstrated that the lattice
of the film expands because of the incorporation of indium, which brings about
the decrease in band gap and finally enhances more gas generation. These
findings regain the basic understanding of room temperature liquid metal inside
electrolyte.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.08995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.08995</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bushell</keyname><forenames>Zoe L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broderick</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nattermann</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joseph</keyname><forenames>Rita M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keddie</keyname><forenames>Joseph L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rorison</keyname><forenames>Judy M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volz</keyname><forenames>Kerstin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sweeney</keyname><forenames>Stephen J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Valence band-anticrossing in GaP$_{1-x}$Bi$_{x}$ dilute bismide alloys:
  giant bowing of the band gap and spin-orbit splitting energy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using spectroscopic ellipsometry measurements on GaP$_{1-x}$Bi$_{x}$/GaP
epitaxial layers up to $x = 3.7$% we observe a giant bowing of the direct band
gap ($E_{g}^{\Gamma}$) and valence band spin-orbit splitting energy
($\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$). $E_{g}^{\Gamma}$ ($\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$) is measured
to decrease (increase) by approximately 200 meV (240 meV) with the
incorporation of 1% Bi, corresponding to a greater than fourfold increase in
$\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$ in going from GaP to GaP$_{0.99}$Bi$_{0.01}$. The
evolution of $E_{g}^{\Gamma}$ and $\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$ with $x$ is
characterised by strong, composition-dependent bowing. We demonstrate that a
simple valence band-anticrossing model, parametrised directly from atomistic
supercell calculations, quantitatively describes the measured evolution of
$E_{g}^{\Gamma}$ and $\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$ with $x$. In contrast to the
well-studied GaAs$_{1-x}$Bi$_{x}$ alloy, in GaP$_{1-x}$Bi$_{x}$ substitutional
Bi creates localised impurity states lying energetically within the GaP host
matrix band gap. This leads to the emergence of an optically active band of
Bi-hybridised states, accounting for the overall large bowing of
$E_{g}^{\Gamma}$ and $\Delta_{\textrm{SO}}$ and in particular for the giant
bowing observed for $x \lesssim 1$%. Our analysis provides insight into the
action of Bi as an isovalent impurity, and constitutes the first detailed
experimental and theoretical analysis of the GaP$_{1-x}$Bi$_{x}$ alloy band
structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09003</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Pancheri</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonolis</keyname><forenames>Luisa</forenames></author></authors><title>The path to high-energy electron-positron colliders: from Wideroe's
  betatron to Touschek's AdA and to LEP</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures, presented at Bristol Workshop on the History of
  Particle Colliders, to be published in the 2017 Newsletter of IOP History of
  Physics group</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the road which led to the construction and exploitation of
electron positron colliders, hightlighting how the young physics student Bruno
Touschek met the Norwegian engineer Rolf Wideroe in Germany, during WWII, and
collaborated in building the 15 MeV betatron, a secret project directed by
Wideroe and financed by the Ministry of Aviation of the Reich. This is how
Bruno Touschek learnt the science of making particle accelerators and was
ready, many years later, to propose and build AdA, the first electron positron
collider, in Frascati, Italy, in 1960. We shall then see how AdA was brought
from Frascati to Orsay, in France. Taking advantage of the Orsay Linear
Accelerator as injector, the Franco-Italian team was able to prove that
collisions had taken place, opening the way to the use of particle colliders as
a mean to explore high energy physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09016</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>Siddarth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>Geoff</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boots</keyname><forenames>Byron</forenames></author></authors><title>Learning Hidden Quantum Markov Models</title><categories>stat.ML quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hidden Quantum Markov Models (HQMMs) can be thought of as quantum
probabilistic graphical models that can model sequential data. We extend
previous work on HQMMs with three contributions: (1) we show how classical
hidden Markov models (HMMs) can be simulated on a quantum circuit, (2) we
reformulate HQMMs by relaxing the constraints for modeling HMMs on quantum
circuits, and (3) we present a learning algorithm to estimate the parameters of
an HQMM from data. While our algorithm requires further optimization to handle
larger datasets, we are able to evaluate our algorithm using several synthetic
datasets. We show that on HQMM generated data, our algorithm learns HQMMs with
the same number of hidden states and predictive accuracy as the true HQMMs,
while HMMs learned with the Baum-Welch algorithm require more states to match
the predictive accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09023</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jianlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopinatth</keyname><forenames>Rahul Chandwani Varun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyce</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pflugfelder</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Gangjun</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-infrared laser thermal conjunctivoplasty</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conjunctivochalasis is a common cause of tear dysfunction due to the
conjunctiva becoming loose and wrinkly with age. The current solutions to this
disease include either surgical excision in the operating room, or
thermoreduction of the loose tissue with hot wire in the clinic. We developed a
near-infrared (NIR) laser thermal conjunctivoplasty (LTC) system, which gently
shrinks the redundant tissue. The NIR light is mainly absorbed by water, so the
heating is even and there is no bleeding. The system utilizes a 1460-nm
programmable laser diode system as a light source. A miniaturized handheld
probe delivers the laser light and focuses the laser into a 10x1 mm2 line. A
foot pedal is used to deliver a preset number of calibrated laser pulses. A
fold of loose conjunctiva is grasped by a pair of forceps. The infrared laser
light is delivered through an optical fiber and a laser line is focused exactly
on the conjunctival fold by a cylindrical lens. Ex vivo experiments using
porcine eye were performed with the optimal laser parameters. It was found that
up to 50% of conjunctiva shrinkage could be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09059</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Arguilla</keyname><forenames>Maxx Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katoch</keyname><forenames>Jyoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krymowski</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cultrara</keyname><forenames>Nicholas D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jinsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xi</keyname><forenames>Xiaoxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanks</keyname><forenames>Amanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Shishi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Richard D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Roland J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulstrup</keyname><forenames>S&#xf8;ren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bostwick</keyname><forenames>Aaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jozwiak</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>McComb</keyname><forenames>Dave</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotenberg</keyname><forenames>Eli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Windl</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawakami</keyname><forenames>Roland K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldberger</keyname><forenames>Joshua E.</forenames></author></authors><title>NaSn2As2: An Exfoliatable Layered van der Waals Zintl Phase</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>ACS Nano, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b04609</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discovery of new families of exfoliatable 2D crystals that have diverse
sets of electronic, optical, and spin-orbit coupling properties, enables the
realization of unique physical phenomena in these few-atom thick building
blocks and in proximity to other materials. Herein, using NaSn2As2 as a model
system, we demonstrate that layered Zintl phases having the stoichiometry
ATt2Pn2 (A = Group 1 or 2 element, Tt = Group 14 tetrel element and Pn = Group
15 pnictogen element) and feature networks separated by van der Waals gaps can
be readily exfoliated with both mechanical and liquid-phase methods. We
identified the symmetries of the Raman active modes of the bulk crystals via
polarized Raman spectroscopy. The bulk and mechanically exfoliated NaSn2As2
samples are resistant towards oxidation, with only the top surface oxidizing in
ambient conditions over a couple of days, while the liquid-exfoliated samples
oxidize much more quickly in ambient conditions. Employing angle-resolved
photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES), density functional theory (DFT), and
transport on bulk and exfoliated samples, we show that NaSn2As2 is a highly
conducting 2D semimetal, with resistivities on the order of 10-6 {\Omega} m.
Due to peculiarities in the band structure, the dominating p-type carriers at
low temperature are nearly compensated by the opening of n-type conduction
channels as temperature increases. This work further expands the family of
exfoliatable 2D materials to layered van der Waals Zintl phases, opening up
opportunities in electronics and spintronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09076</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Allahverdyan</keyname><forenames>Armen E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galstyan</keyname><forenames>Aram</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of Leadership in Communication</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cs.SI</categories><comments>17 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>PLoS ONE 11, e0159301 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a neuro-inspired model that mimics a discussion (or information
dissemination) process in a network of agents. During their interaction, agents
redistribute activity and network weights, resulting in emergence of leader(s).
The model is able to reproduce the basic scenarios of leadership known in
nature and society: laissez-faire (irregular activity, weak leadership, sizable
inter-follower interaction, autonomous sub-leaders); participative or
democratic (strong leadership, but with feedback from followers); and
autocratic (no feedback, one-way influence). Several pertinent aspects of these
scenarios are found as well---e.g., hidden leadership (a hidden clique of
agents driving the official autocratic leader), and successive leadership (two
leaders influence followers by turns). We study how these scenarios emerge from
inter-agent dynamics and how they depend on behavior rules of agents---in
particular, on their inertia against state changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09081</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures of Mechanosensitive Gating</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Biophys. J., 112(1) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.bpj.2016.12.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The question of how mechanically-gated membrane channels open and close is
notoriously difficult to address, especially if the protein structure is not
available. This perspective highlights the relevance of micropipette-aspirated
single-particle tracking--- used to obtain a channel's diffusion coefficient,
$D$, as a function of applied membrane tension, $\sigma$--- as an indirect
assay for determining functional behaviour in mechanosensitive channels. Whilst
ensuring that the protein remains integral to the membrane, such methods can be
used to identify not only the gating mechanism of a protein, but also
associated physical moduli, such as torsional- and dilational-rigidity, which
correspond to the protein's effective shape change. As an example, three
distinct $D$ versus $\sigma$ &quot;signatures&quot; are calculated, corresponding to
gating by dilation, gating by tilt, and a combination of both dilation and
tilt. Both advantages and disadvantages of the approach are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09087</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ayub</keyname><forenames>Muhammad</forenames></author></authors><title>Cold Atoms in Driven Optical Lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>175 pages, PhD Thesis (2013), Department of Electronics, Quaid-i-Azam
  University, Islamabad, Pakistan</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The center of mass dynamics of cold atoms and the Bose-Einstein condensate in
one dimensional optical lattice is considered both in the absence and in the
presence of external forcing. We discuss three situations for matter waves:
first, the cold atoms; second, sufficiently dilute condensate where the
dynamics are governed by the single particle wave packet dynamics; third,
strong interaction regime, where, inter-atomic interaction can no longer be
ignored. The analytical formalism developed for the two regimes, namely, deep
optical lattice and shallow optical lattice. Parametric dependencies of energy
spectrum and classical period, revival time and super revival are explained for
the two regimes.
  The dynamics of condensate in driven optical lattice crystal are analyzed by
studying dynamical stability of the condensate. The stability is determined by
the dispersion behavior of the condensate excited in driven optical lattice.
The recurrence behavior of the condensate close to the nonlinear resonances is
analyzed as a function of time for delicate recurrences which take place for
instance when lattice is weakly perturbed and robust recurrences which may
manifest themselves for sufficiently strong external driving force.
  The analysis is not only valid for dilute condensate but also applicable for
strongly interacting homogeneous condensate provided, the external modulation
causes no significant change in density profile of the condensate. We explain
parametric dependence of the dynamical recurrence times which can easily be
realized in laboratory experiments. In addition, we find a good agreement
between the obtained analytical results and numerical calculations. The
stability of condensate is also explored in driven optical lattice numerically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09088</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Ruixing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dosanjh</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonn</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extracting phase information about the superconducting order parameter
  from defect bound states</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Impurity bound states and quasi-particle scattering from these can serve as
sensitive probes for identifying the pairing state of a superconducting
condensate. We introduce and discuss defect bound state quasi-particle
interference (DBS-QPI) imaging as a tool to extract information about the
symmetry of the order parameter from spatial maps of the density of states
around magnetic and non-magnetic impurities. We show that the phase information
contained in the scattering patterns around impurities can provide valuable
information beyond what is obtained through conventional QPI imaging. Keeping
track of phase, rather than just magnitudes, in the Fourier transforms is
achieved through phase-referenced Fourier transforms that preserve both real
and imaginary parts of the QPI images. We further compare DBS-QPI to other
approaches which have been proposed to use either QPI or defect scattering to
distinguish different symmetries of the order parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09089</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Ruixing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dosanjh</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonn</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the Superconducting Order Parameter from Defect Bound
  State Quasiparticle Interference</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconducting order parameter is directly related to the pairing
interaction, with the amplitude determined by the interaction strength, while
the phase reflects the spatial structure of the interaction. However, given the
large variety of materials and their rich physical properties within the
iron-based high-Tc superconductors, the structure of the order parameter
remains controversial in many cases. Here, we introduce Defect Bound State
Quasi Particle Interference (DBS-QPI) as a new method to determine the
superconducting order parameter. Using a low-temperature scanning tunneling
microscope, we image in-gap bound states in the stoichiometric iron-based
superconductor LiFeAs and show that the bound states induced by defect
scattering are formed from Bogoliubov quasiparticles that have significant
spatial extent. Quasiparticle interference from these bound states has unique
signatures from which one can determine the phase of the order parameter as
well as the nature of the defect, i.e. whether it is better described as a
magnetic vs a nonmagnetic scatterer. DBS-QPI provides an easy but general
method to characterize the pairing symmetry of superconducting condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09092</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Staliunas</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marko&#x161;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmiak</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering properties of a PT dipole</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96 043852 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.043852</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetic response of PT-dipole is studied both analytically and
numerically. In analytical approach, dipole is represented by two point
scatterers. Within the first Born approximation, the asymmetry of the
scattering field with respect to the orientation of dipole is proven. In
numerical simulations, dipole is represented by two infinitely long, parallel
cylinders with opposite sign of imaginary part of refractive index. Numerical
data confirm the validity of the Born approximation in the weak scattering
limit, while significant deviations from the Born approximation were observed
for stronger scatterers and in the near-field range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09098</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Jianbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yongze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformable Soft Quantum Device based on Liquid Metals with Sandwiched
  Liquid Junctions</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum tunneling effect has been an important issue in both fundamental
science and practical applications. Classical quantum tunneling devices are
generally rigid in structures which may encounter technical difficulties during
fabrication, functional tuning and shape adapting. Here through introducing the
room-temperature liquid metals as two conductive electrodes and a soft even
liquid insulating layer sandwiched between them, we proposed a conceptually
innovative all-soft or liquid quantum device which would help realize a couple
of unconventional quantum capabilities such as flexibility, deformability,
transformability, and reconfigurability, etc. which may not be easily offered
by a rigid quantum device. Representative structural configurations to make
such transformable quantum devices via sandwiching various liquid
metal-insulating layer-liquid metal (LM-IL-LM) components are suggested. The
feasibility for making such an all-soft quantum device is interpreted through
experimental evidences and theoretical evaluations. Potential future
applications of the proposed devices in a group of emerging fields including
intelligent quantum systems and quantum computing are prospected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09105</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Hanna</keyname><forenames>Botros N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dinh</keyname><forenames>Nam T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Youngblood</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolotnov</keyname><forenames>Igor A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coarse-Grid Computational Fluid Dynamic (CG-CFD) Error Prediction using
  Machine Learning</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>WORKING PAPER (Submitted to Journal of Fluids Engineering, October
  2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the progress in high performance computing, Computational Fluid
Dynamics (CFD) simulations are still computationally expensive for many
practical engineering applications such as simulating large computational
domains and highly turbulent flows. One of the major reasons of the high
expense of CFD is the need for a fine grid to resolve phenomena at the relevant
scale, and obtain a grid-independent solution. The fine grid requirements often
drive the computational time step size down, which makes long transient
problems prohibitively expensive. In the research presented, the feasibility of
a Coarse Grid CFD (CG-CFD) approach is investigated by utilizing Machine
Learning (ML) algorithms. Relying on coarse grids increases the discretization
error. Hence, a method is suggested to produce a surrogate model that predicts
the CG-CFD local errors to correct the variables of interest. Given
high-fidelity data, a surrogate model is trained to predict the CG-CFD local
errors as a function of the coarse grid local features. ML regression
algorithms are utilized to construct a surrogate model that relates the local
error and the coarse grid features. This method is applied to a
three-dimensional flow in a lid driven cubic cavity domain. The performance of
the method was assessed by training the surrogate model on the flow full field
spatial data and tested on new data (from flows of different Reynolds number
and/or computed by different grid sizes). The proposed method maximizes the
benefit of the available data and shows potential for a good predictive
capability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09121</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;tz</keyname><forenames>Gunter M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Fibonacci universality classes in nonlinear fluctuating
  hydrodynamics</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><msc-class>82C27 (Primary) 82C05, 60K35 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a lattice gas model that without fine tuning of parameters is
expected to exhibit the so far elusive modified Kardar-Parisi-Zhang (KPZ)
universality class. To this end, we review briefly how non-linear fluctuating
hydrodynamics in one dimension predicts that all dynamical universality classes
in its range of applicability belong to an infinite discrete family which we
call Fibonacci family since their dynamical exponents are the Kepler ratios
$z_i = F_{i+1}/F_{i}$ of neighbouring Fibonacci numbers $F_i$, including
diffusion ($z_2=2$), KPZ ($z_3=3/2$), and the limiting ratio which is the
golden mean $z_\infty=(1+\sqrt{5})/2$. Then we revisit the case of two
conservation laws to which the modified KPZ model belongs. We also derive
criteria on the macroscopic currents to lead to other non-KPZ universality
classes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09129</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Multanen</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pogreb</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Yelena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shulzinger</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whyman</keyname><forenames>Gene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Under-liquid Self-Assembly of Submerged Buoyant Polymer Particles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>21 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>LANGMUIR Volume: 32 Issue: 23 Pages: 5714-5720 Published: JUN 14
  2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b00636</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The self-assembly of submerged cold-plasma-treated polyethylene beads is
reported. The plasma-treated immersed millimetrically-sized polyethylene beads
formed well-ordered 2D quasi-crystalline structures. The submerged floating of
light polyethylene beads is possible due to the energy gain achieved by the
wetting of the high-energy plasma-treated polymer surface prevailing over the
energy loss due to the upward climb of the liquid over the beads. The capillary
immersion attraction force is responsible for the observed self-assembly. The
observed 2D quasi-crystalline structures demonstrate dislocations and point
defects. Mechanical vibration of self-assembled rafts built of polyethylene
beads leads to the healing of point defects. The immersion capillary lateral
force governs the self-assembly, whereas the elastic force is responsible for
the repulsion of polymer beads.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09134</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whyman</keyname><forenames>Gene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shulzinger</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Starostin</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Propelling Rotator Driven by Soluto-Capillary Marangoni Flows</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS Volume: 110 Issue: 13 Article Number:
  131604 Published: MAR 27 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979590</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The self-propelled, longstanding rotation of the polymer tubing containing
camphor continuing for dozens of hours is reported. The rotator is driven by
the solutocapillary Marangoni flows owing to the dissolution of camphor. The
phenomenological model of self-propulsion is suggested and verified. Scaling
laws describing the quasi-stationary self-propulsion are proposed and tested
experimentally. The change in the surface tension, arising from the dissolution
of camphor and driving the rotator is estimated as 0.3 mN/m.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09135</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Musin</keyname><forenames>Albina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grynyov</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Propulsion of a Metallic Superoleophobic Micro-Boat</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>23 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>JOURNAL OF COLLOID AND INTERFACE SCIENCE Volume: 479 Pages:
  182-188 Published: OCT 1 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcis.2016.06.066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The self-propulsion of a heavy, superoleophobic, metallic micro-boat carrying
a droplet of various aqueous alcohol solutions as a fuel tank is reported. The
micro boat is driven by the solutocapillary Marangoni flow. The jump in the
surface tension owing to the condensation of alcohols on the water surface was
established experimentally. Maximal velocities of the self-propulsion were
registered as high as 0.05 m/s. The maximal velocity of the center mass of the
boat correlates with the maximal change in the surface tension, due to the
condensation of alcohols. The mechanism of the self-locomotion is discussed.
The phenomenological dynamic model describing the self-propulsion is reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09144</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Soffel</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopeikin</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Wen-Biao</forenames></author></authors><title>Advanced relativistic VLBI model for geodesy</title><categories>astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories><comments>37 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Geodesy, 91: 783 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00190-016-0956-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our present relativistic part of the geodetic VLBI model for Earthbound
antennas is a consensus model which is considered as a standard for processing
high-precision VLBI observations. It was created as a compromise between a
variety of relativistic VLBI models proposed by different authors as documented
in the IERS Conventions 2010. The accuracy of the consensus model is in the
picosecond range for the group delay but this is not sufficient for current
geodetic pur- poses. This paper provides a fully documented derivation of a new
relativistic model having an accuracy substantially higher than one picosecond
and based upon a well accepted formalism of relativistic celestial mechanics,
astrometry and geodesy. Our new model fully confirms the consensus model at the
picosecond level and in several respects goes to a great extent beyond it. More
specifically, terms related to the acceleration of the geocenter are considered
and kept in the model, the gravitational time-delay due to a massive body
(planet, Sun, etc.) with arbitrary mass and spin-multipole moments is derived
taking into account the motion of the body, and a new formalism for the
time-delay problem of radio sources located at finite distance from VLBI
stations is presented. Thus, the paper presents a substantially elaborated
theoretical justification of the consensus model and its significant extension
that allows researchers to make concrete estimates of the magnitude of residual
terms of this model for any conceivable configuration of the source of light,
massive bodies, and VLBI stations. The largest terms in the relativistic time
delay which can affect the current VLBI observations are from the quadrupole
and the angular momentum of the gravitating bodies that are known from the
literature. These terms should be included in the new geodetic VLBI model for
improving its consistency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09145</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Molenaar</keyname><forenames>Gijs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>KERN</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  KERN is a bi-annually released set of radio astronomical software packages.
It should contain most of the standard tools that a radio astronomer needs to
work with radio telescope data. The goal of KERN is to save time and prevent
frustration in setting up of scientific pipelines, and to assist in achieving
scientific reproducibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09158</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Multanen</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grynyov</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musin</keyname><forenames>Albina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Yelena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Camphor-Engine-Driven Micro-Boat Guides Evolution of Chemical Gardens</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS Volume: 7 Article Number: 3930 Published: JUN
  21 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-04337-w</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A micro-boat self-propelled by a camphor engine, carrying seed crystals of
FeCl3, promoted the evolution of chemical gardens when placed on the surface of
aqueous solutions of potassium hexacyanoferrate. Inverse chemical gardens
(growing from the top downward) were observed. The growth of the inverse
chemical gardens was slowed down with an increase in the concentration of the
potassium hexacyanoferrate. Heliciform precipitates were formed under the
self-propulsion of the micro-boat. A phenomenological model, satisfactorily
describing the self locomotion of the camphor-driven micro-boat, is introduced
and checked.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09165</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>Debora P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buss</keyname><forenames>Karina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silvano</keyname><forenames>Caio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DAvila</keyname><forenames>Beatriz N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anteneodo</keyname><forenames>Celia</forenames></author></authors><title>Physics courses of the Federal University of Santa Catarina : evasion
  and gender</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, in Portuguese, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we analyse all existing data related to the number of incomers
and outcomers (who actually obtain the degree) of the following courses offered
at the Federal University of Santa Catarina: physics teaching, bachelor in
physics, master of sciences in physics and doctorate in physics, corresponding
to the 1998-2017 period, according to their availability. The data point
towards a great male predominance (larger than 76%) and a huge evasion of both
sexes (in average, less than 20% of the undergraduate incomers obtain the
degree), the evasion being lower in the postgraduate courses and always
slightly higher for women.
  The average number of incomers and outcomers per year decreases as the
students advance from graduate to postgraduate courses, although many students
in the postgraduate courses come from other institutions. The proportion of
women decreases as the carrier advances.
  The results indicate the need of complementary studies that can help the
identification of the causes of such a high evasion in order to minimize them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09185</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Raktima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magudapathy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardar</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandian</keyname><forenames>Ramanathaswamy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>Sandip</forenames></author></authors><title>VO2 microcrystals as advanced smart window material at semiconductor to
  metal transition</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>2017 J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 50 465602</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6463/aa8e87</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Textured VO2(011) microcrystals are grown in the monoclinic, M1 phase which
undergo a reversible first order semiconductor to metal transition (SMT)
accompanied by a structural phase transition to rutile tetragonal, R phase.
Around the phase transition, VO2 also experiences noticeable change in its
optical and electrical properties. A change in color of the VO2 micro crystals
from white to cyan around the transition temperature is observed, which is
further understood by absorption of red light using temperature dependent
ultraviolet-visible spectroscopic analysis and photoluminescence studies. The
absorption of light in the red region is explained by the optical transition
between Hubbard states, confirming the electronic correlation as the driving
force for SMT in VO2. The thermochromism in VO2 has been studied for smart
window applications so far in the IR region, which supports the opening of the
band gap in semiconducting phase; whereas there is hardly any report in the
management of visible light. The filtering of blue light along with reflection
of infrared above the semiconductor to metal transition temperature make VO2
applicable as advanced smart windows for overall heat management of a closure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09191</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chudoba</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyda</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzubiella</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>A temperature-dependent implicit-solvent model of polyethylene glycol in
  aqueous solution</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A temperature (T)-dependent coarse-grained (CG) Hamiltonian of polyethylene
glycol/oxide (PEG/PEO) in aqueous solution is reported to be used in
implicit-solvent material models in a wide temperature (i.e., solvent quality)
range. The T-dependent nonbonded CG interactions are derived from a combined
&quot;bottom-up&quot; and &quot;top-down&quot; approach. The pair potentials calculated from
atomistic replica-exchange molecular dynamics simulations in combination with
the iterative Boltzmann inversion are post-refined by benchmarking to
experimental data of the radius of gyration. For better handling and a fully
continuous transferability in T-space, the pair potentials are conveniently
truncated and mapped to an analytic formula with three structural parameters
expressed as explicit continuous functions of T. It is then demonstrated that
this model without further adjustments successfully reproduces other
experimentally known key thermodynamic properties of semi-dilute PEG solutions
such as the full equation of state (i.e., T-dependent osmotic pressure) for
various chain lengths as well as their cloud point (or collapse) temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09196</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Laloy</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe9;rault</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacques</keyname><forenames>Diederik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>Niklas</forenames></author></authors><title>Inversion using a new low-dimensional representation of complex binary
  geological media based on a deep neural network</title><categories>stat.ML physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Advances in Water Resources (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.advwatres.2017.09.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Efficient and high-fidelity prior sampling and inversion for complex
geological media is still a largely unsolved challenge. Here, we use a deep
neural network of the variational autoencoder type to construct a parametric
low-dimensional base model parameterization of complex binary geological media.
For inversion purposes, it has the attractive feature that random draws from an
uncorrelated standard normal distribution yield model realizations with spatial
characteristics that are in agreement with the training set. In comparison with
the most commonly used parametric representations in probabilistic inversion,
we find that our dimensionality reduction (DR) approach outperforms principle
component analysis (PCA), optimization-PCA (OPCA) and discrete cosine transform
(DCT) DR techniques for unconditional geostatistical simulation of a
channelized prior model. For the considered examples, important compression
ratios (200 - 500) are achieved. Given that the construction of our
parameterization requires a training set of several tens of thousands of prior
model realizations, our DR approach is more suited for probabilistic (or
deterministic) inversion than for unconditional (or point-conditioned)
geostatistical simulation. Probabilistic inversions of 2D steady-state and 3D
transient hydraulic tomography data are used to demonstrate the DR-based
inversion. For the 2D case study, the performance is superior compared to
current state-of-the-art multiple-point statistics inversion by sequential
geostatistical resampling (SGR). Inversion results for the 3D application are
also encouraging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09199</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaniel</keyname><forenames>Gilad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Multanen</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Paradoxical Coffee-Stain Effect Driven by the Marangoni Flow Observed on
  Oil-Infused Surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES A-PHYSICOCHEMICAL AND ENGINEERING ASPECTS
  Volume: 522 Pages: 355-360 Published: JUN 5 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.colsurfa.2017.03.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Formation of coffee stain deposits under evaporation of droplets containing
aqueous solution of salts placed on silicone-oil impregnated substrates was
observed. The formation of ring-like deposits was registered for various molar
concentrations of salts for the droplets of 5-300 microlitres in volume. The
effect occurred when the contact line was de-pinned, and the evaporation from
the edge of a droplet was stopped by the silicone oil. The formation of the
coffee stain deposit is related to the soluto-capillary Marangoni flow; the
influence of the thermo-capillary flow taking place in parallel is negligible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09213</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fraix-Burnet</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames><affiliation>IPAG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>D'Onofrio</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames><affiliation>OAPD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Marziani</keyname><forenames>Paola</forenames></author></authors><title>Phylogenetic Analyses of Quasars and Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Frontiers in Astronomy and Space Sciences, Frontiers Media, 2017,
  4, pp.20</journal-ref><doi>10.3389/fspas.2017.00020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phylogenetic approaches have proven to be useful in astrophysics. We have
recently published a Maximum Parsimony (or cladistics) analysis on two samples
of 215 and 85 low-z quasars (z &lt; 0.7) which offer a satisfactory coverage of
the Eigenvector 1-derived main sequence. Cladistics is not only able to group
sources radiating at higher Eddington ratios, to separate radio-quiet (RQ) and
radio-loud (RL) quasars and properly distinguishes core-dominated and
lobe-dominated quasars, but it suggests a black hole mass threshold for
powerful radio emission as already proposed elsewhere. An interesting
interpretation from this work is that the phylogeny of quasars may be
represented by the ontogeny of their central black hole, i.e. the increase of
the black hole mass. However these exciting results are based on a small sample
of low-z quasars, so that the work must be extended. We are here faced with two
difficulties. The first one is the current lack of a larger sample with similar
observables. The second one is the prohibitive computation time to perform a
cladistic analysis on more that about one thousand objects. We show in this
paper an experimental strategy on about 1500 galaxies to get around this
difficulty. Even if it not related to the quasar study, it is interesting by
itself and opens new pathways to generalize the quasar findings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09219</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Brida</keyname><forenames>Mattia Dalla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giusti</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepe</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD in a moving frame: an exploratory study</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure; Proceedings of the 35th International Symposium on
  Lattice Field Theory, 18-24 June 2017, Granada, Spain</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The framework of shifted boundary conditions has proven to be a very powerful
tool for the non-perturbative investigation of thermal quantum field theories.
For instance, it has been successfully considered for the determination of the
equation of state of SU(3) Yang-Mills theory with high accuracy. The set-up can
be generalized to QCD and it is expected to lead to a similar breakthrough. We
present first results for QCD with three flavours of non-perturbatively
O($a$)-improved Wilson fermions and shifted boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09221</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Chanbum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kandu&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chudoba</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronneburg</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Risse</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballauff</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzubiella</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular simulations of electrolyte structure and dynamics in
  lithium-sulfur battery solvents</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The performance of modern lithium-sulfur (Li/S) battery systems critically
depends on the electrolyte and solvent compositions. For fundamental molecular
insights and rational guidance of experimental developments, efficient and
sufficiently accurate molecular simulations are thus in urgent need. Here, we
construct a molecular dynamics (MD) computer simulation model of representative
state-of-the art electrolyte-solvent systems for Li/S batteries constituted by
lithium-bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide (LiTFSI) and LiNO3 electrolytes in
mixtures of the organic solvents 1,2-dimethoxyethane (DME) and 1,3-dioxolane
(DOL). We benchmark and verify our simulations by comparing structural and
dynamic features with various available experimental reference systems and
demonstrate their applicability for a wide range of electrolyte-solvent
compositions. For the state-of-the-art battery solvent, we finally calculate
and discuss the detailed composition of the first lithium solvation shell, the
temperature dependence of lithium diffusion, as well as the electrolyte
conductivities and lithium transference numbers. Our model will serve as a
basis for efficient future predictions of electrolyte structure and transport
in complex electrode confinements for the optimization of modern Li/S batteries
(and related devices).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09223</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ivchenko</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganichev</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-dependent photogalvanic effects (A Review)</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we review both theoretical and experimental studies on
spin-related photogalvanic effects. A short phenomenological introduction is
followed by the discussion of the circular photogalvanic effect, the direct and
inverse spin-galvanic effects and the trembling motion of spin-polarized
electrons. Then we consider the pure spin currents and magneto-gyrotropic
photocurrents. Finally, we discuss the spin-dependent photocurrents in
topological insulators and Weyl semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09224</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kazachkov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Multanen</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danchuk</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bormashenko</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Friction, Free Axes of Rotation and Entropy</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 images</comments><journal-ref>ENTROPY Volume: 19 Issue: 3 Article Number: 123 Published: MAR
  2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19030123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Friction forces acting on rotators may promote their alignment and therefore
eliminate degrees of freedom in their movement. The alignment of rotators by
friction force was demonstrated by experiments performed with different
spinners, demonstrating how friction generates negentropy in a system of
rotators. A gas of rigid rotators influenced by friction force is considered.
The orientational negentropy generated by a friction force was estimated with
the Sackur-Tetrode equation. The minimal change in total entropy of a system of
rotators, corresponding to their eventual alignment, decreases with
temperature. The reported effect may be of the primary importance for a phase
equilibrium and motion of ubiquitous colloidal and granular systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09232</id><created>2017-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Makarenko</keyname><forenames>O</forenames></author></authors><title>Model equations and structures formation for the media with memory</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><journal-ref>Ukr. J. Phys. 2012, Vol. 57, N 4, p.408-421</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose new types of models of the appearance of small- and large scale
structures in media with memory, including a hyperbolic modification of the
Navier-Stokes equations and a class of dynamical low-dimensional models with
memory effects. On the basis of computer modeling, the formation of the
small-scale structures and collapses and the appearance of new chaotic
solutions are demonstrated. Possibilities of the application of some proposed
models to the description of the burst-type processes and collapses o nthe Sun
are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09237</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nibbelink</keyname><forenames>Stefan Groot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loukas</keyname><forenames>Orestis</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;tter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parr</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaudrevange</keyname><forenames>Patrick K. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tension Between a Vanishing Cosmological Constant and Non-Supersymmetric
  Heterotic Orbifolds</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>1+39 pages</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP 1104/17</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate under which conditions the cosmological constant vanishes
perturbatively at the one-loop level for heterotic strings on
non-supersymmetric toroidal orbifolds. To obtain model-independent results,
which do not rely on the gauge embedding details, we require that the
right-moving fermionic partition function vanishes identically in every
orbifold sector. This means that each sector preserves at least one, but not
always the same Killing spinor. The existence of such Killing spinors is
related to the representation theory of finite groups, i.e. of the point group
that underlies the orbifold. However, by going through all inequivalent
(Abelian and non-Abelian) point groups of six-dimensional toroidal orbifolds we
show that this is never possible: For any non-supersymmetric orbifold there is
always (at least) one sector, that does not admit any Killing spinor. The
underlying mathematical reason for this no-go result is formulated in a
conjecture, which we have tested by going through an even larger number of
finite groups. This conjecture could be applied to situations beyond symmetric
toroidal orbifolds, like asymmetric orbifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09248</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Molinari</keyname><forenames>Luca Guido</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on Wick's theorem in many-body theory</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.str-el math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In these pedagogical notes I introduce the operator form of Wick's theorem,
i.e. a procedure to bring to normal order a product of 1-particle creation and
destruction operators, with respect to some reference many-body state. Both the
static and the time- ordered cases are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09252</id><created>2017-10-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Grytsay</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musatenko</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Organization and Fractality in a Metabolic Process of the Krebs
  Cycle</title><categories>q-bio.MN nlin.AO nlin.CD</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1602.09054</comments><journal-ref>Ukr.Biochem.J. 2013; Volume 85, Issue 5, Sep-Oct, pp. 191-200</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ubj85.05.191</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the help of a mathematical model, the metabolic process of the Krebs
cycle is studied. The autocatalytic processes resulting in both the formation
of the self-organization in the Krebs cycle and the appearance of a cyclicity
of its dynamics are determined. Some structural-functional connections creating
the synchronism of an autoperiodic functioning at the transport in the
respiratory chain and the oxidative phosphorylation are investigated. The
conditions for breaking the synchronization of processes, increasing the
multiplicity of a cyclicity, and for the appearance of chaotic modes are
analyzed. The phase-parametric diagram of a cascade of bifurcations showing the
transition to a chaotic mode by the Feigenbaum scenario is obtained. The
fractal nature of the revealed cascade of bifurcations is demonstrated. The
strange attractors formed as a result of the folding are obtained. The results
obtained give the idea of structural-functional connections, due to which the
self-organization appears in the metabolic process running in a cell. The
constructed mathematical model can be applied to the study of the toxic and
allergic effects of drugs and various substances on the metabolism of a cell.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09255</id><created>2017-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>Isha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babu</keyname><forenames>Sujin B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Aggregation kinetics of irreversible patches coupled with reversible
  isotropic interaction leading to chains, bundles and globules</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present study we are performing simulation of simple model of two
patch colloidal particles undergoing irreversible diffusion limited cluster
aggregation using patchy Brownian cluster dynamics. In addition to the
irreversible aggregation of patches, the spheres are coupled with isotropic
reversible aggregation through the Kern-Frenkel potential. Due to the presence
of anisotropic and isotropic potential we have also defined 3 different kinds
of clusters formed due to anisotropic potential and isotropic potential only as
well as both the potentials together. We have investigated the effect of patch
size on self-assembly under different solvent qualities for various volume
fractions. We will show that at low volume fractions during aggregation
process, we end up in a chain conformation for smaller patch size while in a
globular conformation for bigger patch size. We also observed a chain to bundle
transformation depending on the attractive interaction strength between the
chains or in other words depending on the quality of the solvent. We will also
show that bundling process is very similar to nucleation and growth phenomena
observed in colloidal system with short range attraction. We have also studied
the bond angle distribution for this system, where for small patches only 2
angles are more probable indicating chain formation, while for bundling at very
low volume fraction a tail is developed in the distribution. While for the case
of higher patch angle this distribution is broad compared to the case of low
patch angles showing we have a more globular conformation. We are also
proposing a model for the formation of bundles which are similar to amyloid
fibers using two patch colloidal particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09256</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chassande-Mottin</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebigot</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magaldi</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chase</keyname><forenames>Eve</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pai</keyname><forenames>Archana</forenames></author><author><keyname>V</keyname><forenames>Gayathri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedovato</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author></authors><title>Wavelet graphs for the direct detection of gravitational waves</title><categories>astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures. Presented at XXVth Colloque GRETSI, Lyon 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A second generation of gravitational wave detectors will soon come online
with the objective of measuring for the first time the tiny gravitational
signal from the coalescence of black hole and/or neutron star binaries. In this
communication, we propose a new time-frequency search method alternative to
matched filtering techniques that are usually employed to detect this signal.
This method relies on a graph that encodes the time evolution of the signal and
its variability by establishing links between coefficients in the multi-scale
time-frequency decomposition of the data. We provide a proof of concept for
this approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09260</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Sumanta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shendre</keyname><forenames>Sushant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Zhigang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Vijay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Dao Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dang</keyname><forenames>Cuong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Weijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demir</keyname><forenames>Hilmi Volkan</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature-dependent Optoelectronic Properties of Quasi-2D Colloidal
  Cadmium Selenide Nanoplatelets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Published in Royal Society of Chemistry, Nanoscale (12 pages, 9
  figures)</comments><journal-ref>Sumanta Bose et al., Nanoscale, 2017,9, 6595-6605</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7NR00163K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colloidal Cadmium Selenide (CdSe) nanoplatelets (NPLs) are a recently
developed class of efficient luminescent nanomaterial suitable for
optoelectronic device applications. A change in temperature greatly affects
their electronic bandstructure and luminescence properties. It is important to
understand how-and-why the characteristics of NPLs are influenced, particularly
at elevated temperature, where both reversible and irreversible quenching
processes come into picture. Here we present a study on the effect of elevated
temperature on the characteristics of colloidal CdSe NPLs. We used an
effective-mass envelope function theory based 8-band k$\cdot$p model and
density-matrix theory considering exciton-phonon interaction. We observed the
photoluminescence (PL) spectra at various temperatures for their photon
emission energy, PL linewidth and intensity by considering the exciton-phonon
interaction with both acoustic and optical phonons using Bose-Einstein
statistical factors. With rise in temperature we observed a fall in the
transition energy (emission redshift), matrix element, Fermi factor and quasi
Fermi separation, with reduction in intraband state gaps and increased
interband coupling. Also, there was a fall in the PL intensity, along with
spectral broadening due to an intraband scattering effect. The predicted
transition energy values and simulated PL spectra at varying temperatures
exhibit appreciable consistency with experimental results. Our findings have
important implications for application of NPLs in optoelectronic devices, such
as NPL lasers and LEDs, operating much above room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09268</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09268</id><created>2017-10-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bowman</keyname><forenames>Clark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaplain</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matzavinos</keyname><forenames>Anastasios</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative particle dynamics simulation of critical pore size in a
  lipid bilayer membrane</title><categories>cond-mat.soft q-bio.SC</categories><msc-class>92B99, 76Z99</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate with computer simulations the critical radius of pores in a
lipid bilayer membrane. Ilton et al. (2016) recently showed that nucleated
pores in a homopolymer film can increase or decrease in size, depending on
whether they are larger or smaller than a critical size which scales linearly
with film thickness. Using dissipative particle dynamics, a particle-based
simulation method, we investigate the same scenario for a lipid bilayer
membrane whose structure is determined by lipid-water interactions. We simulate
a perforated membrane in which holes larger than a critical radius grow, while
holes smaller than the critical radius close, as in the experiment of Ilton et
al. (2016). By altering system parameters such as the number of particles per
lipid and the periodicity, we also describe scenarios in which pores of any
initial size can seal or even remain stable, showing a fundamental difference
in the behavior of lipid membranes from polymer films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09273</id><created>2017-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Lipovka</keyname><forenames>Anton A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meza</keyname><forenames>Armando</forenames></author></authors><title>Green function for the Poisson equation in a general case of
  astrophysical interest</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In present paper we suggest exact solution of the Poisson problem which
appears in frequently addressed applications regarding calculation of the
gravitational potential of spiral galaxies. We suggest an analytical solution
for the problem in cylindrical coordinates by using the finite integral
transform technique. The final solution is presented as expansion on the
eigenfunctions of the corresponding Sturm-Liouville problem. Green function of
the problem is constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09278</id><created>2017-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Traversa</keyname><forenames>Fabio L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cicotti</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheldon</keyname><forenames>Forrest</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Ventra</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of an exponential speed-up in the solution of hard optimization
  problems</title><categories>cs.AI cs.CC nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optimization problems pervade essentially every scientific discipline and
industry. Many such problems require finding a solution that maximizes the
number of constraints satisfied. Often, these problems are particularly
difficult to solve because they belong to the NP-hard class, namely algorithms
that always find a solution in polynomial time are not known. Over the past
decades, research has focused on developing heuristic approaches that attempt
to find an approximation to the solution. However, despite numerous research
efforts, in many cases even approximations to the optimal solution are hard to
find, as the computational time for further refining a candidate solution grows
exponentially with input size. Here, we show a non-combinatorial approach to
hard optimization problems that achieves an exponential speed-up and finds
better approximations than the current state-of-the-art. First, we map the
optimization problem into a boolean circuit made of specially designed,
self-organizing logic gates, which can be built with (non-quantum) electronic
components; the equilibrium points of the circuit represent the approximation
to the problem at hand. Then, we solve its associated non-linear ordinary
differential equations numerically, towards the equilibrium points. We
demonstrate this exponential gain by comparing a sequential MatLab
implementation of our solver with the winners of the 2016 Max-SAT competition
on a variety of hard optimization instances. We show empirical evidence that
our solver scales linearly with the size of the problem, both in time and
memory, and argue that this property derives from the collective behavior of
the simulated physical circuit. Our approach can be applied to other types of
optimization problems and the results presented here have far-reaching
consequences in many fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09279</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghannad</keyname><forenames>Zahra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pajouh</keyname><forenames>Hossein Hakimi</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous diffusion due to the non-Markovian process of the dust
  particle velocity in complex plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, Published in Physics Letters A journal. arXiv
  admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1704.07980</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.10.026</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the motion of a dust particle under the influence of the random
force due to dust charge fluctuations is considered as a non-Markovian
stochastic process. Memory effects in the velocity process of the dust particle
are studied. A model is developed based on the fractional Langevin equation for
the motion of the dust grain. The fluctuation-dissipation theorem for the dust
grain is derived from this equation. The mean-square displacement and the
velocity autocorrelation function of the dust particle are obtained in terms of
the Mittag-Leffler functions. Their asymptotic behavior and the dust particle
temperature due to charge fluctuations are studied in the long-time limit. As
an interesting result, it is found that the presence of memory effects in the
velocity process of the dust particle as a non-Markovian process can cause an
anomalous diffusion in dusty plasmas. In this case, the velocity
autocorrelation function of the dust particle has a power-law decay like
$t^{-\alpha-2}$, where the exponent $\alpha$ take values $0&lt;\alpha&lt;1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09281</id><created>2017-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Savitzky</keyname><forenames>Benjamin H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baggari</keyname><forenames>Ismail El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clement</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waite</keyname><forenames>Emily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheckelton</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasco</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Admasu</keyname><forenames>Alemayehu S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jaewook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheong</keyname><forenames>Sang-Wook</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>Tyrel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hovden</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kourkoutis</keyname><forenames>Lena F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Image registration of low signal-to-noise cryo-STEM data</title><categories>eess.SP physics.data-an</categories><comments>25 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combining multiple fast image acquisitions to mitigate scan noise and drift
artifacts has proven essential for picometer precision, quantitative analysis
of atomic resolution scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) data. For
very low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) image stacks - frequently required for
undistorted imaging at liquid nitrogen temperatures - image registration is
particularly delicate, and standard approaches may either fail, or produce
subtly specious reconstructed lattice images. We present an approach which
effectively registers and averages image stacks which are challenging due to
their low-SNR and propensity for unit cell misalignments. Registering all
possible image pairs in a multi-image stack leads to significant information
surplus. In combination with a simple physical picture of stage drift, this
enables identification of incorrect image registrations, and determination of
the optimal image shifts from the complete set of relative shifts. We
demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on experimental, cryogenic STEM
datasets, highlighting subtle artifacts endemic to low-SNR lattice images and
how they can be avoided. High-SNR average images with information transfer out
to 0.72 A are achieved at 300 kV and with the sample cooled to near liquid
nitrogen temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09284</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhaba</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parameterization of the deuteron wave functions and form factors</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1706.08306</comments><journal-ref>World Scientific News Vol. 87, P. 222-232 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Minimization of the number of numerically calculated coefficients for new
analytical forms as a product of exponential function r1 by the sum of the
exponential terms Ai*exp(-ai*r2) have been done. The optimum is N=10.
Calculations have been done for realistic phenomenological Reid93 potential.
Spherical S0 and quadrupole S2 form factors is parameterized by the
coefficients for deuteron wave function in coordinate representation. The
result t20(p) in wide area of momentas for Reid93 potential agreed well with
the literature results for other potential nucleon-nucleon models, and with
experimental datas of world collaborations and reviews. The obtained results
will allow studying the deuteron electromagnetic structure, its form-factors,
differential cross section of double scattering in more detail in future, and
also for calculations the theoretical values of spin observables in dp-
scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09341</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Borovikov</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendelev</keyname><forenames>Mikhail I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Alexander H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solute effects on interfacial dislocation emission in nanomaterials:
  nucleation site competition and neutralization</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interfacial nucleation is the dominant process of dislocation generation
during the plastic deformation of nano-crystalline materials. Solute additions
intended to stabilize nano-crystalline metals against grain growth, may
segregate to the grain boundaries and triple junctions where they can affect
the process of the dislocation emission. In this Letter we demonstrate that the
effect of solute addition in a nano-crystalline material containing competing
solute segregation sites and dislocation sources can be very complex due to
different rates of segregation at different interfaces. Moreover, at large
concentrations, when the solutes form clusters near the grain boundaries or
triple junctions, the interfaces between these clusters and the matrix can
introduce new dislocation emission sources, which can be activated under lower
applied stress. Thus, the strength maximum can occur at a certain solute
concentration: adding solutes beyond this optimal solute concentration can
reduce the strength of the material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09344</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanborn</keyname><forenames>Barbara A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The uncertainty principle and the energy identity for holomorphic maps
  in geometric quantum mechanics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theory of geometric quantum mechanics describes a quantum system as a
Hamiltonian dynamical system with a complex projective Hilbert space as its
phase space, thus equipped with a Riemannian metric in addition to a symplectic
structure. This paper extends the geometric quantum theory to include aspects
of the symplectic topology of the state space by identifying the
Robertson-Schr\&quot;{o}dinger uncertainty relation for pure quantum states as the
differential version of the energy identity in the theory of $J$-holomorphic
curves. We consider a family of maps from a Riemann surface into a
finite-dimensional quantum state space by using the vector fields generated by
two quantum observables,and show that the Fubini-Study metric tensor pulls back
by such a map to the covariance tensor for the two observables. By calculating
the map energy density in the pull-back metric, the uncertainty relation is
represented as an equality that compares the map energy differential to the sum
of the pull-back of the symplectic form and a positive definite term that
vanishes when the map is holomorphic. Saturation of the
Robertson-Schr\&quot;{o}dinger inequality occurs when the map is conformal and the
off-diagonal covariance terms vanish. For compact Riemann surfaces where such a
map can be globally defined, if the map is holomorphic, it is harmonic and its
image is a minimal surface. In this case, the uncertainty product integral is a
topological invariant that depends only on the homology class of the curve
modulo its boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09345</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Baranov</keyname><forenames>Denis G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krasnok</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent Virtual Absorption Based on Complex Zero Excitation for Ideal
  Light Capturing</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>To be published in Optica</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Absorption of light is directly associated with dissipative processes in a
material. In suitably tailored resonators, a specific level of dissipation can
support coherent perfect absorption, the time-reversed analogue of lasing,
which enables total absorption and zero scattering in open cavities. On the
contrary, the scattering zeros of lossless objects strictly occur at complex
frequencies. While usually considered non-physical due to their divergent
response in time, these zeros play a crucial role in the overall scattering
dispersion. Here, we introduce the concept of coherent virtual absorption,
accessing these modes by temporally shaping the incident waveform. We show that
engaging these complex zeros enables storing and releasing the electromagnetic
energy at will within a lossless structure for arbitrary amounts of time, under
the control of the impinging field. The effect is robust with respect to
inevitable material dissipation and can be realized in systems with any number
of input ports. The observed effect may have important implications for
flexible control of light propagation and storage, low-energy memory, and
optical modulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09348</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raga</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Kamenetzky</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco-Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A comparison of the radio and optical time-evolution of HH~1 and 2</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>To appear in Revista Mexicana de Astronomia y Astrofisica,7 pages, 8
  figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparison between the time-evolution over the past $\sim 20$
years of the radio continuum and H$\alpha$ emission of HH~1 and 2. We find that
the radio continuum and the H$\alpha$ emission of both objects show very
similar trends, with HH~1 becoming fainter and HH~2 brightening quite
considerably (about a factor of 2). We also find that the $F_{\rm
H\alpha}/F_{ff}$ (H$\alpha$ to free-free continuum) ratio of HH~1 and 2 has
higher values than the ones typically found in planetary nebulae (PNe) which we
interpret as an indication that the H$\alpha$ and free-free emission of HH~1/2
is produced in emitting regions with lower temperatures ($\sim 2000$~K) than
the emission of PNe (with $\sim 10^4$~K).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09356</id><created>2017-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Atanasov</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnetter</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>Sparse Grid Discretizations based on a Discontinuous Galerkin Method</title><categories>cs.NA physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine and extend Sparse Grids as a discretization method for partial
differential equations (PDEs). Solving a PDE in $D$ dimensions has a cost that
grows as $O(N^D)$ with commonly used methods. Even for moderate $D$ (e.g.
$D=3$), this quickly becomes prohibitively expensive for increasing problem
size $N$. This effect is known as the Curse of Dimensionality. Sparse Grids
offer an alternative discretization method with a much smaller cost of $O(N
\log^{D-1}N)$. In this paper, we introduce the reader to Sparse Grids, and
extend the method via a Discontinuous Galerkin approach. We then solve the
scalar wave equation in up to $6+1$ dimensions, comparing cost and accuracy
between full and sparse grids. Sparse Grids perform far superior, even in three
dimensions. Our code is freely available as open source, and we encourage the
reader to reproduce the results we show.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
