<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:52:25Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-03-14" from="2016-03-13" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0904.2509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0904.2509</id><created>2009-04-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meszaros</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the birth of fast rotating magnetars through high-energy
  neutrinos</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in PRD</comments><report-no>YITP-09-30</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.D 79 (2009) 103001</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.79.103001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the high-energy neutrino emission expected from newly born
magnetars surrounded by their stellar ejecta. Protons might be accelerated up
to 0.1-100 EeV energies possibly by, e.g., the wave dissipation in the winds,
leading to hadronic interactions in the stellar ejecta. The resulting PeV-EeV
neutrinos can be detected by IceCube/KM3Net with a typical peak time scale of a
few days after the birth of magnetars, making the characteristic soft-hard-soft
behavior. Detections would be important as a clue to the formation mechanism of
magnetars, although there are ambiguities coming from uncertainties of several
parameters such as velocity of the ejecta. Non-detections would also lead to
useful constraints on the scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1002.3980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1002.3980</id><created>2010-02-22</created><updated>2010-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beacom</keyname><forenames>John F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Very-High-Energy Gamma-Ray Signal from Nuclear Photodisintegration as a
  Probe of Extragalactic Sources of Ultrahigh-Energy Nuclei</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication in PRD, with extended
  descriptions. Conclusions unchanged</comments><report-no>YITP-10-21</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.D 82 (2010) 043008</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.82.043008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is crucial to identify the ultrahigh-energy cosmic-ray (UHECR) sources and
probe their unknown properties. Recent results from the Pierre Auger
Observatory favor a heavy nuclear composition for the UHECRs. Under the
requirement that heavy nuclei survive in these sources, using gamma-ray bursts
as an example, we predict a diagnostic gamma-ray signal, unique to nuclei - the
emission of de-excitation gamma rays following photodisintegration. These gamma
rays, boosted from MeV to TeV-PeV energies, may be detectable by gamma-ray
telescopes such as VERITAS, HESS, and MAGIC, and especially the next-generation
CTA and AGIS. They are a promising messenger to identify and study individual
UHE nuclei accelerators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1003.4959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1003.4959</id><created>2010-03-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beacom</keyname><forenames>John F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Background Flux from Sources of Ultrahigh-Energy Cosmic-Ray
  Nuclei</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>YITP-10-22</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.D 81 (2010) 123001</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.81.123001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by Pierre Auger Observatory results favoring a heavy nuclear
composition for ultrahigh-energy (UHE) cosmic rays, we investigate implications
for the cumulative neutrino background. The requirement that nuclei not be
photodisintegrated constrains their interactions in sources, therefore limiting
neutrino production via photomeson interactions. Assuming a $dN_{\rm
CR}/dE_{\rm CR} \propto E_{\rm CR}^{-2}$ injection spectrum and
photodisintegration via the giant dipole resonance, the background flux of
neutrinos is lower than $E_\nu^2 \Phi_\nu \sim {10}^{-9} {\rm GeV} {\rm
cm}^{-2} {\rm s}^{-1} {\rm sr}^{-1}$ if UHE nuclei ubiquitously survive in
their sources. This is smaller than the analogous Waxman-Bahcall flux for UHE
protons by about one order of magnitude, and is below the projected IceCube
sensitivity. If IceCube detects a neutrino background, it could be due to other
sources, e.g., hadronuclear interactions of lower-energy cosmic rays; if it
does not, this supports our strong restrictions on the properties of sources of
UHE nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.6470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.6470</id><created>2013-07-24</created><updated>2015-02-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finster</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smoller</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author></authors><title>Refined Error Estimates for the Riccati Equation with Applications to
  the Angular Teukolsky Equation</title><categories>math.CA gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, LaTeX, 4 figures, 4 ancillary files, minor corrections
  (published version)</comments><journal-ref>Methods and Applications of Analysis 22 (2015) 67-100</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/MAA.2015.v22.n1.a3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive refined rigorous error estimates for approximate solutions of
Sturm-Liouville and Riccati equations with real or complex potentials. The
approximate solutions include WKB approximations, Airy and parabolic cylinder
functions, and certain Bessel functions. Our estimates are applied to solutions
of the angular Teukolsky equation with a complex aspherical parameter in a
rotating black hole Kerr geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.5865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.5865</id><created>2013-09-23</created><updated>2014-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bloch</keyname><forenames>Spencer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanhove</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>The elliptic dilogarithm for the sunset graph</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>3 figures, 43 pages. v2: minor corrections. version to be published
  in The Journal of Number Theory</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Number Theory, Volume 148, March 2015, Pages 328-364</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jnt.2014.09.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the sunset graph defined as the scalar two-point self-energy at
two-loop order. We evaluate the sunset integral for all identical internal
masses in two dimensions. We give two calculations for the sunset amplitude;
one based on an interpretation of the amplitude as an inhomogeneous solution of
a classical Picard-Fuchs differential equation, and the other using arithmetic
algebraic geometry, motivic cohomology, and Eisenstein series. Both methods use
the rather special fact that the amplitude in this case is a family of periods
associated to the universal family of elliptic curves over the modular curve
X_1(6). We show that the integral is given by an elliptic dilogarithm evaluated
at a sixth root of unity modulo periods. We explain as well how this elliptic
dilogarithm value is related to the regulator of a class in the motivic
cohomology of the universal elliptic family.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.3266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.3266</id><created>2014-02-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Rubens D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>Guilherme M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Andre M. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anderson localization on the Falicov-Kimball model with Coulomb disorder</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>European Physical Journal B 87, 160 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2014-50221-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The role of Coulomb disorder is analysed in the Anderson-Falicov-Kimball
model. Phase diagrams of correlated and disordered electron systems are
calculated within dynamical mean-field theory applied to the Bethe lattice, in
which metal-insulator transitions led by structural and Coulomb disorders and
correlation can be identified. Metallic, Mott insulator, and Anderson insulator
phases, as well as the crossover between them are studied in this perspective.
We show that Coulomb disorder has a relevant role in the phase-transition
behavior as the system is led towards the insulator regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.6313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.6313</id><created>2014-07-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harmon</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahin-Tiras</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohlgenannt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flatt&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous organic magnetoresistance from competing
  carrier-spin-dependent interactions with localized electronic and nuclear
  spins</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. 90, 060204(R) (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.90.060204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a new regime for low-field magnetoresistance in organic
semiconductors, in which the spin-relaxing effects of localized nuclear spins
and electronic spins interfere. The regime is studied by the controlled
addition of localized electronic spins to a material that exhibits substantial
room-temperature magnetoresistance ($\sim 20$\%). Although initially the
magnetoresistance is suppressed by the doping, at intermediate doping there is
a regime where the magnetoresistance is insensitive to the doping level. For
much greater doping concentrations the magnetoresistance is fully suppressed.
The behavior is described within a theoretical model describing the effect of
carrier spin dynamics on the current.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.0249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.0249</id><created>2014-08-01</created><updated>2014-09-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monticone</keyname><forenames>D. Gatto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traina</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grilj</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brida</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boarino</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enrico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degiovanni</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skukan</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jak&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical stimulation of single-photon emission from nitrogen-vacancy
  centers in diamond with sub-superficial graphitic electrodes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories><comments>This article has been withdrawn due to the inclusion of additional
  upgrades and modifications, which significantly improve the paper. A new
  submission will be performed at a later stage</comments><doi>10.1038/srep15901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Focused MeV ion beams with micrometric resolution are suitable tools for the
direct writing of conductive graphitic channels buried in an insulating diamond
bulk. Their effectiveness has been shown for the fabrication of multi-electrode
ionizing radiation detectors and cellular biosensors. In this work we
investigate such fabrication method for the electrical excitation of color
centers in diamond. Differently from optically-stimulated light emission from
color centers in diamond, electroluminescence (EL) requires a high current
flowing in the diamond subgap states between the electrodes. With this purpose,
buried graphitic electrode pairs with a spacing of 10 $\mu$m were fabricated in
the bulk of a single-crystal diamond sample using a 6 MeV C microbeam. The
electrical characterization of the structure showed a significant current above
an effective voltage threshold of 150V, which was interpreted according to the
theory of Space Charge Limited Current. The EL imaging allowed to identify the
electroluminescent regions and the residual vacancy distribution associated
with the fabrication technique. Measurements evidenced bright
electroluminescent emission from native neutrally-charged nitrogen-vacancy
centers ($NV^0$); the acquired spectra highlighted the absence of EL associated
with radiation damage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3556</id><created>2014-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Yeh</keyname><forenames>Shu-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kais</keyname><forenames>Sabre</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the Role of the Eighth Bacteriochlorophyll in holo-FMO Complex
  by Simulated Two-Dimensional Electronic Spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 141, 234105 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4903546</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Fenna-Matthews-Olson (FMO) protein-pigment complex acts as a molecular
wire between the outer antenna system and the reaction center (RC); it is an
important model system to study the excitonic energy transfer. Recent
crystallographic studies report the existence of an additional (eighth)
bacteriochlorophyll a (BChl a). To understand the functionality of this eighth
BChl, we simulated the two-dimensional electronic spectra of both the 7-site
(apo form) and the 8-site (holo form) variant of the FMO complex from green
sulfur bacteria, Prosthecochloris aestuarii. By comparing the difference
between the spectrum, it was found that the eighth BChl can affect two
different excitonic energy transfer pathways, these being: (1) directly involve
in the first pathway 6 $\rightarrow$ 3 $\rightarrow$ 1 of the apo form model by
passing the excitonic energy to exciton 6; and (2) increase the excitonic wave
function overlap between excitons 4 and 5 in the second pathway (7
$\rightarrow$ 4,5 $\rightarrow$ 2 $\rightarrow$ 1) and thus increase the
possible downward sampling routes across the BChls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.3292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.3292</id><created>2014-09-10</created><updated>2014-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Solano-Altamirano</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malcolm</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldman</keyname><forenames>Saul</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas bubble dynamics in soft materials</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, 1 table, (Included also &quot;Supplementary
  information&quot;: 2 pages, 1 table)</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 11 (2015) 202</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C4SM02037E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Epstein and Plesset's seminal work on the rate of gas bubble dissolution and
growth in a simple liquid is generalized to render it applicable to a gas
bubble embedded in a soft elastic medium. Both the underlying diffusion
equation and the expression for the gas bubble pressure were modified to allow
for the non-zero shear modulus of the elastic medium. The extension of the
diffusion equation results in a trivial shift (by an additive constant) in the
value of the diffusion coefficient, and does not change the form of the rate
equations. But the use of a Generalized Young-Laplace equation for the bubble
pressure resulted in significant differences on the dynamics of bubble
dissolution and growth, relative to a simple liquid medium. Depending on
whether the salient parameters (solute concentration, initial bubble radius,
surface tension, and shear modulus) lead to bubble growth or dissolution, the
effect of allowing for a non-zero shear modulus in the Generalized
Young-Laplace equation is to speed up the rate of bubble growth, or to reduce
the rate of bubble dissolution, respectively. The relation to previous work on
visco-elastic materials is discussed, as is the connection of this work to the
problem of Decompression Sickness (specifically, &quot;the bends&quot;). Examples of
tissues to which our expressions can be applied are provided. Also, a new
phenomenon is predicted whereby, for some parameter values, a bubble can be
metastable and persist for long times, or it may grow, when embedded in a
homogeneous under-saturated soft elastic medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.4396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.4396</id><created>2014-10-16</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Ansuman</forenames></author></authors><title>Blurred path-spin entanglement in Stern-Gerlach apparatus: interplay
  between magnetic inhomogeneity and Larmor precession</title><categories>nucl-th hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure Text body rewritten, figures improved and added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that the non-adiabatic evolution of spin states in Stern-Gerlach
apparatus can blur the manifestation of path spin entanglement. This fact
introduces a contradiction to the usual perception of spin measurement even in
a formally ideal situation. Through quantitative calculation, we have pointed
out the specific reason behind the breakdown of adiabatic evolution to be the
spatial inhomogeneity of applied magnetic field. The angle $\theta$ between the
$z$ component of magnetic moment of the particle and applied magnetic field is
also a determining factor for the category of evolution of spin states.
Adiabaticity always can be restored by choosing a sufficiently small value of
$\theta$. Considering azimuthal inhomogeneity, we have examined the nature of
path spin entanglement in the context of Stern-Gerlach experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6748</id><created>2014-11-25</created><updated>2016-03-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parida</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Biswonath</forenames></author></authors><title>Planck-scale induced left-right gauge theory at LHC and experimental
  tests</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>47 pages, PdfLaTeX, 14 figures. References added, Typo corrected;
  Accepted in Nuclear Physics B</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B 906 (2016) 77-104</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.02.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent measurements at LHC has inspired searches for TeV scale left-right
gauge theory originating from grand unified theories. We show that inclusion of
Planck-scale induced effects due to ${\rm dim.}5$ operator not only does away
with all the additional intermediate symmetries, but also it predicts the
minimal set of light Higgs scalars tailored after neutrino masses and dilepton,
or trilepton signals. The heavy-light neutrino mixings are predicted from
charged fermion mass fits in $SO(10)$ and LFV constraints which lead to new
predictions for dilepton or trilepton production signals. Including
fine-structure constant matching and two-loop, and threshold effects predicts
$M_{W_R}= g_{2R}\times 10^{4.3\pm 1.5 \pm 0.2}$ GeV and proton lifetime
$\tau_p=10^{36.15\pm 5.8\pm 0.2}$ yrs with $W_R$ gauge boson coupling
$g_{2R}=0.56-0.57$. Predictions on lepton flavour and lepton number violations
are accessible to ongoing experiments. Current CMS data on di-electron excess
at $\sqrt s= 8$ TeV are found to be consistent with $W_R$ gauge boson mass
$M_{W_R}\ge 1.9-2.2$ TeV which also agrees with the values obtained from dijet
resonance production data. We also discuss plausible explanations for diboson
production excesses observed at LHC and make predictions expected at $\sqrt s
=14$ TeV
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7595</id><created>2014-11-27</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chicherin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derkachov</keyname><forenames>Sergey E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiridonov</keyname><forenames>Vyacheslav P.</forenames></author></authors><title>From Principal Series to Finite-Dimensional Solutions of the Yang-Baxter
  Equation</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP math.QA</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 028</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.028</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We start from known solutions of the Yang-Baxter equation with a spectral
parameter defined on the tensor product of two infinite-dimensional principal
series representations of the group $\mathrm{SL}(2,\mathbb{C})$ or Faddeev's
modular double. Then we describe its restriction to an irreducible
finite-dimensional representation in one or both spaces. In this way we obtain
very simple explicit formulas embracing rational and trigonometric
finite-dimensional solutions of the Yang-Baxter equation. Finally, we construct
these finite-dimensional solutions by means of the fusion procedure and find a
nice agreement between two approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.03478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.03478</id><created>2014-08-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sharif</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yousaf</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Density Inhomogeneities with Polynomial $f(R)$ Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>references are updated</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys. Space Sci. 352(2014)321</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-014-1913-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the effects of polynomial $f(R)$ model on the
stability of homogeneous energy density in self-gravitating spherical stellar
object. For this purpose, we construct couple of evolution equations which
relate the Weyl tensor with matter parameters. We explore different factors
responsible for density inhomogeneities with non-dissipative dust, isotropic as
well as anisotropic fluids and dissipative dust cloud. We find that shear,
pressure, dissipative parameters and $f(R)$ terms affect the existence of
inhomogeneous energy density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02022</id><created>2015-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Adam H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoder</keyname><forenames>Bruce L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luckhaus</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saak</keyname><forenames>Clara-Magdalena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doppelbauer</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Signorell</keyname><forenames>Ruth</forenames></author></authors><title>Angle-Resolved Photoemission of Solvated Electrons in Sodium-Doped
  Clusters</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.,6, 1487-1492, (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.5b00477</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Angle-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy of the unpaired electron in
sodium-doped water, methanol, ammonia, and dimethyl ether clusters is
presented. The experimental observations and the complementary calculations are
consistent with surface electrons for the cluster size range studied. Evidence
against internally solvated electrons is provided by the photoelectron angular
distribution. The trends in the ionization energies seem mainly determined by
the degree of hydrogen bonding in the solvent and the solvation of the ion
core. The onset ionization energies of water and methanol clusters do not level
off at small cluster sizes, but decrease slightly with increasing cluster size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.05193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.05193</id><created>2015-03-17</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kearney</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>Hojin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zurek</keyname><forenames>Kathryn M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is a Higgs Vacuum Instability Fatal for High-Scale Inflation?</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>31 pages, 3 figures; v2: references added, journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 91, 123537 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.123537</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the inflationary evolution of a scalar field $h$ with an unstable
potential for the case where the Hubble parameter $H$ during inflation is
larger than the instability scale $\Lambda_I$ of the potential. Quantum
fluctuations in the field of size $\delta h \sim \frac{H}{2 \pi}$ imply that
the unstable part of the potential is sampled during inflation. We investigate
the evolution of these fluctuations to the unstable regime, and in particular
whether they generate cosmological defects or even terminate inflation. We
apply the results of a toy scalar model to the case of the Standard Model (SM)
Higgs boson, whose quartic evolves to negative values at high scales, and
extend previous analyses of Higgs dynamics during inflation utilizing
statistical methods to a perturbative and fully gauge-invariant formulation. We
show that the dynamics are controlled by the renormalization group-improved
quartic coupling $\lambda(\mu)$ evaluated at a scale $\mu = H$, such that Higgs
fluctuations are enhanced by the instability if $H &gt; \Lambda_I$. Even if $H &gt;
\Lambda_I$, the instability in the SM Higgs potential does not end inflation;
instead the universe slowly sloughs off crunching patches of space that never
come to dominate the evolution. As inflation proceeds past 50 $e$-folds, a
significant proportion of patches exit inflation in the unstable vacuum, and as
much as 1% of the spacetime can rapidly evolve to a defect. Depending on the
nature of these defects, however, the resulting universe could still be
compatible with ours.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.00773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.00773</id><created>2015-04-03</created><updated>2016-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heo</keyname><forenames>Jae Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Dark Matter and Dark Radiation</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>To appear in JKPS, 14 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J.Korean Phys.Soc. 68 (2016) 5, 715-721</journal-ref><doi>10.3938/jkps.68.715</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light dark-matter ($M\leq20$ MeV) particles freeze out after neutrino
decoupling. If the dark-matter particle couples to a neutrino or an
electromagnetic plasma, the late time entropy production from dark-matter
annihilation can change the neutrino-to-photon temperature ratio, and equally
the effective number of neutrinos $N_{eff}$. We study the non-equilibrium
effects of dark-matter annihilation on the $N_{eff}$ and the effects by using a
thermal equilibrium approximation. Both results are constrained with Planck
observations. We demonstrate that the lower bounds of the dark-matter mass and
the possibilities of the existence of additional radiation particles are more
strongly constrained for dark-matter annihilation process in non-equilibrium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04122</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dangbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Jianrong</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Junhan</forenames></author></authors><title>One possible explanation for the Balmer and Lyman line shifts in quasars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 1 figure, Submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Internal line shifts in quasars spectra have played a more prominent role in
our understanding of quasar structure and dynamics. The observed different
redshift among broad hydrogen lines is still an amazing puzzle in the study of
quasars. We have argued that the broad hydrogen lines, as well as the
low-ionization lines in quasars, are significantly contributed by the Cerenkov
quasi-line emission of the fast electrons in the dense clouds/filaments/sheets
($N_{\rm H}\geq 10^{14}~{\rm cm^{-3}}$); whereas this line-like radiation
mechanism is invalid for producing the high ionization lines. In order to
account for redshift difference, the Cerenkov line-like radiation mechanism
could provide a plausible resolution: it is the `Cerenkov line redshift', which
is different from line to line, causes the peculiar redshift-differences among
Ly$\alpha$, H$\alpha$ and H$\beta$ lines. The different redshifts among
different broad hydrogen lines could stand for an evidence to quantitatively
support that the observed broad hydrogen lines should be blended by both the
real line emission and the Cerenkov quasi-line emission. The good fitting to
the observed redshifts of quasars confirms the existence of Cerenkov component
in the broad hydrogen lines, which indicates that, in the blended Ly$\alpha$
line, the line-intensity of the Cerenkov component approximately equals that of
the accompanying `normal line' (an approximate equipartition of intensity
between the two components in the broad Ly$\alpha$ line). This result
illustrates the importance of the Cerenkov component in the broad lines of
quasars, which can be further confirmed by future observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04577</id><created>2015-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tamma</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Analogue algorithm for parallel factorization of an exponential number
  of large integers I. Theoretical description</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>to be published in Quantum Information Processing (QIP)</comments><journal-ref>V. Tamma, Quantum Inf. Process. 11128:1190, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-015-1190-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a novel analogue algorithm that allows the simultaneous
factorization of an exponential number of large integers with a polynomial
number of experimental runs. It is the interference-induced periodicity of
&quot;factoring&quot; interferograms measured at the output of an analogue computer that
allows the selection of the factors of each integer [1,2,3,4]. At the present
stage the algorithm manifests an exponential scaling which may be overcome by
an extension of this method to correlated qubits emerging from n-order quantum
correlations measurements. We describe the conditions for a generic physical
system to compute such an analogue algorithm. A particular example given by an
&quot;optical computer&quot; based on optical interference will be addressed in the
second paper of this series [5].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04584</id><created>2015-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tamma</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Analogue algorithm for parallel factorization of an exponential number
  of large integers II. Optical implementation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>to be published in Quantum Information Processing (QIP)</comments><journal-ref>V. Tamma, Quantum Inf Process 11128:1189, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-015-1189-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a detailed analysis of the optical realization [1, 3, 2, 4] of the
analogue algorithm described in the first paper of this series [5] for the
simultaneous factorization of an exponential number of integers. Such an
analogue procedure, which scales exponentially in the context of first order
interference, opens up the horizon to polynomial scaling by exploiting
multi-particle quantum interference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01796</id><created>2015-06-05</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heinemann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palczynski</keyname><forenames>Karol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzubiella</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klapp</keyname><forenames>Sabine H. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coarse-grained electrostatic interactions of coronene: Towards the
  crystalline phase</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 174110 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4935063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we present and compare two different, coarse-grained
approaches to model electrostatic interactions of disc-shaped aromatic
molecules, specifically coronene. Our study builds on previous work [J. Chem.
Phys. 141, 214110 (2014)] where we proposed, based on a systematic
coarse-graining procedure starting from the atomistic level, an anisotropic
effective (Gay-Berne-like) potential capable of describing van-der-Waals
contributions to the interaction energy. To take into account electrostatics,
we introduce, first, a linear quadrupole moment along the symmetry axis of the
coronene disc. The second approach takes into account the fact that the partial
charges within the molecules are distributed in a ring-like fashion. We then
reparametrize the effective Gay-Berne-like potential such that it matches, at
short distances, the ring-ring potential. To investigate the validity of these
two approaches, we perform many-particle Molecular Dynamics (MD) simulations,
focusing on the crystalline phase (karpatite) where electrostatic interaction
effects are expected to be particularly relevant for the formation of tilted
stacked columns. Specifically, we investigate various structural parameters as
well as the melting transition. We find that the second approach yields
consistent results with those from experiments despite the fact that the
underlying potential decays with the wrong distance dependence at large
molecule separations. Our strategy can be transferred to a broader class of
molecules, such as benzene or hexabenzocoronene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02846</id><created>2015-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Shankaraiah</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murthy</keyname><forenames>K. P. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lookman</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shenoy</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Re-equilibration after quenches in athermal
  martensites:Conversion-delays for vapour to liquid domain-wall phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures. Under process with Phys. Rev. B (2015)</comments><journal-ref>PhysRevB.91.214108 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.214108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entropy barriers and ageing states appear in martensitic
structural-transition models, slowly re-equilibrating after temperature
quenches, under Monte Carlo dynamics. Concepts from protein folding and ageing
harmonic oscillators turn out to be useful in understanding these
nonequilibrium evolutions. We show how the athermal, non-activated delay time
for seeded parent-phase austenite to convert to product-phase martensite,
arises from an identified entropy barrier in Fourier space. In an ageing state
of low Monte Carlo acceptances, the strain structure factor makes
constant-energy searches for rare pathways, to enter a Brillouin zone `golf
hole' enclosing negative energy states, and to suddenly release entropically
trapped stresses. In this context, a stress-dependent effective temperature can
be defined, that re-equilibrates to the quenched bath temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06583</id><created>2015-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Dittrich</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Exner</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pankrashkin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>On eigenvalue asymptotics for strong delta-interactions supported by
  surfaces with boundaries</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.SP quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, to be submitted to Asymptotic Analysis</comments><msc-class>47A75</msc-class><journal-ref>Asymptot. Anal. 97 (2016) 1-25</journal-ref><doi>10.3233/ASY-151341</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $S\subset\mathbb{R}^3$ be a $C^4$-smooth relatively compact orientable
surface with a sufficiently regular boundary. For $\beta\in\mathbb{R}_+$, let
$E_j(\beta)$ denote the $j$th negative eigenvalue of the operator associated
with the quadratic form \[ H^1(\mathbb{R}^3)\ni u\mapsto \iiint_{\mathbb{R}^3}
|\nabla u|^2dx -\beta \iint_S |u|^2d\sigma, \] where $\sigma$ is the
two-dimensional Hausdorff measure on $S$. We show that for each fixed $j$ one
has the asymptotic expansion \[ E_j(\beta)=-\dfrac{\beta^2}{4}+\mu^D_j+ o(1)
\;\text{ as }\; \beta\to+\infty\,, \] where $\mu_j^D$ is the $j$th eigenvalue
of the operator $-\Delta_S+K-M^2$ on $L^2(S)$, in which $K$ and $M$ are the
Gauss and mean curvatures, respectively, and $-\Delta_S$ is the
Laplace-Beltrami operator with the Dirichlet condition at the boundary of $S$.
If, in addition, the boundary of $S$ is $C^2$-smooth, then the remainder
estimate can be improved to ${\mathcal O}(\beta^{-1}\log\beta)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01590</id><created>2015-07-06</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langaeble</keyname><forenames>Kasper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sannino</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>SIMP model at NNLO in chiral perturbation theory</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>RevTeX, two-columns, 7 pages, 6 figures (updated to match published
  version)</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2015-025, DNRF90, DIAS-2015-25</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 075036 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.075036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the phenomenological viability of a recently proposed class of
composite dark matter models where the relic density is determined by 3 to 2
number-changing processes in the dark sector. Here the pions of the strongly
interacting field theory constitute the dark matter particles. By performing a
consistent next-to-leading and next-to-next-to-leading order chiral
perturbative investigation we demonstrate that the leading order analysis
cannot be used to draw conclusions about the viability of the model. We further
show that higher order corrections substantially increase the tension with
phenomenological constraints challenging the viability of the simplest
realisation of the strongly interacting massive particle (SIMP) paradigm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02136</id><created>2015-07-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tchernij</keyname><forenames>S. Ditalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tengattini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grilj</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skukan</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boarino</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degiovanni</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enrico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traina</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jak&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electroluminescence from nitrogen-vacancy and interstitial-related
  centers in bulk diamond stimulated by ion-beam-fabricated sub-superficial
  graphitic micro-electrodes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the fabrication and characterization of a single-crystal diamond
device for the electrical stimula- tion of light emission from nitrogen-vacancy
(NV0) and other defect-related centers. Pairs of sub-superficial graphitic
micro-electrodes embedded in insulating diamond were fabricated by a 6 MeV C3+
micro-beam irra- diation followed by thermal annealing. A photoluminescence
(PL) characterization evidenced a low radiation damage concentration in the
inter-electrode gap region, which did not significantly affect the PL features
domi- nated by NV centers. The operation of the device in electroluminescence
(EL) regime was investigated by ap- plying a bias voltage at the graphitic
electrodes, resulting in the injection of a high excitation current above a
threshold voltage (~300V), which effectively stimulated an intense EL emission
from NV0 centers. In addition, we report on the new observation of two
additional sharp EL emission lines (at 563 nm and 580 nm) related to
interstitial defects formed during MeV ion beam fabrication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04351</id><created>2015-07-15</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lesgourgues</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques-Tavares</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmaltz</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence for dark matter interactions in cosmological precision data?</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures; v2 small correction to example models, added
  acknowledgement; v3 updated likelihoods and changed allowed range for
  N_fluid, conclusions unchanged. Matches version accepted for publication in
  JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/02/037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a two-parameter extension of the cosmological standard model
$\Lambda$CDM in which cold dark matter interacts with a new form of dark
radiation. The two parameters correspond to the energy density in the dark
radiation fluid $\Delta N_\mathrm{fluid}$ and the interaction strength between
dark matter and dark radiation. The interactions give rise to a very weak &quot;dark
matter drag&quot; which damps the growth of matter density perturbations throughout
radiation domination, allowing to reconcile the tension between predictions of
large scale structure from the CMB and direct measurements of $\sigma_8$. We
perform a precision fit to Planck CMB data, BAO, large scale structure, and
direct measurements of the expansion rate of the universe today. Our model
lowers the $\chi$-squared relative to $\Lambda$CDM by about 12, corresponding
to a preference for non-zero dark matter drag by more than $3 \sigma$. Particle
physics models which naturally produce a dark matter drag of the required form
include the recently proposed non-Abelian dark matter model in which the dark
radiation corresponds to massless dark gluons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04621</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moya-Cessa</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soto-Eguibar</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arrizon</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga-Segundo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized revival and splitting of an arbitrary optical field in GRIN
  media</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assuming a non-paraxial propagation operator, we study the propagation of an
electromagnetic field with an arbitrary initial condition in a quadratic GRIN
medium. We show that at certain specific periodic distances, the propagated
field is given by the fractional Fourier transform of a superposition of the
initial field and of a reflected version of it. We also prove that for
particular wavelengths, there is a revival and a splitting of the initial
field. We apply this results, first to an initial field given by a Bessel
function and show that it splits into two generalized Bessel functions, and
second, to an Airy function. In both cases our results are compared with the
exact numerical ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05756</id><created>2015-07-21</created><updated>2016-03-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finster</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smoller</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author></authors><title>A Spectral Representation for Spin-Weighted Spheroidal Wave Operators
  with Complex Aspherical Parameter</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.CA math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>82 pages, LaTeX, 8 figures, minor improvements (published version)</comments><journal-ref>Methods and Applications of Analysis 23 (2016) 35-118</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/MAA.2016.v23.n1.a2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A family of spectral decompositions of the spin-weighted spheroidal wave
operator is constructed for complex aspherical parameters with bounded
imaginary part. As the operator is not symmetric, its spectrum is complex and
Jordan chains may appear. We prove uniform upper bounds for the length of the
Jordan chains and the norms of the idempotent operators mapping onto the
invariant subspaces. The completeness of the spectral decomposition is proven.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07849</id><created>2015-07-28</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Uphoff</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brekenfeld</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rempe</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>An integrated quantum repeater at telecom wavelength with single atoms
  in optical fiber cavities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics B 122, 46 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-015-6299-2</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum repeaters promise to enable quantum networks over global distances by
circumventing the exponential decrease in success probability inherent in
direct photon transmission. We propose a realistic, functionally integrated
quantum repeater implementation based on single atoms in optical cavities.
Entanglement is directly generated between the single-atom quantum memory and a
photon at telecom wavelength. The latter is collected with high efficiency and
adjustable temporal and spectral properties into a spatially well-defined
cavity mode. It is heralded by a near-infrared photon emitted from a second,
orthogonal cavity. Entanglement between two remote quantum memories can be
generated via an optical Bell-state measurement, while we propose entanglement
swapping based on a highly efficient, cavity-assisted atom-atom gate. Our
quantum repeater scheme eliminates any requirement for wavelength conversion
such that only a single system is needed at each node. We investigate a
particular implementation with rubidium and realistic parameters for
Fabry-Perot cavities based on CO$_2$ laser-machined optical fibers. We show
that the scheme enables the implementation of a rather simple quantum repeater
that outperforms direct entanglement generation over large distances and does
not require any improvements in technology beyond the state of the art.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08625</id><created>2015-07-30</created><updated>2015-09-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>Cristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peiro</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robles</keyname><forenames>Sandra</forenames></author></authors><title>On the importance of direct detection combined limits for spin
  independent and spin dependent dark matter interactions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 10 figures, 2 appendices. Minor text corrections.
  References added</comments><report-no>FTUAM-15-21, IFT-UAM/CSIC-15-080</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 03 (2016) 019</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/03/019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we show how the inclusion of dark matter (DM) direct detection
upper bounds in a theoretically consistent manner can affect the allowed
parameter space of a DM model. Traditionally, the limits from DM direct
detection experiments on the elastic scattering cross section of DM particles
as a function of their mass are extracted under simplifying assumptions.
Relaxing the assumptions related to the DM particle nature, such as the neutron
to proton ratio of the interactions, or the possibility of having similar
contributions from the spin independent (SI) and spin dependent (SD)
interactions can vary significantly the upper limits. Furthermore, it is known
that astrophysical and nuclear uncertainties can also affect the upper bounds.
To exemplify the impact of properly including all these factors, we have
analysed two well motivated and popular DM scenarios: neutralinos in the NMSSM
and a Z' portal with Dirac DM. We have found that the allowed parameter space
of these models is subject to important variations when one includes both the
SI and SD interactions at the same time, realistic neutron to proton ratios, as
well as using different self-consistent speed distributions corresponding to
popular DM halo density profiles, and distinct SD structure functions. Finally,
we provide all the necessary information to include the upper bounds of
SuperCDMS and LUX taking into account all these subtleties in the investigation
of any particle physics model. The data for each experiment and example codes
are available at this site http://goo.gl/1CDFYi, and their use is detailed in
the appendices of this work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02039</id><created>2015-08-09</created><updated>2016-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Li-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of $\psi(3770)$ decaying to Baryon anti-Baryon Pairs</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>version accepted by Physics Letters B, revised, discussed added,
  references added</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 756 (2016) 77-83</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.03.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To study the decays of $\psi(3770)$ going to baryon anti-baryon pairs
($B\bar{B}$), all available experiments of measuring the cross sections of
$e^+e^- \to B\bar{B}$ at center-of-mass energy ranging from 3.0 GeV to 3.9 GeV
are combined. To relate the baryon octets, a model based on the SU(3) flavor
symmetry is used and the SU(3) breaking effects are also considered. Assuming
the elctric and magnetic form factors are equal ($|G_E|=|G_M|$), a global fit
including the interference between the QED process and the resonant process is
performed. The branching fraction of $\psi(3770) \to B\bar{B}$ is determined to
be $(2.4\pm0.8\pm0.3)\times10^{-5}$, $(1.7\pm0.6\pm0.1)\times10^{-5}$,
$(4.5\pm0.9\pm0.1)\times10^{-5}$, $(4.5\pm0.9\pm0.1)\times10^{-5}$,
$(2.0\pm0.7\pm0.1)\times10^{-5}$, and $(2.0\pm0.7\pm0.1)\times10^{-5}$ for
$B=p, \Lambda, \Sigma^+, \Sigma^0, \Xi^-$ and $\Xi^0$, respectively, where the
first uncertainty is from the global fit and the second uncertainty is the
systematic uncertainty due to the assumption $|G_E|=|G_M|$. They are at least
one order of magnitude larger than a simple scaling of the branching fraction
of $J/\psi\to B\bar{B}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04577</id><created>2015-08-19</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jex</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotoreichik</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>On absence of bound states for weakly attractive
  $\delta^\prime$-interactions supported on non-closed curves in $\mathbb{R}^2$</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57 (2016), 022101</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939749</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $\Lambda\subset\mathbb{R}^2$ be a non-closed piecewise-$C^1$ curve, which
is either bounded with two free endpoints or unbounded with one free endpoint.
Let $u_\pm|_\Lambda \in L^2(\Lambda)$ be the traces of a function $u$ in the
Sobolev space $H^1({\mathbb R}^2\setminus \Lambda)$ onto two faces of
$\Lambda$. We prove that for a wide class of shapes of $\Lambda$ the
Schr\&quot;odinger operator $\mathsf{H}_\omega^\Lambda$ with
$\delta^\prime$-interaction supported on $\Lambda$ of strength $\omega \in
L^\infty(\Lambda;\mathbb{R})$ associated with the quadratic form \[
H^1(\mathbb{R}^2\setminus\Lambda)\ni u \mapsto \int_{\mathbb{R}^2}\big|\nabla u
\big|^2 \mathsf{d} x
  - \int_\Lambda \omega \big| u_+|_\Lambda - u_-|_\Lambda \big|^2 \mathsf{d} s
\] has no negative spectrum provided that $\omega$ is pointwise majorized by a
strictly positive function explicitly expressed in terms of $\Lambda$. If,
additionally, the domain $\mathbb{R}^2\setminus\Lambda$ is quasi-conical, we
show that $\sigma(\mathsf{H}_\omega^\Lambda) = [0,+\infty)$. For a bounded
curve $\Lambda$ in our class and non-varying interaction strength
$\omega\in\mathbb{R}$ we derive existence of a constant $\omega_* &gt; 0$ such
that $\sigma(\mathsf{H}_\omega^\Lambda) = [0,+\infty)$ for all $\omega \in
(-\infty, \omega_*]$; informally speaking, bound states are absent in the weak
coupling regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07585</id><created>2015-08-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Fengqiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Yafei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelleher</keyname><forenames>Edmund</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guoxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yongbing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shining</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable gain-switched thulium fiber laser with 140 nm tuning range</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1109/LPT.2016.2541694</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a gain-switched thulium fiber laser that can be continuously
tuned over 140 nm, while maintaining stable nanosecond single-pulse operation.
To the best of our knowledge, this system represents the broadest tuning range
for a gain-switched fiber laser. The system simplicity and wideband wavelength
tunability combined with the ability to control the temporal characteristics of
the gain-switched pulses mean this is a versatile source highly suited to a
wide range of applications in the eye-safe region of the infrared, including
spectroscopy, sensing and material processing, as well as being a practical
seed source for pumping nonlinear processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07796</id><created>2015-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaltenbaek</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing quantum physics in space using high-mass matter-wave
  interferometry</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, conference proceedings to appear in Proceedings of 50th
  Rencontres de Moriond (March 2015), Gravitation: 100 Years after GR</comments><journal-ref>Proc. 50th Rencontres de Moriond, pp. 141-144 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum superposition is central to quantum theory but challenges our
concepts of reality and spacetime when applied to macroscopic objects like
Schr\&quot;odinger's cat. For that reason, it has been a long-standing question
whether quantum physics remains valid unmodified even for truly macroscopic
objects. By now, the predictions of quantum theory have been confirmed via
matter-wave interferometry for massive objects up to $10^4\,$ atomic mass units
(amu). The rapid development of new technologies promises to soon allow tests
of quantum theory for significantly higher test masses by using novel
techniques of quantum optomechanics and high-mass matter-wave interferometry.
Such experiments may yield novel insights into the foundations of quantum
theory, pose stringent limits on alternative theoretical models or even uncover
deviations from quantum physics. However, performing experiments of this type
on Earth may soon face principal limitations due to requirements of long times
of flight, ultra-low vibrations, and extremely high vacuum. Here, we present a
short overview of recent developments towards the implementation of the
proposed space-mission MAQRO, which promises to overcome those limitations and
to perform matter-wave interferometry in a parameter regime orders of magnitude
beyond state-of-the-art.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00805</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2016-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kohta</forenames><affiliation>PSU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Guetta</keyname><forenames>Dafne</forenames><affiliation>OAR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ahlers</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames><affiliation>UW-Madison</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hidden Cosmic-Ray Accelerators as an Origin of TeV-PeV Cosmic Neutrinos</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>6+3 pages, 2+1 figures, version to appear in PRL, with expanded
  Supplementary Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.Lett. 116 (2016) 071101</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.071101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The latest IceCube data suggest that the all-flavor cosmic neutrino flux may
be as large as 10^-7 GeV/cm^2/s/sr around 30 TeV. We show that, if sources of
the TeV-PeV neutrinos are transparent to gamma rays with respect to two-photon
annihilation, strong tensions with the isotropic diffuse gamma-ray background
measured by Fermi are unavoidable, independently of the production mechanism.
We further show that, if the IceCube neutrinos have a photohadronic (pgamma)
origin, the sources are expected to be opaque to 1-100 GeV gamma rays. With
these general multimessenger arguments, we find that the latest data suggest a
population of cosmic-ray accelerators hidden in GeV-TeV gamma rays as a
neutrino origin. Searches for x-ray and MeV gamma-ray counterparts are
encouraged, and TeV-PeV neutrinos themselves will serve as special probes of
dense source environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02118</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2016-02-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Casteels</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Storme</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boit&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciuti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Power-laws in the dynamic hysteresis of quantum nonlinear photonic
  resonators</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Extended version accepted for publication in PRA</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 033824 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.033824</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore theoretically the physics of dynamic hysteresis for
driven-dissipative nonlinear photonic resonators. In the regime where the
semiclassical mean-field theory predicts bistability, the exact steady-state
density matrix is known to be unique, being a statistical mixture of two
states: in particular, no static hysteresis cycle of the excited population
occurs as a function of the driving intensity. Here, we predict that in the
quantum regime a dynamic hysteresis with a rich phenomenology does appear when
sweeping the driving amplitude in a finite time. The hysteresis area as a
function of the sweep time reveals a double power-law decay, with a behavior
qualitatively different from the mean-field predictions. The dynamic hysteresis
power-law in the slow sweep limit defines a characteristic time, which depends
dramatically on the size of the nonlinearity and on the frequency detuning
between the driving and the resonator. In the strong nonlinearity regime, the
characteristic time oscillates as a function of the intrinsic system parameters
due to multiphotonic resonances. We show that the dynamic hysteresis for the
considered class of driven-dissipative systems is due to a non-adiabatic
response region with connections to the Kibble-Zurek mechanism for quenched
phase transitions. We also consider the case of two coupled driven-dissipative
nonlinear resonators, showing that dynamic hysteresis and power-law behavior
occur also in presence of correlations between resonators. Our theoretical
predictions can be explored in a broad variety of physical systems, e.g.,
circuit QED superconducting resonators and semiconductor optical microcavities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03232</id><created>2015-09-10</created><updated>2016-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Triparno</forenames><affiliation>Calcutta Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Brahmachari</keyname><forenames>Biswajoy</forenames><affiliation>Vidyasagar Evening Coll</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Raychaudhuri</keyname><forenames>Amitava</forenames><affiliation>Calcutta Univ</affiliation></author></authors><title>Implications of the CMS search for W_R on Grand Unification</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, v2: Published version. Clarifications and references added</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1602 (2016) 023</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CMS experiment at the Large Hadron Collider has reported a 2.8$\sigma$
excess in the $(2e)(2jets)$ channel around 2.1 TeV. Interpretation of this data
is reconsidered in terms of the production of a right-handed weak gauge boson,
$W_R$, of the left-right symmetric model and in an $SO(10)$ grand unified
theory abiding by the Extended Survival Hypothesis. The left-right symmetric
model can be consistent with this excess if (a) the heavy right-handed neutrino
has a mass near $W_R$, or (b) if $g_L \neq g_R$, or (c) the right-handed CKM
matrix is nontrivial. Combinations of the above possibilities are also viable.
A $W_R$ with a mass in the TeV region if embedded in $SO(10)$ is not compatible
with $g_L = g_R$. Rather, it implies $0.64 \leq g_R/g_L \leq 0.78$. Further, a
unique symmetry-breaking route -- the order being left-right discrete symmetry
breaking first, followed by $SU(4)_C$ and finally $SU(2)_R$ -- to the standard
model is picked out. The $L \leftrightarrow R$ discrete symmetry has to be
broken at around $10^{16}$ GeV. The grand unification scale is pushed to
$10^{18}$ GeV making the detection of proton decay in ongoing searches rather
unlikely. The $SU(4)_C$ breaking scale can be at its allowed lower limit of
$10^6$ GeV so that $n - \bar{n}$ oscillation or flavour changing processes such
as $K_L \rightarrow \mu e$ and $B_{d,s} \rightarrow \mu e$ may be detectable.
The Higgs scalar multiplets responsible for $SO(10)$ symmetry breaking at
various stages are uniquely identified so long as one adheres to a minimalist
principle. We also remark, {\em en passant}, about a partially unified
Pati-Salam model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03334</id><created>2015-09-10</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fr&#xf6;wis</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekatski</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting large quantum Fisher information with finite measurement
  precision</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures; v2: improved presentation, close to published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 090801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.090801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an experimentally accessible scheme to determine lower bounds on
the quantum Fisher information (QFI), which ascertains multipartite
entanglement or usefulness for quantum metrology. The scheme is based on
comparing the measurement statistics of a state before and after a small
unitary rotation. We argue that, in general, limited resolution of collective
observables prevents the detection of large QFI. This can be overcome by
performing an additional operation prior to the measurement. We illustrate the
power of this protocol for present-day spin-squeezing experiments, where the
same operation used for the preparation of the initial spin-squeezed state
improves the lower bound on the QFI by two orders of magnitude. We also
establish a connection to Leggett-Garg inequalities. We show how to simulate a
variant of the inequalities with our protocol and demonstrate that a large QFI
is necessary for their violation with coarse-grained detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05614</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Siemer</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;pfer</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinhans</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Cost-Optimal Operation of Energy Storage Units: Benefits of a
  Problem-Specific Approach</title><categories>math.OC physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Energy Storage 6, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.est.2016.01.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The integration of large shares of electricity produced by non-dispatchable
Renewable Energy Sources (RES) leads to an increasingly volatile energy
generation side, with temporary local overproduction. The application of energy
storage units has the potential to use this excess electricity from RES
efficiently and to prevent curtailment. The objective of this work is to
calculate cost-optimal charging strategies for energy storage units used as
buffers. For this purpose, a new mathematical optimization method is presented
that is applicable to general storage-related problems. Due to a tremendous
gain in efficiency of this method compared with standard solvers and proven
optimality, calculations of complex problems as well as a high-resolution
sensitivity analysis of multiple system combinations are feasible within a very
short time. As an example technology, Power-to-Heat converters used in
combination with thermal storage units are investigated in detail and optimal
system configurations, including storage units with and without energy losses,
are calculated and evaluated. The benefits of a problem-specific approach are
demonstrated by the mathematical simplicity of our approach as well as the
general applicability of the proposed method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07847</id><created>2015-09-25</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garbrecht</keyname><forenames>Bjorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millington</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining the effective action by a method of external sources</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>31 pages; typos corrected; to match published version</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP-1016-15</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B906 (2016) 105-132</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.02.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel method of evaluating the effective action, wherein the
physical one- and two-point functions are obtained in the limit of
non-vanishing external sources. We illustrate the self-consistency of this
method by recovering the usual 2PI effective action due to Cornwall, Jackiw and
Tomboulis, differing only by the fact that the saddle-point evaluation of the
path integral is performed along the extremal quantum, rather than classical,
path. As such, this approach is of particular relevance to situations where the
dominant quantum and classical paths are non-perturbatively far away from
one-another. A pertinent example is the decay of false vacua in
radiatively-generated potentials, as may occur for the electroweak vacuum of
the Standard Model. In addition, we describe how the external sources may
instead be chosen so as to yield the two-particle-point-irreducible (2PPI)
effective action of Coppens and Verschelde. Finally, in the spirit of the
symmetry-improved effective action of Pilaftsis and Teresi, we give an example
of how the external sources can be used to preserve global symmetries in
truncations of the 2PI effective action. Specifically, in the context of an
O(2) model with spontaneous symmetry breaking, we show that this approach
allows the Hartree-Fock approximation to be re-organized, such that the
Goldstone boson remains massless algebraically in the symmetry-broken phase and
we obtain the correct second-order thermal phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08983</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vicente</keyname><forenames>Gustavo S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>Leandro A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>Rudnei O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Eternal inflation in a dissipative and radiation environment: Heated
  demise of eternity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, 12 figures. Minimal changes to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 063509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.063509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Eternal inflation is studied in the context of warm inflation. We focus on
different tools to analyze the effects of dissipation and the presence of a
thermal radiation bath on the fluctuation-dominated regime, for which the
self-reproduction of Hubble regions can take place. The tools we explore are
the threshold inflaton field and threshold number of e-folds necessary to
establish a self-reproduction regime and the counting of Hubble regions, using
generalized conditions for the occurrence of a fluctuation-dominated regime. We
obtain the functional dependence of these quantities on the dissipation and
temperature. A Sturm-Liouville analysis of the Fokker-Planck equation for the
probability of having eternal inflation and an analysis for the probability of
having eternal points are performed. We have considered the representative
cases of inflation models with monomial potentials of the form of chaotic and
hilltop ones. Our results show that warm inflation tends to initially favor the
onset of a self-reproduction regime for smaller values of the dissipation. As
the dissipation increases, it becomes harder than in cold inflation (i.e., in
the absence of dissipation) to achieve a self-reproduction regime for both
types of models analyzed. The results are interpreted and explicit analytical
expressions are given whenever that is possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00778</id><created>2015-10-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jianfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Jiajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yunfang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Weihao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shubin</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author></authors><title>An Analogue Front-End ASIC Prototype Designed For PMT Signal Readout</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 29 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/6/066101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Large High Altitude Air Shower Observatory (LHAASO) is designed for high
energy gamma ray and cosmic ray detection. A Water Cherenkov Detector Array
which is sensitive to gamma ray showers above a few hundred GeV is proposed to
survey gamma ray sources. The WCDA consists of 3600 PhotoMultiplier Tubes (PMT)
which collect the Cherenkov light produced by the shower particles in water.
Both high precision time and charge measurement are required over a large
dynamic range from 1 photo electron (P.E.) to 4000 P.E. Prototype of an
analogue front-end Application Specific Integrated Circuit (ASIC) fabricated in
Chartered 0.35 {\mu}m CMOS technology is designed to read out PMT signal in the
WCDA. This ASIC employs leading edge discrimination and RC4 shaping structure;
combined with the following Time-to-Digital Converter (TDC) and
Analog-to-Digital Converter (ADC), both the arrival time and charge of the PMT
signal can be measured. Initial test results indicate that time resolution is
better than 350 ps and charge resolution is better than 10% at 1 P.E. and
better than 1% with large input signals (300 P.E. to 4000 P.E.). Besides, this
ASIC has a small channel-to-channel crosstalk and low ambient temperature
dependency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01116</id><created>2015-10-05</created><updated>2015-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barucca</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tantari</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lillo</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author></authors><title>Centrality metrics and localization in core-periphery networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 023401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/02/023401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two concepts of centrality have been defined in complex networks. The first
considers the centrality of a node and many different metrics for it has been
defined (e.g. eigenvector centrality, PageRank, non-backtracking centrality,
etc). The second is related to a large scale organization of the network, the
core-periphery structure, composed by a dense core plus an outlying and
loosely-connected periphery. In this paper we investigate the relation between
these two concepts. We consider networks generated via the Stochastic Block
Model, or its degree corrected version, with a strong core-periphery structure
and we investigate the centrality properties of the core nodes and the ability
of several centrality metrics to identify them. We find that the three measures
with the best performance are marginals obtained with belief propagation,
PageRank, and degree centrality, while non-backtracking and eigenvector
centrality (or MINRES}, showed to be equivalent to the latter in the large
network limit) perform worse in the investigated networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03064</id><created>2015-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wosnitzka</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedrocchi</keyname><forenames>Fabio L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DiVincenzo</keyname><forenames>David P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Methodology for bus layout for topological quantum error correcting
  codes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Quantum Technology (2016) 3:4</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjqt/s40507-016-0042-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most quantum computing architectures can be realized as two-dimensional
lattices of qubits that interact with each other. We take transmon qubits and
transmission line resonators as promising candidates for qubits and couplers;
we use them as basic building elements of a quantum code. We then propose a
simple framework to determine the optimal experimental layout to realize
quantum codes. We show that this engineering optimization problem can be
reduced to the solution of standard binary linear programs. While solving such
programs is a NP-hard problem, we propose a way to find scalable optimal
architectures that require solving the linear program for a restricted number
of qubits and couplers. We apply our methods to two celebrated quantum codes,
namely the surface code and the Fibonacci code.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04410</id><created>2015-10-15</created><updated>2015-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Calman</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorow</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fogler</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butov</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishchenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geim</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Control of excitons in multi-layer van der Waals heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 108, 101901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4943204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental study of excitons in a double quantum well van der
Waals heterostructure made of atomically thin layers of \Mo* and hexagonal
boron nitride (hBN). The emission of neutral and charged excitons is controlled
by gate voltage, temperature, and both the helicity and the power of optical
excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04423</id><created>2015-10-15</created><updated>2016-02-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garattini</keyname><forenames>Remo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Constant from a Deformation of the Wheeler-DeWitt Equation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 0 figures, Accepted in Nucl. Phys. B</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B905, 313 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2016.02.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider the Wheeler-DeWitt equation modified by a
deformation of the second quantized canonical commutation relations. Such
modified commutation relations are induced by a Generalized Uncertainty
Principle. Since the Wheeler-DeWitt equation can be related to a
Sturm-Liouville problem where the associated eigenvalue can be interpreted as
the cosmological constant, it is possible to explicitly relate such an
eigenvalue to the deformation parameter of the corresponding Wheeler-DeWitt
equation. The analysis is performed in a Mini-Superspace approach where the
scale factor appears as the only degree of freedom. The deformation of the
Wheeler-DeWitt equation gives rise to a Cosmological Constant even in absence
of matter fields. As a Cosmological Constant cannot exists in absence of the
matter fields in the undeformed Mini-Superspace approach, so the existence of a
non-vanishing Cosmological Constant is a direct consequence of the deformation
by the Generalized Uncertainty Principle. In fact, we are able to demonstrate
that a non-vanishing Cosmological Constant exists even in the deformed flat
space. We also discuss the consequences of this deformation on the big bang
singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06931</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Tafti</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>Q. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haldolaarachchige</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Consequences of breaking time reversal symmetry in LaSb: a resistivity
  plateau and extreme magnetoresistance</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 figures, 25 pages including supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 272 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3581</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time reversal symmetry (TRS) protects the metallic surface modes of
topological insulators (TIs). The transport signature of robust metallic
surface modes of TIs is a plateau that arrests the exponential divergence of
the insulating bulk with decreasing temperature. This universal behavior is
observed in all TI candidates ranging from Bi2Te2Se to SmB6. Recently, several
topological semimetals (TSMs) have been found that exhibit extreme
magnetoresistance (XMR) and TI universal resistivity behavior revealed only
when breaking TRS, a regime where TIs theoretically cease to exist. Among these
new materials, TaAs and NbP are nominated for Weyl semimetal due to their lack
of inversion symmetry, Cd3As2 is nominated for Dirac semimetal due to its
linear band crossing at the Fermi level, and WTe2 is nominated for resonant
compensated semimetal due to its perfect electron-hole symmetry. Here we
introduce LaSb, a simple rock-salt structure material without broken inversion
symmetry, without perfect linear band crossing, and without perfect
electron-hole symmetry. Yet LaSb portrays all the exotic field induced
behaviors of the aforementioned semimetals in an archetypal fashion. It shows
(a) the universal TI resistivity with a plateau at 15 K, revealed by a magnetic
field, (b) ultrahigh mobility of carriers in the plateau region, (c) quantum
oscillations with a non-trivial Berry phase, and (d) XMR of about one million
percent at 9 tesla rivaled only by WTe2 and NbP. Due to its dramatic
simplicity, LaSb is the ideal model system to formulate a theoretical
understanding of the exotic consequences of breaking TRS in TSMs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08718</id><created>2015-10-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Yakunin</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suslov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novik</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dvoretsky</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhailov</keyname><forenames>N. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetotransport in Double Quantum Well with Inverted Energy Spectrum:
  HgTe/CdHgTe</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085308 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first experimental study of the double-quantum-well (DQW)
system made of 2D layers with inverted energy band spectrum: HgTe. The
magnetotransport reveals a considerably larger overlap of the conduction and
valence subbands than in known HgTe single quantum wells (QW), which may be
regulated by an applied gate voltage $V_g$. This large overlap manifests itself
in a much higher critical field $B_c$ separating the range above it where the
quantum peculiarities shift linearly with $V_g$ and the range below with a
complicated behavior. In the latter case the $N$-shaped and double-$N$-shaped
structures in the Hall magnetoresistance $\rho_{xy}(B)$ are observed with their
scale in field pronouncedly enlarged as compared to the pictures observed in an
analogous single QW. The coexisting electrons and holes were found in the whole
investigated range of positive and negative $V_g$ as revealed from fits to the
low-field $N$-shaped $\rho_{xy}(B)$ and from the Fourier analysis of
oscillations in $\rho_{xx}(B)$. A peculiar feature here is that the found
electron density $n$ remains almost constant in the whole range of investigated
$V_g$ while the hole density $p$ drops down from the value a factor of 6 larger
than $n$ at extreme negative $V_g$ to almost zero at extreme positive $V_g$
passing through the charge neutrality point. We show that this difference
between $n$ and $p$ stems from an order of magnitude larger density of states
for holes in the lateral valence band maxima than for electrons in the
conduction band minimum. We interpret the observed reentrant sign-alternating
$\rho_{xy}(B)$ between electronic and hole conductivities and its zero
resistivity state in the quantum Hall range of fields on the basis of a
calculated picture of magnetic levels in a DQW.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08931</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-03-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandigrami</keyname><forenames>Prithviraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portman</keyname><forenames>John J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing allosteric transitions in the domains of calmodulin through
  coarse-grained simulations</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 105102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4943130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Calmodulin (CaM) is a ubiquitous calcium binding protein consisting of two
structurally similar domains with distinct stabilities, binding affinities, and
flexibilities. We present coarse grained simulations that suggest the mechanism
for the domain's allosteric transitions between the open and closed
conformations depend on subtle differences in the folded state topology of the
two domains. Throughout a wide temperature range, the simulated transition
mechanism of the N-terminal domain (nCaM) follows a two-state transition
mechanism while domain opening in the C-terminal domain (cCaM) involves
unfolding and refolding of the tertiary structure. The appearance of the
unfolded intermediate occurs at a higher temperature in nCaM than it does in
cCaM consistent with nCaM's higher thermal stability. Under approximate
physiological conditions, the simulated unfolded state population of cCaM
accounts for 10% of the population with nearly all of the sampled transitions
(approximately 95%) unfolding and refolding during the conformational change.
Transient unfolding significantly slows the domain opening and closing rates of
cCaM. This potentially influences the mechanism of calcium binding to each
domain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05766</id><created>2015-11-18</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alpin</keyname><forenames>Timur Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakin</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Einstein-Maxwell-aether-axion theory: Dynamo-optical anomaly in the
  electromagnetic response</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 0 figures; replaced with the revised version published in
  the International Journal of Modern Physics D</comments><journal-ref>IJMPD 25, 1650048 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271816500486</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a pp-wave symmetric model in the framework of the
Einstein-Maxwell-aether-axion theory. Exact solutions to the equations of axion
electrodynamics are obtained for the model, in which pseudoscalar, electric and
magnetic fields were constant before the arrival of a gravitational pp-wave. We
show that dynamo-optical interactions, i.e. couplings of the electromagnetic
field to a dynamic unit vector field, attributed to the velocity of a cosmic
substratum (aether, vacuum, dark fluid...), provide the response of axionically
active electrodynamic system to display anomalous behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08207</id><created>2015-11-25</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>von Hausegger</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertsch</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Subir</forenames></author></authors><title>Footprints of Loop I on Cosmic Microwave Background Maps</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures; accepted for publication in JCAP with minor
  changes</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 03 (2016)023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/03/023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmology has made enormous progress through studies of the cosmic microwave
background, however the subtle signals being now sought such as B-mode
polarisation due to primordial gravitational waves are increasingly hard to
disentangle from residual Galactic foregrounds in the derived CMB maps. We
revisit our finding that on large angular scales there are traces of the nearby
old supernova remnant Loop I in the WMAP 9-year map of the CMB and confirm this
with the new SMICA map from the Planck satellite.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09252</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-01-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Yun-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Kai-Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Neng-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for gamma-ray emission from eight dwarf spheroidal galaxy
  candidates discovered in Year Two of Dark Energy Survey with Fermi-LAT data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>To appear in Phys. Rev. D, Fig.4 has been updated and main
  conclusions are unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review D 93, 043518 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.043518</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Very recently the Dark Energy Survey (DES) Collaboration has released their
second group of Dwarf spheroidal (dSph) galaxy candidates. With the
publicly-available Pass 8 data of Fermi-LAT we search for $\gamma-$ray
emissions from the directions of these eight newly discovered dSph galaxy
candidates. No statistically significant $\gamma-$ray signal has been found in
the combined analysis of these sources. With the empirically estimated
J-factors of these sources, the constraint on the annihilation channel of
$\chi\chi \rightarrow \tau^{+}\tau^{-}$ is comparable to the bound set by the
joint analysis of fifteen previously known dSphs with kinematically constrained
J-factors for the dark matter mass $m_\chi&gt;250$ GeV. In the direction of Tucana
III (DES J2356-5935), one of the nearest dSph galaxy candidates that is $\sim
25$ kpc away, there is a weak $\gamma-$ray signal and its peak test statistic
(TS) value for the dark matter annihilation channel $\chi\chi\rightarrow
\tau^{+}\tau^{-1}$ is $\approx 6.7$ at $m_\chi \sim 15$ GeV. The significance
of the possible signal likely increases with time. More data is highly needed
to pin down the physical origin of such a GeV excess.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02421</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Rong-Jia</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum hoop conjecture and a natural cutoff for vacuum energy of a
  scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>3 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Results in Physics 6 (2016) 98-99</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.rinp.2016.02.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose here a quantum hoop conjecture which states: the de Broglie
wavelength of a quantum system cannot be arbitrarily small, it must be larger
than the characterized Schwarzschild radius of the quantum system. Based on
this conjecture, we find an upper bound for the wave number (or the momentum)
of a particle, which offers a natural cutoff for the vacuum energy of a scalar
field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04947</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mondaini</keyname><forenames>Rubem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fratus</keyname><forenames>Keith R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srednicki</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigol</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenstate thermalization in the two-dimensional transverse field Ising
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures, as published</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 032104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.032104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the onset of eigenstate thermalization in the two-dimensional
transverse field Ising model (2D-TFIM) in the square lattice. We consider two
non-equivalent Hamiltonians: the ferromagnetic 2D-TFIM and the
antiferromagnetic 2D-TFIM in the presence of a uniform longitudinal field. We
use full exact diagonalization to examine the behavior of quantum chaos
indicators and of the diagonal matrix elements of operators of interest in the
eigenstates of the Hamiltonian. A finite size scaling analysis reveals that
quantum chaos and eigenstate thermalization occur in those systems whenever the
fields are nonvanishing and not too large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04950</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rosado</keyname><forenames>Pablo A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasky</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thrane</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xingjiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandel</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sesana</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Detectability of Gravitational Waves from High-Redshift Binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>PRL 116, 101102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.101102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent non-detection of gravitational-wave backgrounds from pulsar timing
arrays casts further uncertainty on the evolution of supermassive black hole
binaries. We study the capabilities of current gravitational-wave observatories
to detect individual binaries and demonstrate that, contrary to conventional
wisdom, some are in principle detectable throughout the Universe. In
particular, a binary with rest-frame mass $\gtrsim10^{10}\,M_\odot$ can be
detected by current timing arrays at arbitrarily high redshifts. The same claim
will apply for less massive binaries with more sensitive future arrays. As a
consequence, future searches for nanohertz gravitational waves could be
expanded to target evolving high-redshift binaries. We calculate the maximum
distance at which binaries can be observed with pulsar timing arrays and other
detectors, properly accounting for redshift and using realistic binary
waveforms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07194</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-02-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Shouryya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostmann</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Lena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gro&#xdf;mann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strunz</keyname><forenames>Walter T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of interacting bosons using the Herman-Kluk semiclassical
  initial value representation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures; accepted for publication in present form by J.
  Phys. A: Math. Theor</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 165303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/16/165303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experimental progress using ultracold gases in optical lattices
necessitates a quantitative theoretical description for a significant number of
bosons. In the present paper, we investigate if time-dependent semiclassical
initial value methods, with propagators expressed as integrals over phase space
using classical trajectories, is suitable to describe interacting bosons,
concentrating on a single mode. Despite the nonlinear contribution from the
self-interaction, the corresponding classical dynamics allows for a largely
analytical treatment of the semiclassical propagator. We find that the
Herman-Kluk (HK) propagator conserves unitarity in the semiclassical limit
($n\to\infty$), but a decay of the norm is seen for low $n$. The frozen
Gaussian approximation (FGA, i.e. HK with unit prefactor) is explicitly shown
to violate unitarity in the present system for non-vanishing interaction
strength, even in the semiclassical limit. Furthermore, we show by evaluating
the phase space integral in steepest descent approximation, that the HK
propagator reproduces the exact spectrum correctly in the limit $n\to \infty$.
An error is, however, incurred in next-to-next-to-leading order (small
parameter $1/n$), as seen upon numerical evaluation of the integral or by
considering finite $n$ corrections to steepest descent. The FGA, in contrast,
is only accurate to lowest order, and an erroneous next-to-leading order term
in the energy spectrum was found analytically. Finally, as an example
application, we study the dynamics of wave packets by computing the time
evolution of the Wigner function. While the often-used truncated Wigner
approximation cannot capture any interferences present in the exact quantum
mechanical solution (known analytically), we find that the HK approach, despite
also using classical information only, reproduces the salient features of the
exact solution correctly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09095</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bern&#xe1;d</keyname><forenames>J&#xf3;zsef Zsolt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>Juan Mauricio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunz</keyname><forenames>Ludwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alber</keyname><forenames>Gernot</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiphoton-state-assisted entanglement purification of material qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 032317 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.032317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an entanglement purification scheme based on material qubits and
ancillary coherent multiphoton states. We consider a typical QED scenario where
material qubits implemented by two-level atoms fly sequentially through a
cavity and interact resonantly with a single mode of the radiation field. We
explore the theoretical possibilities of realizing a high-fidelity two-qubit
quantum operation necessary for the purification protocol with the help of a
postselective balanced homodyne photodetection. We demonstrate that the
obtained probabilistic quantum operation can be used as a bilateral operation
in the proposed purification scheme. It is shown that the probabilistic nature
of this quantum operation is counterbalanced in the last step of the scheme
where qubits are not discarded after inadequate qubit measurements. As this
protocol requires present-day experimental setups and generates high-fidelity
entangled pairs with high repetition rates, it may offer interesting
perspectives for applications in quantum information theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09190</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jiangping</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying the Genes of Unconventional High Temperature Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Science Bulletin, 2016, 61(7) 561-569</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We elucidate a recently emergent framework in unifying the two families of
high temperature (high $T_c$) superconductors, cuprates and iron-based
superconductors. The unification suggests that the latter is simply the
counterpart of the former to realize robust extended s-wave pairing symmetries
in a square lattice. The unification identifies that the key ingredients (gene)
of high $T_c$ superconductors is a quasi two dimensional electronic environment
in which the d-orbitals of cations that participate in strong in-plane
couplings to the p-orbitals of anions are isolated near Fermi energy. With this
gene, the superexchange magnetic interactions mediated by anions could maximize
their contributions to superconductivity. Creating the gene requires special
arrangements between local electronic structures and crystal lattice
structures. The speciality explains why high $T_c$ superconductors are so rare.
An explicit prediction is made to realize high $T_c$ superconductivity in
$Co/Ni$-based materials with a quasi two dimensional hexagonal lattice
structure formed by trigonal bipyramidal complexes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00597</id><created>2016-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Recho</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranft</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcq</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>One-dimensional collective migration of a proliferating cell monolayer</title><categories>q-bio.QM physics.bio-ph q-bio.CB</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 2381-2391 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5SM02857D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The importance of collective cellular migration during embryogenesis and
tissue repair asks for a sound understanding of underlying principles and
mechanisms. Here, we address recent in vitro experiments on cell monolayers
which show that the advancement of the leading edge relies on cell
proliferation and protrusive activity at the tissue margin. Within a simple
viscoelastic mechanical model amenable to detailed analysis, we identify a key
parameter responsible for tissue expansion, and we determine the dependence of
the monolayer velocity as a function of measurable rheological parameters. Our
results allow us to discuss the effects of pharmacological perturbations on the
observed tissue dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01181</id><created>2016-01-06</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf6;rbe</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s F.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Simple Proof of Sklyanin's Formula for Canonical Spectral Coordinates
  of the Rational Calogero-Moser System</title><categories>math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><msc-class>14H70, 37J15, 53D20</msc-class><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 027</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.027</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We use Hamiltonian reduction to simplify Falqui and Mencattini's recent proof
of Sklyanin's expression providing spectral Darboux coordinates of the rational
Calogero-Moser system. This viewpoint enables us to verify a conjecture of
Falqui and Mencattini, and to obtain Sklyanin's formula as a corollary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03621</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yifei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahin-Tiras</keyname><forenames>Kevser</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harmon</keyname><forenames>Nicholas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohlgenannt</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flatt&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Immense magnetic response of exciplex light emission due to correlated
  spin-charge dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, PRX in press</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 011011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.011011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As carriers slowly move through a disordered energy landscape in organic
semiconductors, tiny spatial variations in spin dynamics relieve spin blocking
at transport bottlenecks or in the electron-hole recombination process that
produces light. Large room-temperature magnetic-field effects (MFE) ensue in
the conductivity and luminescence. Sources of variable spin dynamics generate
much larger MFE if their spatial structure is correlated on the nanoscale with
the energetic sites governing conductivity or luminescence such as in
co-evaporated organic blends within which the electron resides on one molecule
and the hole on the other (an exciplex). Here we show that exciplex
recombination in blends exhibiting thermally-activated delayed fluorescence
(TADF) produces MFE in excess of 60% at room temperature. In addition, effects
greater than 4000% can be achieved by tuning the device's current-voltage
response curve by device conditioning. These immense MFEs are both the largest
reported values for their device type at room temperature. Our theory traces
this MFE and its unusual temperature dependence to changes in spin mixing
between triplet exciplexes and light-emitting singlet exciplexes. In contrast,
spin mixing of excitons is energetically suppressed, and thus spin mixing
produces comparatively weaker MFE in materials emitting light from excitons by
affecting the precursor pairs. Demonstration of immense MFE in common organic
blends provides a flexible and inexpensive pathway towards magnetic
functionality and field sensitivity in current organic devices without
patterning the constituent materials on the nanoscale. Magnetic fields increase
the power efficiency of unconditioned devices by 30% at room temperature, also
showing that magnetic fields may increase the efficiency of the TADF process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08161</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amaral</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calliari</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>T. Ferreira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tempor&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von der Weid</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-Poisson States Heralded at a Hong-Ou-Mandel Interference Peak</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A peak in coincidence events has been observed in a modified Hong-Ou-Mandel
interferometer fed with weak coherent states inside the region of overlapping
wave-packets. The inversion of the usual interference pattern represented by
the HOM dip is equally observed when the wave packets are frequency displaced.
The higher rate of coincidences indicates that photons are more likely to take
on different output paths of the interferometer. This effect was harnessed so a
detection on one of the arms could herald the presence of a photon in the
other. The second order autocorrelation function at zero time was
experimentally determined by means of the Hanburry-Brown and Twiss experiment
and its value below 1 confirmed the sub-Poisson photon statistics of the
heralded states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01824</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Bacaksiz</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cahangirov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senger</keyname><forenames>R. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peeters</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahin</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bilayer SnS$_{2}$: Easy-tunable Stacking Sequence by Charging and
  Loading Pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.125403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Employing density functional theory-based methods, we investigate monolayer
and bilayer structures of hexagonal SnS$_{2}$, which is recently synthesized
monolayer metal dichalcogenide. Comparison of 1H and 1T phases of monolayer
SnS$_{2}$ confirms the ground state to be the 1T phase. In its bilayer
structure we examine different stacking configurations of the two layers. It is
found that the interlayer coupling in bilayer SnS$_{2}$ is weaker than that of
typical transition-metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) so that alternative stacking
orders have similar structural parameters and they are separated with low
energy barriers. Possible signature of the stacking order in SnS$_{2}$ bilayer
has been sought in the calculated absorbance and reflectivity spectra. We also
study the effects of the external electric field, charging, and loading
pressure on the characteristic properties of bilayer SnS$_{2}$. It is found
that (i) the electric field increases the coupling between the layers at its
prefered stacking order, so the barrier height increases, (ii) the bang gap
value can be tuned by the external E-field and under sufficient E-field, the
bilayer SnS$_{2}$ can become semi-metal, (iii) the most favorable stacking
order can be switched by charging and (iv) a loading pressure exceeding 3 GPa
changes the stacking order. E-field tunable bandgap and easy-tunable stacking
sequence of SnS$_{2}$ layers make this 2D crystal structure a good candidate
for field effect transistor and nanoscale lubricant applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02321</id><created>2016-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ya-ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Wei-xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chang-wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pei-ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Sheng-shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Shi-shen</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-gap quantum spin Hall state in functionalized dumbbell stanene</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett., 108, 073104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4942380</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional dumbbell (DB) stanene has been proposed as a promising
candidate material for realizing quantum spin Hall effect (QSHE) by Tang et al
[P. Tang, P. Chen, W. Cao, H. Huang, S. Cahangirov, L. Xian, Y. Xu, S. C.
Zhang, W. Duan, A. Rubio. Phys. Rev. B, 90, 121408 (2014)]. However, the small
bulk-gap limits its possible applications at room temperature. Based on
first-principles calculations, we predict that its band gap can be enhanced to
148 meV under methyl-functionalization, which can be further tuned by applying
lattice strain. The QSHE is confirmed by s-px,y band inversion, topological
invariant Z2 = 1, and helical gapless edge within bulk band gap. Notably, the
characteristic properties of edge states, such as the large Fermi velocity and
Dirac cone, can be modulated by edge modification. The effects of substrates on
topological properties are explored when it is grown on various substrates,
like SiC, h-BN, and Bi2Te3 sheets. These findings provide significant guidance
for future fabrication and realistic applications of QSHE based on stanene in
spintronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04767</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Roger A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reddy</keyname><forenames>Dileep V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitullo</keyname><forenames>Dashiell L. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raymer</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double-heralded generation of two-photon-states by spontaneous
  four-wave-mixing in the presence of noise</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures. Submitted to Optics Express on 1 February, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 5809-5821 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.005809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an experimental method for creating and verifying photon-number
states created by non-degenerate, third-order nonlinear-optical photon-pair
sources. By using spatially multiplexed, thresholding single-photon detectors
and inverting a conditional probability matrix, we determine the photon-number
probabilities created through heralded spontaneous four-wave-mixing. The
deleterious effects of noise photons on reliable heralding are investigated and
shown to degrade the conditional preparation of two-photon number states more
than they degrade conditional single-photon states. We derive the equivalence
between the presence of unwanted noise in the herald channel and loss in the
signal channel of heralded experiments. A procedure for characterizing the
noise-photon contributions, and a means of estimating the herald noise-free
photon-number distribution is demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05160</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Hualai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Cunjing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Quanshui</forenames></author></authors><title>Liquid dispensing and writing by a nano-grooved pin</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn physics.optics</categories><comments>31 pages in total. Maintext: 10 pages, 4 figures. Supplementary
  information: 21 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Liquid dispensing and writing in the extremely small size regime are
important for applications in many current technologies, such as micro/nano
fabrication, biological/chemical patterning and analysis, and drug discovery.
Most of current dispensing/writing methods can be sorted into a category of
liquid flowing through tiny tubes or nozzles that requires inputting an impulse
energy, which leads to complex procedures, expensive equipment and narrow
material applicability, especially for biomaterials. Here, we report a method
that may lead to a new category: liquid flows over the tapered surface of a pin
with longitudinal nano grooves on the surface to uninterruptedly perform
droplet dispensing and direct writing. The dispensed droplet diameters were
controllable from several microns down to 150 nm, and the written line heights
were as low as 5 nm. The mechanism underlying automatic liquid storage on
conical surface and spontaneous liquid transport through nano grooves is
revealed and well modeled by a simple relationship. Furthermore, the
nano-grooved pins are much simpler and cheaper in fabrication than nanoscale
tubes and nozzles, and pins have much depressed clogging problems that are
typically troublesome for tubes and nozzles. Our new strategy may constitute a
basis for creating liquid dispensing/writing technologies that are
simultaneously smaller, simpler, faster and applicable for more types of
materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05818</id><created>2016-02-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Khuntia</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bert</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendels</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koteswararao</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahajan</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baenitz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baines</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furukawa</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Liquid State in the 3D Frustrated Antiferromagnet PbCuTe2O6: NMR
  and muSR Studies</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>To appear in Physical Review Letters</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 107203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.107203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PbCuTe2O6 is a rare example of a spin liquid candidate featuring a three
dimensional magnetic lattice. Strong geometric frustration arises from the
dominant antiferromagnetic interaction which generates a hyperkagome network of
Cu2+ ions although additional interactions enhance the magnetic lattice
connectivity. Through a combination of magnetization measurements and local
probe investigation by NMR and muSR down to 20 mK, we provide a robust evidence
for the absence of magnetic freezing in the ground state. The local spin
susceptibility probed by the NMR shift hardly deviates from the macroscopic one
down to 1 K pointing to a homogeneous magnetic system with a low defect
concentration. The saturation of the NMR shift and the sublinear power law
temperature (T) evolution of the 1/T1 NMR relaxation rate at low T point to a
non-singlet ground state favoring a gapless fermionic description of the
magnetic excitations. Below 1 K a pronounced slowing down of the spin dynamics
is witnessed, which may signal a reconstruction of spinon Fermi surface.
Nonetheless, the compound remains in a fluctuating spin liquid state down to
the lowest temperature of the present investigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07174</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-03-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Balvert</keyname><forenames>Marleen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorissen</keyname><forenames>Bram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hertog</keyname><forenames>Dick den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>Aswin</forenames></author></authors><title>Dwell time modulation restrictions do not necessarily improve treatment
  plan quality for prostate HDR brachytherapy</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics in Medicine and Biology, 60(2), 537-548, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-9155/60/2/537</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inverse planning algorithms for dwell time optimisation in interstitial
high-dose-rate (HDR) brachytherapy may produce solutions with large dwell time
variations within catheters, which may result in undesirable selective
high-dose subvolumes. Extending the optimisation model with a dwell time
modulation restriction (DTMR) that limits dwell time differences between
neighboring dwell positions has been suggested to eliminate this issue. DTMRs
may additionally reduce the sensitivity for uncertainties in dwell positions
that result from catheter reconstruction errors and source positioning
inaccuracies. This study quantifies the reduction of high-dose subvolumes and
the robustness against these uncertainties by applying a DTMR to template-based
prostate HDR brachytherapy implants.
  Three different DTMRs were consecutively applied to a linear dose-based
penalty model (LD) and a dose-volume based model (LDV), both obtained from
literature. The models were solved with DTMR levels ranging from no restriction
to uniform dwell times within catheters. Uncertainties were simulated on
clinical cases using in-house developed software, and dose-volume metrics were
calculated in each simulation. For the assessment of high-dose subvolumes, the
dose homogeneity index (DHI) and the contiguous dose volume histogram were
analysed. Robustness was measured by the improvement of the lowest $D_{90\%}$
of the planning target volume (PTV) observed in the simulations.
  For (LD), a DTMR yields an increase in DHI of 30% and reduces the size of the
largest high-dose volume by 2 to 5 cc. This came at a cost of a reduction in
$D_{90\%}$ of the PTV of 10%, which often implies that it drops below the
desired minimum of 100%. For (LDV), none of the DTMRs improved high-dose volume
measures. DTMRs were not capable of improving robustness of PTV $D_{90\%}$
against uncertainty in dwell positions for both models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08024</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Manson</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benedek</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miret-Artes</keyname><forenames>Salvador</forenames></author></authors><title>The electron-phonon coupling strength at metal surfaces directly
  determined from the Helium atom scattering Debye-Waller factor</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem.Letters 7 (2016) 1016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b00139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new quantum-theoretical derivation of the elastic and inelastic scattering
probability of He atoms from a metal surface, where the energy and momentum
exchange with the phonon gas can only occur through the mediation of the
surface free-electron density, shows that the Debye-Waller exponent is directly
proportional to the electron-phonon mass coupling constant $\lambda$. The
comparison between the values of $\lambda$ extracted from existing data on the
Debye-Waller factor for various metal surfaces and the $\lambda$ values known
from literature indicates a substantial agreement, which opens the possibility
of directly extracting the electron-phonon coupling strength in quasi-2D
conducting systems from the temperature or incident energy dependence of the
elastic Helium atom scattering intensities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08136</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carbajo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calendron</keyname><forenames>Anne-Laure</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cankaya</keyname><forenames>Huseyin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcorta</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravi</keyname><forenames>Koustuban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahr</keyname><forenames>Frederike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xiaojun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallahi</keyname><forenames>Arya</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;rtner</keyname><forenames>Franz X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Path Towards Relativistic Transients at Millimeter Wavelengths</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author because some of the
  content may appear to contain error or needs to be verified before
  re-submission</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We refine the method towards extraction of sub-cycle transients in the 0.1-1
THz frequency (mm-wavelength) range from optical rectification in lithium
niobate using tilted pulse fronts. Our scheme exploits previously unexplored
spatio-temporal shaping of the pump pulses, resulting in highly efficient and
near diffraction-limited sub-THz transients reaching 0.2 GV/m electric field
strengths in free-space using only mJ-level optical ps-pulses. We address
experimentally and theoretically the means to producing above-GV/m relativistic
sub-THz transients with proper beam confinement and under moderate pumping
conditions, thereby bringing widespread access to strong-field and nonlinear
terahertz applications and devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08339</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08339</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Welch</keyname><forenames>Lester C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillating Flavors in Massless Neutrinos</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Typos fixed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By considering Dirac's equation using quaternions ($\mathbb{H}$) with their
greater degree of freedom in imaginaries, it is shown that a model can be
created with oscillations among flavors even if the particles, are massless.
Furthermore the solutions are spin $\frac{1}{2}$ and have helicities depending
on whether their energy is positive or negative.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00039</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hristov</keyname><forenames>Kiril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katmadas</keyname><forenames>Stefanos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lodato</keyname><forenames>Ivano</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher derivative corrections to BPS black hole attractors in 4d gauged
  supergravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>35 pages, no figures; v2: references and acknowledgements added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze BPS black hole attractors in 4d gauged supergravity in the
presence of higher derivative supersymmetric terms, including a
Weyl-squared-type action, and determine the resulting corrections to the
Bekenstein-Hawking entropy. The near-horizon geometry AdS$_2 \times$S$^2$ (or
other Riemann surface) preserves half of the supercharges in $N=2$ supergravity
with Fayet-Iliopoulos gauging. We derive a relation between the entropy and the
black hole charges that suggests via AdS/CFT how subleading corrections
contribute to the supersymmetric index in the dual microscopic picture.
  Depending on the model, the attractors are part of full black hole solutions
with different asymptotics, such as Minkowski, AdS$_4$, and hvLif$_4$. We give
explicit examples for each of the asymptotic cases and comment on the
implications. Among other results, we find that the Weyl-squared terms spoil
the exact two-derivative relation to non-BPS asymptotically flat black holes in
ungauged supergravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01680</id><created>2016-03-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Saghayezhian</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Lina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Gaomin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Hangwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plummer</keyname><forenames>E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jiandi</forenames></author></authors><title>Polar compensation at the surface of SrTiO3 (111)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted to Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 125408 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.125408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have systematically investigated the annealing effect on the structure and
composition of the polar surface of SrTiO3 (111), starting with an ex-situ
chemical etch. The relative surface concentration between Ti and Sr strongly
depends on both the annealing temperature and the oxygen processing. There is a
critical annealing temperature at which the maximum concentration ratio of Ti
to Sr is achieved, while still maintaining a (1 x 1) surface structure. We
demonstrate that with proper processing it is possible to avoid surface
reconstruction over a broad temperature range. Our results provide an optimal
temperature window for epitaxial film growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02788</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gararella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation-mediated Plasticity in CuZr based Metallic Glass
  Composites: A Quantitative Mechanistic Understanding</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>32 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present a thorough stress analysis of the Cu-Zr
metallic-glass composite with embedded B2 particles subject to a martensitic
transformation. Within the framework of the Eshelby theory, we are able to
explain, in a quantitative manner, (1) the formation of three types of shear
bands with distinct morphologies as observed experimentally in the severely
deformed Cu-Zr metallic-glass composite and (2) the work hardening ability of
the Cu-Zr metallic-glass composite as related to the coupled effects of elastic
back stress and elastic mismatch caused by the martensitic transformation.
Furthermore, we also discuss the issues about the stress affected zone of the
individual B2 phase and the stability of the crystalline-amorphous interface.
Given the general agreement between the theoretical and experimental findings,
we believe that the outcome of our current work can lead to a deeper
understanding of the transformation-induced plasticity in the Cu-Zr based
metallic glass composites, which should be very useful to the design of the
metallic-glass composites with improved ductility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02993</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-03-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Servin</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padilla</keyname><forenames>Moises</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnica</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of multi-wavelength temporal phase-shifting algorithms
  optimized for high signal-to-noise ratio and high detuning robustness using
  the frequency transfer function</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 18 figures, 09-03-2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Synthesis of single-wavelength temporal phase-shifting algorithms (PSA) for
interferometry is well-known and firmly based on the frequency transfer
function (FTF) paradigm. Here we extend the single-wavelength FTF-theory to
dual and multi-wavelength PSA-synthesis when several simultaneous laser-colors
are present. The FTF-based synthesis for dual-wavelength PSA (DW-PSA) is
optimized for high signal-to-noise ratio and minimum number of temporal
phase-shifted interferograms. The DW-PSA synthesis herein presented may be used
for interferometric contouring of discontinuous industrial objects. Also DW-PSA
may be useful for DW shop-testing of deep free-form aspheres. As shown here,
using the FTF-based synthesis one may easily find explicit DW-PSA formulae
optimized for high signal-to-noise and high detuning robustness. To this date,
no general synthesis and analysis for temporal DW-PSAs has been given; only
had-hoc DW-PSAs formulas have been reported. Consequently, no explicit formulae
for their spectra, their signal-to-noise, their detuning and harmonic
robustness has been given. Here for the first time a fully general procedure
for designing DW-PSAs (or triple-wavelengths PSAs) with desire spectrum,
signal-to-noise ratio and detuning robustness is given. We finally generalize
DW-PSA to higher number of wavelength temporal PSAs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03045</id><created>2016-03-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Inoue</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gyenis</keyname><forenames>Andras</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Seong Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Ni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernevig</keyname><forenames>B. Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazdani</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasiparticle interference of the Fermi arcs and surface-bulk
  connectivity of a Weyl semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>published in Science on March 11th</comments><journal-ref>Science Vol. 351, Issue 6278, pp. 1184 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aad8766</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weyl semimetals host topologically protected surface states, with arced Fermi
surface contours that are predicted to propagate through the bulk when their
momentum matches that of the surface projections of the bulk's Weyl nodes. We
use spectroscopic mapping with a scanning tunneling microscope to visualize
quasi-particle scattering and interference at the surface of the Weyl semimetal
TaAs. Our measurements reveal 10 different scattering wave vectors, which can
be understood and precisely reproduced with a theory that takes into account
the shape, spin texture, and momentum-dependent propagation of the Fermi arc
surface states into the bulk. Our findings provide evidence that Weyl nodes act
as sinks for electron transport on the surface of these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03123</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolokolova</keyname><forenames>Ludmilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Aigen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebreton</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;my</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Scattering and Thermal Emission by Primitive Dust Particles in
  Planetary Systems</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>61 pages, 23 figures, to appear in Light Scattering Reviews, Volume
  11 (Springer, ISBN: 978-3-662-49536-0)</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-662-49538-4_8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This review focuses on numerical approaches to deducing the light-scattering
and thermal-emission properties of primitive dust particles in planetary
systems from astronomical observations. The particles are agglomerates of small
grains with sizes comparable to visible wavelength and compositions being
mainly magnesium-rich silicates, iron-bearing metals, and organic refractory
materials in pristine phases. These unique characteristics of primitive dust
particles reflect their formation and evolution around main-sequence stars of
essentially solar composition. The development of light-scattering theories has
been offering powerful tools to make a thorough investigation of light
scattering and thermal emission by primitive dust agglomerates in such a
circumstellar environment. In particular, the discrete dipole approximation,
the T-matrix method, and effective medium approximations are the most popular
techniques for practical use in astronomy. Numerical simulations of light
scattering and thermal emission by dust agglomerates of submicrometer-sized
constituent grains have a great potential to provide new state-of-the-art
knowledge of primitive dust particles in planetary systems. What is essential
to this end is to combine the simulations with comprehensive collections of
relevant results from not only astronomical observations, but also in-situ data
analyses, laboratory sample analyses, laboratory analogue experiments, and
theoretical studies on the origin and evolution of the particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03168</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wada</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senshu</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Cohesion of Amorphous Silica Spheres: Toward a Better Understanding of
  the Coagulation Growth of Silicate Dust Aggregates</title><categories>astro-ph.EP cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>in The Astrophysical Journal, 812:67 (12pp), 2015 October 10</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/812/1/67</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adhesion forces between submicrometer-sized silicate grains play a crucial
role in the formation of silicate dust agglomerates, rocky planetesimals, and
terrestrial planets. The surface energy of silicate dust particles is the key
to their adhesion and rolling forces in a theoretical model based on the
contact mechanics. Here we revisit the cohesion of amorphous silica spheres by
compiling available data on the surface energy for hydrophilic amorphous silica
in various circumstances. It turned out that the surface energy for hydrophilic
amorphous silica in a vacuum is a factor of 10 higher than previously assumed.
Therefore, the previous theoretical models underestimated the critical velocity
for the sticking of amorphous silica spheres, as well as the rolling friction
forces between them. With the most plausible value of the surface energy for
amorphous silica spheres, theoretical models based on the contact mechanics are
in harmony with laboratory experiments. Consequently, we conclude that silicate
grains with a radius of $0.1~\mu$m could grow to planetesimals via coagulation
in a protoplanetary disk. We argue that the coagulation growth of silicate
grains in a molecular cloud is advanced either by organic mantles rather than
icy mantles or, if there are no mantles, by nanometer-sized grain radius.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03239</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Vahabi</keyname><forenames>Mahsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Abhinav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Licup</keyname><forenames>Albert James</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Oosten</keyname><forenames>Anne S. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galie</keyname><forenames>Peter A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janmey</keyname><forenames>Paul A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacKintosh</keyname><forenames>Fred C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Elasticity of fibrous networks under axial prestress</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present theoretical and experimental studies of the elastic response of
fibrous networks subjected to uniaxial strain. Uniaxial compression or
extension is applied to extracellular networks of fibrin and collagen using a
shear rheometer with free water in/outflow. Both axial stress and the network
shear modulus are measured. Prior work [van Oosten et al., Scientific Reports,
2015, 6, 19270] has shown softening/stiffening of these networks under
compression/extension, together with a nonlinear response to shear, but the
origin of such behaviour remains poorly understood. Here, we study how uniaxial
strain influences the nonlinear mechanics of fibrous networks. Using a
computational network model with bendable and stretchable fibres, we show that
the softening/stiffening behaviour can be understood for fixed lateral
boundaries in 2D and 3D networks with comparable average connectivities to the
experimental extracellular networks. Moreover, we show that the onset of
stiffening depends strongly on the imposed uniaxial strain. Our study
highlights the importance of both axial strain and boundary conditions in
determining the mechanical response of hydrogels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03427</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Tito</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical configuration of a super-dense hot compact object with
  particular EoS</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 21 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The equation of state (EoS) $P = P (\rho, ...)$ -- pressure as a function of
density and other thermodynamical quantities -- is what generates
particularities of mass--radius distribution $M (R)$ for super--dense compact
stellar bodies, the remnants of cosmic cataclysms. In view of recent nuclear
experiments, we propose one particular EoS, which admits the critical state
characterized by density $\rho_c$ and temperature $T_c$, and which under
certain conditions permits a radial distribution of the super--dense matter in
&quot;liquid&quot; phase. We establish such conditions and demonstrate that a stable
configuration is indeed possible (only) for temperatures smaller than the
critical one. Using Tolman--Oppenheimer--Volkoff equations for hydrostatic
equilibrium, we derive the mass--radius relation for the super--dense compact
objects with masses smaller than the Sun, $M \ll M_{\odot}$. The obtained
results are within the constraints established by both heavy--ion collision
experiments and theoretical studies of neutron--rich matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03429</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Roldan</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barros</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author></authors><title>Geometrical Aspects of non-gravitational interactions</title><categories>gr-qc physics.class-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we look for a geometric description of non-gravitational forces.
The basic ideas are proposed studying the interaction between a punctual
particle and an electromagnetic external field. For this purpose, we introduce
the concept of proper space-time, that allow us to describe this interaction in
a way analogous to the one that the general relativity theory does for
gravitation. The field equations that define this geometry are similar to the
Einstein's equations, where in general, the energy-momentum tensor have
information of both, the particle and the external field. In this formalism we
consider the particle path as being a geodesic in a curved space-time, and so,
the electromagnetic force is understood in a purely geometric way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03454</id><created>2015-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Geiger</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gassenq</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartmann</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widiez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escalante</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guilloy</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauc</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouchon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>G. Osvaldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tardif</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieutord</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchemin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niquet</keyname><forenames>Y. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reboud</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelnokov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faist</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigg</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uniaxially stressed germanium with fundamental direct band gap</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the crossover from indirect- to direct band gap in
tensile-strained germanium by temperature-dependent photoluminescence. The
samples are strained microbridges that enhance a biaxial strain of 0.16% up to
3.6% uniaxial tensile strain. Cooling the bridges to 20 K increases the
uniaxial strain up to a maximum of 5.4%. Temperature-dependent
photoluminescence reveals the crossover to a fundamental direct band gap to
occur between 4.0% and 4.5%. Our data are in good agreement with new
theoretical computations that predict a strong bowing of the band parameters
with strain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03460</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Jun</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giarra</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Haisheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Main</keyname><forenames>Russell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlachos</keyname><forenames>Pavlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Confocal laser scanning microscopy image correlation for nanoparticle
  flow velocimetry</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>30 pages, 13 figures, 2 tables, submitted to Measurement Science and
  Technology - Special Issue Article (PIV 2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new particle image correlation technique for resolving
nanoparticle flow velocity using confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM). The
two primary issues that complicate nanoparticle scanning laser image
correlation (SLIC) based velocimetry are (1) the use of diffusion dominated
nanoparticles as flow tracers, which introduce a random decorrelating error
into the velocity estimate, and (2) the effects of the scanning laser image
acquisition, which introduces a bias error. To date, no study has quantified
these errors or demonstrated a means to deal with them in SLIC velocimetry. In
this work, we build upon the robust phase correlation (RPC) and existing
methods of SLIC to quantify and mitigate these errors. First, we implement an
ensemble RPC instead of using an ensemble standard cross correlation, and
develop an SLIC optimal filter that maximizes the correlation strength in order
to reliably and accurately detect the correlation peak representing the most
probable average displacement of the nanoparticles. Secondly, we developed an
analytical model of the SLIC measurement bias error due to image scanning of
diffusion dominated tracer particles. We show that the bias error depends only
on the ratio of the mean velocity of the tracer particles to that of the laser
scanner and we use this model to correct the induced errors. We validated our
technique using synthetic images and experimentally obtained SLIC images of
nanoparticle flow through a micro-channel. Our technique reduced the error by
up to a factor of ten compared to other SLIC algorithms for the images tested
in this study. Moreover, our optimized RPC filter is reducing the number of
image pairs required for the convergence of the ensemble correlation by two
orders of magnitude compared to the standard cross correlation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03468</id><created>2016-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>El-Omari</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The singular values of the logarithmic potential transform on bound
  states spaces of Landau Hamiltonian</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The singular values of the logarithmic potential transform on the generalized
Bergmann space is calculated explicitly, too behavior in infinity
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03470</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Cundy</keyname><forenames>Nigel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Weonjong</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete Monopole Dominance of the Yang-Mills Confining Potential</title><categories>hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>35 pages, 13 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1503.07033</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We continue our investigation of quark confinement using a particular variant
of the Cho-Duan-Ge gauge independent Abelian decomposition. The decomposition
splits the gauge field into a restricted Abelian part and a coloured part in a
way that preserves gauge covariance. The restricted part of the gauge field can
be divided into a Maxwell term and a topological term. Previously, we showed
that by a particular choice of this decomposition we could fully describe the
confining potential using only the restricted gauge field. We proposed that
various topological objects (a form of magnetic monopole) could arise in the
restricted field which would drive confinement. Our mechanism does not
explicitly refer to a dual Meissner effect, nor does it use centre vortices. We
did not need to gauge fix or introduce any new dynamical fields.
  We show that if we do gauge fix as well as performing the Abelian
decomposition then it is possible to ensure that the topological part of the
restricted field fully accounts for the confining potential. Our relationship
is exact: there is no approximation or model involved. This isolates the
objects responsible for confinement from non-confining contributions to the
gauge field, allowing a direct search for our proposed topological objects.
Using numerical studies in SU(2), we confirm that our proposed monopoles are
present in the field, and the winding number associated with these monopoles is
a key factor driving quark confinement.
  In SU(2), our monopoles are described by two parameters. We show that it is
possible to re-parametrise the Yang Mills action and the functional integration
measure in terms of these variables (plus the necessary additional parameters).
We can thus treat the monopoles as dynamical variables in the functional
integral. This might be the first step in a future analytical computation to
complement our numerical results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03471</id><created>2016-03-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gudder</keyname><forenames>Stan</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Quantum Gravity and Quantum Field Theory</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>30 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a discrete 4-dimensional module over the integers that appears
to have maximal symmetry. By adjoining the usual Minkowski distance, we obtain
a discrete 4-dimensional Minkowski space. Forming universe histories in this
space and employing the standard causal order, the histories become causal
sets. These causal sets increase in size rapidly and describe an inflationary
period for the early universe. We next consider the symmetry group $G$ for the
module. We show that $G$ has order 24 and we construct its group table. In a
sense $G$ is a discrete approximation to the Lorentz group. However, we note
that it contains no boosts and is essentially a rotation group. Unitary
representations of $G$ are constructed. The energy-momentum space dual to the
discrete module is obtained and a quantum formalism is derived. A discrete Fock
space is introduced on this structure and free quantum fields are considered.
Finally, we take the first step in a study of interacting quantum fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03478</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Chandralekha</forenames></author></authors><title>Surveying Graduate Students' Attitudes and Approaches to Problem Solving</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, PACS: 01.40Fk,01.40.gb,01.40G-,1.30.Rr, Keywords: Physics
  Education Research, Pedagogy, Teaching, Learning, Graduate students,
  education, attitude, approach, problem solving</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Special Topics Physics Education Research, 6, 1-16
  (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevSTPER.6.020124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Students' attitudes and approaches to problem solving in physics can
profoundly influence their motivation to learn and development of expertise. We
developed and validated an Attitudes and Approaches to Problem Solving survey
by expanding the Attitudes towards Problem Solving survey of Marx and Cummings
and administered it to physics graduate students. Comparison of their responses
to the survey questions about problem solving in their own graduate level
courses vs. problem solving in the introductory physics courses provides
insight into their expertise in introductory and graduate level physics. The
physics graduate students' responses to the survey questions were also compared
with those of introductory physics and astronomy students and physics faculty.
We find that, even for problem solving in introductory physics, graduate
students' responses to some survey questions are less expert-like than those of
the physics faculty. Comparison of survey responses of graduate students and
introductory students for problem solving in introductory physics suggests that
graduate students' responses are in general more expert-like than those of
introductory students. However, survey responses suggest that graduate-level
problem solving by graduate students on several measures has remarkably similar
trends to introductory-level problem solving by introductory students.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03497</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yubin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>XianZhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fengshan</forenames></author></authors><title>The Flattening of Dust Attenuation Curve to z=2.5</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 Pages, 3 Figures, submitted to ApJL: comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the evolution of dust attenuation curve using a sample of 9504
disk star-forming galaxies (SFGs) selected from the CANDELS and 3D-HST surveys
and a new technique relying on the fact that disk SFGs of similar stellar
masses at the same cosmic epoch are statistically identical in stellar
populations. We attribute the discrepancy in median magnitude between face-on
(b/a&gt;0.7) and edge-on (b/a&lt;=0.4) subsamples solely to dust attenuation, and
obtain the average attenuation in the rest-frame UV and optical as functions of
stellar mass and redshift out to z=2.5. Our results show that the attenuation
curve becomes remarkably flatter at increasing redshift for both massive and
low-mass disk SFGs, and remains likely unchanged with galaxy stellar mass at a
fixed epoch within uncertainties. Compared with the Calzetti law, our dust
attenuation curves appear to be slightly steeper at 0.5&lt;z&lt;1.4 and remarkably
flatter at 1.4&lt;z&lt;2.5. Our findings are consistent with a picture in which the
evolution of dust grain size distribution is mainly responsible for the
evolution of the dust attenuation curve in SFGs; dust shattering becomes a
dominant process at z&lt;~1.4, resulting in an enrichment of small dust grains and
consequently a steeper attenuation curve. We stress that extinction correction
for high-z galaxies should be done using mass- and redshift-dependent
attenuation curves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03525</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Terasaki</keyname><forenames>Ichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Igarashi</keyname><forenames>Taichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asai</keyname><forenames>Shinichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okazaki</keyname><forenames>Ryuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasui</keyname><forenames>Yukio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Kensuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumai</keyname><forenames>Reiji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakao</keyname><forenames>Hironori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Youichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel Charge Ordering in the Trimer Iridium Oxide BaIrO3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages 5 figures, Crystals (in press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have prepared polycrystalline samples of the trimer Ir oxide BaIrO3 with
face-shared Ir3O12 trimers, and have investigated the origin of the phase
transition at 182 K by measuring resistivity, thermopower, magnetization and
synchrotron x-ray diffraction. We propose a possible electronic model and
transition mechanism, starting from a localized electron picture on the basis
of the Rietveld refinement. Within this model, BaIrO3 can be basically regarded
as a Mott insulator, when the Ir3O12 trimer is identified to one pseudo-atom or
one lattice site. The transition can be viewed as a transition from the Mott
insulator phase to a kind of charge ordered insulator phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03531</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>G. Narsinga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sankar</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Akansha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muthuselvam</keyname><forenames>I. Panneer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>W. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Viveka Nand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guang-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tellurium-bridged two-leg spin ladder in Ba$_2$CuTeO$_6$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>29 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 104401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.104401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present single-crystal growth and magnetic property studies of
tellurium-bridged copper spin-1/2 system Ba$_2$CuTeO$_6$. The spin-exchange
interaction among copper spins via Cu-O-Te-O-Cu super-superexchange route leads
to a novel two-leg spin ladder system. Spin susceptibility $\chi$(T) data
indicates that the triclinic Ba$_2$CuTeO$_6$ undergoes a stepwise crossover for
exchange couplings revealed by a broad maximum near T$_{max}$$\sim$75~K and an
anisotropic cusp in $\frac{d\chi}{dT}$(T) to signify a three dimensional (3D)
antiferromagnetic long-range ordering (LRO). The 3D LRO has been suggested from
the anisotropic behavior of $\chi$(T) with strong c-axis spin anisotropy and
the signature of spin flop transition from the isothermal magnetization below
$T_N$. Analysis of magnetic heat capacity (Cm) at $T_N$~15 K indicates that
most of the spin entropy (~92% ) has already been released above $T_N$, which
supports the picture of consecutive spin entropy reduction upon cooling with
Te-bridged two-leg spin ladder system with strong intraladder and interladder
couplings. Theoretical DFT+U calculations have been performed to search for the
ground state magnetic configuration and also to evaluate exchange coupling
constants that support the magnetic model deduced from the combined spin
susceptibility and crystal structure symmetry analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03532</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Bao</forenames></author></authors><title>Regularization to orthogonal-polynomials fitting with application to
  magnetization data</title><categories>cs.NA cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure, 3 tables; comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An obstacle encountered in applying orthogonal-polynomials fitting is how to
select out the proper fitting expression. By adding a Laplace term to the error
expression and introducing the concept of overfitting degree, a regularization
and corresponding cross validation scheme is proposed for two-variable
polynomials fitting. While the Fortran implementation of above scheme is
applied to magnetization data, a satisfactory fitting precision is reached, and
overfitting problem can be quantitatively assessed, which therefore offers the
quite reliable base for future comprehensive investigations of magnetocaloric
and phase-transition properties of magnetic functional materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03534</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leung</keyname><forenames>Denny H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Waishing</forenames></author></authors><title>All 2-positive linear maps from M3 to M3 are decomposable</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following an idea of Choi, we obtain a decomposition theorem for k-positive
linear maps from Mm to Mn, where 2&lt;=k&lt;min{m,n}. As a consequence, we give an
affirmative answer to Kye's conjecture (also solved independently by Choi) that
every 2-positive linear map from M3 to M3 is decomposable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03552</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Quax</keyname><forenames>Rick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Har-Shemesh</keyname><forenames>Omri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thurner</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sloot</keyname><forenames>Peter M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stripping syntax from complexity: An information-theoretical perspective
  on complex systems</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 Fig, 30 References</comments><msc-class>94A-02</msc-class><acm-class>F.0</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Claude Shannons information theory (1949) has had a revolutionary impact on
communication science. A crucial property of his framework is that it decouples
the meaning of a message from the mechanistic details from the actual
communication process itself, which opened the way to solve long-standing
communication problems. Here we argue that a similar impact could be expected
by applying information theory in the context of complexity science to answer
long-standing, cross-domain questions about the nature of complex systems. This
happens by decoupling the domain-specific model details (e.g., neuronal
networks, ecosystems, flocks of birds) from the cross-domain phenomena that
characterize complex systems (e.g., criticality, robustness, tipping points).
This goes beyond using information theory as a non-linear correlation measure,
namely it allows describing a complex system entirely in terms of the storage,
transfer, and modification of informational bits. After all, a phenomenon that
does not depend on model details should best be studied in a framework that
strips away all such details. We highlight the first successes of
information-theoretic descriptions in the recent complexity literature, and
emphasize that this type of research is still in its infancy. Finally we sketch
how such an information-theoretic description may even lead to a new type of
universality among complex systems, with a potentially tremendous impact. The
goal of this perspective article is to motivate a paradigm shift in the young
field of complexity science using a lesson learnt in communication science.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03562</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Manoharan</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johri</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Induja</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplanetary Consequences of Coronal Mass Ejection Events occurred
  during 18--25 June 2015</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures; Accepted for publication in ASP Conference Series</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we review the preliminary results on the propagation effects
and interplanetary consequences of fast and wide coronal mass ejection (CME)
events, occurred during 18--25 June 2015, in the Sun-Earth distance range. The
interplanetary scintillation (IPS) images reveal that the large-scale
structures of CME-driven disturbances filled nearly the entire inner
heliosphere with a range of speeds, $\sim$300--1000 {\kmps}. The comparison of
speed data sets, from IPS technique results in the inner heliosphere and {\it
in-situ} measurements at 1 AU, indicates that the drag force imposed by the
low-speed wind dominated heliosphere on the propagation of CMEs may not be
effective. The arrival of shocks at 1 AU suggests that a shock can be driven in
the interplanetary medium by the central part of the moving CME and also by a
different part away from its centre. The increased flux of proton at energies
$&gt;$10 MeV is consistent with the acceleration of particles by the shock ahead
of the CME.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03563</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonfiglio</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cappello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escande</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact Of A Uniform Plasma Resistivity In MHD Modelling Of Helical
  Solutions For The Reversed Field Pinch Dynamo</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Proceeding paper of the 13th International Congress on Plasma
  Physics, Kiev, May 22-26, 2006. This manuscript has been submitted to arXiv
  because it is no longer present in the conference website
  http://www.icpp2006.kiev.ua/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Till now the magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) simulation of the reversed field pinch
(RFP) has been performed by assuming axis-symmetric radial time independent
dissipation profiles. In helical states this assumption is not correct since
these dissipations should be flux functions, and should exhibit a helical
symmetry as well. Therefore more correct simulations should incorporate
self-consistent dissipation profiles. As a first step in this direction, the
case of uniform dissipation profiles was considered by using the 3D nonlinear
visco-resistive MHD code SpeCyl. It is found that a flattening of the
resistivity profile results in the reduction of the dynamo action, which brings
to marginally-reversed or even non-reversed equilibrium solutions. The physical
origin of this result is discussed in relation to the electrostatic drift
explanation of the RFP dynamo. This sets constraints on the functional choice
of dissipations in future self-consistent simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03572</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonfiglio</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cappello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veranda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chac&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escande</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of magnetic perturbations on the 3D MHD self-organization of
  shaped tokamak plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Proceeding paper of the 7th IAEA Technical Meeting on 'Theory of
  Plasmas Instabilities', Frascati (Italy), March 4-6, 2015. This manuscript
  will be published on the conference website
  http://www.iaeatm-inst2015.enea.it/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of magnetic perturbations (MPs) on the helical self-organization
of shaped tokamak plasmas is discussed in the framework of the nonlinear 3D MHD
model. Numerical simulations performed in toroidal geometry with the
\textsc{pixie3d} code [L. Chac\'on, Phys. Plasmas {\bf 15}, 056103 (2008)] show
that $n=1$ MPs significantly affect the spontaneous quasi-periodic sawtoothing
activity of such plasmas. In particular, the mitigation of sawtooth
oscillations is induced by $m/n=1/1$ and $2/1$ MPs. These numerical findings
provide a confirmation of previous circular tokamak simulations, and are in
agreement with tokamak experiments in the RFX-mod and DIII-D devices. Sawtooth
mitigation via MPs has also been observed in reversed-field pinch simulations
and experiments. The effect of MPs on the stochastization of the edge magnetic
field is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03580</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Catalano</keyname><forenames>Gelsomina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Florio</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giffoni</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Willingness to pay for basic research: a contingent valuation experiment
  on the large hadron collider</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 9 tables, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An increasing number of countries and institutions are investing in
large-scale research infrastructures (RIs) and in basic research. Scientific
discoveries, which are expected thanks to RIs, may have a non-use value, in
analogy with environmental and cultural public goods. This paper provides, for
the first time, an empirical estimation of the willingness to pay (WTP) for
discoveries in basic research by the general public. We focus on the Large
Hadron Collider (LHC), the largest particle accelerator worldwide, where in
2012 the Higgs boson was discovered. Nobody knows the practical value of such
discovery, beyond knowledge per se. The findings of our study are based on a
dichotomous choice contingent valuation (CV) survey carried out in line with
the NOAA guidelines. The survey involved 1,022 undergraduate students enrolled
in more than 30 different degrees (including the humanities) at five
universities located in four countries (Italy, France, Spain, UK). We ask two
main research questions: Which are the determinants of the WTP for the LHC
discoveries? What is the average contribution that the respondents would be
willing to pay? Our results confirm that income, interest and attitudes towards
basic research are positively associated with the WTP, while other potential
explanatory variables play a limited role. The estimated mean of WTP for basic
research in particle physics is EUR 7.7 per person una-tantum. Although this is
a small amount compared to other CV studies for environmental and cultural
goods, it points to positive social attitudes for basic science as a public
good.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03582</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Juntao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Qing-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interference Effect of Majorana Fermions in a Spin-orbit Coupled
  Superconducting Wire</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two majorana Fermions (MFs) localized at the two ends of the topological
superconducting wire can interfere with each other and form the well known
$4\pi$ Josephson current. We reveal that the density of states (Dos) for the
electron part and the hole part also follow a parity correlated $4\pi$ period
oscillation, while the Dos displays a $2\pi$ period oscillation when two
trivial states interfere with each other. Thus, the period of Dos oscillation
can be used to distinguish the MFs from the trivial localized states.
Interestingly, such phenomena can be directly observed in a short
superconducting wire controlled by the gate voltage. This largely simplifies
the experimental setup. We suggest that the interference effects can be
detected through two STM leads or two norm leads.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03584</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ning</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum magnetotransport properties of topological insulators under
  strain</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments reveal that the strained bulk HgTe can be regard as a
three-dimensional topological insulator (TI). Motivated by this, we explore the
strain effects on the magnetotransport properties of the HgTe surface states at
magnetic field. We analytically derive the zero frequency Hall and collisional
conductivities, and find that the substrate induced strain associated with the
surface index of carriers, can result in the well seperated surface quantum
Hall plateaus and Shubnikov-de Haas oscillations. These effects can be used to
generate and detect surface polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03625</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Thangjam</keyname><forenames>Guneshwar</forenames></author></authors><title>Mineralogy and Geology of asteroid (4) Vesta from Dawn Framing Camera</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>PhD Thesis, Clausthal University of Techonlogy, 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis presents insights into the surface compositional heterogeneity
and geology of asteroid Vesta. Lithologic mapping using Framing Camera onboard
the NASA Dawn spacecraft revealed that the majority of the surface is
howarditic in composition (Thangjam et al. 2013). An important outcome of this
thesis is identification of olivine-rich exposures for the first time using FC
color data (Thangjam et al., 2014). Another significant contribution from this
thesis is an innovative three-dimensional approach of spectral analysis that
could be used to study surface compositional heterogeneity of Vesta (Thangjam
et al., 2016). The three band parameter space with defined polyhedrons is more
advanced and robust compared to the generally used two-dimensional spectral
analysis i.e., two band parameter space. A revised petrologic evolution model
is presented to explain the ongoing problem of missing olivine-rich mantle of
Vesta and also the petrogenesis of HED meteorites (howardite, eucrite,
diogenite clan of stony achondrites).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03630</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicolaides</keyname><forenames>Cleanthes A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonances in the continuum, field induced nonstationary states, and the
  state and property specific treatment of the many electron problem</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, 1 Figure, Chapter in the Lowdin volume, Advances in Quantum
  Chemistry, Edited by J. Sabin and E. Brandas</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper summarizes elements of theories and computational methods that we
have constructed and applied over the years for the nonperturbative solution of
many electron problems, in the absence or presence of strong external fields,
concerning resonance and nonstationary states with a variety of electronic
structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03643</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Dinh</keyname><forenames>Tien-Cuong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Viet-Anh</forenames></author></authors><title>Large deviations principle for some beta-ensembles</title><categories>math.CV math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1505.08050</comments><msc-class>32U15 (32L05, 60F10)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let L be a positive line bundle over a projective complex manifold X.
Consider the space of holomorphic sections of the tensor power of order p of L.
The determinant of a basis of this space, together with some given probability
measure on a weighted compact set in X, induces naturally a beta-ensemble,
i.e., a random point process on the compact set. Physically, this general
setting corresponds to a gas of free fermions in X and may admit some random
matrix models. The empirical measures, associated with such beta-ensembles,
converge almost surely to an equilibrium measure when p goes to infinity. We
establish a large deviations principle (LDP) with an effective speed of
convergence for these empirical measures. Our study covers the case of some
beta-ensembles on a compact subset of a real sphere or of a real Euclidean
space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03654</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Florio</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forte</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pancotti</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirtori</keyname><forenames>Emanuela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignetti</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring cost-benefit analysis of research, development and innovation
  infrastructures: an evaluation framework</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>86 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents the results and the lessons learned on how to apply
ex-ante CBQ for major RDI infrastructures by a team of economists and
scientists at the University of Milan and CSIL during a three-year research
project supported by a EIBURS grant of the European Investment Bank Institute.
Albeit the comprehensive conceptual framework presented in the paper builds on
principles firmly rooted in CBA tradition, their application to the RDI sector
is still in its infancy. So far, the model has been applied on two cases in
physics involving particle accelerators (the Large Hadron Collider, LHC, at
CERN and the National Centre for Oncological Treatment, CNAO, in Italy).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03660</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Boggia</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames><affiliation>Albert-Ludwigs-Universitaet, Freiburg</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>Raquel</forenames><affiliation>INFN, Turin and Turin U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Passarino</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames><affiliation>INFN, Turin and Turin U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Low energy behaviour of standard model extensions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 8 figures</comments><report-no>FR-PHENO-2016-004</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The integration of heavy scalar fields is discussed in a class of BSM models,
containing more that one representation for scalars and with mixing. The
interplay between integrating out heavy scalars and the Standard Model
decoupling limit is examined. In general, the latter cannot be obtained in
terms of only one large scale and can only be achieved by imposing further
assumptions on the couplings. Systematic low-energy expansions are derived in
the more general, non-decoupling scenario, including mixed tree-loop and mixed
heavy-light generated operators. The number of local operators is larger than
the one usually reported in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03662</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Creek</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donninger</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlag</keyname><forenames>Wilhelm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snelson</keyname><forenames>Stanley</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear stability of the Skyrmion</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>31 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a rigorous proof for the linear stability of the Skyrmion. In
addition, we provide new proofs for the existence of the Skyrmion and the GGMT
bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03664</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Metri</keyname><forenames>Prashant G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tawade</keyname><forenames>Jagdish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abel</keyname><forenames>M Subhash</forenames></author></authors><title>Thin film flow and heat transfer over an unsteady stretching sheet with
  thermal radiation, internal heating in presence of external magnetic field</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a mathematical analysis of thin film flow and heat
transfer to a laminar liquid film from a horizontal stretching sheet. The flow
of thin liquid film and subsequent heat transfer from the stretching surface is
investigated with the aid of similarity transformations. Similarity
transformations are used to convert unsteady boundary layer equations to a
system of non-linear ordinary differential equations. The resulting non-linear
differential equations are solved numerically using Runge-kutta-Fehlberg and
Newton-Raphson schemes. A relationship between film thickness $\beta$ and the
unsteadiness parameter $S$ is found, the effect of unsteadiness parameter $S$,
and the Prandtl number $Pr$, Magnetic field parameter $Mn$, Radiation parameter
$Nr$ and viscous dissipation parameter $Ec$ and heat source parameter $\gamma$
on the temperature distributions are presented and discussed in detail. Present
analysis shows that the combined effect of magnetic field, thermal radiation,
heat source and viscous dissipation. The results which form special case of the
present study are in excellent agreement with the results reported in the
literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03716</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Mailian</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mailian</keyname><forenames>Aram</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transformation in Self-Organized Carbon Tribolayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The simplest way to obtain thin carbon layers is to draw or rub with a
graphite rod. During rubbing, forces of friction acting in graphite/substrate
tribological system cause drastic changes in the structure of the interface
stratum developing thereby stable self-organized and ordered thin structure. We
present a pioneering experimental investigation of structural and morphological
transformations in carbon tribolayers (CTL). By optical microscopy observation
it is found that CTL is a multilayer structure, the essential building block of
which is a transparent phase shaped as a lamina in-between the surface and
bottom disordered layers of CTL. The surface of the lamina exhibits non-linear
electrical conductivity near zero bias on I-V characteristics. The optical
properties of the whole CTL are mostly controlled by physical processes
occurring in the transparent lamina. The Raman spectrum of CTL contains narrow
bands at 1,589 cm-1 and 1,346 cm-1 corresponding to G and D bands of carbon
crystal lattice. The observed features are interpreted using the relationship
between the bond length and corresponding band frequency, r2{\omega}= const.
Optical absorption of CTL has a feature at 4.6 eV originating from strong
electron-hole interaction. From comparative analysis of experimental data,
structural-spectral correspondence is found. It is concluded that because of
phase transformation during rubbing, a carbon structure consisting of sp3
lamina with a nano-scaled thick sp2 layer on the top is shaped.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03718</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Coden</keyname><forenames>Diego S. Acosta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferr&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>Sergio S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal control of a charge qubit in a double quantum dot with a Coulomb
  impurity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the efficiency of modulated laser pulses to produce efficient and
fast charge localization transitions in a two-electron double quantum dot. We
use a configuration interaction method to calculate the electronic structure of
a quantum dot model within the effective mass approximation. The interaction
with the electric field of the laser is considered within the dipole
approximation and optimal control theory is applied to design high-fidelity
ultrafast pulses in pristine samples. We assessed the influence of the presence
of Coulomb charged impurities on the efficiency and speed of the pulses. A
protocol based on a two-step optimization is proposed for preserving both
advantages of the original pulse. The processes affecting the charge
localization is explained from the dipole transitions of the lowest lying
two-electron states, as described by a discrete model with an effective
electron-electron interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03722</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Tabert</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carbotte</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Conductivity of Weyl Semimetals and Signatures of the Gapped
  Semimetal Phase Transition</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085442 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085442</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interband optical response of a three-dimensional Dirac cone is linear in
photon energy ($\Omega$). Here, we study the evolution of the interband
response within a model Hamiltonian which contains Dirac, Weyl and gapped
semimetal phases. In the pure Dirac case, a single linear dependence is
observed, while in the Weyl phase, we find two quasilinear regions with
different slopes. These regions are also distinct from the large-$\Omega$
dependence. As the boundary between the Weyl (WSM) and gapped phases is
approached, the slope of the low-$\Omega$ response increases, while the
photon-energy range over which it applies decreases. At the phase boundary, a
square root behaviour is obtained which is followed by a gapped response in the
gapped semimetal phase. The density of states parallels these behaviours with
the linear law replaced by quadratic behaviour in the WSM phase and the square
root dependence at the phase boundary changed to $|\omega|^{3/2}$. The optical
spectral weight under the intraband (Drude) response at low temperature ($T$)
and/or small chemical potential ($\mu$) is found to change from $T^2$ ($\mu^2$)
in the WSM phase to $T^{3/2}$ ($|\mu|^{3/2}$) at the phase boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03723</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Burderi</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Salvo</keyname><forenames>Tiziana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iaria</keyname><forenames>Rosario</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum clock: A critical discussion on spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, published in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review D 93, 064017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.064017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We critically discuss the measure of very short time intervals. By means of a
Gedankenexperiment, we describe an ideal clock based on the occurrence of
completely random events. Many previous thought experiments have suggested
fundamental Planck-scale limits on measurements of distance and time. Here we
present a new type of thought experiment, based on a different type of clock,
that provide further support for the existence of such limits. We show that the
minimum time interval $\Delta t$ that this clock can measure scales as the
inverse of its size $\Delta r$. This implies an uncertainty relation between
space and time: $\Delta r$ $\Delta t$ $&gt; G \hbar / c^4$; where G, $\hbar$ and c
are the gravitational constant, the reduced Planck constant, and the speed of
light, respectively. We outline and briefly discuss the implications of this
uncertainty conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03726</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Chang-ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuck</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Hojoong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Risheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Hong X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parametric down-conversion photon pair source on a nanophotonic chip</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum photonic chips, which integrate quantum light sources alongside
active and passive optical elements, as well as single photon detectors, show
great potential for photonic quantum information processing and quantum
technology. Mature semiconductor nanofabrication processes allow for scaling
such photonic integrated circuits to on-chip networks of increasing complexity.
Second order nonlinear materials are the method of choice for generating
photonic quantum states in the overwhelming part of linear optic experiments
using bulk components but integration with waveguide circuitry on a
nanophotonic chip proved to be challenging. Here we demonstrate such an on-chip
parametric down-conversion source of photon pairs based on second order
nonlinearity in an Aluminum nitride microring resonator. We show the potential
of our source for quantum information processing by measuring high-visibility
antibunching of heralded single photons with nearly ideal state purity. Our
down conversion source operates with high brightness and low noise, yielding
pairs of correlated photons at MHz-rates with high coincidence-to-accidental
ratio. The generated photon pairs are spectrally far separated from the pump
field, providing good potential for realizing sufficient on-chip filtering and
monolithic integration of quantum light sources, waveguide circuits and single
photon detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03735</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Latawiec</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burek</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sohn</keyname><forenames>Young-Ik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lon&#x10d;ar</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author></authors><title>Faraday cage angled-etching of nanostructures in bulk dielectrics</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For many emerging optoelectronic materials, heteroepitaxial growth techniques
do not offer the same high material quality afforded by bulk, single-crystal
growth. However, the need for optical, electrical, or mechanical isolation at
the nanoscale level often necessitates the use of a dissimilar substrate, upon
which the active device layer stands. Faraday cage angled-etching (FCAE)
obviates the need for these planar, thin-film technologies by enabling in-situ
device release and isolation through an angled-etching process. By placing a
Faraday cage around the sample during inductively-coupled plasma reactive ion
etching (ICP-RIE), the etching plasma develops an equipotential at the cage
surface, directing ions normal to its face. In this Article, the effects
Faraday cage angle, mesh size, and sample placement have on etch angle,
uniformity, and mask selectivity are investigated within a silicon etching
platform. Simulation results qualitatively confirm experiments and help to
clarify the physical mechanisms at work. These results will help guide FCAE
process design across a wide range of material platforms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03740</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shao-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramasubramaniam</keyname><forenames>Ashwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Raman scattering and anomalous Stokes anti-Stokes ratio in MoTe2 atomic
  layers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 Figures and 2 Tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stokes and anti-Stokes Raman scattering are performed on atomic layers of
hexagonal molybdenum ditelluride (MoTe2), a prototypical transition metal
dichalcogenide (TMDC) semiconductor. The data reveal all six types of zone
center optical phonons, along with their corresponding Davydov splittings,
which have been challenging to see in other TMDCs. We discover that the
anti-Stokes Raman intensity of the low energy layer-breathing mode becomes more
intense than the Stokes peak under certain experimental conditions, and find
the effect to be tunable by excitation frequency and number of atomic layers.
These observations are interpreted as a result of resonance effects arising
from the C excitons in the vicinity of the Brillouin zone center in the
photon-electron-phonon interaction process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-03-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03746</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Nemat-Nasser</keyname><forenames>Sia</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified Homogenization of Photonic/Phononic Crystals: Controllable
  First-band Negative Refraction</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 22 figures, no tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown, for the first time, that negative refraction with positive phase
velocity refraction can be realized (and controlled) over a wide range of
frequency on the first (lowest) pass band of simple photonic and phononic
crystals. First a unified approach is presented to accurately, efficiently, and
uniquely produce the homogenized effective material properties of doubly
periodic phononic crystals for anti-plane shear (SH) and photonic crystals for
transverse electric (TE) and transverse magnetic (TM) electromagnetic
Bloch-form waves in such a manner that they exactly reproduce the band
structure of the composite over any desired frequency band. Then the
correspondence between phononic and photonic field equations is established and
their effective homogenized material parameters are calculated. Finally
illustrative examples are worked out for each case, revealing a rich body of
refractive characteristics of these crystals, and showing by means of these
examples that the homogenized effective parameters do yield the exact results,
and that the resulting homogenized medium does in fact embody exactly the
actual band structure and dispersive properties of the considered
phononic/photonic crystal. As a consequence when the homogenized medium is
placed in contact with a normal homogeneous half-space, it could display, even
on the first pass band, positive, negative, or even no energy refraction
depending on the frequency and wave vector of plane waves incident from the
normal homogeneous solid to the interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
