<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:12:57Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-06-08" from="2017-06-08" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.6376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.6376</id><created>2011-10-28</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grimus</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludl</keyname><forenames>Patrick Otto</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite flavour groups of fermions</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>89 pages, 6 figures, some references added, rearrangement of part of
  the material, section on SU(3) subgroups substantially extended, some minor
  revisions. Version for publication in J. Phys. A. Table 12 corrected to match
  eq.(256), table 14 and eq.(314) corrected to match the 2-dimensional irreps
  defined on p.67</comments><report-no>UWThPh-2011-30</report-no><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/45/23/233001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an overview of the theory of finite groups, with regard to their
application as flavour symmetries in particle physics. In a general part, we
discuss useful theorems concerning group structure, conjugacy classes,
representations and character tables. In a specialized part, we attempt to give
a fairly comprehensive review of finite subgroups of SO(3) and SU(3), in which
we apply and illustrate the general theory. Moreover, we also provide a concise
description of the symmetric and alternating groups and comment on the
relationship between finite subgroups of U(3) and finite subgroups of SU(3).
Though in this review we give a detailed description of a wide range of finite
groups, the main focus is on the methods which allow the exploration of their
different aspects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.7424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.7424</id><created>2014-09-25</created><updated>2015-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolai</keyname><forenames>Dhriti Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mallick</keyname><forenames>Anish</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenfunction Statistics for Anderson Model with H\&quot;{o}lder continuous
  single site Potential</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>35J10, 81Q10, 35P20</msc-class><journal-ref>A. Proc Math Sci (2016) 126: 577</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12044-016-0301-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider random Schr\&quot;{o}dinger operators on $\ell^2(\mathbb{Z}^d)$ when
the distribution of single site potentials is $\alpha$-H\&quot;{o}lder continuous
($0&lt;\alpha\leq 1$). In localized regime we study the distribution of
eigenfunctions simultaneously in space and energy. In a certain scaling limit
we prove limits point are Poisson.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07254</id><created>2015-03-24</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fazlyab</keyname><forenames>Mahyar</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xf6;rfler</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preciado</keyname><forenames>Victor M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal network design for synchronization of coupled oscillators</title><categories>math.OC math.DS nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper studies the problem of designing networks of nonidentical coupled
oscillators in order to achieve a desired level of phase cohesiveness, defined
as the maximum asymptotic phase difference across the edges of the network. In
particular, we consider the following two design problems: (i) the
nodal-frequency design problem, in which we tune the natural frequencies of the
oscillators given the topology of the network, and (ii) the (robust)
edge-weight design problem, in which we design the edge weights assuming that
the natural frequencies are given (or belong to a given convex uncertainty
set). For both problems, we optimize an objective function of the design
variables while considering a desired level of phase cohesiveness as our design
constraint. This constraint defines a convex set in the nodal-frequency design
problem. In contrast, in the edge-weight design problem, the phase cohesiveness
constraint yields a non-convex set, unless the underlying network is either a
tree or an arbitrary graph with identical edge weights. We then propose a
convex semidefinite relaxation to approximately solve the (non-convex)
edge-weight design problem for general (possibly cyclic) networks with
nonidentical edge weights. We illustrate the applicability of our results by
analyzing several network design problems of practical interest, such as power
re-dispatch in power grids, sparse network design, (robust) network design for
distributed wireless analog clocks, and the detection of edges leading to the
Braess' paradox in power grids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07668</id><created>2015-03-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Benitez</keyname><forenames>Maria Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hrabec</keyname><forenames>Ales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihai</keyname><forenames>Andrei P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burnell</keyname><forenames>Gavin</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGrouther</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marrows</keyname><forenames>Christopher H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McVitie</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic microscopy of topologically protected homochiral domain walls
  in an ultrathin perpendicularly magnetized Co film</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1038/ncomms9957</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next-generation concepts for solid-state memory devices are based on
current-driven domain wall propagation, where the wall velocity governs the
device performance. It has been shown that the domain wall velocity and the
direction of travel is controlled by the nature of the wall and its chirality.
This chirality is attributed to effects emerging from the lack of inversion
symmetry at the interface between a ferromagnet and a heavy metal, leading to
an interfacial Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction that can control the shape and
chirality of the magnetic domain wall. Here we present direct imaging of domain
walls in Pt/Co/AlO$_x$ films using Lorentz transmission electron microscopy,
demonstrating the presence of homochiral, and thus topologically protected,
N\'{e}el walls. Such domain walls are good candidates for dense data storage,
bringing the bit size down close to the limit of the domain wall width.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05812</id><created>2015-05-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Jason A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lombardi</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Rasio</keyname><forenames>Frederic A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalogera</keyname><forenames>Vassiliki</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability and Coalescence of Massive Twin Binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>51 pages, 26 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 806, Issue 1, article id. 135,
  23 pp. (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/806/1/135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive stars are usually found in binaries, and binaries with periods less
than 10 days may have a preference for near equal component masses. In this
paper we investigate the evolution of these binaries all the way to contact and
the possibility that these systems can be progenitors of double neutron star
binaries. The small orbital separations of observed double neutron star
binaries suggest that the progenitor systems underwent a common envelope phase
at least once during their evolution. Bethe &amp; Brown (1998) proposed that
massive binary twins will undergo a common envelope evolution while both
components are ascending the red giant branch or asymptotic giant branch
simultaneously, also known as double-core evolution. Using models generated
from the stellar evolution code Evolve Zero Age Main Sequence, we determine the
range of mass ratios resulting in both components simultaneously ascending the
RGB or AGB as a function of the difference in birth times, t. We find that,
even for a generous t=5 Myr, the minimum mass ratio qmin=0.933 for an 8 Solar
Mass primary and increases for larger primaries. We use a hydrodynamics code,
StarSmasher, to study specifically the evolution of q=1 common envelope systems
as a function of initial component mass, age, and orbital separation. We find
the dynamical stability limit, the largest orbital separation where the binary
becomes dynamically unstable, as a function of the component mass and age.
Finally, we calculate the efficiency of ejecting matter during the inspiral
phase to extrapolate the properties of the remnant binary from our numerical
results, assuming the common envelope is completely ejected. We find that for
the nominal core masses, there is a minimum orbital separation for a given
component mass such that the helium cores survive common envelope evolution in
a tightly bound binary and are viable progenitors for double neutron stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05410</id><created>2015-06-15</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frey</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstone</keyname><forenames>Robert L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cognitive mechanisms for human flocking dynamics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures, supporting information available at
  http://enfascination.com/cloud/index.php/s/igZa7GS1b2qF4qy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-level &quot;adaptive&quot; and higher-level &quot;sophisticated&quot; human reasoning
processes have been proposed to play opposing roles in the emergence of
unpredictable collective behaviors like crowd panics, traffic jams, and market
bubbles. While adaptive processes are ubiquitous in mechanistic theories of
emergent social complexity, complementary theories understand incentives,
education, and other inducements to rationality as able to suppress such
outcomes.
  We show in a series of laboratory experiments that, rather than suppressing
complex social dynamics, sophisticated reasoning processes can support them.
Our experiments elicit flocking behavior in groups and show that it is driven
by the human ability to recursively anticipate the reasoning of others. We
identify this sophisticated flocking in three different games---the Beauty
Pageant, Mod Game, and Runway Game---across which game theory predicts no
formal similarity. The persistence of sophisticated flocking across unrelated
game types not only speaks to the phenomenon's robustness, it also suggests
that people are treating three supposedly different decision settings as
conceptually similar, implicating a second sophisticated cognitive ability:
human concept formation. We also find in participants' underlying reasoning
that the number of recursions they perform is limited not by any individual's
cognitive abilities, but by a social norm that emerges during flocking.
  By implicating both recursive reasoning and concept formation in complex
dynamics, we support interdisciplinary perspectives that emergent complexity is
typical of even the most intelligent populations and carefully designed social
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07650</id><created>2015-07-28</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hosomichi</keyname><forenames>Kazuo</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbifolds, Defects and Sphere Partition Function</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>1+24 pages, v4: a major revision reflecting the result of the
  followup work arXiv:1705:10623</comments><report-no>NCTS-TH/1503</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gauge theories in the presence of codimension two vortex defects are known to
be related to the theories on orbifolds. By using this relation we study the
localized path integrals of 2D N=(2,2) SUSY gauge theories with point-like
vortex defects. We present a formula for the correlation functions of vortex
defects inserted at the north and the south poles of squashed spheres. For
Abelian gauge theories the correlators are locally constant as functions of the
parameters of the defect, but exhibit discontinuity at some threshold values
determined by the deficit angle at the poles and the R-charges of the matter
multiplets. For non-Abelian gauge groups the correlators depend non-trivially
on the types of gauge symmetry breaking due to the defects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01544</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2016-12-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gangaraj</keyname><forenames>S. Ali Hassani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Low</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemilentsau</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>George W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directive Surface Plasmons on Tunable Two-Dimensional Hyperbolic
  Metasurfaces and Black Phosphorus: Green's Function and Complex Plane
  Analysis</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ANTENNAS AND PROPAGATION, VOL. 65, NO. 3,
  MARCH 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TAP.2016.2633900</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the electromagnetic response of two- and quasi-two-dimensional
hyperbolic materials, on which a simple dipole source can excite a
well-confined and tunable surface plasmon polariton (SPP). The analysis is
based on the Green's function for an anisotropic two-dimensional surface, which
nominally requires the evaluation of a two-dimensional Sommerfeld integral. We
show that for the SPP contribution this integral can be evaluated efficiently
in a mixed continuous-discrete form as a continuous spectrum contribution
(branch cut integral) of a residue term, in distinction to the isotropic case,
where the SPP is simply given as a discrete residue term. The regime of strong
SPP excitation is discussed, and complex-plane singularities are identified,
leading to physical insight into the excited SPP. We also present a stationary
phase solution valid for large radial distances. Examples are presented using
graphene strips to form a hyperbolic metasurface, and thin-film black
phosphorus. The Green's function and complex-plane analysis developed allows
for the exploration of hyperbolic plasmons in general 2D materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01034</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Witzany</keyname><forenames>Vojtech</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laemmerzahl</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudo-Newtonian equations for evolution of particles and fluids in
  stationary space-times</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 841.105 (2017): 14pp</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa71a5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pseudo-Newtonian potentials are a tool often used in theoretical astrophysics
to capture some key features of a black-hole space-time in a Newtonian
framework. As a result, one can use Newtonian numerical codes, and Newtonian
formalism in general, in an effective description of important astrophysical
processes such as accretion onto black holes.
  In this paper we develop a general pseudo-Newtonian formalism which pertains
to the motion of particles, light, and fluids in stationary space-times. In
return, we are able to assess the applicability of the pseudo-Newtonian scheme.
The simplest and most elegant formulas are obtained in space-times without
gravitomagnetic effects, such as the Schwarzschild rather than the Kerr
space-time; the quantitative errors are smallest for motion with low binding
energy. Included is a ready-to-use set of fluid equations in Schwarzschild
space-time in Cartesian and radial coordinates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03655</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2017-02-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Golkov</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shokef</keyname><forenames>Yair</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape regulation generates elastic interaction between living cells</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 063011 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa70ef</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The organization of live cells to tissues is associated with the mechanical
interaction between cells, which is mediated through their elastic environment.
We model cells as spherical active force dipoles surrounded by an infinite
elastic matrix, and analytically evaluate the interaction energy for different
scenarios of their regulatory behavior. We obtain attraction for homeostatic
(set point) forces and repulsion for homeostatic displacements. When the
translational motion of the cells is regulated, the interaction energy decays
with distance as $1/d^4$, while when it is not regulated the energy decays as
$1/d^6$. This arises from the same reasons as the van der Waals interaction
between induced electric dipoles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00876</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2016-04-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Segall</keyname><forenames>Nimrod</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teomy</keyname><forenames>Eial</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shokef</keyname><forenames>Yair</forenames></author></authors><title>Jamming vs. Caging in Three Dimensional Jamming Percolation</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>To appear in JSTAT special issue on structure in glassy and jammed
  systems</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics - Theory and Experiment 054051
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/05/054051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a three-dimensional kinetically-constrained model that
exhibits two types of phase transitions at different densities. At the jamming
density $ \rho_J $ there is a mixed-order phase transition in which a finite
fraction of the particles become frozen, but the other particles may still
diffuse throughout the system. At the caging density $ \rho_C &gt; \rho_J $, the
mobile particles are trapped in finite cages and no longer diffuse. The caging
transition occurs due to a percolation transition of the unfrozen sites, and we
numerically find that it is a continuous transition with the same critical
exponents as random percolation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08661</id><created>2016-02-27</created><updated>2017-01-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Shao-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Xian-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yu-Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>First law of black hole mechanics in variable background fields</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, presentation improved, clarifications and references added</comments><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2246-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that in general theories of gravity with the diffeomorphism
symmetry, the black hole entropy is a Noether charge. But what will happen if
the symmetry is explicitly broken? By investigating the covariant first law of
black hole mechanics with background fields, we show that the Noether entropy
is still applicable due to the local nature of the black hole entropy.
Moreover, motivated by the proposal that the cosmological constant behaves as a
thermodynamic variable, we allow the non-dynamical background fields to be
varied. To illustrate this general formalism, we study a generic static black
brane in the massive gravity. Using the first law and the scaling argument, we
obtain two Smarr formulas. We show that both of them can be retrieved without
relying on the first law, hence providing a self-consistent check of the
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05193</id><created>2016-03-12</created><updated>2016-03-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gangaraj</keyname><forenames>S. Ali Hassani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemilentsau</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>George W.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effects of three-dimensional defects on one-way surface plasmon
  propagation for photonic topological insulators comprised of continuous media</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the one-way surface plasmon-polariton (SPP) at the
interface of a continuous magneto-plasma material and metal. We demonstrated
that TM modes inside a continuous material can be assigned non-trivial Chern
numbers analogous to those of topological photonic crystals; moreover these
Chern numbers can be calculated analytically. This leads to the appearance of
topologically protected surface modes propagating at frequencies inside the
bandgap of the magneto-plasma. Previous works considered 2D structures; here we
consider the effects of 3D defects, and show that, although backward
propagation/reflection cannot occur, side scattering does take place and it has
significant effect on the propagation of the surface mode. Several different
waveguiding geometries are considered for reducing the effects of
side-scattering, and we also consider the effects of metal loss.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06291</id><created>2016-03-20</created><updated>2016-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nii</keyname><forenames>Taiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iinuma</keyname><forenames>Masataka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Holger F.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the relation between measurement outcomes and physical properties</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, updated references and clarification of weak value
  reference below Eq.(12)</comments><doi>10.1007/s40509-017-0114-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most difficult problems in quantum mechanics is the analysis of
the measurement processes. In this paper, we point out that many of these
difficulties originate from the different roles of measurement outcomes and
observable quantities, which cannot simply be identified with each other. Our
analysis shows that the Hilbert space formalism itself describes a fundamental
separation between quantitative properties and qualitative outcomes that needs
to be taken into account in an objective description of quantum measurements.
We derive fundamental relations between the statistics of measurement outcomes
and the values of physical quantities that explain how the objective properties
of a quantum system appear in the context of different measurement
interactions. Our results indicate that non-classical correlations can be
understood in terms of the actual role of physical properties as quantifiable
causes of the external effects observed in a quantum measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06834</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2017-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crevecoeur</keyname><forenames>Guibert U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the distance scale factor and the Hubble parameter in the
  light of Plancks results</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures Section 4 &quot;Comments&quot; has been developed and
  several references have been added. The rest of the text, including
  equations, figures and results of computations remain unchanged</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As the 2015 results of Plancks mission have recently been made available, it
is interesting to check the evolution of the scale factor and of the Hubble
parameter in the light of these results. Two models in line with Einsteins
field equations and with the hot big bang scenario for a flat Universe are used
to allow a comparison : (1) the classical one using density parameters for
matter content (baryonic and dark matter) and dark energy ; (2) an alternative
model, already used in the past, and assuming the Hubble parameter to contain a
term constant in time. Both models are coherent with each other except for some
discrepancy about the density, which can be ascribed to the different
hypotheses made. This opens a way for further interpretation of the origin of
dark energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04426</id><created>2016-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Takumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaha</keyname><forenames>Shinichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delbecq</keyname><forenames>Matthieu R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoneda</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>Kenta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allison</keyname><forenames>Giles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noiri</keyname><forenames>Akito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Kento</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarucha</keyname><forenames>Seigo</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection and control of charge states in a quintuple quantum dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 39113 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep39113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A semiconductor quintuple quantum dot with two charge sensors and an
additional contact to the center dot from an electron reservoir is fabricated
to demonstrate the concept of scalable architecture. This design enables
formation of the five dots as confirmed by measurements of the charge states of
the three nearest dots to the respective charge sensor. The gate performance of
the measured stability diagram is well reproduced by a capacitance model.These
results provide an important step towards realizing controllable large scale
multiple quantum dot systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02732</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02732</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sonnenschein</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weissman</keyname><forenames>Dorin</forenames></author></authors><title>A tetraquark or not a tetraquark: A holography inspired stringy hadron
  (HISH) perspective</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>v1: 28 pages, v2: typos fixed, references added, 29 pages, v3:
  revised, published version, 30 pages</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B920 (2017) 319-344</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.04.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest to use the state $Y(4630)$, which decays predominantly to
$\Lambda_c\bar\Lambda_c$, as a window to the landscape of tetraquarks. We
propose a simple criterion to decide whether a state is a genuine stringy
exotic hadron - a tetraquark - or a &quot;molecule&quot;. If it is the former it should
be on a (modified) Regge trajectory. We present the predictions of the mass and
width of the higher excited states on the $Y(4630)$ trajectory. We argue that
there should exist an analogous &quot;$Y_b$&quot; state that decays to
$\Lambda_b\bar\Lambda_b$ and describe its trajectory. We conjecture also a
similar trajectory for tetraquarks containing strange quarks, and the modified
Regge trajectories can in fact be predicted for any resonances found decaying
to a baryon-antibaryon pair. En route to the results regarding tetraquarks, we
also make some additional predictions on higher excited charmonium states. We
briefly discuss the zoo of exotic stringy hadrons and in particular we sketch
all the possibilities of tetraquark states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08430</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinitsyn</keyname><forenames>Nikolai A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau-Zener extension of the Tavis-Cummings model: structure of the
  solution</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Corrected a typo in Eq. (50)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 033808 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.033808</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the recently discovered solution of the driven Tavis-Cummings
model (DTCM). It describes interaction of arbitrary number of two-level systems
with a bosonic mode that has linearly time-dependent frequency. We derive
compact and tractable expressions for transition probabilities in terms of the
well known special functions. In the new form, our formulas are suitable for
fast numerical calculations and analytical approximations. As an application,
we obtain the semiclassical limit of the exact solution and compare it to prior
approximations. We also reveal connection between DTCM and $q$-deformed
binomial statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00932</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arunachalam</keyname><forenames>Srinivasan</forenames><affiliation>CWI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>de Wolf</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames><affiliation>CWI and U of Amsterdam</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optimal Quantum Sample Complexity of Learning Algorithms</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC cs.LG</categories><comments>31 pages LaTeX. Arxiv abstract shortened to fit in their
  1920-character limit. Version 3: many small changes, no change in results</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  $ \newcommand{\eps}{\varepsilon} $In learning theory, the VC dimension of a
concept class $C$ is the most common way to measure its &quot;richness.&quot; In the PAC
model $$ \Theta\Big(\frac{d}{\eps} + \frac{\log(1/\delta)}{\eps}\Big) $$
examples are necessary and sufficient for a learner to output, with probability
$1-\delta$, a hypothesis $h$ that is $\eps$-close to the target concept $c$. In
the related agnostic model, where the samples need not come from a $c\in C$, we
know that $$ \Theta\Big(\frac{d}{\eps^2} + \frac{\log(1/\delta)}{\eps^2}\Big)
$$ examples are necessary and sufficient to output an hypothesis $h\in C$ whose
error is at most $\eps$ worse than the best concept in $C$.
  Here we analyze quantum sample complexity, where each example is a coherent
quantum state. This model was introduced by Bshouty and Jackson, who showed
that quantum examples are more powerful than classical examples in some
fixed-distribution settings. However, Atici and Servedio, improved by Zhang,
showed that in the PAC setting, quantum examples cannot be much more powerful:
the required number of quantum examples is $$
\Omega\Big(\frac{d^{1-\eta}}{\eps} + d + \frac{\log(1/\delta)}{\eps}\Big)\mbox{
for all }\eta&gt; 0. $$ Our main result is that quantum and classical sample
complexity are in fact equal up to constant factors in both the PAC and
agnostic models. We give two approaches. The first is a fairly simple
information-theoretic argument that yields the above two classical bounds and
yields the same bounds for quantum sample complexity up to a $\log(d/\eps)$
factor. We then give a second approach that avoids the log-factor loss, based
on analyzing the behavior of the &quot;Pretty Good Measurement&quot; on the quantum state
identification problems that correspond to learning. This shows classical and
quantum sample complexity are equal up to constant factors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05191</id><created>2016-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Dubkov</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chizh</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuryev</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Room-temperature formation of Pt$_3$Si/Pt$_2$Si films on poly-Si
  substrates</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 816(1), 012011 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/816/1/012011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a way of formation of thin bilayer Pt$_3$Si/Pt$_2$Si films at room
temperature on poly-Si substrates by Pt magnetron sputtering and wet etching,
obtain such film, investigate its structure and phase composition and estimate
the thickness of its layers. We verify by direct x-ray
photoelectron-spectroscopic measurements our previous observation of the
Pt$_2$Si layer formaton between Pt and poly-Si films as a result of Pt
magnetron sputtering at room temperature. This layer likely appears due to high
enough temperature of Pt ions in the magnetron plasma sufficient for chemical
reaction of the silicide film formation on the Si surface. The Pt$_3$Si layer
likely forms from the Pt--Pt$_3$Si layer (Pt$_{95}$Si$_5$), which arises under
Pt film during the magnetron sputtering, as a result of Pt removal by wet
etching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08757</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ibrahim</keyname><forenames>Yahaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liverpool</keyname><forenames>Tanniemola B.</forenames></author></authors><title>How walls affect the dynamics of self-phoretic microswimmers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Europ. Phys. J. Special Topics 225 (2016) 1843-1874</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60148-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of a nearby planar wall on the propulsion of a spherical
phoretic micro-swimmer driven by reactions on its surface. An asymmetric
coverage of catalysts on its surface which absorb reactants and generate
products gives rise to an anisotropic interfacial flow that propels the
swimmer. We analyse the near-wall dynamics of such a self-phoretic swimmer as a
function of the asymmetric catalytic coverage of the surface. By an analysis of
the fundamental singularities of the flow and concentration or electrostatic
potential gradients generated we are able to obtain and rationalise a phase
diagram of behaviours as a function of the characteristics of the swimmer
surface. We find a variety of possible behaviours, from &quot;bound states&quot; where
the swimmer remains near the wall to &quot;scattering&quot; or repulsive trajectories in
which the swimmer ends far from the wall. The formation of some of the bound
states is a purely wall-phoretic effect and cannot be obtained by simply
mapping a phoretic swimmer to a hydrodynamic one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01154</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dettmann</keyname><forenames>Carl P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Georgiou</keyname><forenames>Orestis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>Georgie</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral statistics of random geometric graphs</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures. Substantially updated from previous version</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 118 (2017) 18003</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/18003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use random matrix theory to study the spectrum of random geometric graphs,
a fundamental model of spatial networks. Considering ensembles of random
geometric graphs we look at short range correlations in the level spacings of
the spectrum via the nearest neighbour and next nearest neighbour spacing
distribution and long range correlations via the spectral rigidity Delta_3
statistic. These correlations in the level spacings give information about
localisation of eigenvectors, level of community structure and the level of
randomness within the networks. We find a parameter dependent transition
between Poisson and Gaussian orthogonal ensemble statistics. That is the
spectral statistics of spatial random geometric graphs fits the universality of
random matrix theory found in other models such as Erdos-Renyi, Barabasi-Albert
and Watts-Strogatz random graph.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08429</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Genoni</keyname><forenames>Marco G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cram\'er-Rao bound for time-continuous measurements in linear Gaussian
  quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 012116 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.012116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a compact and reliable method to calculate the Fisher information
for the estimation of a dynamical parameter in a continuously measured linear
Gaussian quantum system. Unlike previous methods in the literature, which
involve the numerical integration of a stochastic master equation for the
corresponding density operator in a Hilbert space of infinite dimension, the
formulas here derived depends only on the evolution of first and second moments
of the quantum states, and thus can be easily evaluated without the need of any
approximation. We also present some basic but physically meaningful examples
where this result is exploited, calculating analytical and numerical bounds on
the estimation of the squeezing parameter for a quantum parametric amplifier,
and of a constant force acting on a mechanical oscillator in a standard
optomechanical scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03268</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03268</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Glick-Magid</keyname><forenames>Ayala</forenames><affiliation>HUJI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mishnayot</keyname><forenames>Yonatan</forenames><affiliation>HUJI, WIS, SNRC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mukul</keyname><forenames>Ish</forenames><affiliation>WIS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hass</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames><affiliation>WIS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ron</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames><affiliation>HUJI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vaintraub</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames><affiliation>SNRC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gazit</keyname><forenames>Doron</forenames><affiliation>HUJI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Beta spectrum of unique first-forbidden decays as a novel test for
  fundamental symmetries</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Published version</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.02.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the Standard Model, the weak interaction of quarks and leptons is
characterized by certain symmetry properties, such as maximal breaking of
parity and favored helicity. These are related to the $V-A$ structure of the
weak interaction. These characteristics were discovered by studying
correlations in the directions of the outgoing leptons in nuclear beta decays.
These days, correlation measurements in nuclear beta decays are intensively
studied to probe for signatures for deviations from these symmetries, which are
an indication of Beyond Standard Model physics. We show that the structure of
the energy spectrum of emitted electrons in unique first-forbidden
$\beta$-decays is sensitive to the symmetries of the weak interaction, and thus
can be used as a novel probe of physics beyond the standard model. Furthermore,
the energy spectrum gives constraints both in the case of right and left
coupling of the new symmetry currents. We show that a measurement with modest
energy resolution of about 20 keV is expected to lead to new constraints on
beyond the standard model interactions with tensor symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08699</id><created>2016-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Xingchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbosa</keyname><forenames>Felippe A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Samantha P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutt</keyname><forenames>Avik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardenas</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okawachi</keyname><forenames>Yoshitomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bryant</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaeta</keyname><forenames>Alexander L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipson</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Breaking the Loss Limitation of On-chip High-confinement Resonators</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optica 4(6), 619-624 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000619</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On-chip optical resonators have the promise of revolutionizing numerous
fields including metrology and sensing; however, their optical losses have
always lagged behind their larger discrete resonator counterparts based on
crystalline materials and flowable glass. Silicon nitride (Si3N4) ring
resonators open up capabilities for optical routing, frequency comb generation,
optical clocks and high precision sensing on an integrated platform. However,
simultaneously achieving high quality factor and high confinement in Si3N4
(critical for nonlinear processes for example) remains a challenge. Here, we
show that addressing surface roughness enables us to overcome the loss
limitations and achieve high-confinement, on-chip ring resonators with a
quality factor (Q) of 37 million for a ring with 2.5 {\mu}m width and 67
million for a ring with 10 {\mu}m width. We show a clear systematic path for
achieving these high quality factors. Furthermore, we extract the loss limited
by the material absorption in our films to be 0.13 dB/m, which corresponds to
an absorption limited Q of at least 170 million by comparing two resonators
with different degrees of confinement. Our work provides a chip-scale platform
for applications such as ultra-low power frequency comb generation, high
precision sensing, laser stabilization and sideband resolved optomechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06544</id><created>2016-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Guy</keyname><forenames>Mallory L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Schooten</keyname><forenames>Kipp J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Lihuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramanathan</keyname><forenames>Chandrasekhar</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemisorption of water on the surface of silicon microparticles measured
  by DNP-enhanced NMR</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C. 121, 2748-2754 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b11065</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use dynamic nuclear polarization (DNP) enhanced nuclear magnetic resonance
(NMR) at liquid helium temperatures to directly detect hydrogen attached to the
surface of silicon microparticles. The proton NMR spectrum from a dry sample of
polycrystalline silicon powder (1-5 $\mu$m) shows a distinctively narrow
Lorentzian-shaped resonance with a width of 6.2 kHz, indicative of a very
sparse distribution of protons attached to the silicon surface. These protons
are within a few atomic monolayers of the silicon surface. The high sensitivity
NMR detection of surface protons from low surface area ($0.26 - 1.3 \: m^2/g$)
particles is enabled by an overall signal enhancement of 4150 over the room
temperature NMR signal at the same field. When the particles were suspended in
a solvent with 80% H2O and 20% D2O, the narrow peak was observed to grow in
intensity over time, indicating growth of the sparse surface proton layer.
However, when the particles were suspended in a solvent with 20% H2O and 80%
D2O, the narrow bound-proton peak was observed to shrink due to exchange
between the surface protons and the deuterium in solution. This decrease was
accompanied by a concomitant growth in the intensity of the frozen solvent
peak, as the relative proton concentration of the solvent increased. When the
particles were suspended in the organic solvent hexane, the proton NMR spectra
remained unchanged over time. These results are consistent with the known
chemisorption of water on the silicon surface resulting in the formation of
hydride and hydroxyl species. Low-temperature DNP NMR can thus be used as a
non-destructive probe of surface corrosion for silicon in aqueous environments.
This is important in the context of using silicon MEMS and bioMEMS devices in
such environments, for silicon micro- and nano-particle MRI imaging agents, and
the use of nanosilicon for splitting water in fuel cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06690</id><created>2016-10-21</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Noda</keyname><forenames>Sousuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nambu</keyname><forenames>Yasusada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Masaaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Analog rotating black holes in a magnetohydrodynamic inflow</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures, final version to match the published version</comments><msc-class>83C57, 83C80</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 104055 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.104055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a model of the analog geometry in a magnetohydrodynamic (MHD)
flow. For the MHD flow with magnetic pressure-dominated and gas
pressure-dominated conditions, we obtain the magnetoacoustic metric for the
fast MHD mode. For the slow MHD mode, on the other hand, the wave is governed
by the advective-type equation without an isotropic dispersion term. Thus, the
&quot;distance&quot; perpendicular to the wave propagation is not defined and the
magnetoacoustic metric cannot be introduced. To investigate the properties of
the magnetoacoustic geometry for the fast mode, we prepare a two-dimensional
axisymmetric inflow and examine the behavior of magnetoacoustic rays which is a
counterpart of the MHD waves in the eikonal limit. We find that the
magnetoacoustic geometry is classified into three types depending on two
parameters characterizing the background flow:~analog spacetimes of rotating
black holes, ultra spinning stars with ergoregions, and spinning stars without
ergoregions. We address the effects of the magnetic pressure on the effective
geometries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07257</id><created>2016-10-23</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Leandro M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex behavior in chains of nonlinear oscillators</title><categories>nlin.CD nlin.AO</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4984800</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article outlines sufficient conditions under which a one-dimensional
chain of identical nonlinear oscillators can display complex spatio-temporal
behavior. The units are described by phase equations and consist of excitable
oscillators. The interactions are local and the network is poised to a critical
state by balancing excitation and inhibition locally. The results presented
here suggest that in networks composed of many oscillatory units with local
interactions, excitability together with balanced interactions are sufficient
to give rise to complex emergent features. For values of the parameters where
complex behavior occurs, the system also displays a high-dimensional
bifurcation where an exponentially large number of equilibria are borne in
pairs out of multiple saddle-node bifurcations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07673</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ashton</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinnott</keyname><forenames>Susan B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hennig</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology-Scaling Identification of Layered Solids and Stable Exfoliated
  2D Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 106101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.106101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Materials Project crystal structure database has been searched for
materials possessing layered motifs in their crystal structures using a
topology-scaling algorithm. The algorithm identifies and measures the sizes of
bonded atomic clusters in a structure's unit cell, and determines their scaling
with cell size. The search yielded 826 stable layered materials, which are
considered as candidates for the formation of two-dimensional monolayers via
exfoliation. Density-functional theory calculates the exfoliation energy of
each material and 681 monolayers are found to exhibit exfoliation energies
below those of certain already-extant two-dimensional materials, indicating the
possibility of exfoliating them from bulk phases. The crystal structures of
these two-dimensional materials provide templates for future theoretical
searches of stable two-dimensional materials. The optimized structures and
other data for all 826 monolayers are provided at https://materialsweb.org .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00647</id><created>2016-11-02</created><updated>2017-02-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hrabec</keyname><forenames>Ales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampaio</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belmeguenai</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Isabell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weil</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ch&#xe9;rif</keyname><forenames>Salim Mourad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stachkevitch</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacques</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiaville</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rohart</keyname><forenames>Stanislas</forenames></author></authors><title>Current-induced skyrmion generation and dynamics in symmetric bilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1038/ncomms15765</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic skyrmions are textures behaving as quasiparticles which are
topologically different from other states. Their discovery in systems with
broken inversion symmetry sparked the search for materials containing such
magnetic phase at room temperature. Their topological properties combined with
the chirality-related spin-orbit torques make them interesting objects to
control the magnetization at nanoscale. Here we show that a pair of coupled
skyrmions with the same topological charge and opposite chiralities can be
stabilized in a symmetric magnetic bilayer system by combining
Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction (DMI) and dipolar coupling effects. This
effect opens a new path for skyrmion stabilization with much lower DMI. We then
demonstrate in a single device with two different electrodes that such
skyrmions can be efficiently and independently written and shifted by electric
current at large velocities. The skyrmionic nature of the observed
quasiparticles is further confirmed by using the gyrotropic force as a
topological filter. These results set the ground for emerging spintronic
technologies where issues concerning skyrmion stability, nucleation, and
propagation are paramount.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01670</id><created>2016-11-05</created><updated>2017-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gangaraj</keyname><forenames>S. Ali Hassani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silveirinha</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rio G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>George W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Berry phase, Berry Connection, and Chern Number for a Continuum
  Bianisotropic Material from a Classical Electromagnetics Perspective</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>IEEE JOURNAL ON MULTISCALE AND MULTIPHYSICS COMPUTATIONAL
  TECHNIQUES, VOL. 2, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/JMMCT.2017.2654962</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The properties that quantify photonic topological insulators (PTIs), Berry
phase, Berry connection, and Chern number, are typically obtained by making
analogies between classical Maxwell's equations and the quantum mechanical
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation, writing both in Hamiltonian form. However, the
aforementioned quantities are not necessarily quantum in nature, and for
photonic systems they can be explained using only classical concepts. Here we
provide a derivation and description of PTI quantities using classical
Maxwell's equations, we demonstrate how an electromagnetic mode can acquire
Berry phase, and we discuss the ramifications of this effect. We consider
several examples, including wave propagation in a biased plasma, and radiation
by a rotating isotropic emitter. These concepts are discussed without invoking
quantum mechanics, and can be easily understood from an engineering
electromagnetics perspective.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06563</id><created>2016-11-20</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pezzulla</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoop</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holmes</keyname><forenames>Douglas P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Curvature-Driven Morphing of Non-Euclidean Shells</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society A 773(2201), 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspa.2017.0087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate how thin structures change their shape in response to
non-mechanical stimuli that can be interpreted as variations in the structure's
natural curvature. Starting from the theory of non-Euclidean plates and shells,
we derive an effective model that reduces a three-dimensional stimulus to the
natural fundamental forms of the mid-surface of the structure, incorporating
expansion, or growth, in the thickness. Then, we apply the model to a variety
of thin bodies, from flat plates to spherical shells, obtaining excellent
agreement between theory and numerics. We show how cylinders and cones can
either bend more or unroll, and eventually snap and rotate. We also study the
nearly-isometric deformations of a spherical shell and describe how this shape
change is ruled by the geometry of a spindle. As the derived results stem from
a purely geometrical model, they are general and scalable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08996</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Engwirda</keyname><forenames>Darren</forenames></author></authors><title>JIGSAW-GEO (1.0): locally orthogonal staggered unstructured grid
  generation for general circulation modelling on the sphere</title><categories>physics.ao-ph cs.CG physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Final revisions, as per: Engwirda, D.: JIGSAW-GEO (1.0): locally
  orthogonal staggered unstructured grid generation for general circulation
  modelling on the sphere, Geosci. Model Dev., 10, 2117-2140,
  https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-10-2117-2017, 2017</comments><doi>10.5194/gmd-10-2117-2017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An algorithm for the generation of non-uniform, locally-orthogonal staggered
unstructured spheroidal grids is described. This technique is designed to
generate very high-quality staggered Voronoi/Delaunay meshes appropriate for
general circulation modelling on the sphere, including applications to
atmospheric simulation, ocean-modelling and numerical weather prediction. Using
a recently developed Frontal-Delaunay refinement technique, a method for the
construction of high-quality unstructured spheroidal Delaunay triangulations is
introduced. A locally-orthogonal polygonal grid, derived from the associated
Voronoi diagram, is computed as the staggered dual. It is shown that use of the
Frontal-Delaunay refinement technique allows for the generation of very
high-quality unstructured triangulations, satisfying a-priori bounds on element
size and shape. Grid-quality is further improved through the application of
hill-climbing type optimisation techniques. Overall, the algorithm is shown to
produce grids with very high element quality and smooth grading
characteristics, while imposing relatively low computational expense. A
selection of uniform and non-uniform spheroidal grids appropriate for
high-resolution, multi-scale general circulation modelling are presented. These
grids are shown to satisfy the geometric constraints associated with
contemporary unstructured C-grid type finite-volume models, including the Model
for Prediction Across Scales (MPAS-O). The use of user-defined mesh-spacing
functions to generate smoothly graded, non-uniform grids for multi-resolution
type studies is discussed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09023</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Debattista</keyname><forenames>Victor P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ness</keyname><forenames>Melissa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Oscar A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeman</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoccali</keyname><forenames>Manuela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minniti</keyname><forenames>Dante</forenames></author></authors><title>Separation of Stellar Populations by an Evolving Bar: Implications for
  the Bulge of the Milky Way</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Updated version as published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 469 (2): 1587-1611</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx947</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel interpretation of the previously puzzling different
behaviours of stellar populations of the Milky Way's bulge. We first show, by
means of pure N-body simulations, that initially co-spatial stellar populations
with different in-plane random motions separate when a bar forms. The radially
cooler populations form a strong bar, and are vertically thin and
peanut-shaped, while the hotter populations form a weaker bar and become a
vertically thicker box. We demonstrate that it is the radial, not the vertical,
velocity dispersion that dominates this evolution. Assuming that early stellar
discs heat rapidly as they form, then both the in-plane and vertical random
motions correlate with stellar age and chemistry, leading to different density
distributions for metal-rich and metal-poor stars. We then use a
high-resolution simulation, in which all stars form out of gas, to demonstrate
that this is what happens. When we apply these results to the Milky Way we show
that a very broad range of observed trends for ages, densities, kinematics and
chemistries, that have been presented as evidence for contradictory paths to
the formation of the bulge, are in fact consistent with a bulge which formed
from a continuum of disc stellar populations which were kinematically separated
by the bar. For the first time we are able to account for the bulge's main
trends via a model in which the bulge formed largely in situ. Since the model
is generic, we also predict the general appearance of stellar population maps
of external edge-on galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04526</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flamary</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;mi</forenames></author></authors><title>Astronomical image reconstruction with convolutional neural networks</title><categories>cs.CV astro-ph.IM stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  State of the art methods in astronomical image reconstruction rely on the
resolution of a regularized or constrained optimization problem. Solving this
problem can be computationally intensive and usually leads to a quadratic or at
least superlinear complexity w.r.t. the number of pixels in the image. We
investigate in this work the use of convolutional neural networks for image
reconstruction in astronomy. With neural networks, the computationally
intensive tasks is the training step, but the prediction step has a fixed
complexity per pixel, i.e. a linear complexity. Numerical experiments show that
our approach is both computationally efficient and competitive with other state
of the art methods in addition to being interpretable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04837</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kormos</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimbor&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>Zolt&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature driven quenches in the Ising model: appearance of negative
  R\'enyi mutual information</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>Invited contribution to the special issue &quot;Emerging Talents&quot; of
  Journal of Physics A</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 264005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa70f6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of the transverse field Ising chain after a local
quench in which two independently thermalised chains are joined together and
are left to evolve unitarily. In the emerging non-equilibrium steady state the
R\'enyi mutual information with different indices are calculated between two
adjacent segments of the chain, and are found to scale logarithmically in the
subsystem size. Surprisingly, for R\'enyi indices $\alpha&gt;2$ we find cases
where the prefactor of the logarithmic dependence is negative. The fact that
the naively defined R\'enyi mutual information might be negative has been
pointed out before, however, we provide the first example for this scenario in
a realistic many-body setup. Our numerical and analytical results indicate that
in this setup it can be negative for any index $\alpha&gt;2$ while it is always
positive for $\alpha &lt;2.$ Interestingly, even for $\alpha&gt;2$ the calculated
prefactors show some universal features: for example, the same prefactor is
also shown to govern the logarithmic time dependence of the R\'enyi mutual
information before the system relaxes locally to the steady state. In
particular, it can decrease in the non-equilibrium evolution after the quench.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05622</id><created>2016-12-16</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haga</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maitra</keyname><forenames>Rachel Lash</forenames></author></authors><title>Factor Ordering and Path Integral Measure for Quantum Gravity in (1+1)
  Dimensions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 039, 19 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.039</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a mathematically rigorous path integral representation of the time
evolution operator for a model of (1+1) quantum gravity that incorporates
factor ordering ambiguity. In obtaining a suitable integral kernel for the
time-evolution operator, one requires that the corresponding Hamiltonian is
self-adjoint; this issue is subtle for a particular category of factor
orderings. We identify and parametrize a complete set of self-adjoint
extensions and provide a canonical description of these extensions in terms of
boundary conditions. Moreover, we use Trotter-type product formulae to
construct path-integral representations of time evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07936</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>A Model of Radiational Gaseous Stars</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a model concerning radiational gaseous stars and establish the
existence theory of stationary solutions to the free boundary problem of
hydrostatic equations describing the radiative equilibrium. We also concern the
local well-posedness of the moving boundary problem of the corresponding
Navier-Stokes-Fourier-Poisson system and construct a prior estimates of strong
and classical solutions. Our results explore the vacuum behaviour of density
and temperature near the free boundary for the equilibrium and capture such
degeneracy in the evolutionary problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08664</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>BESIII Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Ablikim</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achasov</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ai</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albayrak</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambrose</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amoroso</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakina</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferroli</keyname><forenames>R. Baldini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ban</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertani</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bettoni</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briere</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calcaterra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cetin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelkov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cibinetto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dbeyssi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedovich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denig</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denysenko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Destefanis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Mori</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>L. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>S. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farinelli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fava</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feldbauer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>elici</keyname><forenames>G. F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>C. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fioravanti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritsch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garzia</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goetzen</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>W. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradl</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>A. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>L . B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haddadi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinsius</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holtmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>W. Ikegami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantar-Nayestanaki</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavatsyuk</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiese</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kloss</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolcu</keyname><forenames>O. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopf</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornicer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupsc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leithoff</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leng</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>F. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Q. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Z. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>D. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loehner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>M. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Q. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>F. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggiora</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malik</keyname><forenames>Q. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messchendorp</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezzadri</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>C. Morales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morello</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muchnoi</keyname><forenames>N. Yu .</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muramatsu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musiol</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nerling</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolaev</keyname><forenames>I. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouyang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pacetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patteri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelizaeus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>K .</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettersson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poling</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>H. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>L. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashid</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redmer</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ripka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rong</keyname><forenames>G .</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosner</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>X. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savri&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoenning</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>P. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spataro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>G . X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tapan</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thorndike</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiemens</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uman</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varner</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z . Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidenkaff</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedner</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>L. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiu</keyname><forenames>Q. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>J . S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>C. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuncu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafar</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhemchugov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zotti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of $J/\psi$ and
  $\psi(3686)\rightarrow\Sigma(1385)^{0}\bar\Sigma(1385)^{0}$ and
  $\Xi^0\bar\Xi^{0}$</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures. This version is consistent with paper published
  in Phys.Lett. B770 (2017) 217-225</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B770 (2017) 217-225</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the decays of $J/\psi$ and $\psi(3686)$ to the final states
$\Sigma(1385)^{0}\bar\Sigma(1385)^{0}$ and $\Xi^0\bar\Xi^{0}$ based on a single
baryon tag method using data samples of $(1310.6 \pm 7.0) \times 10^{6}$
$J/\psi$ and $(447.9 \pm 2.9) \times 10^{6}$ $\psi(3686)$ events collected with
the BESIII detector at the BEPCII collider. The decays to
$\Sigma(1385)^{0}\bar\Sigma(1385)^{0}$ are observed for the first time. The
measured branching fractions of $J/\psi$ and
$\psi(3686)\rightarrow\Xi^0\bar\Xi^{0}$ are in good agreement with, and much
more precise, than the previously published results. The angular parameters for
these decays are also measured for the first time. The measured angular decay
parameter for $J/\psi\rightarrow\Sigma(1385)^{0}\bar\Sigma(1385)^{0}$, $\alpha
=-0.64 \pm 0.03 \pm 0.10$, is found to be negative, different to the other
decay processes in this measurement. In addition, the &quot;12\% rule&quot; and isospin
symmetry in the $J/\psi$ and $\psi(3686)\rightarrow\Xi\bar\Xi$ and
$\Sigma(1385)\bar{\Sigma}(1385)$ systems are tested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06198</id><created>2017-01-22</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rusin</keyname><forenames>Tomasz M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zawadzki</keyname><forenames>Wlodek</forenames></author></authors><title>On calculation of RKKY range function in one dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, some text added, accepted to: Journal of
  Magnetism and Magnetic Materials</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2017.06.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of strong singularity in the calculation of range function for the
RKKY interaction in 1D electron gas is discussed. The method of handling this
singularity is presented. A possible way of avoiding the singularity in the
Ruderman-Kittel perturbation theory in 1D is described.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08170</id><created>2017-01-27</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Contagion dynamics of extremist propaganda in social networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures; to appear in Information Sciences</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent terrorist attacks carried out on behalf of ISIS on American and
European soil by lone wolf attackers or sleeper cells remind us of the
importance of understanding the dynamics of radicalization mediated by social
media communication channels. In this paper, we shed light on the social media
activity of a group of twenty-five thousand users whose association with ISIS
online radical propaganda has been manually verified. By using a computational
tool known as dynamical activity-connectivity maps, based on network and
temporal activity patterns, we investigate the dynamics of social influence
within ISIS supporters. We finally quantify the effectiveness of ISIS
propaganda by determining the adoption of extremist content in the general
population and draw a parallel between radical propaganda and epidemics
spreading, highlighting that information broadcasters and influential ISIS
supporters generate highly-infectious cascades of information contagion. Our
findings will help generate effective countermeasures to combat the group and
other forms of online extremism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08722</id><created>2017-01-30</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hucht</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author></authors><title>The square lattice Ising model on the rectangle II: Finite-size scaling
  limit</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-lat math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures, second part of arXiv:1609.01963, some text and
  references added, several small errors fixed, figure 5 changed, accepted</comments><msc-class>82B20, 82B23</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 265205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6b7a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the results published recently [J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 065201
(2017)], the universal finite-size contributions to the free energy of the
square lattice Ising model on the $L\times M$ rectangle, with open boundary
conditions in both directions, are calculated exactly in the finite-size
scaling limit $L,M\to\infty$, $T\to T_\mathrm{c}$, with fixed temperature
scaling variable $x\propto(T/T_\mathrm{c}-1)M$ and fixed aspect ratio
$\rho\propto L/M$. We derive exponentially fast converging series for the
related Casimir potential and Casimir force scaling functions. At the critical
point $T=T_\mathrm{c}$ we confirm predictions from conformal field theory by
Cardy &amp; Peschel [Nucl. Phys. B 300, 377 (1988)] and by Kleban &amp; Vassileva [J.
Phys. A: Math. Gen. 24, 3407 (1991)]. The presence of corners and the related
corner free energy has dramatic impact on the Casimir scaling functions and
leads to a logarithmic divergence of the Casimir potential scaling function at
criticality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01089</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mannel</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusov</keyname><forenames>Aleksey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shahriaran</keyname><forenames>Farnoush</forenames></author></authors><title>Inclusive Semitauonic $B$ Decays to Order ${\cal O}
  (\Lambda_{QCD}^3/m_b^3)$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables</comments><report-no>SI-HEP-2017-01, QFET-2017-01</report-no><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics B 921 (2017) 211-224</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.05.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the decay width and the $\tau$-lepton energy distribution as
well as relevant moments for inclusive $\bar B \to X_c \tau \bar \nu_\tau$
process including power corrections up to order $\Lambda_{QCD}^3/m_b^3$ and QCD
corrections to the partonic level. We compare the result with the sum of the
standard-model predictions of the branching fractions of the exclusive
semileptonic $\bar B \to (D, D^*, D^{**}) \tau \bar \nu_\tau$ decays as well as
with the relevant experimental data. Our prediction is in agreement with the
LEP measurement and is consistent with the standard-model calculation of the
exclusive modes. We discuss the impact from physics beyond the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01781</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reynoso</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baltan&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saarikoski</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>V&#xe1;zquez-Lozano</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nitta</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frustaglia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin resonance under topological driving fields</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>Published version (revised), 7 pages, 5 figures, 3 technical
  appendices</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 063010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa723a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of a localized spin-1/2 driven by a time-periodic
magnetic field that undergoes a topological transition. Despite the strongly
non-adiabatic effects dominating the spin dynamics, we find that the field's
topology appears clearly imprinted in the Floquet spin states through an
effective Berry phase emerging in the quasienergy. This has remarkable
consequences on the spin resonance condition suggesting a whole new class of
experiments to spot topological transitions in the dynamics of spins and other
two-level systems, from nuclear magnetic resonance to strongly-driven
superconducting qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03712</id><created>2017-02-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Volmer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pissinger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ersfeld</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhlen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampfer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beschoten</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inter-valley dark trion states with spin lifetimes of 150 ns in WSe$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235408 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate long trion spin lifetimes in a WSe$_2$ monolayer of up to 150
ns at 5 K. Applying a transverse magnetic field in time-resolved Kerr-rotation
measurements reveals a complex composition of the spin signal of up to four
distinct components. The Kerr rotation signal can be well described by a model
which includes inhomogeneous spin dephasing and by setting the trion spin
lifetimes to the measured excitonic recombination times extracted from
time-resolved reflectivity measurements. We observe a continuous shift of the
Kerr resonance with the probe energy, which can be explained by an
adsorbate-induced, inhomogeneous potential landscape of the WSe$_2$ flake. A
further indication of extrinsic effects on the spin dynamics is given by a
change of both the trion spin lifetime and the distribution of g-factors over
time. Finally, we detect a Kerr rotation signal from the trion's higher-energy
triplet state when the lower-energy singlet state is optically pumped by
circularly polarized light. We explain this by the formation of dark trion
states, which are also responsible for the observed long trion spin lifetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00058</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owhadi</keyname><forenames>Houman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauvageau</keyname><forenames>Joe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watkinson</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>On testing the simulation theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures, final version to appear in IJQF</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Can the theory that reality is a simulation be tested? We investigate this
question based on the assumption that if the system performing the simulation
is finite (i.e. has limited resources), then to achieve low computational
complexity, such a system would, as in a video game, render content (reality)
only at the moment that information becomes available for observation by a
player and not at the moment of detection by a machine (that would be part of
the simulation and whose detection would also be part of the internal
computation performed by the Virtual Reality server before rendering content to
the player). Guided by this principle we describe conceptual wave/particle
duality experiments aimed at testing the simulation theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00798</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Colonna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernal</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gavoci</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novara</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saracco</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of processing conditions on the thermal and electrical
  conductivity of poly (butylene terephthalate) nanocomposites prepared via
  ring-opening polymerization</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.matdes.2017.01.067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Successful preparation of polymer nanocomposites, exploiting graphene-related
materials, via melt mixing technology requires precise design, optimization and
control of processing. In the present work, the effect of different processing
parameters during the preparation of poly (butylene terephthalate)
nanocomposites, through ring-opening polymerization of cyclic butylene
terephthalate in presence of graphite nanoplatelets (GNP), was thoroughly
addressed. Processing temperature (240{\deg}C or 260{\deg}C), extrusion time (5
or 10 minutes) and shear rate (50 or 100 rpm) were varied by means of a full
factorial design of experiment approach, leading to the preparation of
polybutylene terephthalate/GNP nanocomposite in 8 different processing
conditions. Morphology and quality of GNP were investigated by means of
electron microscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, thermogravimetry and
Raman spectroscopy. Molecular weight of the polymer matrix in nanocomposites
and nanoflake dispersion were experimentally determined as a function of the
different processing conditions. The effect of transformation parameters on
electrical and thermal properties was studied by means of electrical and
thermal conductivity measurement. Heat and charge transport performance
evidenced a clear correlation with the dispersion and fragmentation of the GNP
nanoflakes; in particular, gentle processing conditions (low shear rate, short
mixing time) turned out to be the most favourable condition to obtain high
conductivity values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00805</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Colonna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monticelli</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saracco</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Morphology and properties evolution upon ring-opening polymerization
  during extrusion of cyclic butylene terephthalate and
  graphene-related-materials into thermally conductive nanocomposites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.eurpolymj.2017.02.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the study of thermal conductivity before and after in-situ
ring-opening polymerization of cyclic butylene terephthalate into poly
(butylene terephthalate) in presence of graphene-related materials (GRM) is
addressed, to gain insight in the modification of nanocomposites morphology
upon polymerization. Five types of GRM were used: one type of graphite
nanoplatelets, two different grades of reduced graphene oxide (rGO) and the
same rGO grades after thermal annealing for 1 hour at 1700{\deg}C under vacuum
to reduce their defectiveness. Polymerization of CBT into pCBT, morphology and
nanoparticle organization were investigated by means of differential scanning
calorimetry, electron microscopy and rheology. Electrical and thermal
properties were investigated by means of volumetric resistivity and bulk
thermal conductivity measurement. In particular, the reduction of nanoflake
aspect ratio during ring-opening polymerization was found to have a detrimental
effect on both electrical and thermal conductivities in nanocomposites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00844</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Graf</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence and Stability of Circular Orbits in Time-Dependent Spherically
  Symmetric Spacetimes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>24 pages, 1 figure, slightly reworked and expanded - main results
  unchanged</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a general spherically four--dimensional metric the notion of
&quot;circularity&quot; of a family of equatorial geodesic trajectories is defined in
geometrical terms. The main object turns out to be the angular--momentum
function $J$ obeying a consistency condition involving the mean extrinsic
curvature of the submanifold containing the geodesics. The ana\-ly\-sis of
linear stability is reduced to a simple dynamical system formally describing a
damped harmonic oscillator. For static metrics the existence of such geodesics
is given when $J^2 &gt; 0$, and $(J^2)' &gt; 0$ for stability. The formalism is then
applied to the Schwarzschild--de Sitter solution, both in its static and in its
time--dependent cosmological version, as well to the Kerr--de Sitter solution.
In addition we present an approximate solution to a cosmological metric
containing a massive source and solving the Einstein field equation for a
massless scalar.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04671</id><created>2017-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Abchuyeh</keyname><forenames>Mohsen Amini</forenames></author></authors><title>Spread of wave packets in disordered hierarchical lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>Accepted in EPL</comments><report-no>117 (2017),30003</report-no><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters (EPL) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/30003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the spreading of the wave packet in the generalized
Rosenzweig-Porter random matrix ensemble in the region of non-ergodic extended
states $1&lt;\gamma&lt;2$. We show that despite non-trivial fractal dimensions $0 &lt;
D_{q}=2-\gamma&lt;1$ characterize wave function statistics in this region, the
wave packet spreading $\langle r^{2} \rangle \propto t^{\beta}$ is governed by
the &quot;diffusion&quot; exponent $\beta=1$ outside the ballistic regime $t&gt;\tau\sim 1$
and $\langle r^{2}\rangle \propto t^{2}$ in the ballistic regime for
$t&lt;\tau\sim 1$. This demonstrates that the multifractality exhibits itself only
in {\it local} quantities like the wave packet survival probability but not in
the large-distance spreading of the wave packet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05408</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kameyama</keyname><forenames>Masaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nawata</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Refined large N duality for knots</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.AG math.GT math.MP</categories><comments>Two Mathematica notebooks are attached as ancillary files; in v2, the
  title is changed, an extension to non-torus knots is included in section 6,
  typos are corrected, and references are added</comments><report-no>CALT-2017-010</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate large $N$ duality of $\mathrm{U}(N)$ refined Chern-Simons theory
with a torus knot/link in $S^3$. By studying refined BPS states in M-theory, we
provide the explicit form of low-energy effective actions of Type IIA string
theory with D4-branes on the $\Omega$-background. This form enables us to
relate refined Chern-Simons invariants of a torus knot/link in $S^3$ to refined
BPS invariants in the resolved conifold. Assuming that the extra
$\mathrm{U}(1)$ global symmetry acts on BPS states trivially, the duality
predicts graded dimensions of cohomology groups of moduli spaces of M2-M5 bound
states associated to a torus knot/link in the resolved conifold. Thus, this
formulation can be also interpreted as a positivity conjecture of refined
Chern-Simons invariants of torus knots/links. We also discuss about an
extension to non-torus knots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05937</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zech</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerruti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazin</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Expected signatures from hadronic emission processes in the TeV spectra
  of BL Lac objects</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>18 pages, 20 figures, plus appendix. A problem with formatting of the
  bibliography has been fixed and a few minor language revisions have been done</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 602, A25 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629997</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The wealth of recent data from imaging air Cherenkov telescopes (IACTs),
ultra-high energy cosmic-ray experiments and neutrino telescopes have fuelled a
renewed interest in hadronic emission models for gamma-loud blazars. We explore
physically plausible solutions for a lepto-hadronic interpretation of the
stationary emission from high-frequency peaked BL Lac objects (HBLs). The
modelled spectral energy distributions are then searched for specific
signatures at very high energies that could help to distinguish the hadronic
origin of the emission from a standard leptonic scenario. By introducing a few
basic constraints on parameters of the model, such as assuming the
co-acceleration of electrons and protons, we significantly reduced the number
of free parameters. We then systematically explored the parameter space of the
size of the emission region and its magnetic field for two bright gamma-loud
HBLs, PKS 2155-304 and Mrk 421. For all solutions close to equipartition
between the energy densities of protons and of the magnetic field, and with
acceptable jet power and light-crossing timescales, we inspected the spectral
hardening in the multi-TeV domain from proton-photon induced cascades and
muon-synchrotron emission inside the source. Very-high-energy spectra simulated
with the available instrument functions from the future Cherenkov Telescope
Array (CTA) were evaluated for detectable features as a function of exposure
time, source redshift, and flux level. Over a large range of model parameters,
the spectral hardening due to internal synchrotron-pair cascades, the &quot;cascade
bump&quot;, should be detectable for acceptable exposure times with the future CTA
for a few nearby and bright HBLs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06250</id><created>2017-03-18</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Motegi</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author></authors><title>Domain wall boundary partition function of the six-vertex model with
  triangular boundary</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Superceded by the forthcoming updated version of arXiv:1703.07924</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce and study the domain wall boundary partition function of the
integrable six-vertex model with triangular boundary. We first formulate the
domain wall boundary partition function with triangular boundary by using the
$U_q(sl_2)$ $R$-matrix and a special class of the triangular $K$-matrix. By
using its graphical representation, we make the Izergin-Korepin analysis with
the help of the Yang-Baxter relation and the reflection equation to give a
characterization of the partition function. The explict form of the symmetric
function representing the partition function is presented by showing that it
satisfies all the required properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06999</id><created>2017-03-20</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>Ask Hjorth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuisma</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;fgren</keyname><forenames>Joakim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pouillon</keyname><forenames>Yann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erhart</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hyldgaard</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author></authors><title>libvdwxc: A library for exchange-correlation functionals in the vdW-DF
  family</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Modelling Simul. Mater. Sci. Eng. 25 065004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-651X/aa7320</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present libvdwxc, a general library for evaluating the energy and
potential for the family of vdW-DF exchange--correlation functionals. libvdwxc
provides an efficient implementation of the vdW-DF method and can be interfaced
with various general-purpose DFT codes. Currently, the GPAW and Octopus codes
implement interfaces to libvdwxc. The present implementation emphasizes
scalability and parallel performance, and thereby enables \textit{ab initio}
calculations of nanometer-scale complexes. The numerical accuracy is
benchmarked on the S22 test set whereas parallel performance is benchmarked on
ligand-protected gold nanoparticles
($\text{Au}_{144}(\text{SC}_{11}\text{NH}_{25})_{60}$) up to 9696 atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08892</id><created>2017-03-26</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Everts</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samin</keyname><forenames>Sela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elbers</keyname><forenames>Nina. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hoeven</keyname><forenames>Jessi E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Blaaderen</keyname><forenames>Alfons</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Roij</keyname><forenames>Ren&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Colloid-oil-water-interface interactions in the presence of multiple
  salts: charge regulation and dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>13+2 pages, 5+3 figures; V2: small clarifications in the text</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 19, 14345 - 14357 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7CP01935A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically and experimentally investigate colloid-oil-water-interface
interactions of charged, sterically stabilized, poly(methyl-methacrylate)
colloidal particles dispersed in a low-polar oil (dielectric constant
$\epsilon=5-10$) that is in contact with an adjacent water phase. In this model
system, the colloidal particles cannot penetrate the oil-water interface due to
repulsive van der Waals forces with the interface whereas the multiple salts
that are dissolved in the oil are free to partition into the water phase. The
sign and magnitude of the Donnan potential and/or the particle charge is
affected by these salt concentrations such that the effective interaction
potential can be highly tuned. Both the equilibrium effective colloid-interface
interactions and the ion dynamics are explored within a Poisson-Nernst-Planck
theory, and compared to experimental observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00235</id><created>2017-04-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Keeney</keyname><forenames>Brian A.</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stocke</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Danforth</keyname><forenames>Charles W.</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shull</keyname><forenames>J. Michael</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pratt</keyname><forenames>Cameron T.</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Froning</keyname><forenames>Cynthia S.</forenames><affiliation>Univ of Texas, Austin, TX</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames><affiliation>CASA, Univ. of Colorado, Boulder, CO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Penton</keyname><forenames>Steven V.</forenames><affiliation>STScI, Baltimore, MD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Savage</keyname><forenames>Blair D.</forenames><affiliation>Univ of Wisconsin, Madison, WI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Characterizing the Circumgalactic Medium of Nearby Galaxies with HST/COS
  and HST/STIS Absorption-Line Spectroscopy: II. Methods and Models</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>51 pages, 20 figures, 11 tables, accepted for publication in the
  Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa6b59</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present basic data and modeling for a survey of the cool, photo-ionized
Circum-Galactic Medium (CGM) of low-redshift galaxies using far-UV QSO
absorption line probes. This survey consists of &quot;targeted&quot; and &quot;serendipitous&quot;
CGM subsamples, originally described in Stocke et al. (2013, Paper 1). The
targeted subsample probes low-luminosity, late-type galaxies at $z&lt;0.02$ with
small impact parameters ($\langle\rho\rangle = 71$ kpc), and the serendipitous
subsample probes higher luminosity galaxies at $z\lesssim0.2$ with larger
impact parameters ($\langle\rho\rangle = 222$ kpc). HST and FUSE UV
spectroscopy of the absorbers and basic data for the associated galaxies,
derived from ground-based imaging and spectroscopy, are presented. We find
broad agreement with the COS-Halos results, but our sample shows no evidence
for changing ionization parameter or hydrogen density with distance from the
CGM host galaxy, probably because the COS-Halos survey probes the CGM at
smaller impact parameters. We find at least two passive galaxies with H I and
metal-line absorption, confirming the intriguing COS-Halos result that galaxies
sometimes have cool gas halos despite no on-going star formation. Using a new
methodology for fitting H I absorption complexes, we confirm the CGM cool gas
mass of Paper 1, but this value is significantly smaller than found by the
COS-Halos survey. We trace much of this difference to the specific values of
the low-$z$ meta-galactic ionization rate assumed. After accounting for this
difference, a best-value for the CGM cool gas mass is found by combining the
results of both surveys to obtain $\log{(M/M_{\odot})}=10.5\pm0.3$, or ~30% of
the total baryon reservoir of an $L \geq L^*$, star-forming galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00983</id><created>2017-04-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Bannow</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenow</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hader</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moloney</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonner</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>An ab initio based approach to optical properties of semiconductor
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Modelling Simul. Mater. Sci. Eng. 25, 065001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-651X/aa7478</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A procedure is presented that combines density functional theory computations
of bulk semiconductor alloys with the semiconductor Bloch equations, in order
to achieve an ab initio based prediction of the optical properties of
semiconductor alloy heterostructures. The parameters of an eight-band
kp-Hamiltonian are fitted to the effective band structure of an appropriate
alloy. The envelope function approach is applied to model the quantum well
using the kp-wave functions and eigenvalues as starting point for calculating
the optical properties of the heterostructure. It is shown that Luttinger
parameters derived from band structures computed with the TB09 density
functional reproduce extrapolated values. The procedure is illustrated by
computing the absorption spectra for a (AlGa)As/Ga(AsP)/(AlGa)As quantum well
system with varying phosphide content in the active layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01517</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-05-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bonelli</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassi</keyname><forenames>Alba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanzini</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>New results in $\mathcal{N}=2$ theories from non-perturbative string</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, 1 figure. v3: Many clarifications and some new results on
  exact S-duality added. Typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the magnetic phase of SU(N) $\mathcal{N}=2$ Super Yang-Mills
theories in the self-dual Omega background in terms of a new class of multi-cut
matrix models. These arise from a non-perturbative completion of topological
strings in the dual four dimensional limit which engineers the gauge theory in
the strongly coupled magnetic frame. The corresponding spectral determinants
provide natural candidates for the tau functions of isomonodromy problems for
flat spectral connections associated to the Seiberg-Witten geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04298</id><created>2017-04-13</created><updated>2017-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fuks</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jeong Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Seung J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scrutinizing the Higgs quartic coupling at a future 100 TeV
  proton-proton collider with taus and b-jets</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables, version accepted by PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B771 (2017) 354-358</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Higgs potential consists of an unexplored territory in which the
electroweak symmetry breaking is triggered, and it is moreover directly related
to the nature of the electroweak phase transition. Measuring the Higgs boson
cubic and quartic couplings, or getting equivalently information on the exact
shape of the Higgs potential, is therefore an essential task. However, direct
measurements beyond the cubic self-interaction of the Higgs boson consist of a
huge challenge, even for a future proton-proton collider expected to operate at
a center-of-mass energy of 100 TeV. We present a novel approach to extract
model-independent constraints on the triple and quartic Higgs self-coupling by
investigating triple Higgs-boson hadroproduction at a center-of-mass energy of
100 TeV, focusing on the $\tau \tau b \bar{b} b \bar{b}$ channel that was
previously overlooked due to a supposedly too large background. It is thrown
into sharp relief that the assist from transverse variables such as $m_{T2}$
and a boosted configuration ensures a high signal sensitivity. We derive the
luminosities that would be required to constrain given deviations from the
Standard Model in the Higgs self-interactions, showing for instance that a
$2\sigma$ sensitivity could be achieved for an integrated luminosity of 30
ab$^{-1}$ when Standard Model properties are assumed. With the prospects of
combining these findings with other triple-Higgs search channels, the Standard
Model Higgs quartic coupling could in principle be reached with a significance
beyond the $3\sigma$ level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06635</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Prentice</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzali</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A physically motivated classification of stripped-envelope supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (3): 2672-2694</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx980</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The classification of stripped-envelope supernovae (SE-SNe) is revisited
using modern data-sets. Spectra are analysed using an empirical method to
&quot;blindly&quot; categorise SNe according to spectral feature strength and appearance.
This method makes a clear distinction between SNe that are He-rich (IIb/Ib) and
He-poor (Ic) and further analysis is performed on each subgroup. For He-rich
SNe the presence of H becomes the focus. The strength, velocity, and ratio
between absorption and emission of H$\alpha$ is measured, along with additional
analysis of He I lines, in order to categorise the SNe. The He-poor SNe are
ordered according to the number of absorption features $N$ present in the
spectra, which is a measure of the degree of line blending. The kinetic energy
per unit mass $E_\mathrm{k}/M_\mathrm{ej}$ is strongly affected by mass at high
velocity and such situations principally occur when the outer density profile
of the ejecta is shallow, leading to the blending of lines. Using the results,
the existing SE-SN taxonomic scheme is adapted. He-rich SNe are split into four
groups, IIb, IIb(I), Ib(II), and Ib, which represent H-rich to H-poor SNe. The
SNe Ic category of broad-lined Ic (Ic-BL) is abandoned in favour of quantifying
the line blending via $\left&lt;N\right&gt;$ before peak. To better reflect the
physical parameters of the explosions, the velocity of Si II at peak and the
half-luminosity decay time $t_{+1/2}$ are included to give SNe Ic a designation
of Ic-$\left&lt;N\right&gt;\left(v_\mathrm{p,SiII}/t_{+1/2}\right)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01560</id><created>2017-05-03</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Booth</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dent</keyname><forenames>William R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jord&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lestrade</keyname><forenames>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hales</keyname><forenames>Antonio S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyatt</keyname><forenames>Mark C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casassus</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ertel</keyname><forenames>Steve</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greaves</keyname><forenames>Jane S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennedy</keyname><forenames>Grant M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matr&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augereau</keyname><forenames>Jean-Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villard</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>The Northern Arc of $\epsilon$ Eridani's Debris Ring as Seen by ALMA</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, accepted by MNRAS, v2: corrected typos in equations 2 and 3</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 469, 3, 3200-3212 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first ALMA observations of the closest known extrasolar debris
disc. This disc orbits the star $\epsilon$ Eridani, a K-type star just 3.2pc
away. Due to the proximity of the star, the entire disc cannot fit within the
ALMA field of view. Therefore, the observations have been centred 18&quot; North of
the star, providing us with a clear detection of the northern arc of the ring,
at a wavelength of 1.3mm. The observed disc emission is found to be narrow with
a width of just 11-13AU. The fractional disc width we find is comparable to
that of the Solar System's Kuiper Belt and makes this one of the narrowest
debris discs known. If the inner and outer edges are due to resonances with a
planet then this planet likely has a semi-major axis of 48AU. We find tentative
evidence for clumps in the ring, although there is a strong chance that at
least one is a background galaxy. We confirm, at much higher significance, the
previous detection of an unresolved emission at the star that is above the
level of the photosphere and attribute this excess to stellar chromospheric
emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04726</id><created>2017-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hod</keyname><forenames>Shahar</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-bound state resonances of charged massive scalar fields in the
  near-extremal Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om black-hole spacetime</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal C 77, 351 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasi-bound states of charged massive scalar fields in the near-extremal
charged Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om black-hole spacetime are studied {\it
analytically}. These discrete resonant modes of the composed black-hole-field
system are characterized by the physically motivated boundary condition of
ingoing waves at the black-hole horizon and exponentially decaying (bounded)
radial eigenfunctions at spatial infinity. Solving the Klein-Gordon wave
equation for the linearized scalar fields in the black-hole spacetime, we
derive a remarkably compact analytical formula for the complex frequency
spectrum which characterizes the quasi-bound state resonances of the composed
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om-black-hole-charged-massive-scalar-field system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05358</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Chang-Hun</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of lepton mass matrices and TeV-scale phenomenology in the
  minimal left-right symmetric model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a systematic procedure of constructing lepton mass matrices that
satisfy all the experimental constraints in the light lepton sector of the
minimal left-right symmetric model with type-I seesaw dominance. This method is
unique since it is applicable to the most general cases of type-I seesaw with
complex electroweak vacuum expectation values in the model. With this method,
we investigate the TeV-scale phenomenology in the normal hierarchy without
fine-tuning of model parameters, focusing on the charged lepton flavour
violation, neutrinoless double beta decay, and electric dipole moments of
charged leptons. We examine the predictions for typical ranges of associated
observables such as branching ratios of rare lepton decays, and study how those
experimental constraints affect the model parameter space. The most notable
result is that the regions of parameter space that allow small light neutrino
masses have been constrained by the present experimental bounds from charged
lepton flavour violation. Furthermore, we also find that the mass of the
lightest heavy neutrino should be relatively small in order to satisfy those
experimental constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09139</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maziero</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author></authors><title>The Maccone-Pati uncertainty relation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Didactic text, English version</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Bras. Ens. Fis. 39, e4306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1590/1806-9126-RBEF-2017-0014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of incompatible observables constitutes one of the most
prominent characteristics of quantum mechanics (QM) and can be revealed and
formalized through uncertainty relations. The
Heisenberg-Robertson-Schr\&quot;odinger uncertainty relation (HRSUR) was proved at
the dawn of quantum formalism and is ever-present in the teaching and research
on QM. Notwithstanding, the HRSUR possess the so called triviality problem.
That is to say, the HRSUR yields no information about the possible
incompatibility between two observables if the system was prepared in a state
which is an eigenvector of one of them. After about 85 years of existence of
the HRSUR, this problem was solved recently by Lorenzo Maccone and Arun K.
Pati. In this article, we start doing a brief discussion of general aspects of
the uncertainty principle in QM and recapitulating the proof of HRSUR.
Afterwards we present in simple terms the proof of the Maccone-Pati uncertainty
relation, which can be obtained basically via the application of the
parallelogram law and Cauchy-Schwarz inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.11111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.11111</id><created>2017-05-31</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Changtao</forenames></author></authors><title>Some remarks on Einstein-Randers metrics</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MG math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures</comments><msc-class>53B40, 53C60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this essay, we study the sufficient and necessary conditions for a Randers
metrc to be of constant Ricci curvature without the restriction of strong
convexity (regularity). The classification result for the case
$\|\beta\|_{\alpha}&gt;1$ is provided, which is similar to the famous
Bao-Robles-Shen's result for strongly convex Randers metrics
($\|\beta\|_{\alpha}&lt;1$).
  Based on some famous Einstein-Lorentz metrics in General Relativity, such as
Minkowski metric, Sitter metric, anti de Sitter metric, Schwarzschild metric,
Kerr metric, C-metric, Kasner metric, Levi-Civita metric,
Cartor-Novotn\'{y}-Horsk\'{y} metric, etc., many non-regular Einstein-Randers
metrics are constructed.
  Besides, we find that the case $\|\beta\|_{\alpha}\equiv1$ is very
distinctive. These metrics will be called singular Randers metrics or parabolic
Finsler metrics since their indicatrixs are parabolic hypersurface. A
preliminary discussion for such metrics is provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00972</id><created>2017-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>de Divitiis</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite scale local Lyapunov exponents distribution in fully developed
  homogeneous isotropic turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>original research article, 8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work analyzes the distribution function of the finite scale local
Lyapunov exponent of a pair fluid particles trajectories in fully developed
incompressible homogeneous isotropic turbulence. According to the hypothesis of
fully developed chaos, this PDF is reasonably estimated by maximizing the
entropy associated to such distribution, resulting to be an uniform
distribution function in a proper interval of variation of the local Lyapunov
exponents. From this PDF, we determine the relationship between the average and
maximum Lyapunov exponents and the longitudinal velocity correlation function.
This link, which leads to the closure of von K\`arm\`an--Howarth and Corrsin
equations, agrees with the relation obtained in the previous work, supporting
the proposed PDF calculation, at least for the purposes of the energy cascade
effect estimation. Furthermore, through the property that the Lyapunov vectors
tend to align to the direction of the maximum growth rate of trajectories
distance, we obtain the link between maximum and average Lyapunov exponents in
line with the previous result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01149</id><created>2017-06-04</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Gregory W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comment On Berry Connections</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages. V2: Some silly misprints fixed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When families of quantum systems are equipped with a continuous family of
Hamiltonians such that there is a gap in the common spectrum one can define a
notion of a Berry connection. In this note we stress that, in general, since
the Hilbert bundle defining the family of quantum systems does not come with a
canonical trivialization there is in fact not a single Berry connection but
rather a family of Berry connections. Two examples illustrate that this remark
can have physical consequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01301</id><created>2017-06-05</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rose</keyname><forenames>Luigi Delle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khalil</keyname><forenames>Shaaban</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Simon J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzo</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Un</keyname><forenames>Cem S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Naturalness and Dark Matter Properties of the BLSSM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Prepared for proceedings for DIS2017, talk presented by Simon King</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this report, we compare the naturalness and Dark Matter (DM) properties of
the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model (MSSM) and the $B-L$ Supersymmetric
Standard Model (BLSSM), with universality in both cases. We do this by adopting
standard measures for the quantitative analysis of the Fine-Tuning (FT), at
both low (i.e. supersymmetric (SUSY)) and high (i.e. unification) scales. We
will see a similar level of FT for both models in these scenarios, with a
slightly better FT for the BLSSM at SUSY scales and MSSM at Grand Unification
Theory (GUT) scales. When including DM relic constraints, we drastically
confine the MSSM's parameter space, whereas we still find a large parameter
space available for the non-minimal scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01881</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Krivoruchenko</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superposition principle and Kirchhoff's integral theorem</title><categories>hep-th math.HO</categories><comments>24 pages, Extended notes of a lecture delivered to students of Moscow
  Institute of Physics and Technology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The need for modification of the Huygens-Fresnel superposition principle
arises even in the description of the free fields of massive particles and,
more extensively, in nonlinear field theories. A wide range of formulations and
superposition schemes for secondary waves are captured by Kirchhoff's integral
theorem. We discuss various versions of this theorem as well as its connection
with the superposition principle and the method of Green's functions. A
superposition scheme inherent in linear field theories, which is not based on
Kirchhoff's integral theorem but instead relies on the completeness condition,
is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01884</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Spector</keyname><forenames>Oded</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brosch</keyname><forenames>Noah</forenames></author></authors><title>EIG - II. Intriguing characteristics of the most extremely isolated
  galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>40 pages; 17 figures; 12 tables</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 2017; 469(1): 347-382</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx689</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have selected a sample of 41 extremely isolated galaxies (EIGs) from the
local universe using both optical and HI ALFALFA redshifts (Spector &amp; Brosch
2016). Narrow band H$_\alpha$ and wide band imaging along with public data were
used to derive star formation rates (SFRs), star formation histories (SFHs),
and morphological classifications for the EIGs. We have found that the extreme
isolation of the EIGs does not affect considerably their star-formation
compared to field galaxies. EIGs are typically `blue cloud' galaxies that fit
the `main sequence of star forming galaxies' and may show asymmetric star
formation and strong compact star-forming regions.
  We discovered surprising environmental dependencies of the HI content,
M$_{HI}$, and of the morphological type of EIGs; The most isolated galaxies (of
subsample EIG-1) have lower M$_{HI}$ on average (with $2.5\,\sigma$ confidence)
and a higher tendency to be early-types (with 0.94 confidence) compared to the
less isolated galaxies of subsample EIG-2. To the best of our knowledge this is
the first study that finds an effect in which an isolated sample shows a higher
fraction of early-types compared to a less isolated sample.
  Both early-type and late-type EIGs follow the same colour-to-M$_{*}$,
SFR-to-M$_{*}$ (`main sequence') and M$_{HI}$-to-$M_{*}$ relations. This
indicates that the mechanisms and factors governing star formation, colour and
the M$_{HI}$-to-M$_{*}$ relation are similar in early-type and late-type EIGs,
and that the morphological type of EIGs is not governed by their M$_{HI}$
content, colour or SFR.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01914</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Stein</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nature vs. Nurture in Discrete Spin Dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of predictability, or &quot;nature vs. nurture&quot;, in both ordered and
disordered Ising systems following a deep quench from infinite to zero
temperature is reviewed. Two questions are addressed. The first deals with the
nature of the final state: for an infinite system, does every spin flip
infinitely often, or does every spin flip only finitely many times, or do some
spins flip infinitely often and others finitely often? Once this question is
determined, the evolution of the system from its initial state can be studied
with attention to the issue of how much information contained in the final
state depends on that contained in the initial state, and how much depends on
the detailed history of the system. This problem has been addressed both
analytically and numerically in several papers, and their main methods,
results, and conclusions will be reviewed. The discussion closes with some open
problems that remain to be addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01915</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Wenquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chaofan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yanfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Changchun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Xiaobi</forenames></author></authors><title>A new efficient staggered grid finite difference scheme for elastic wave
  equation modeling</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Staggered grid finite difference scheme is widely used for the first order
elastic wave equation, which constitutes the basis for least-squares reverse
time migration and full waveform inversion. It is of great importance to
improve the efficiency and accuracy of wave equation modeling. Usually the same
staggered grid finite difference scheme is used for all the spatial derivatives
in the first order elastic wave equation. In this paper, we propose a new
staggered grid finite difference scheme which can improve the efficiency while
preserving the same accuracy for the first order elastic wave equation
simulation. It uses second order staggered grid finite difference scheme for
some of the first order spatial derivatives while utilizing longer staggered
grid finite difference operator for other first order spatial derivatives. We
The staggered grid finite difference coefficients of the new finite difference
scheme are determined in the space domain by a linear method. We demonstrate by
dispersion analysis and numerical simulation the effectiveness of the proposed
method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01917</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Drumond</keyname><forenames>Raphael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf3;ller</keyname><forenames>Nat&#xe1;lia S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounding entanglement spreading after a local quench</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 95, 062301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the variation of von Neumann entropy of subsystem reduced states
of general many- body lattice spin systems due to local quantum quenches. We
obtain Lieb-Robinson-like bounds that are independent of the subsystem volume.
The main assumptions are that the Hamiltonian satisfies a Lieb-Robinson bound
and that the volume of spheres on the lattice grows at most exponentially with
their radius. More specifically, the bound exponentially increases with time
but exponentially decreases with the distance between the subsystem and the
region where the quench takes place. The fact that the bound is independent of
the subsystem volume leads to stronger constraints (than previously known) on
the propagation of information throughout many-body systems. In particular, it
shows that bipartite entanglement satisfies an effective &quot;light cone&quot;,
regardless of system size. Further implications to t density-matrix
renormalization-group simulations of quantum spin chains and limitations to the
propagation of information are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01924</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Debarba</keyname><forenames>Tiago</forenames></author></authors><title>Koashi-Winter relation for {\alpha}-Renyi entropies</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages, no figures. Comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents a generalization of the Koashi-Winter relation for
$\alpha$-Renyi entropies. This result is based on the Renyi\apos s entropy
version of quantum Jensen Shannon divergence. By means of this definition, a
classical correlations quantifier $C_{\alpha}(\rho_{AB}) =
\sup_{\xi_{AB}^{M_B}} Q_{\alpha}(\xi_{AB}^{M_B})$ is proposed, where the
optimization is taken over the ensembles $\xi_{AB}^{M_B}$ created by the
outputs of the local measurement process. The main result is applied to the
capacity of a quantum classical channel over a tripartite pure state
$\psi_{ABE}$, that is rated above in function of the probability of success to
discriminate the states in the ensemble $\xi_{AE}^{M_E}$, created by the local
dephasing over partition $E$, and the asymptotic log generalized robustness of
partition $AB$. Some analytical results are calculated for classical
correlations and entanglement of formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01925</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>May</keyname><forenames>Andrew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yaohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calder</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>David S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Tribhuwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakmak</keyname><forenames>Ercan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Huibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jiaqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>Michael A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic order and interactions in ferrimagnetic Mn3Si2Te6</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Main article plus Supplemental</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 95, 174440 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.174440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetism in Mn$_3$Si$_2$Te$_6$ has been investigated using thermodynamic
measurements, first principles calculations, neutron diffraction and diffuse
neutron scattering on single crystals. These data confirm that
Mn$_3$Si$_2$Te$_6$ is a ferrimagnet below a Curie temperature of $T_C$
approximately 78K. The magnetism is anisotropic, with magnetization and neutron
diffraction demonstrating that the moments lie within the basal plane of the
trigonal structure. The saturation magnetization of approximately 1.6$\mu_B$/Mn
at 5K originates from the different multiplicities of the two
antiferromagnetically-aligned Mn sites. First principles calculations reveal
antiferromagnetic exchange for the three nearest Mn-Mn pairs, which leads to a
competition between the ferrimagnetic ground state and three other magnetic
configurations. The ferrimagnetic state results from the energy associated with
the third-nearest neighbor interaction, and thus long-range interactions are
essential for the observed behavior. Diffuse magnetic scattering is observed
around the 002 Bragg reflection at 120K, which indicates the presence of strong
spin correlations well above $T_C$. These are promoted by the competing ground
states that result in a relative suppression of $T_C$, and may be associated
with a small ferromagnetic component that produces anisotropic magnetism below
$\approx$330K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01935</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hubeny</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanz</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author></authors><title>TLUSTY User's Guide II: Reference Manual</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>94 pages, 0 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second part of a three-volume guide to TLUSTY and SYNSPEC. It
presents a detailed reference manual for TLUSTY, which contains a detailed
description of basic physical assumptions and equations used to model an
atmosphere, together with an overview of the numerical methods to solve these
equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01937</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hubeny</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanz</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author></authors><title>TLUSTY User's Guide III: Operational Manual</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>144 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a detailed operational manual for TLUSTY. It provides a
guide for understanding the essential features and the basic modes of operation
of the program. To help the user, it is divided into two parts. The first part
describes the most important input parameters and available numerical options.
The second part covers additional details and a comprehensive description of
all physical and numerical options, and a description of all input parameters,
many of which needed only in special cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01942</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Mackenzie</keyname><forenames>Andrew P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scaffidi</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hicks</keyname><forenames>Clifford W</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maeno</keyname><forenames>Yoshiteru</forenames></author></authors><title>Even odder after twenty-three years: the superconducting order parameter
  puzzle of Sr2RuO4</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this short review, we aim to provide a topical update on the status of
efforts to understand the superconductivity of Sr2RuO4. We concentrate on the
quest to identify a superconducting order parameter symmetry that is compatible
with all the major pieces of experimental knowledge of the material, and
highlight some major discrepancies that have become even clearer in recent
years. As the pun in the title suggests, we have tried to start the discussion
from scratch, making no assumptions even about fundamental issues such as the
parity of the superconducting state. We conclude that no consensus is currently
achievable in Sr2RuO4, and that the reasons for this go to the heart of how
well some of the key probes of unconventional superconductivity are really
understood. This is therefore a puzzle that merits continued in-depth study.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01953</id><created>2017-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Zanin</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romance</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moral</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Criado</keyname><forenames>Regino</forenames></author></authors><title>Credit card fraud detection through parenclitic network analysis</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The detection of frauds in credit card transactions is a major topic in
financial research, of profound economic implications. While this has hitherto
been tackled through data analysis techniques, the resemblances between this
and other problems, like the design of recommendation systems and of diagnostic
/ prognostic medical tools, suggest that a complex network approach may yield
important benefits. In this contribution we present a first hybrid data mining
/ complex network classification algorithm, able to detect illegal instances in
a real card transaction data set. It is based on a recently proposed network
reconstruction algorithm that allows creating representations of the deviation
of one instance from a reference group. We show how the inclusion of features
extracted from the network data representation improves the score obtained by a
standard, neural network-based classification algorithm; and additionally how
this combined approach can outperform a commercial fraud detection system in
specific operation niches. Beyond these specific results, this contribution
represents a new example on how complex networks and data mining can be
integrated as complementary tools, with the former providing a view to data
beyond the capabilities of the latter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01957</id><created>2017-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Kais</keyname><forenames>Sabre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alharbi</keyname><forenames>Fahhad H</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic Energy Density Functionals by Axiomatic Approach</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Quantum Chemistry, Vol. 117, #e25373,
  2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/qua.25373</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An axiomatic approach is herein used to determine the physically acceptable
forms for general $D$-dimensional kinetic energy density functionals (KEDF).
The resulted expansion captures most of the known forms of one-point KEDFs. By
statistically training the KEDF forms on a model problem of non-interacting
kinetic energy in 1D (6 terms only), the mean relative accuracy for 1000
randomly generated potentials is found to be better than the standard KEDF by
several orders of magnitudes. The accuracy improves with the number of occupied
states and was found to be better than $10^{-4}$ for a system with four
occupied states. Furthermore, we show that free fitting of the coefficients
associated with known KEDFs approaches the exactly analytic values. The
presented approach can open a new route to search for physically acceptable
kinetic energy density functionals and provide an essential step towards more
accurate large-scale orbital free density functional theory calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01974</id><created>2017-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Alharbi</keyname><forenames>Fahhad H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashkeev</keyname><forenames>Sergey N</forenames></author><author><keyname>El-Mellouhi</keyname><forenames>Fedwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;thi</keyname><forenames>Hans P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tabet</keyname><forenames>Nouar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kais</keyname><forenames>Sabre</forenames></author></authors><title>An Efficient Descriptor Model for Designing Materials for Solar Cells</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>NPJ Computational Materials, Vol. 1, #15003, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/npjcompumats.2015.3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An efficient descriptor model for fast screening of potential materials for
solar cell applications is presented. It works for both excitonic and
non-excitonic solar cells materials, and in addition to the energy gap it
includes the absorption spectrum ($\alpha(E)$) of the material. The charge
transport properties of the explored materials are modeled using the
characteristic diffusion length ($L_{d}$) determined for the respective family
of compounds. The presented model surpasses the widely used Scharber model
developed for bulk-heterojunction solar cells [Scharber \textit{et al.,
Advanced Materials}, 2006, Vol. 18, 789]. Using published experimental data, we
show that the presented model is more accurate in predicting the achievable
efficiencies. Although the focus of this work is on organic photovoltaics
(OPV), for which the original Scharber model was developed, the model presented
here is applicable also to other solar cell technologies. To model both
excitonic and non-excitonic systems, two different sets of parameters are used
to account for the different modes of operation. The analysis of the presented
descriptor model clearly shows the benefit of including $\alpha(E)$ and $L_{d}$
in view of improved screening results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01976</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Xiaomei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Zhanghua</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavity enhanced terahertz fingerprint detection with ultrahigh
  sensitivity</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new scheme of realizing terahertz fingerprint detection with
ultrahigh sensitivity. Instead of using the direct absorption of terahertz
through a bare sample in the regular transmission scheme, a cavity mode
resonating at the characteristic frequency of the sample is used and due to the
high dependence of the cavity mode transmission on the material loss, an
amplified transmission decaying is observed when the sample is loaded into the
cavity. Furthermore, this scheme retains the feature of substance
identification. A one-dimensional photonic crystal cavity is used as the
example for the detection of {\alpha}-lactose and an efficient detection of 7nm
{\alpha}-lactose can be achieved, which corresponds to 1/80000 of the free
space wavelength at the characteristic frequency of 0.529THz, exhibiting
sensitivity 500 times higher than the regular method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01984</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Bryan W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sung</keyname><forenames>Chih-Jen</forenames></author></authors><title>UConnRCMPy: Python-based data analysis for rapid compression machines</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, presented at the 10th US National Combustion
  Meeting</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The ignition delay of a fuel/air mixture is an important quantity in
designing combustion devices, and these data are also used to validate chemical
kinetic models for combustion. One of the typical experimental devices used to
measure the ignition delay is called a Rapid Compression Machine (RCM). This
paper presents UConnRCMPy, an open-source Python package to process
experimental data from the RCM at the University of Connecticut. Given an
experimental measurement, UConnRCMPy computes the thermodynamic conditions in
the reaction chamber of the RCM during an experiment along with the ignition
delay. UConnRCMPy implements an extensible framework, so that alternative
experimental data formats can be incorporated easily. In this way, UConnRCMPy
improves the consistency of RCM data processing and enables the community to
reproduce data analysis procedures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01995</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Leo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Soonwon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukin</keyname><forenames>Mikhail D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry-protected dissipative preparation of matrix product states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and analyze a method for efficient dissipative preparation of
matrix product states that exploits their symmetry properties. Specifically, we
construct an explicit protocol that makes use of driven-dissipative dynamics to
prepare the Affleck-Kennedy-Lieb-Tasaki (AKLT) states, which features
symmetry-protected topological order and non-trivial edge excitations. We show
that the use of symmetry allows for robust experimental implementation without
fine-tuned control parameters. Numerical simulations show that the preparation
time scales polynomially in system size $n$. Furthermore, we demonstrate that
this scaling can be improved to $\mathcal{O}(\log^2n)$ by using parallel
preparation of AKLT segments and fusing them via quantum feedback. A concrete
scheme using excitation of trapped neutral atoms into Rydberg state via
Electromagnetically Induced Transparency is proposed, and generalizations to a
broader class of matrix product states are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02008</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Chao</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichardt</keyname><forenames>Ben W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Test to separate quantum theory from non-signaling theories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Bell test separates quantum mechanics from a classical, local realist
theory of physics. However, a Bell test cannot separate quantum physics from
all classical theories. Classical devices supplemented with non-signaling
correlations, e.g., the Popescu-Rohrlich &quot;nonlocal box,&quot; can pass a Bell test
with probability at least as high as any quantum devices can. After all,
quantum entanglement does not allow for signaling faster than the speed of
light, so in a sense is a weaker special case of non-signaling correlations. It
could be that underneath quantum mechanics is a deeper non-signaling theory.
  We present a test to separate quantum theory from powerful non-signaling
theories. The test extends the CHSH game to involve three space-like separated
devices. Quantum devices sharing a three-qubit GHZ state can pass the test with
probability 5.1% higher than classical devices sharing arbitrary non-signaling
correlations between pairs.
  More generally, we give a test that k space-like separated quantum devices
can pass with higher probability than classical devices sharing arbitrary
(k-1)-local non-signaling correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02011</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Z. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>W. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Design of a Peanut Hohlraum with Low Gas-Fill Density for the Laser
  Megajoule</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments on the National Ignition Facility [D.E. Hinkel et al.,
Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 225002 (2016)] demonstrates that utilizing a long, large
case-to-capsule ratio (=3) conventional cylindrical hohlraum at moderate
gas-fill density (=0.6 mg/cm3 4He) improves the drive symmetry controaums has a
little chance to achieve ignition at an acceptable energy level due to its
small margin for the laser cone propagation. In this letter, a noncylindrical
hohlraum, called as peanut hohlraum, using a larger case-to-capsule (=3.46) at
lower gas-fill density (=0.3 mg/cm3 4He) is proposed to ignite a high-foot
pusher capsule with a shorter pulse (~9ns). The peanut hohlraum requires about
2.5 MJ laser energy to achieve 306 eV peak drive temperature while the low-z
plasma electron density on the inner cone path is maintained very low which
results in little simulated Raman backscattering and the high-z bubble still
stays away from the inner cone path without the laser absorption in it, which
favor the drive symmetry control. Crossed-beam energy transfer is also
neglectable because the crossing position is far away from the LEH. The peanut
hohlraum can provide a good drive environment for capsule to achieve ignition,
so it is undoubted that it will add to the diversity of ICF approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02024</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Xiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Yi-Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Van der Waals phase transition for a hairy black hole</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted by Advances in High Energy Physics(The special issue:
  Applications of the Holographic Duality to Strongly Coupled Quantum Systems)</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Van der Waals(VdW) phase transition in a hairy black hole is investigated
by analogizing its charge, temperature, and entropy as the temperature,
pressure, and volume in the fluid respectively. The two point correlation
function(TCF), which is dual to the geodesic length, is employed to probe this
phase transition. We find the phase structure in the temperature$-$geodesic
length plane resembles as that in the temperature$-$thermal entropy plane
besides the scale of the horizontal coordinate. In addition, we find the equal
area law(EAL) for the first order phase transition and critical exponent of the
heat capacity for the second order phase transition in the
temperature$-$geodesic length plane are consistent with that in
temperature$-$thermal entropy plane, which implies that the TCF is a good probe
to probe the phase structure of the back hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02035</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Bi</keyname><forenames>Jichao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lu-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xiaofan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yingbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yuan Yan</forenames></author></authors><title>The damage inflicted by a computer virus: A new estimation method</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper addressed the issue of estimating the damage caused by a computer
virus. First, an individual-level delayed SIR model capturing the spreading
process of a digital virus is derived. Second, the damage inflicted by the
virus is modeled as the sum of the economic losses and the cost for developing
the antivirus. Next, the impact of different factors, including the delay and
the network structure, on the damage is explored by means of computer
simulations. Thereby some measures of reducing the damage of a virus are
recommended. To our knowledge, this is the first time the antivirus-developing
cost is taken into account when estimating the damage of a virus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02037</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>Kailash C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Jay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casertano</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bond</keyname><forenames>Howard E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergeron</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelan</keyname><forenames>Edmund P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pueyo</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levay</keyname><forenames>Zoltan G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokol</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominik</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calamida</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kains</keyname><forenames>No&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Livio</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic deflection of background starlight measures the mass of a
  nearby white dwarf star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Main Article (15 pages, 5 Figures), plus Supplementary Material (19
  pages, 10 figures)</comments><doi>10.1126/science.aal2879</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitational deflection of starlight around the Sun during the 1919 total
solar eclipse provided measurements that confirmed Einstein's general theory of
relativity. We have used the Hubble Space Telescope to measure the analogous
process of astrometric microlensing caused by a nearby star, the white dwarf
Stein 2051 B. As Stein 2051 B passed closely in front of a background star, the
background star's position was deflected. Measurement of this deflection at
multiple epochs allowed us to determine the mass of Stein 2051 B -- the sixth
nearest white dwarf to the Sun -- as 0.675 +/- 0.051 solar masses. This mass
determination provides confirmation of the physics of degenerate matter and
lends support to white dwarf evolutionary theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02043</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niemeyer</keyname><forenames>Kyle E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brady</keyname><forenames>Kyle B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sung</keyname><forenames>Chih-Jen</forenames></author></authors><title>Reduced chemistry for butanol isomers at engine-relevant conditions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, 16 figures. Supporting information available via
  https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.6b01857</comments><msc-class>80A30 (Primary), 80A25 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Energy Fuels 31 (2017) 867-881</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.energyfuels.6b01857</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Butanol has received significant research attention as a second-generation
biofuel in the past few years. In the present study, skeletal mechanisms for
four butanol isomers were generated from two widely accepted, well-validated
detailed chemical kinetic models for the butanol isomers. The detailed models
were reduced using a two-stage approach consisting of the directed relation
graph with error propagation and sensitivity analysis. During the reduction
process, issues were encountered with pressure-dependent reactions formulated
using the logarithmic pressure interpolation approach; these issues are
discussed and recommendations made to avoid ambiguity in its future
implementation in mechanism development. The performance of the skeletal
mechanisms generated here was compared with that of detailed mechanisms in
simulations of autoignition delay times, laminar flame speeds, and perfectly
stirred reactor temperature response curves and extinction residence times,
over a wide range of pressures, temperatures, and equivalence ratios. The
detailed and skeletal mechanisms agreed well, demonstrating the adequacy of the
resulting reduced chemistry for all the butanol isomers in predicting global
combustion phenomena. In addition, the skeletal mechanisms closely predicted
the time-histories of fuel mass fractions in homogeneous compression-ignition
engine simulations. The performance of each butanol isomer was additionally
compared with that of a gasoline surrogate with an antiknock index of 87 in a
homogeneous compression-ignition engine simulation. The gasoline surrogate was
consumed faster than any of the butanol isomers, with tert-butanol exhibiting
the slowest fuel consumption rate. While n-butanol and isobutanol displayed the
most similar consumption profiles relative to the gasoline surrogate, the two
literature chemical kinetic models predicted different orderings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02044</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tracy</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laroche</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>S. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chuang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Y. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density-controlled quantum Hall ferromagnetic transition in a
  two-dimensional hole system</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 2468 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-02757-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum Hall ferromagnetic transitions are typically achieved by increasing
the Zeeman energy through in-situ sample rotation, while transitions in systems
with pseudo-spin indices can be induced by gate control. We report here a
gate-controlled quantum Hall ferromagnetic transition between two real spin
states in a conventional two-dimensional system without any in-plane magnetic
field. We show that the ratio of the Zeeman splitting to the cyclotron gap in a
Ge two-dimensional hole system increases with decreasing density owing to
inter-carrier interactions. Below a critical density of $\sim2.4\times 10^{10}$
cm$^{-2}$, this ratio grows greater than $1$, resulting in a ferromagnetic
ground state at filling factor $\nu=2$. At the critical density, a resistance
peak due to the formation of microscopic domains of opposite spin orientations
is observed. Such gate-controlled spin-polarizations in the quantum Hall regime
opens the door to realizing Majorana modes using two-dimensional systems in
conventional, low-spin-orbit-coupling semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02056</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsaplin</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzkin</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>An asymptotic formula for displacement field in triangular lattice with
  vacancy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall physics.class-ph</categories><comments>7 pages; 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A harmonic triangular lattice with a vacancy under imposed volumetric strain
is considered. Simple asymptotic formula for the displacement field is derived.
The formula has reasonable accuracy at all lattice nodes. Strain concentration
factor, defined as the ratio of the maximal deformation of the bonds adjacent
to the vacancy to the deformations of bonds at infinity, is calculated. It is
shown that the asymptotic formula predicts the strain concentration factor with
4% accuracy. The results are compared with predictions of continuum elasticity
theory. Effective diameter of the vacancy is calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02058</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Mamun</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>New self-gravito-acoustic mode in degenerate quantum plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to `Nature Physics'</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of a new perturbation mode [`self-gravito-acoustic mode'
(SGAM)] in cold self-gravitating degenerate quantum plasmas (SGDQPs) is
theoretically predicted. This new SGAM is developed in the perturbed SGDQPs, in
which the compression is mainly provided by the self-gravitational pressure of
the heavy particle species, and the rarefaction is mainly provided by the
degenerate pressure of the light particle species. The SGAM is a new
perturbation mode since it completely disappears if the degenerate pressure of
the light particle species is neglected. The prediction of this new SGAM is
applied in a white dwarf SGDQP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02067</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Araujo</keyname><forenames>N. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zezyulin</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konotop</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Gama</keyname><forenames>M. M. Telo</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical design of spatial patterns of colloidal suspensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.PS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the collective dynamics of colloidal suspensions in the presence of
a time-dependent potential, by means of dynamical density functional theory. We
consider a non-linear diffusion equation for the density and show that spatial
patterns emerge from a sinusoidal external potential with a time-dependent
wavelength. These patterns are characterized by a sinusoidal density with the
average wavelength and a Bessel-function envelope with an induced wavelength
that depends only on the amplitude of the temporal oscillations. As a
generalization of this result, we propose a design strategy to obtain a family
of spatial patterns using time-dependent potentials of practically arbitrary
shape.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02076</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Avsar</keyname><forenames>Ahmet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Jun You</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurpas</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gmitra</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabian</keyname><forenames>Jaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozyilmaz</keyname><forenames>Barbaros</forenames></author></authors><title>Gate-tunable black phosphorus spin valve with nanosecond spin lifetimes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><doi>10.1038/nphys4141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional materials offer new opportunities for both fundamental
science and technological applications, by exploiting the electron spin. While
graphene is very promising for spin communication due to its extraordinary
electron mobility, the lack of a band gap restricts its prospects for
semiconducting spin devices such as spin diodes and bipolar spin transistors.
The recent emergence of 2D semiconductors could help overcome this basic
challenge. In this letter we report the first important step towards making 2D
semiconductor spin devices. We have fabricated a spin valve based on ultra-thin
(5 nm) semiconducting black phosphorus (bP), and established fundamental spin
properties of this spin channel material which supports all electrical spin
injection, transport, precession and detection up to room temperature (RT).
Inserting a few layers of boron nitride between the ferromagnetic electrodes
and bP alleviates the notorious conductivity mismatch problem and allows
efficient electrical spin injection into an n-type bP. In the non-local spin
valve geometry we measure Hanle spin precession and observe spin relaxation
times as high as 4 ns, with spin relaxation lengths exceeding 6 um. Our
experimental results are in a very good agreement with first-principles
calculations and demonstrate that Elliott-Yafet spin relaxation mechanism is
dominant. We also demonstrate that spin transport in ultra-thin bP depends
strongly on the charge carrier concentration, and can be manipulated by the
electric field effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02079</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Iba&#xf1;ez-Azpiroz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>M. dos Santos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;gel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lounis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero-point spin-fluctuations of single adatoms</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 16 4305 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b01344</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stabilizing the magnetic signal of single adatoms is a crucial step towards
their successful usage in widespread technological applications such as
high-density magnetic data storage devices. The quantum mechanical nature of
these tiny objects, however, introduces intrinsic zero-point spin-fluctuations
that tend to destabilize the local magnetic moment of interest by dwindling the
magnetic anisotropy potential barrier even at absolute zero temperature. Here,
we elucidate the origins and quantify the effect of the fundamental ingredients
determining the magnitude of the fluctuations, namely the ($i$) local magnetic
moment, ($ii$) spin-orbit coupling and ($iii$) electron-hole Stoner
excitations. Based on a systematic first-principles study of 3d and 4d adatoms,
we demonstrate that the transverse contribution of the fluctuations is
comparable in size to the magnetic moment itself, leading to a remarkable
$\gtrsim$50$\%$ reduction of the magnetic anisotropy energy. Our analysis gives
rise to a comprehensible diagram relating the fluctuation magnitude to
characteristic features of adatoms, providing practical guidelines for
designing magnetically stable nanomagnets with minimal quantum fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02083</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Saxena</keyname><forenames>Akrati</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gera</keyname><forenames>Ralucca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iyengar</keyname><forenames>S. R. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Faster Method to Estimate Closeness Centrality Ranking</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Closeness centrality is one way of measuring how central a node is in the
given network. The closeness centrality measure assigns a centrality value to
each node based on its accessibility to the whole network. In real life
applications, we are mainly interested in ranking nodes based on their
centrality values. The classical method to compute the rank of a node first
computes the closeness centrality of all nodes and then compares them to get
its rank. Its time complexity is $O(n \cdot m + n)$, where $n$ represents total
number of nodes, and $m$ represents total number of edges in the network. In
the present work, we propose a heuristic method to fast estimate the closeness
rank of a node in $O(\alpha \cdot m)$ time complexity, where $\alpha = 3$. We
also propose an extended improved method using uniform sampling technique. This
method better estimates the rank and it has the time complexity $O(\alpha \cdot
m)$, where $\alpha \approx 10-100$. This is an excellent improvement over the
classical centrality ranking method. The efficiency of the proposed methods is
verified on real world scale-free social networks using absolute and weighted
error functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02091</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsirvoulis</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morbidelli</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delbo</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsiganis</keyname><forenames>Kleomenis</forenames></author></authors><title>Reconstructing the size distribution of the primordial Main Belt</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2017.05.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we aim to constrain the slope of the size distribution of
main-belt asteroids, at their primordial state. To do so we turn out attention
to the part of the main asteroid belt between 2.82 and 2.96~AU, the so-called
&quot;pristine zone&quot;, which has a low number density of asteroids and few, well
separated asteroid families. Exploiting these unique characteristics, and using
a modified version of the hierarchical clustering method we are able to remove
the majority of asteroid family members from the region. The remaining,
background asteroids should be of primordial origin, as the strong 5/2 and 7/3
mean-motion resonances with Jupiter inhibit transfer of asteroids to and from
the neighboring regions. The size-frequency distribution of asteroids in the
size range $17&lt;D(\rm{km})&lt;70$ has a slope $q\simeq-1$. Using Monte-Carlo
methods, we are able to simulate, and compensate for the collisional and
dynamical evolution of the asteroid population, and get an upper bound for its
size distribution slope $q=-1.43$. In addition, applying the same 'family
extraction' method to the neighboring regions, i.e. the middle and outer belts,
and comparing the size distributions of the respective background populations,
we find statistical evidence that no large asteroid families of primordial
origin had formed in the middle or pristine zones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02096</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Payez</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoenmaekers</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>Parameter-space study of kinetic-impactor mission design</title><categories>astro-ph.EP math.OC physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Contributed to the proceedings of the 5th Planetary Defense
  Conference (PDC 2017), Tokyo, May 15th-19th 2017. 10 pages</comments><report-no>IAA-PDC-17-05-18</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While almost all potentially hazardous asteroids (PHAs) with a size larger
than one kilometre have been discovered, it is well-known that the vast
majority of the smaller ones are in fact yet to be found. There is therefore an
excellent motivation to consider at once all possible Earth-crossing orbits,
and to undertake a systematic study of mitigation missions for the entire
parameter space of orbital elements. It is shown that the whole parameter space
can be reduced, without loss of generality, to only three relevant
dimensionless parameters: the eccentricity and inclination of the asteroid
orbit, and the asteroid true anomaly at impact. Ballistic kinetic-impactor
mitigation missions are studied for the entire parameter space, considering
critical feasibility constraints such as the launcher performance and the
illumination conditions at deflection. Different classes of optimal solutions
are found to exist and can be directly linked to asteroid orbital properties.
The aim of this work is to help identify an appropriate response to the
potential threat of a collision of a near-Earth object with our planet, to
provide a preliminary mission design, and to determine in which parts of
parameter space difficulties may arise. (abridged)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02098</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ionov</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shematovich</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlyuchenkov</keyname><forenames>Ya. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Photoelectrons on the Structure and Dynamics of the Upper
  Atmosphere of a Hot Jupiter</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Astronomy Reports, 6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1134/S1063772917050018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A self-consistent, aeronomic model of the upper atmosphere of a &quot;hot Jupiter&quot;
including reactions involving suprathermal photoelectrons is presented. This
model is used to compute the height profiles of the gas density, velocity, and
temperature in the atmosphere of the exoplanet HD 209458b. It is shown that
including suprathermal electrons when computing the heating and cooling
functions reduces the mass loss rate of the atmosphere by a factor of five.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02103</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gefen</keyname><forenames>Tuvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xfc;rner</keyname><forenames>Felix M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unden</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheuer</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naydenov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markham</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pezzagna</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meijer</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>Ilai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plenio</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retzker</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuinness</keyname><forenames>Liam P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jelezko</keyname><forenames>Fedor</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-millihertz magnetic spectroscopy with a nanoscale quantum sensor</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Related work: Boss et. al., 10.1126/science.aam7009; Bucher et. al.,
  arXiv:1705.08887. Supplementary Information available at:
  www.sciencemag.org/content/356/6340/832/suppl/DC1</comments><journal-ref>Science 356, 6340 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aam5532</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Precise timekeeping is critical to metrology, forming the basis by which
standards of time, length and fundamental constants are determined. Stable
clocks are particularly valuable in spectroscopy as they define the ultimate
frequency precision that can be reached. In quantum metrology, where the phase
of a qubit is used to detect external fields, the clock stability is defined by
the qubit coherence time, which determines the spectral linewidth and frequency
precision. Here we demonstrate a quantum sensing protocol where the spectral
precision goes beyond the sensor coherence time and is limited by the stability
of a classical clock. Using this technique, we observe a precision in frequency
estimation scaling in time $T$, as $T^{-3/2}$ for classical oscillating fields.
The narrow linewidth magnetometer based on single spins in diamond is used to
sense nanoscale magnetic fields with an intrinsic frequency resolution of 607
$\mu$Hz, 8 orders of magnitude narrower than the qubit coherence time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02105</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Mauro</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>L'eliosismologia: onde sismiche per studiare l'interno del Sole</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>in Italian</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the last 50 years we have been witness of an extraordinary revolution
in the knowledge and understanding of our star thanks to the development of
Helioseismology, the study of solar oscillations. Similar to what happens on
the Earth during earthquakes, the interior of the Sun is continuously pervaded
by seismic waves which produce small oscillations on the photosphere. These
oscillations bring the signature of several processes which happen in the
interior of the solar structure and the seismic frequencies of the oscillation
modes detected on the solar surface are directly related to physical parameters
of the internal layers crossed by the seismic waves. The study of oscillations
represents, then, the only method to infer directly the internal structure and
dynamics of the Sun. This article will present the general characteristics of
solar oscillations, the main important results and the advances obtained in
stellar physics thanks to the methods of Helioseismology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02122</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Junshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering by a periodic array of subwavelength slits I: field
  enhancement in the diffraction regime</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the first part in a series of two papers that concern with the
quantitative analysis of the electromagnetic field enhancement and anomalous
diffraction by a periodic array of subwavelength slits. The scattering problem
in the diffraction regime is investigated in this part, for which the size of
the period is comparable to the incident wavelength. We distinguish scattering
resonances and real eigenvalues, and derive their asymptotic expansions when
they are away from the Rayleigh cut-off frequencies. Furthermore, we present
quantitative analysis of the field enhancement at resonant frequencies, by
quantifying both the enhancement order and the associated resonant modes. The
field enhancement near the Rayleigh cut-off frequencies is also investigated.
It is demonstrated that the field enhancement becomes weaker at the resonant
frequency if it is close to the Rayleigh cut-off frequencies. Finally, we also
characterize the embedded eigenvalues for the underlying periodic structure,
and point out that transmission anomaly such as Fano resonant phenomenon does
not occur for the narrow slit array.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02126</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Junshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering by a periodic array of subwavelength slits II: surface bound
  state, total transmission and field enhancement in homogenization regimes</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second part in a series of two papers that concern with the
quantitative analysis of the electromagnetic field enhancement and anomalous
diffraction by a periodic array of subwavelength slits. In this part, we
explore the scattering problem in the homogenization regimes, where the size of
the period is much smaller than the incident wavelength. In particular, two
homogenization regimes are investigated, where the size of the pattered slits
has the same order as the size of the period in the first configuration, and
the size of the slit is much smaller than the size of the period in the second
configuration. By presenting rigorous asymptotic analysis, we demonstrate that
surface plasmonic effect mimicking that of plasmonic metals occurs in the first
homogenization regime. The corresponding dispersion curve lies below the light
line and the associated eigenmodes are surface bound sates. In addition, for
the incident plane wave, we discover and justify a novel phenomenon of total
transmission which occurs either at certain frequencies for all incident
angles, or at a special incident angle but for all frequencies. For the second
homogenization regime, the non-resonant field enhancement is investigated, and
it is shown that the fast transition of the magnetic field in the slit induces
strong electric field enhancement. Moreover, the enhancement becomes stronger
when the coupling of the slits is weaker.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02134</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Calero</keyname><forenames>Gabriel G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abru&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>H&#xe9;ctor D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiesner</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Block Copolymer Derived Multifunctional Gyroidal Monoliths for 3-D
  Electrical Energy Storage Applications</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>30 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multifunctional three-dimensional (3-D) nano-architectures, integrating all
device components within tens of nanometers, offer great promise for next
generation electrical energy storage applications, but have remained
challenging to achieve. The lack of appropriate synthesis methods, enabling
precise 3-D spatial control at the nanoscale, remains a key issue holding back
the development of such intricate architectures. Here we present an approach to
such systems based on the bottom-up synthesis of penta-continuous nanohybrid
monoliths with four functional components integrated in a triblock terpolymer
derived core-shell double gyroid architecture. Two distinct 3 D
interpenetrating networks serving as cathode and current collector are
separated from a carbon anode matrix by continuous, ultrathin polymer
electrolyte shells. All periodically ordered domains are less than 20 nm in
their layer dimensions and integrated throughout the macroscopic monolith.
Initial electrochemical measurements with the Li-ion/S system exhibit
reversible battery-like charge-discharge characteristics with orders of
magnitude decreases in footprint area over conventional flat thin layer
designs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02145</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Egel</keyname><forenames>Amos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pattelli</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzamuto</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiersma</keyname><forenames>Diederik S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemmer</keyname><forenames>Uli</forenames></author></authors><title>CELES: CUDA-accelerated simulation of electromagnetic scattering by
  large ensembles of spheres</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Quantitative Spectroscopy and Radiative Transfer,
  Volume 199, September 2017, Pages 103-110, ISSN 0022-4073</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jqsrt.2017.05.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CELES is a freely available MATLAB toolbox to simulate light scattering by
many spherical particles. Aiming at high computational performance, CELES
leverages block-diagonal preconditioning, a lookup-table approach to evaluate
costly functions and massively parallel execution on NVIDIA graphics processing
units using the CUDA computing platform. The combination of these techniques
allows to efficiently address large electrodynamic problems ($&gt;10^4$
scatterers) on inexpensive consumer hardware. In this paper, we validate near-
and far-field distributions against the well-established multi-sphere
$T$-matrix (MSTM) code and discuss the convergence behavior for ensembles of
different sizes, including an exemplary system comprising $10^5$ particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02153</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Henneken</keyname><forenames>Edwin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurtz</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Usage Bibliometrics as a Tool to Measure Research Activity</title><categories>cs.DL astro-ph.IM cs.CY cs.IR physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in Handbook of
  Quantitative Science and Technology Research, Springer</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measures for research activity and impact have become an integral ingredient
in the assessment of a wide range of entities (individual researchers,
organizations, instruments, regions, disciplines). Traditional bibliometric
indicators, like publication and citation based indicators, provide an
essential part of this picture, but cannot describe the complete picture. Since
reading scholarly publications is an essential part of the research life cycle,
it is only natural to introduce measures for this activity in attempts to
quantify the efficiency, productivity and impact of an entity. Citations and
reads are significantly different signals, so taken together, they provide a
more complete picture of research activity. Most scholarly publications are now
accessed online, making the study of reads and their patterns possible.
Click-stream logs allow us to follow information access by the entire research
community, real-time. Publication and citation datasets just reflect activity
by authors. In addition, download statistics will help us identify publications
with significant impact, but which do not attract many citations. Click-stream
signals are arguably more complex than, say, citation signals. For one, they
are a superposition of different classes of readers. Systematic downloads by
crawlers also contaminate the signal, as does browsing behavior. We discuss the
complexities associated with clickstream data and how, with proper filtering,
statistically significant relations and conclusions can be inferred from
download statistics. We describe how download statistics can be used to
describe research activity at different levels of aggregation, ranging from
organizations to countries. These statistics show a correlation with
socio-economic indicators. A comparison will be made with traditional
bibliometric indicators. We will argue that astronomy is representative of more
general trends.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02154</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Lyapilin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okorokov</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Seebeck effect and magnon-magnon drag in Pt/YIG/Pt structures</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1506.06037 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation of the two: injected (&quot;coherent&quot;) and &quot;thermally&quot; excited,
different in energies magnon subsystems and the influence of its interaction
with phonons and between on drag effect under spin Seebeck effect conditions in
the magnetic insulator part of the metal/ferromagnetic insulator/metal
structure is studied. An approximation of the effective parameters, when each
of the interacting subsystems (&quot;injected&quot;, &quot;thermal&quot; magnons, and phonons) is
characterized by its own effective temperature and drift velocities have been
considered. The analysis of the macroscopic momentum balance equations of the
systems of interest conducted for different ratios of the drift velocities of
the magnon and phonon currents show that the &quot;injected&quot; magnons relaxation on
the &quot;thermal&quot; ones is possible to be dominant over its relaxation on phonons.
This interaction will be the defining in the forming of the temperature
dependence of the spin-wave current under spin Seebeck effect conditions, and
inelastic part of the magnon-magnon interaction is the dominant spin relaxation
mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02166</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Sj&#xf6;strand</keyname><forenames>Torbj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author></authors><title>The Development of MPI Modelling in PYTHIA</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>To be published in &quot;Multiple Parton Interactions at the LHC&quot;, P.
  Bartalini and J. R. Gaunt, eds., World Scientific; 42 pages, 5 figures</comments><report-no>LU TP 17-22, MCnet-17-10</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many of the basic ideas in multiparton interaction (MPI) phenomenology were
first developed in the context of the PYTHIA event generator, and MPIs have
been central in its modelling of both minimum-bias and underlying-event physics
in one unified framework. This chapter traces the evolution towards an
increasingly sophisticated description of MPIs in PYTHIA, including topics such
as the ordering of MPIs, the regularization of the divergent QCD cross section,
the impact-parameter picture, colour reconnection, multiparton PDFs and beam
remnants, interleaved and intertwined evolution, and diffraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02169</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Ngoc Thanh Thuy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Duy Khanh</forenames></author><author><keyname>E.</keyname><forenames>Glukhova O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Ming-Fa</forenames></author></authors><title>Diversified essential properties in halogenated graphenes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1702.02031</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The significant halogenation effects on the essential properties of graphene
are investigated by the first-principles method. The geometric structures,
electronic properties, and magnetic configurations are greatly diversified
under the various halogen adsorptions. Fluorination, with the strong
multi-orbital chemical bondings, can create the buckled graphene structure,
while the other halogenations do not change the planar {\sigma} bonding in the
presence of single-orbital hybridization. Electronic structures consist of the
carbon-, adatom- and (carbon, adatom)-dominated energy bands. All halogenated
graphenes belong to hole-doped metals except that fluorinated systems are
middle-gap semiconductors at sufficiently high concentration. Moreover, the
metallic ferromagnetism is revealed in certain adatom distributions. The
unusual hybridization-induced features are clearly evidenced in many van Hove
singularities of the density of states. The structure- and adatom-enriched
essential properties are compared with the measured results, and potential
applications are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02184</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Smirnova</keyname><forenames>Daria</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-ballisticity of self-repelling polymers in Z^d</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we prove sub-ballisticity for a class of self-repelling
polymers inZ^d. Self-repelling polymers are a two-way generalization of the
model of self-avoiding walks, for which the sub-ballisticity was proved by H.
Duminil-Copin and A. Hammond. Namely, we consider an arbitrary finite symmetric
distribution of steps and a more flexible penalization for self-intersections
than in the self-avoiding walks model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02195</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yongjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Li Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lingyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimize Nonlinear Beam Dynamical System with Square Matrix Method</title><categories>nlin.CD physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear dynamics has an important role when designing modern synchrotron
lattices. In this letter, we introduce a new method of using a square matrix to
analyze periodic nonlinear dynamical systems [1, 2]. Applying the method to the
National Synchrotron Light Source II storage ring lattice has helped to
mitigate the chaotic motion within its dynamic aperture. For a given dynamical
system, the vector space of a square matrix can be separated into different low
dimension invariant subspaces according to their eigenvalues. When Jordan
decomposition is applied to one of the eigenspaces, it yields a set of accurate
action-angle variables. The distortion of the new action-angle variables
provides a measure of the nonlinearity. Our studies show that the common
convention of confining the tune-shift with amplitude to avoid the crossing of
resonance lines may not be absolutely necessary. We demonstrate that the third
order resonance can be almost perfectly compensated with this technique. The
method itself is general, and could be applied to other nonlinear systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02213</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Trouilhet</keyname><forenames>JF.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paletou</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Girard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>MISTIS, INRIA Grenoble</affiliation></author></authors><title>Inference of an explanatory variable from observations in a
  high-dimensional space: application to high-resolution spectra of stars</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>IEEE International Workshop of Electronics, Control, Measurement,
  Signals and their application to Mechatronics (ECMSM), May 2017, San
  Sebastian, Spain. 2017 (http://ecmsm2017.mondragon.edu/)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our aim is to evaluate fundamental parameters from the analysis of the
electromagnetic spectra of stars. We may use $10^3$-$10^5$ spectra; each
spectrum being a vector with $10^2$-$10^4$ coordinates. We thus face the
so-called &quot;curse of dimensionality&quot;. We look for a method to reduce the size of
this data-space, keeping only the most relevant information.As a reference
method, we use principal component analysis (PCA) to reduce dimensionality.
However, PCA is an unsupervised method, therefore its subspace was not
consistent with the parameter. We thus tested a supervised method based on
Sliced Inverse Regression (SIR), which provides a subspace consistent with the
parameter. It also shares analogies with factorial discriminant analysis: the
method slices the database along the parameter variation, and builds the
subspace which maximizes the inter-slice variance, while standardizing the
total projected variance of the data. Nevertheless the performances of SIR were
not satisfying in standard usage, because of the non-monotonicity of the
unknown function linking the data to the parameter and because of the noise
propagation. We show that better performances can be achieved by selecting the
most relevant directions for parameter inference. Preliminary tests are
performed on synthetic pseudo-line profiles plus noise. Using one direction, we
show that compared to PCA, the error associated with SIR is 50$\%$ smaller on a
non-linear parameter, and 70$\%$ smaler on a linear parameter. Moreover, using
a selected direction, the error is 80$\%$ smaller for a non-linear parameter,
and 95$\%$ smaller for a linear parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02218</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Jahromi</keyname><forenames>Ali K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shabahang</keyname><forenames>Soroush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondakci</keyname><forenames>H. Esat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orsilla</keyname><forenames>Seppo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melanen</keyname><forenames>Petri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abouraddy</keyname><forenames>Ayman F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transparent Perfect Mirror</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>The paper is highlighted in Nature Photonics:
  http://www.nature.com/nphoton/journal/v11/n6/full/nphoton.2017.90.html The
  supplementary data is available in:
  http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00052</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 4, 1026-1032 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mirror that reflects light fully and yet is transparent appears
paradoxical. Current so-called transparent or &quot;one-way&quot; mirrors are not
perfectly reflective and thus can be distinguished from a standard mirror.
Constructing a transparent &quot;perfect&quot; mirror has profound implications for
security, privacy, and camouflage. However, such a hypothetical device cannot
be implemented in a passive structure. We demonstrate here a transparent
perfect mirror in a non-Hermitian configuration: an active optical cavity where
a certain prelasing gain extinguishes Poynting's vector at the device entrance.
At this threshold, all vestiges of the cavity's structural resonances are
eliminated and the device presents spectrally flat unity-reflectivity, thus,
becoming indistinguishable from a perfect mirror when probed optically across
the gain bandwidth. Nevertheless, the device is rendered transparent by virtue
of persisting amplified transmission resonances. We confirm these predictions
in two photonic realizations: a compact integrated active waveguide and a
macroscopic all-optical-fiber system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02219</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Chanda</keyname><forenames>Sumanto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghose-Choudhury</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author></authors><title>Jacobi-Maupertuis metric of Lienard type equations and Jacobi Last
  Multiplier</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a construction of the Jacobi-Maupertuis (JM) principle for an
equation of the Lienard type, viz \ddot{x} + f(x)x^2 + g(x) = 0 using Jacobi's
last multiplier. The JM metric allows us to reformulate the Newtonian equation
of motion for a variable mass as a geodesic equation for a Riemannian metric.
We illustrate the procedure with examples of Painleve-Gambier XXI, the Jacobi
equation and the Henon-Heiles system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02228</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Burrello</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepori</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paganelli</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trombettoni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Abelian gauge potentials on cubic lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>To appear on: &quot;Advances in Quantum Mechanics: Contemporary Trends and
  Open Problems&quot;, G. Dell'Antonio and A. Michelangeli eds., Springer-INdAM
  series 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of the properties of quantum particles in a periodic potential
subject to a magnetic field is an active area of research both in physics and
mathematics; it has been and it is still deeply investigated. In this review we
discuss how to implement and describe tunable Abelian magnetic fields in a
system of ultracold atoms in optical lattices. After discussing two of the main
experimental schemes for the physical realization of synthetic gauge potentials
in ultracold set-ups, we study cubic lattice tight-binding models with
commensurate flux. We finally examine applications of gauge potentials in
one-dimensional rings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02251</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Somnath</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless transition in
  Boron-doped diamond films</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The occurrence of the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless (BKT) transition is
investigated in heavily boron-doped nanocrystalline diamond films through a
combination of current-voltage and resistance measurements. We observe a robust
BKT transition in the nanocrystalline diamond films with smaller grain size
along with transport features related to vortex pinning. The vortex core energy
determined through analysis of the resistance temperature curves was found to
be anti-correlated to the BKT transition temperatures. It is also observed that
the higher BKT temperature is related to an increased vortex-antivortex binding
energy derived from the activated transport regions. Further, the magnetic
field induced superconductor insulator transition shows the possibility of the
charge glass state. The consequences of granularity such as localization and
vortex pinning can lead to tuneable BKT temperatures and strongly affects the
field induced insulating state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
