<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:16:20Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-06-26" from="2017-06-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.0731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.0731</id><created>2011-12-04</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ranjan</keyname><forenames>Akhilesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandan</keyname><forenames>Hemwati</forenames></author></authors><title>Modifications to the Hadronic Regge Trajectories</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 13 figures, Published in MPLA, corrected version</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters A (MPLA); Volume: 27, Issue: 8, 1250047
  (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732312500472</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of quark mass on the Regge trajectory is analysed. Modifications
in the equations of Regge trajectories are shown for mesonic as well as
baryonic systems. For mesonic systems, the Regge trajectories get modified, but
still remain linear. Contrary to the mesonic case, the Regge trajectories for
baryonic systems indicate non-linearity. It is shown that in low mass and
angular momentum region two hadrons with different quark compositions can have
same mass and angular momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.0170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.0170</id><created>2014-03-02</created><updated>2014-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delepouve</keyname><forenames>Thibault</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurau</keyname><forenames>Razvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivasseau</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Universality and Borel Summability of Arbitrary Quartic Tensor Models</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><msc-class>60B99</msc-class><journal-ref>Annales de l'Institut Henri Poincar\'e - Probabilit\'es et
  Statistiques 2016, Vol. 52, No. 2, 821-848</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the study of \emph{melonic} quartic tensor models to models with
arbitrary quartic interactions. This extension requires a new version of the
loop vertex expansion using several species of intermediate fields and iterated
Cauchy-Schwarz inequalities. Borel summability is proven, uniformly as the
tensor size $N$ becomes large. Every cumulant is written as a sum of explicitly
calculated terms plus a remainder, suppressed in $1/N$. Together with the
existence of the large $N$ limit of the second cumulant, this proves that the
corresponding sequence of probability measures is uniformly bounded and obeys
the tensorial universality theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.7608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.7608</id><created>2014-07-28</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yajima</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eguchi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taira</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral anomaly for V-A fields in four- and six-dimensional curved space</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptu115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The chiral U(1) anomalies associated with a fermion of spin 1/2 interacting
with nonabelian vector and axial-vector fields in four- and six-dimensional
curved space are given in tensorial form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.4315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.4315</id><created>2014-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldt</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terentjev</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of the potential landscape on the single-file diffusion through
  channels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 141, 224901 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4903175</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transport of colloid particles through narrow channels is ubiquitous in cell
biology as well as becoming increasingly important for microfluidic
applications or targeted drug delivery. Membrane channels in cells are useful
models for artificial designs because of their high efficiency, selectivity and
robustness to external fluctuations. Here we model the passive channels that
let cargo simply diffuse through them, affected by a potential profile along
the way. Passive transporters achieve high levels of efficiency and specificity
from binding interactions with the cargo inside the channel. This however leads
to a paradox: why should channels which are so narrow that they are blocked by
their cargo evolve to have binding regions for their cargo if that will
effectively block them? Using Brownian dynamics simulations, we show that
different potentials, notably symmetric, increase the flux through narrow
passive channels -- and investigate how shape and depth of potentials influence
the flux. We find that there exist optimal depths for certain potential shapes
and that it is most efficient to apply a small force over an extended region of
the channel. On the other hand, having several spatially discrete binding
pockets will not alter the flux significantly. We also explore the role of
many-particle effects arising from pairwise particle interactions with their
neighbours and demonstrate that the relative changes in flux can be accounted
for by the kinetics of the absorption reaction at the end of the channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02070</id><created>2015-03-05</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prudencio</keyname><forenames>Thiago</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical and spin-optical superpositions modulated by Aharonov-Bohm
  effect</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Quantum Information, 15, 1750028 (2017)
  [17 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749917500289</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generation of Aharonov-Bohm (AB) phase has achieved a state-of-the-art in
mesoscopic systems with manipulation and control of the AB effect. The
possibility of transfer information enconded in such systems to non-classical
states of light increases the possible scenarios where the information can be
manipulated and transfered. In this paper we propose a quantum transfer of the
AB phase generated in a spintronic device, a topological spin transistor (TST),
to an quantum optical device, a coherent state superposition in high-Q cavity
and discuss optical and spin-optical superpositions in the presence of an AB
phase. We demonstrate that the AB phase generated in the TST can be transfered
to the coherent state superposition, considering the interaction with the spin
state and the quantum optical manipulation of the coherent state superposition.
We show that these cases provide examples of two-qubit states modulated by AB
effect and that the phase parameter can be used to control the degree of
rotation of the qubit state. We also show under a measurement on the spin
basis, an optical one-qubit state that can be modulated by the AB effect. In
these cases, we consider a dispesive interaction between a coherent state and a
spin state with an acquired AB phase and also discuss a dissipative case where
a given Lindblad equation is achieved and solved. Keywords: Quantum transfer;
Aharonov-Bohm phase; Spintronics; Quantum Optical Devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04191</id><created>2015-04-16</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fabbri</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple assessment on the hierarchy problem</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><journal-ref>Int.J.Geom.Meth.Mod.Phys.: 13, 1650068 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887816500687</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the simplest extension of the standard model, where torsion
couples to spinor as well as to scalar fields, and in which the cosmological
constant problem is solved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07791</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2015-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kholodenko</keyname><forenames>Arkady L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Black magic session of concordance: Regge mass spectrum from Casson's
  invariant</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>46 pages, 18 figures; some references are updated and may typos had
  been corrected</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A 30 (2015) 1550189</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X15501894</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, there had been a great deal of interest in obtaining and describing
of all kinds of knots in links in hydrodynamics, electrodynamics, non Abelian
gauge field theories and gravity. Although knots and links are observables of
the Chern-Simons (C-S) functional, the dynamical conditions for their
generation lie outside of the scope of the C-S theory. The nontriviality of
dynamical generation of knotted structures is caused by the fact that the
complements of all knots/links, say, in S^3 are 3-manifolds which have
positive, negative or zero curvature. The ability to curve the ambient space
thus far is attributed to masses. The mass theorem of general relativity
requires the ambient 3-manifolds to be of non negative curvature. Recently, we
established that, in the absence of boundaries, complements of dynamically
generated knots/links are represented by 3-manifolds of non negative curvature.
This fact opens the possibility to discuss masses in terms of dynamically
generated knotted/ linked structures. The key tool is the notion of knot/link
concordance. The concept of concordance is an adaptation of the concept of
cobordism to knots and links. The logic of implementation of the concordance
concept to physical masses results in new interpretation of Casson's surgery
formula in terms of the Regge trajectories. The latest thoroughly examined
Chew-Frautschi (C-F) plots associated with these trajectories demonstrate that
the hadron mass spectrum for both mesons and baryons is nicely described by the
data on the corresponding C-F plots. The physics behind Casson's surgery
formula is similar but not identical to that described purely
phenomenologically by Keith Moffatt in 1990. The developed topological
treatment is fully consistent with available rigorous mathematical and
experimentally observed results related to physics of hadrons
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05902</id><created>2015-09-19</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sra</keyname><forenames>Suvrit</forenames></author></authors><title>Logarithmic inequalities under an elementary symmetric polynomial
  dominance order</title><categories>math.CA quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages; updated typesetting, some minor bugfixes</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a dominance order on positive vectors induced by the elementary
symmetric polynomials. Under this dominance order we provide conditions that
yield simple proofs of several monotonicity questions. Notably, our approach
yields a quick (4 line) proof of the so-called
\emph{&quot;sum-of-squared-logarithms&quot;} inequality conjectured in (P.~Neff,
B.~Eidel, F.~Osterbrink, and R.~Martin, \emph{Applied Math. \&amp; Mechanics.,
2013}; P.~Neff, Y.~Nakatsukasa, and A.~Fischle; \emph{SIMAX, 35, 2014}). This
inequality has been the subject of several recent articles, and only recently
it received a full proof, albeit via a more elaborate complex-analytic
approach. We provide an elementary proof, which moreover extends to yield
simple proofs of both old and new inequalities for R\'enyi entropy, subentropy,
and quantum R\'enyi entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02831</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-08-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grover</keyname><forenames>Piyush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boufounos</keyname><forenames>Petros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benosman</keyname><forenames>Mouhacine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nabi</keyname><forenames>Saleh</forenames></author></authors><title>Sparse sensing and DMD based identification of flow regimes and
  bifurcations in complex flows</title><categories>math.DS physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Expanded discussion. Fixed some typos and figures</comments><msc-class>37L65, 37M05, 37N10</msc-class><journal-ref>SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems 16(2) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/15M104565X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a sparse sensing framework based on Dynamic Mode Decomposition
(DMD) to identify flow regimes and bifurcations in large-scale thermo-fluid
systems. Motivated by real-time sensing and control of thermal-fluid flows in
buildings and equipment, we apply this method to a Direct Numerical Simulation
(DNS) data set of a 2D laterally heated cavity. The resulting flow solutions
can be divided into several regimes, ranging from steady to chaotic flow. The
DMD modes and eigenvalues capture the main temporal and spatial scales in the
dynamics belonging to different regimes. Our proposed classification method is
data-driven, robust w.r.t measurement noise, and exploits the dynamics
extracted from the DMD method. Namely, we construct an augmented DMD basis,
with &quot;built-in&quot; dynamics, given by the DMD eigenvalues. This allows us to
employ a short time-series of data from sensors, to more robustly classify flow
regimes, particularly in the presence of measurement noise. We also exploit the
incoherence exhibited among the data generated by different regimes, which
persists even if the number of measurements is small compared to the dimension
of the DNS data. The data-driven regime identification algorithm can enable
robust low-order modeling of flows for state estimation and control.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00808</id><created>2015-11-03</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Popowicz</keyname><forenames>Ziemowit</forenames></author></authors><title>A four component cubic peakon (4CH) equations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>10 pages, minor changes</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A. Math. Theor (50) (2017) 285204</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two different four component Camassa-Holm (4CH) systems with cubic
nonlinearity are proposed. The Lax pair and Hamiltonian structure are defined
for both (CH) systems. The first (4CH) system include as a special case the
(3CH) system considered by Xia, Zhou and Qiao, while the second contains the
two-component generalization of Novikov system considered by Geng and Xiu.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09135</id><created>2015-11-29</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eune</keyname><forenames>Myungseok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gim</keyname><forenames>Yongwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Wontae</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Tolman temperature induced by trace anomaly</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure, version to appear in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C77 (2017) 244</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4812-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the finiteness of stress tensor for a scalar field on the
four-dimensional Schwarzschild black hole in the Israel-Hartle-Hawking vacuum,
the Tolman temperature in thermal equilibrium is certainly divergent on the
horizon due to the infinite blueshift of the Hawking temperature. The origin of
this conflict is due to the fact that the conventional Tolman temperature was
based on the assumption of a traceless stress tensor, which is, however,
incompatible with the presence of the trace anomaly responsible for the Hawking
radiation. Here, we present an effective Tolman temperature which is compatible
with the presence of the trace anomaly by using the modified Stefan-Boltzmann
law. Eventually, the effective Tolman temperature turns out to be finite
everywhere outside the horizon, and so there does not appear infinite blueshift
of the Hawking temperature at the event horizon any more. In particular, it is
vanishing on the horizon, so that the equivalence principle is exactly
recovered at the horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03044</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2017-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heninger</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippolis</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cvitanovic</keyname><forenames>Predrag</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbation theory for the Fokker-Planck operator in chaos</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Communications in Nonlinear Science and Numerical Simulation 55C
  (2018) pp. 16-28</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cnsns.2017.06.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stationary distribution of a fully chaotic system typically exhibits a
fractal structure, which dramatically changes if the dynamical equations are
even slightly modified. Perturbative techniques are not expected to work in
this situation. In contrast, the presence of additive noise smooths out the
stationary distribution, and perturbation theory becomes applicable. We show
that a perturbation expansion for the Fokker-Planck evolution operator yields
surprisingly accurate estimates of long-time averages in an otherwise unlikely
scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01763</id><created>2016-03-05</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kulczycki</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malec</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational waves in Friedman-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker cosmology,
  material perturbations and cosmological rotation, and the Huygens principle</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>misprints corrected, matches version published in Classical and
  Quantum Gravity</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34, 135014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7361</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze propagation equations for the polar modes of gravitational waves
in cosmological space-times. We prove that polar gravitational waves must
perturb the density and non-azimuthal components of the velocity of material
medium of the Friedman-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker spacetimes. Axial
gravitational waves can influence only the azimuthal velocity, leading to local
cosmological rotation. The whole gravitational dynamics reduces to the single
&quot;master equation&quot; that has the same form for polar and axial modes. That allows
us to conclude that the status of the Huygens principle is the same for axial
and polar gravitational waves. In particular, this principle is valid exactly
in radiation spacetimes with the vanishing cosmological constant, and it is
broken otherwise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06058</id><created>2016-03-19</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Harvendra</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement asymmetry for boosted black branes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1507.03836; V2: A
  shortened version. No change in the results; V3: Changed title and some
  additions</comments><journal-ref>Int. Jr. Mod. Phys. A32 (2017) 1750091</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500919</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of asymmetry in entanglement thermodynamics of the CFT
subsystems. It is found that `boosted' $p$-branes backgrounds give rise to the
first law of the entanglement thermodynamics where the CFT pressure plays
decisive role in the entanglement. Two different strip like subsystems, one
parallel to the boost and the other perpendicular, are studied in the
perturbative regime, where $T_{thermal}\ll T_E$. We also discuss the AdS-wave
backgrounds where some universal bounds can be obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06006</id><created>2016-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhaba</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of phases of np- scattering up to Tlab=3 GeV for Reid68 and
  Reid93 potentials on the phase-function method</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1603.05382</comments><journal-ref>Probl. Atom. Scie. Tech. Vol. 5 (105), P. 29-32 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For calculation of the single-channel nucleon-nucleon scattering a
phase-functions method has been proposed. Using a phase-functions method the
following phase shifts of np- scattering numerically for 1S0-, 1P1-, 3P0-,
3P1-, 1D2-, 3D2-, 1F3-, 3F3-, 1G4-, 3G4- states are calculated. The
calculations has been performed using realistic nucleon-nucleon Reid68 and
Reid93 potentials. Obtained phase shifts for energy up to 350 MeV are in good
agreement with the results obtained in the framework of other methods. Using
the obtained phase shifts we have calculated the full cross-section np-
scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04334</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Padilla</keyname><forenames>Moises</forenames></author><author><keyname>Servin</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnica</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author></authors><title>Fourier analysis of RGB fringe-projection profilometry and robust
  phase-demodulation methods against crosstalk distortion</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 24(14), 15417-15428 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.015417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we apply the frequency transfer function (FTF) formalism to
analyze the red, green and blue (RGB) phase-shifting fringe-projection
profilometry technique. The phase-shifted fringe patterns in RGB fringe
projection are typically corrupted by crosstalk because the sensitivity curves
of most projection-recording systems overlap. Crosstalk distortion needs to be
compensated in order to obtain high quality measurements. We study
phase-demodulation methods for null/mild, moderate, and severe levels of RGB
crosstalk. For null/mild crosstalk, we can estimate the searched phase-map
using Bruning's 3-step phase-shifting algorithm (PSA). For moderate crosstalk,
the RGB recorded data is usually preprocessed before feeding it into Bruning's
PSA; alternatively, in this paper we propose a computationally more efficient
approach, which combines crosstalk compensation and phase-demodulation into a
single process. For severe RGB crosstalk, we expect non-sinusoidal fringes'
profiles (distorting harmonics) and significant uncertainties on the crosstalk
calibration (which produces pseudo-detuning error). Analyzing these distorting
phenomena, we conclude that squeezing interferometry is the most robust
demodulation method for RGB fringe-projection techniques. We support our
conclusions with numerical simulations and experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06061</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06061</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finazzo</keyname><forenames>Stefano Ivo</forenames><affiliation>Sao Paulo, IFT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Critelli</keyname><forenames>Renato</forenames><affiliation>Sao Paulo U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rougemont</keyname><forenames>Romulo</forenames><affiliation>Sao Paulo U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Noronha</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames><affiliation>Sao Paulo U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Momentum transport in strongly coupled anisotropic plasmas in the
  presence of strong magnetic fields</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>69 pages, 22 figures, 2 appendices, published in Physical Review D;
  this version comprises a correction in some points of the previous version of
  Appendix B (accepted as an erratum in Physical Review D); all the results of
  the main text remain unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 054020 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.054020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a holographic perspective on momentum transport in strongly
coupled, anisotropic non-Abelian plasmas in the presence of strong magnetic
fields. We compute the anisotropic heavy quark drag forces and Langevin
diffusion coefficients and also the anisotropic shear viscosities for two
different holographic models, namely, a top-down deformation of strongly
coupled $\mathcal{N} = 4$ Super-Yang-Mills (SYM) theory triggered by an
external Abelian magnetic field, and a bottom-up Einstein-Maxwell-dilaton (EMD)
model which is able to provide a quantitative description of lattice QCD
thermodynamics with $(2+1)$-flavors at both zero and nonzero magnetic fields.
We find that, in general, energy loss and momentum diffusion through strongly
coupled anisotropic plasmas are enhanced by a magnetic field being larger in
transverse directions than in the direction parallel to the magnetic field.
Moreover, the anisotropic shear viscosity coefficient is smaller in the
direction of the magnetic field than in the plane perpendicular to the field,
which indicates that strongly coupled anisotropic plasmas become closer to the
perfect fluid limit along the magnetic field. We also present, in the context
of the EMD model, holographic predictions for the entropy density and the
crossover critical temperature in a wider region of the $(T,B)$ phase diagram
that has not yet been covered by lattice simulations. Our results for the
transport coefficients in the phenomenologically realistic magnetic EMD model
could be readily used as inputs in numerical codes for magnetohydrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05874</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05874</id><created>2016-06-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Dezfouli</keyname><forenames>Mohsen Kamandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>Reuven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author></authors><title>Modal theory of modified spontaneous emission for a hybrid plasmonic
  photonic-crystal cavity system</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013846 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013846</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analytical modal description of the rich physics involved in
hybrid plasmonic-photonic devices that is confirmed by full dipole solutions of
Maxwell's equations. Strong frequency-dependence for the spontaneous emission
decay rate of a quantum dipole emitter coupled to these hybrid structures is
predicted. In particular, it is shown that the Fano-type resonances reported
experimentally in hybrid plasmonic systems, arise from a very large
interference between dominant quasinormal modes of the systems in the frequency
range of interest. The presented model forms an efficient basis for modelling
quantum light-matter interactions in these complex hybrid systems and also
enables the quantitativ prediction and understanding of non-radiative coupling
losses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06833</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06833</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chancellor</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author></authors><title>Modernizing Quantum Annealing using Local Searches</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 8 figures, typos in and around eq. 9 and 10 rectified in
  v2, path integral quantum annealing results added in v3 at referees request,
  minor corrections in v4 including addition of simulated annealing data at
  referee request. Note added about relvant citation which was missed in the
  published version in v5</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 2, 023024 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa59c4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I describe how real quantum annealers may be used to perform local (in state
space) searches around specified states, rather than the global searches
traditionally implemented in the quantum annealing algorithm. Such protocols
will have numerous advantages over simple quantum annealing. By using such
searches the effect of problem mis-specification can be reduced, as only energy
differences between the searched states will be relevant. The quantum annealing
algorithm is an analogue of simulated annealing, a classical numerical
technique which has now been superseded. Hence, I explore two strategies to use
an annealer in a way which takes advantage of modern classical optimization
algorithms. Specifically, I show how sequential calls to quantum annealers can
be used to construct analogues of population annealing and parallel tempering
which use quantum searches as subroutines. The techniques given here can be
applied not only to optimization, but also to sampling. I examine the
feasibility of these protocols on real devices and note that implementing such
protocols should require minimal if any change to the current design of the
flux qubit-based annealers by D-Wave Systems Inc. I further provide
proof-of-principle numerical experiments based on quantum Monte Carlo that
demonstrate simple examples of the discussed techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06227</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bodendorfer</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>State refinements and coarse graining in a full theory embedding of loop
  quantum cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages; v2: journal version, many clarifications and minor
  corrections</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 135016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7450</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bridging between descriptions involving few large and many small quantum
numbers is the main open problem in loop quantum gravity. In other words, one
would like to be able to represent the same physical system in terms of a few
&quot;coarse&quot;' quantum numbers, while the effective dynamics at the coarse level
should agree with the one induced by a description involving many small quantum
numbers. Efforts to understand this relationship face the problem of the
enormous computational complexity involved in evolving a generic state
containing many quanta. In a cosmological context however, certain symmetry
assumptions on the quantum states allow to simplify the problem. In this paper,
we will show how quantum states describing a spatially flat homogeneous and
isotropic universe can be refined and coarse grained. Invariance of the
dynamics of the coarse observables is shown to require a certain scaling
property (familiar from loop quantum cosmology) of the quantum states if no
running of parameters is taken into account. The involved states are solutions
to the Hamiltonian constraint when terms coming from spatial derivatives are
neglected, i.e. one works in the approximation of non-interacting FRW patches.
The technical means to arrive at this result are a version of loop quantum
gravity based on variables inspired by loop quantum cosmology, as well as an
exact solution to the quantum dynamics of loop quantum cosmology which extends
to the full theory in the chosen approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08226</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2017-02-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>Henrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riello</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author></authors><title>The Observer's Ghost: a field-space connection-form and its application
  to gauge theories and general relativity</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages + appendix and references v2 includes more discussion on the
  meaning of the field space connection in the path integral</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a functional covariant differential as a tool for studying field
space geometry in a manifestly covariant way. We then touch upon its role in
gauge theories and general relativity over bounded regions, and in BRST
symmetry. Due to the Gribov problem, we argue that our formalism ---allowing
for a non-vanishing functional curvature---is necessary for a global treatment
of gauge-invariance in field space. We conclude by suggesting that the
structures we introduce satisfactorily implement the notion of a
(non-asymptotic) observer in gauge theories and general relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08695</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08695</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pisin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chih-Hung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeom</keyname><forenames>Dong-han</forenames></author></authors><title>Broken bridges: A counter-example of the ER=EPR conjecture</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 06 (2017) 040</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/06/040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we provide a counter-example to the ER=EPR conjecture. In an
anti-de Sitter space, we construct a pair of maximally entangled but separated
black holes. Due to the vacuum decay of the anti-de Sitter background toward a
deeper vacuum, these two parts can be trapped by bubbles. If these bubbles are
reasonably large, then within the scrambling time, there should appear an
Einstein-Rosen bridge between the two black holes. Now by tracing more details
on the bubble dynamics, one can identify parameters such that one of the two
bubbles either monotonically shrinks or expands. Because of the change of
vacuum energy, one side of the black hole would evaporate completely. Due to
the shrinking of the apparent horizon, a signal of one side of the
Einstein-Rosen bridge can be viewed from the opposite side. We analytically and
numerically demonstrate that within a reasonable semi-classical parameter
regime, such process can happen. Bubbles are a non-perturbative effect, which
is the crucial reason that allows the transmission of information between the
two black holes through the Einstein-Rosen bridge, even though the probability
is highly suppressed. Therefore, the ER=EPR conjecture cannot be generic in its
present form and its validity maybe restricted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01121</id><created>2016-09-05</created><updated>2016-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monthus</keyname><forenames>Cecile</forenames></author></authors><title>Multifractality of eigenstates in the delocalized non-ergodic phase of
  some random matrix models : Wigner-Weisskopf approach</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>v2=new presentation+new application (15 pages)</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 295101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa77e1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The delocalized non-ergodic phase existing in some random $N \times N$ matrix
models is analyzed via the Wigner-Weisskopf approximation for the dynamics from
an initial site $j_0$. The main output of this approach is the inverse
$\Gamma_{j_0}(N)$ of the characteristic time to leave the state $j_0$ that
provides some broadening $\Gamma_{j_0}(N) $ for the weights of the
eigenvectors. In this framework, the localized phase corresponds to the region
where the broadening $\Gamma_{j_0}(N) $ is smaller in scaling than the level
spacing $\Delta_{j_0}(N) \propto \frac{1}{N}$, while the delocalized
non-ergodic phase corresponds to the region where the broadening
$\Gamma_{j_0}(N) $ decays with $N$ but is bigger in scaling than the level
spacing $\Delta_{j_0}(N) $. Then the number
$\frac{\Gamma_{j_0}(N)}{\Delta_{j_0}(N)} $ of resonances grows only
sub-extensively in $N$. This approach allows to recover the multifractal
spectrum of the Generalized-Rosenzweig-Potter (GRP) Matrix model [V.E.
Kravtsov, I.M. Khaymovich, E. Cuevas and M. Amini, New. J. Phys. 17, 122002
(2015)]. We then consider the L\'evy generalization of the GRP Matrix model,
where the off-diagonal matrix elements are drawn with an heavy-tailed
distribution of L\'evy index $1&lt;\mu&lt;2$ : the dynamics is then governed by a
stretched exponential of exponent $\beta=\frac{2 (\mu-1)}{\mu}$ and the
multifractal properties of eigenstates are explicitly computed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01703</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Balram</keyname><forenames>Ajit C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu</keyname><forenames>Songyang</forenames></author></authors><title>Positions of the magnetoroton minima in the fractional quantum Hall
  effect</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2017) 90: 124</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-80177-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The multitude of excitations of the fractional quantum Hall state are very
accurately understood, microscopically, as excitations of composite fermions
across their Landau-like $\Lambda$ levels. In particular, the dispersion of the
composite fermion exciton, which is the lowest energy spin conserving neutral
excitation, displays filling-factor-specific minima called &quot;magnetoroton&quot;
minima. Simon and Halperin employed the Chern-Simons field theory of composite
fermions [Phys. Rev. B {\bf 48}, 17368 (1993)] to predict the magnetoroton
minima positions. Recently, Golkar \emph{et al.} [Phys. Rev. Lett. {\bf 117},
216403 (2016)] have modeled the neutral excitations as deformations of the
composite fermion Fermi sea, which results in a prediction for the positions of
the magnetoroton minima. Using methods of the microscopic composite fermion
theory we calculate the positions of the roton minima for filling factors up to
5/11 along the sequence $s/(2s+1)$ and find them to be in reasonably good
agreement with both the Chern-Simons field theory of composite fermions and
Golkar \emph{et al.}'s theory. We also find that the positions of the roton
minima are insensitive to the microscopic interaction in agreement with Golkar
\emph{et al.}'s theory. As a byproduct of our calculations, we obtain the
charge and neutral gaps for the fully spin polarized states along the sequence
$s/(2s\pm 1)$ in the lowest Landau level and the $n=1$ Landau level of
graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06011</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roulet</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nimmrichter</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arrazola</keyname><forenames>Juan Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seah</keyname><forenames>Stella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarani</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author></authors><title>Autonomous Rotor Heat Engine</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures; added a thermodynamic analysis of the engine's
  performance</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062131 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The triumph of heat engines is their ability to convert the disordered energy
of thermal sources into useful mechanical motion. In recent years, much effort
has been devoted to generalizing thermodynamic notions to the quantum regime,
partly motivated by the promise of surpassing classical heat engines. Here, we
instead adopt a bottom-up approach: we propose a realistic autonomous heat
engine that can serve as a testbed for quantum effects in the context of
thermodynamics. Our model draws inspiration from actual piston engines and is
built from closed-system Hamiltonians and weak bath coupling terms. We
analytically derive the performance of the engine in the classical regime via a
set of nonlinear Langevin equations. In the quantum case, we perform numerical
simulations of the master equation. Finally, we perform a dynamic and
thermodynamic analysis of the engine's behaviour for several parameter regimes
in both the classical and quantum case, and find that the latter exhibits a
consistently lower efficiency due to additional noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07846</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dall'Arno</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandsen</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buscemi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedral</keyname><forenames>Vlatko</forenames></author></authors><title>Device-independent tests of quantum measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 + 2 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 250501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.250501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of characterizing the set of input-output
correlations that can be generated by an arbitrarily given quantum measurement.
Our main result is to provide a closed-form, full characterization of such a
set for any qubit measurement, and to discuss its geometrical interpretation.
As applications, we further specify our results to the cases of real and
complex symmetric, informationally complete measurements and mutually unbiased
bases of a qubit, in the presence of isotropic noise. Our results provide the
optimal device-independent tests of quantum measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00005</id><created>2016-09-30</created><updated>2017-03-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khorasani</keyname><forenames>Sina</forenames></author></authors><title>Time Operator in Relativistic Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Communications in Theoretical Physics, Vol. 68, No. 1, pp. 35-38
  (July 1, 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0253-6102/68/1/35</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is first shown that the Dirac's equation in a relativistic frame could be
modified to allow discrete time, in agreement to a recently published upper
bound. Next, an exact self-adjoint $4\times 4$ relativistic time operator for
spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ particles is found and the time eigenstates for the
non-relativistic case are obtained and discussed. Results confirm the quantum
mechanical speculation that particles can indeed occupy negative energy levels
with vanishingly small but non-zero probablity, contrary to the general
expectation from classical physics. Hence, Wolfgang Pauli's objection regarding
the existence of a self-adjoint time operator is fully resolved. It is shown
that using the time operator, a bosonic field referred here to as energons may
be created, whose number state representations in non-relativistic momentum
space can be explicitly found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04440</id><created>2016-10-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Arko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angom</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite temperature expansion dynamics of Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A381, 2483 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.05.055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the effects of finite temperature on the dynamics of Bose-Einstein
condensates (BECs) after it is released from the confining potential. In
addition, we examine the variation in the expansion dynamics of the BECs as the
confining potential is transformed from a multiply to a simply connected
geometry. To include the effects of finite temperatures we use the frozen
thermal cloud approximation, and observe unique features of the condensate
density distribution when released from the confining potential. We find that
at $T\neq 0$, during the initial stages of expansion, the multiply connected
condensate has more pronounced interference rings compared to the case of zero
temperature. Such difference in the dynamical evolution is also evident for
simply connected condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07750</id><created>2016-10-25</created><updated>2017-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ortaggio</keyname><forenames>Marcello</forenames></author></authors><title>On the uniqueness of the Myers-Perry spacetime as a type II(D) solution
  in six dimensions</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>30 pages. v2: a few typos fixed, added references, minor improvements
  (results unchanged)</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1706 (2017) 042</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the class of vacuum (Ricci flat) six-dimensional spacetimes
admitting a non-degenerate multiple Weyl aligned null direction l, thus being
of Weyl type II or more special. Subject to an additional assumption on the
asymptotic fall-off of the Weyl tensor, we prove that these spacetimes can be
completely classified in terms of the two eigenvalues of the (asymptotic) twist
matrix of l and of a discrete parameter $U^0=\pm 1/2, 0$. All solutions turn
out to be Kerr-Schild spacetimes of type D and reduce to a family of
&quot;generalized&quot; Myers-Perry metrics (which include limits and analytic
continuations of the original Myers-Perry black hole metric, such as certain
NUT spacetimes). A special subcase corresponds to twisting solutions with zero
shear. In passing, limits connecting various branches of solutions are briefly
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09373</id><created>2016-10-28</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gauld</keyname><forenames>Rhorry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision determination of the small-$x$ gluon from charm production at
  LHCb</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures. Analysis updated to account for erratum in LHCb
  data - results qualitatively unchanged</comments><report-no>NIKHEF 2016-050</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 072001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.072001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The small-$x$ gluon in global fits of parton distributions is affected by
large uncertainties from the lack of direct experimental constraints. In this
work we provide a precision determination of the small-$x$ gluon from the
exploitation of forward charm production data provided by LHCb for three
different centre-of-mass (CoM) energies: 5~TeV, 7~TeV and 13~TeV. The LHCb
measurements are included in the PDF fit by means of normalized distributions
and cross-section ratios between data taken at different CoM values, $R_{13/7}$
and $R_{13/5}$. We demonstrate that forward charm production leads to a
reduction of the PDF uncertainties of the gluon down to $x\simeq 10^{-6}$ by up
to an order of magnitude, with implications for high-energy colliders, cosmic
ray physics and neutrino astronomy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00366</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zu</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandelbaum</keyname><forenames>Rachel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simet</keyname><forenames>Melanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozo</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>Eli S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Level of Cluster Assembly Bias in SDSS</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, MNRAS published</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1264</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, several studies have discovered a strong discrepancy between the
large-scale clustering biases of two subsamples of galaxy clusters at the same
halo mass, split by their average projected membership distances
$R_{\mathrm{mem}}$. The level of this discrepancy significantly exceeds the
maximum halo assembly bias signal predicted by LCDM. In this study, we explore
whether some of the clustering bias differences could be caused by biases in
$R_{\mathrm{mem}}$ due to projection effects from other systems along the
line-of-sight. We thoroughly investigate the halo assembly bias of the
photometrically-detected redMaPPer clusters in SDSS, by defining a new variant
of the average membership distance estimator $\tilde{R}_{\mathrm{mem}}$ that is
more robust against projection effects in the cluster membership
identification. Using the angular mark correlation functions of clusters, we
show that the large-scale bias differences when splitting by $R_{\mathrm{mem}}$
can be largely attributed to such projection effects. After splitting by
$\tilde{R}_{\mathrm{mem}}$, the anomalously large signal is reduced, giving a
ratio of $1.02\pm0.14$ between the two clustering biases as measured from weak
lensing. Using a realistic mock cluster catalog, we predict that the bias ratio
between two $\tilde{R}_{\mathrm{mem}}$-split subsamples should be $&lt;1.10$,
which is at least 60% weaker than the maximum halo assembly bias signal (1.24)
when split by halo concentration. Therefore, our results demonstrate that the
level of halo assembly bias exhibited by redMaPPer clusters in SDSS is
consistent with the LCDM prediction. With a ten-fold increase in cluster
numbers, deeper ongoing surveys will enable a more robust detection of halo
assembly bias. Our findings also have important implications for how projection
effects and their impact on cluster cosmology can be quantified in photometric
cluster catalogs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00628</id><created>2016-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Felder</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huafeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Baxter operators and asymptotic representations</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>16+5 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/s00029-017-0320-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a category $\mathcal O$ of representations of the elliptic
quantum group associated with $\mathfrak{sl}_2$ with well-behaved $q$-character
theory. We derive separation of variables relations for asymptotic
representations in the Grothendieck ring of this category. Baxter $Q$-operators
are obtained as transfer matrices for asymptotic representations and obey
$TQ$-relations as a consequence of the relations in $K_0(\mathcal O)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02340</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02340</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Matzkin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The theory of the Double Solution: Dynamical issues in quantum systems
  in the semiclassical regime</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><journal-ref>Ann. Fond. Louis Broglie 42, 213 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The &quot;dynamical mismatch&quot; observed in quantum systems in the semiclassical
regime challenge the Pilot wave model. Indeed the dynamics and properties of
such systems depend on the trajectories of the classically equivalent system,
whereas the de Broglie-Bohm trajectories are generically non-classical.\ In
this work we examine the situation for the model favoured by de Broglie, the
theory of the Double Solution (DS). We will see that the original DS model
applied to semiclassical systems is also prone to the dynamical mismatch.\
However we will argue that the DS theory can be modified in order to yield
propagation of the singularity in accord with the underlying classical dynamics
of semiclassical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02510</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wei-Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wangyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Bing-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Anlian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Gui-Fang</forenames></author></authors><title>2D MoS2-Graphene-based multilayer van der Waals heterostructures:
  Enhanced charge transfer and optical absorption, and electric-field tunable
  Dirac point and band gap</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures, 8 Supporting figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.chemmater.7b00281</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multilayer van der Waals (vdWs) heterostructures assembled by diverse
atomically thin layers have demonstrated a wide range of fascinating phenomena
and novel applications. Understanding the interlayer coupling and its
correlation effect is paramount for designing novel vdWs heterostructures with
desirable physical properties. Using a detailed theoretical study of 2D
MoS2-graphene (GR)-based heterostructures based on state-of-the-art hybrid
density functional theory, we reveal that for 2D few-layer heterostructures,
vdWs forces between neighboring layers depend on the number of layers. Compared
to that in bilayer, the interlayer coupling in trilayer vdW heterostructures
can significantly be enhanced by stacking the third layer, directly supported
by short interlayer separations and more interfacial charge transfer. The
trilayer shows strong light absorption over a wide range (&lt;700 nm), making it
very potential for solar energy harvesting and conversion. Moreover, the Dirac
point of GR and band gaps of each layer and trilayer can be readily tuned by
external electric field, verifying multilayer vdWs heterostructures with unqiue
optoelectronic properties found by experiments. These results suggest that
tuning the vdWs interaction, as a new design parameter, would be an effective
strategy for devising particular 2D multilayer vdWs heterostructures to meet
the demands in various applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02997</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Samuelsson</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheradsoud</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sothmann</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal quantum interference thermoelectric heat engine with edge states</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 256801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.256801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show theoretically that a thermoelectric heat engine, operating
exclusively due to quantum-mechanical interference, can reach optimal
linear-response performance. A chiral edge state implementation of a
close-to-optimal heat engine is proposed in an electronic Mach-Zehnder
interferometer with a mesoscopic capacitor coupled to one arm. We demonstrate
that the maximum power and corresponding efficiency can reach 90\% and 83\%,
respectively, of the theoretical maximum. The proposed heat engine can be
realized with existing experimental techniques and has a performance robust
against moderate dephasing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04925</id><created>2016-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mak</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curbis</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werin</keyname><forenames>Sverker</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Jump Method for Efficiency Enhancement in Free-Electron Lasers</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 20, 060703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.20.060703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The efficiency of a free-electron laser can be enhanced by sustaining the
growth of the radiation power beyond the initial saturation. One notable method
is undulator tapering, which involves the variation of the gap height and/or
the period along the undulator. Another method is the introduction of phase
jumps, using phase-shifting chicanes in the drift sections separating the
undulator segments. In this article, we develop a physics model of this phase
jump method, and verify it with numerical simulations. The model elucidates the
energy extraction process in the longitudinal phase space. The main ingredient
is the microbunch deceleration cycle, which enables the microbunched electron
beam to decelerate and radiate coherently beyond the initial saturation. The
ponderomotive bucket is stationary, and energy can even be extracted from
electrons outside the bucket. The model addresses the selection criteria for
the phase jump values, and the requirement on the undulator segment length. It
also describes the mechanism of the final saturation. In addition, we discuss
the similarities and differences between the phase jump method and undulator
tapering, by comparing our phase jump model to the classic
Kroll-Morton-Rosenbluth model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06241</id><created>2016-11-18</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wielgosz</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skocze&#x144;</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertik</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author></authors><title>Using LSTM recurrent neural networks for monitoring the LHC
  superconducting magnets</title><categories>physics.ins-det cs.LG physics.acc-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.06.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconducting LHC magnets are coupled with an electronic monitoring
system which records and analyses voltage time series reflecting their
performance. A currently used system is based on a range of preprogrammed
triggers which launches protection procedures when a misbehavior of the magnets
is detected. All the procedures used in the protection equipment were designed
and implemented according to known working scenarios of the system and are
updated and monitored by human operators.
  This paper proposes a novel approach to monitoring and fault protection of
the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) superconducting magnets which employs
state-of-the-art Deep Learning algorithms. Consequently, the authors of the
paper decided to examine the performance of LSTM recurrent neural networks for
modeling of voltage time series of the magnets. In order to address this
challenging task different network architectures and hyper-parameters were used
to achieve the best possible performance of the solution. The regression
results were measured in terms of RMSE for different number of future steps and
history length taken into account for the prediction. The best result of
RMSE=0.00104 was obtained for a network of 128 LSTM cells within the internal
layer and 16 steps history buffer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02555</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gacesa</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xf4;t&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge transfer in ultracold gases via Feshbach resonances</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures; updated to match the published version</comments><msc-class>81V99</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062704 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062704</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the prospects of controlling charge-exchange in ultracold
collisions of heteroisotopic combinations of atoms and ions of the same
element. The treatment, readily applicable to alkali or alkanine-earth metals,
is illustrated in the process $^9$Be$^{+}$ + $^{10}$Be $\leftrightarrow$
$^{9}$Be + $^{10}$Be$^{+}$, which exhibits favorable electronic, nuclear, and
hyperfine structure. Feshbach resonances are obtained from quantum scattering
calculations in a standard coupled-channel formalism with non-BO terms
originating from the nuclear kinetic operator. Near a narrow resonance
predicted at 322 G, we find the charge-exchange rate coefficient to rise from
practically zero to values larger than $10^{-12}$ cm$^3$/s. Our results suggest
controllable charge-exchange reactions between different isotopes of suitable
atom-ion pairs with potential applications to quantum systems engineered to
study charge diffusion in trapped cold atom-ion mixtures and emulate many-body
physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04312</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leymann</keyname><forenames>H. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorberg</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lettau</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopfmann</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamp</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketzmerick</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiersig</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reitzenstein</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckardt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pump-power-driven mode switching in a microcavity device and its
  relation to Bose-Einstein condensation</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>minor changes, typos corrected, acknowledgments supplemented,
  references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021045 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the switching of the coherent emission mode of a bimodal
microcavity device, occurring when the pump power is varied. We compare
experimental data to theoretical results and identify the underlying mechanism
to be based on the competition between the effective gain on the one hand and
the intermode kinetics on the other. When the pumping is ramped up, above a
threshold the mode with the largest effective gain starts to emit coherent
light, corresponding to lasing. In contrast, in the limit of strong pumping it
is the intermode kinetics that determines which mode acquires a large
occupation and shows coherent emission. We point out that this latter mechanism
is akin to the equilibrium Bose-Einstein condensation of massive bosons. Thus,
the mode switching in our microcavity device can be viewed as a minimal
instance of Bose-Einstein condensation of photons. We, moreover, show that the
switching from one cavity mode to the other occurs always via an intermediate
phase where both modes are emitting coherent light and that it is associated
with both superthermal intensity fluctuations and strong anticorrelations
between both modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09256</id><created>2016-12-29</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of electroweak-induced production of W gamma with two jets
  in pp collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV and constraints on anomalous quartic
  gauge couplings</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SMP-14-011</comments><report-no>CMS-SMP-14-011, CERN-EP-2016-289</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 06 (2017) 106</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement of electroweak-induced production of W gamma and two jets is
performed, where the W boson decays leptonically. The data used in the analysis
correspond to an integrated luminosity of 19.7 inverse femtobarns collected by
the CMS experiment in sqrt(s) = 8 TeV proton-proton collisions produced at the
LHC. Candidate events are selected with exactly one muon or electron, missing
transverse momentum, one photon, and two jets with large rapidity separation.
An excess over the hypothesis of the standard model without electroweak
production of W gamma with two jets is observed with a significance of 2.7
standard deviations. The cross section measured in the fiducial region is 10.8
+/- 4.1 (stat) +/- 3.4 (syst) +/- 0.3 (lumi) fb, which is consistent with the
standard model electroweak predictions. The total cross section for W gamma
production in association with 2 jets in the same fiducial region is measured
to be 23.2 +/- 4.3 (stat) +/- 1.7 (syst) +/- 0.6 (lumi) fb, which is consistent
with the standard model prediction from the combination of electroweak- and
quantum chromodynamics-induced processes. No deviations are observed from the
standard model predictions and experimental limits on anomalous quartic gauge
couplings f[M, 0-7] / Lambda^4, f[T, 0-2] / Lambda^4, and f[T, 5-7] / Lambda^4
are set at 95% confidence level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05082</id><created>2017-01-18</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chatzikaleas</keyname><forenames>Athanasios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donninger</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glogi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Irfan</forenames></author></authors><title>On blowup of co-rotational wave maps in odd space dimensions</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, typos fixed, will appear in Journal of Differential
  Equations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider co-rotational wave maps from the $(1+d)$-dimensional Minkowski
space into the $d$-sphere for $d\geq 3$ odd. This is an energy-supercritical
model which is known to exhibit finite-time blowup via self-similar solutions.
Based on a method developed by the second author and Sch\&quot;orkhuber, we prove
the asymptotic nonlinear stability of the &quot;ground-state&quot; self-similar solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07424</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blanchet</keyname><forenames>Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational waves 100 years after Einstein</title><categories>physics.pop-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, published in &quot;Reflets de la Physique&quot;, one
  historical point clarified, discussion on stellar winds corrected, in French</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LIGO-VIRGO collaboration has detected directly on Earth the gravitational
wave signals generated by the collision and the merger of two massive black
holes at astronomical distance. This major discovery opens up the way to
Gravitational Astronomy, which should revolutionize our comprehension of the
structure of the Universe at large scales, with notably the mechanisms of
formation of black holes and their role in the evolution of the Universe, the
likely emergence of a multi-messenger astronomy joint with electromagnetic
radiation, and a better appraisal of the status of general relativity with
respect to other fundamental interactions. The theoretical and numerical works
on the two-body problem in general relativity play a very important role when
deciphering and interpreting the gravitational wave signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01658</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Zili</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yan-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shiyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Jianlin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Guo-qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Zi Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Jia-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Youguo</forenames></author></authors><title>Gapped spin-1/2 spinon excitations in a new kagome quantum spin liquid
  compound Cu$_3$Zn(OH)$_6$FBr</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages and 3 figures. Supplementary Materials file is in the source
  file and also can be found in CPL published online version</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. Lett., Vol. 34 Issue (7): 077502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0256-307X/34/7/077502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new kagome quantum spin liquid candidate Cu$_3$Zn(OH)$_6$FBr,
which does not experience any phase transition down to 50 mK, more than three
orders lower than the antiferromagnetic Curie-Weiss temperature ($\sim$ 200 K).
A clear gap opening at low temperature is observed in the uniform spin
susceptibility obtained from $^{19}$F nuclear magnetic resonance measurements.
We observe the characteristic magnetic field dependence of the gap as expected
for fractionalized spin-1/2 spinon excitations. Our experimental results
provide firm evidence for spin fractionalization in a topologically ordered
spin system, resembling charge fractionalization in the fractional quantum Hall
state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02355</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Mao</forenames></author></authors><title>Differential equations on unitarity cut surfaces</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures; v2: added more results and references, final
  journal version</comments><report-no>UCLA-17-TEP-102</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 06 (2017) 121</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reformulate differential equations (DEs) for Feynman integrals to avoid
doubled propagators in intermediate steps. External momentum derivatives are
dressed with loop momentum derivatives to form tangent vectors to unitarity cut
surfaces, in a way inspired by unitarity-compatible IBP reduction. For the
one-loop box, our method directly produces the final DEs without any
integration-by-parts reduction. We further illustrate the method by deriving
maximal-cut level differential equations for two-loop nonplanar five-point
integrals, whose exact expressions are yet unknown. We speed up the computation
using finite field techniques and rational function reconstruction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03312</id><created>2017-02-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Falk</keyname><forenames>Abram L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiu</keyname><forenames>Kuan-Chang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farmer</keyname><forenames>Damon B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tersoff</keyname><forenames>Jerry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Yi-Hsien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avouris</keyname><forenames>Phaedon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Shu-Jen</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent plasmon and phonon-plasmon resonances in carbon nanotubes</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures, supplemental material appended</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 257401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.257401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Carbon nanotubes provide a rare access point into the plasmon physics of
one-dimensional electronic systems. By assembling purified nanotubes into
uniformly sized arrays, we show that they support coherent plasmon resonances,
that these plasmons enhance and hybridize with phonons, and that the
phonon-plasmon resonances have quality factors as high as 10. Because coherent
nanotube plasmonics can strengthen light-matter interactions, it provides a
compelling platform for surface-enhanced infrared spectroscopy and tunable,
high-performance optical devices at the nanometer scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05500</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lingam</keyname><forenames>Manasvi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loeb</keyname><forenames>Abraham</forenames></author></authors><title>Natural and Artificial Spectral Edges in Exoplanets</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS Letters; 5 pages; 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS Letters, 470, L82 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Technological civilizations may rely upon large-scale photovoltaic arrays to
harness energy from their host star. Photovoltaic materials, such as silicon,
possess distinctive spectral features, including an &quot;artificial edge&quot; that is
characteristically shifted in wavelength shortwards of the &quot;red edge&quot; of
vegetation. Future observations of reflected light from exoplanets would be
able to detect both natural and artificial edges photometrically, if a
significant fraction of the planet's surface is covered by vegetation or
photovoltaic arrays respectively. The stellar energy thus tapped can be
utilized for terraforming activities by transferring heat and light from the
day side to the night side on tidally locked exoplanets, thereby producing
detectable artifacts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06583</id><created>2017-02-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Dezfouli</keyname><forenames>Mohsen Kamandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Optics Model of Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy for
  Arbitrarily Shaped Plasmonic Resonators</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 4, 1245 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a self-consistent quantum optics approach to calculating the
surface enhanced Raman spectrum of molecules coupled to arbitrarily shaped
plasmonic systems. Our treatment is intuitive to use and provides fresh
analytical insight into the physics of the Raman scattering near metallic
surfaces and can be applied to a wide range of geometries including resonators,
waveguides, as well as hybrid photonic-plasmonic systems. Our general theory
demonstrates that the detected Raman spectrum originates from an interplay
between nonlinear light generation and propagation. Counter intuitively, at the
nonlinear generation stage, we show that the Stokes (anti-Stokes) signal at the
molecule location depends on the plasmonic enhancements, through the local
density of photon states (LDOS), at the anti-Stokes (Stokes) frequency.
However, when propagating from the vibrating molecule to the far field, the
Stokes (anti-Stokes) emission experiences a plasmonic enhancement at the Stokes
(anti-Stokes) frequency, as expected. We identify the limits of the commonly
known E^4 electric-field rule for Raman signal enhancement near plasmonic
surfaces at low pump powers, as well as a different E^8 rule at high pump
powers, and we clarify the role of the LDOS. Our theory uses a generalized
quantum master equation where the plasmonic system is treated as an
environmental bath that is described through the photonic Green function of the
medium. Therefore, any electrodynamics related physics, such as quenching and
propagation, are self-consistently included in the model. The presented
formalism is also capable of spatially describing the full Raman response in a
simple analytical way, which is typically not possible using simpler coupled
mode theories, even if one adopts a quantum picture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08678</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Damasceno</keyname><forenames>Pablo F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glotzer</keyname><forenames>Sharon C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engel</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Close-Packed Three-Dimensional Quasicrystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Cond. Mat. 29, 234005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa6cc1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quasicrystals are frequently encountered in condensed matter. They are
important candidates for equilibrium phases from the atomic scale to the
nanoscale. Here, we investigate the computational self-assembly of four
quasicrystals in a single model system of identical particles interacting with
a tunable isotropic pair potential. We reproduce a known icosahedral
quasicrystal and report a decagonal quasicrystal, a dodecagonal quasicrystal,
and an octagonal quasicrystal. The quasicrystals have low coordination number
or occur in systems with mesoscale density variations. We also report a network
gel phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00025</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Rham</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melville</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author></authors><title>Unitary null energy condition violation in $P(X)$ cosmologies</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 123523 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.123523</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A non-singular cosmological bounce in the Einstein frame can only take place
if the Null Energy Condition (NEC) is violated. We explore situations where a
single scalar field drives the NEC violation and derive the constraints imposed
by demanding tree level unitarity on a cosmological background. We then focus
on the explicit constraints that arise in P(X) theories and show that
constraints from perturbative unitarity make it impossible for the NEC
violation to occur within the region of validity of the effective field theory
without also involving irrelevant operators that arise at a higher scale that
would enter from integrating out more massive degrees of freedom. Within the
context of P(X) theories we show that including such operators allows for a
bounce that does not manifestly violate tree level unitarity, but at the price
of either imposing a shift symmetry or involving technically unnatural small
operator coefficients within the low-energy effective field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02514</id><created>2017-03-07</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Shailesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>Valery A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agafonov</keyname><forenames>Viatcheslav N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation of nanowire surface plasmons by silicon vacancy centers in
  nanodiamonds</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Silicon vacancy (SiV) centers in diamonds have emerged as a very promising
candidate for quantum emitter due to their narrow emission line resulting in
their indistinguishability. While many different quantum emitters have already
been used for excitation of various propagating plasmonic modes, the
corresponding exploitation of SiV centers remained so far uncharted territory.
Here, we report on excitation of surface plasmon modes supported by silver
nanowires using SiV centers in nanodiamonds. The coupling of SiV center
fluorescence to surface plasmons is observed, when a nanodiamond situated close
to a nanowire is illuminated by the pump, as radiated emission from the distal
nanowire end. The effect of coupling is also seen as a change in the SiV center
lifetime. Finally, we discuss possible avenues for strengthening the SiV center
coupling to surface plasmon modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02985</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Ya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Junxian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhoads</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Infante</keyname><forenames>Leopoldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>Sangeeta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Weida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Alistair R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Linhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Chunyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hibon</keyname><forenames>Pascale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Alicia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Xu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Xianzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galaz</keyname><forenames>Gaspar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrientos</keyname><forenames>L. Felipe</forenames></author></authors><title>First Results from the Lyman Alpha Galaxies in the Epoch of Reionization
  (LAGER) Survey: Cosmological Reionization at z ~ 7</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures (updated), 2 tables (updated), Accepted for
  publication in ApJ Letters</comments><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa794f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first results from the ongoing LAGER project (Lyman Alpha
Galaxies in the Epoch of Reionization), which is the largest narrowband survey
for $z \sim$ 7 galaxies to date. Using a specially built narrowband filter
NB964 for the superb large-area Dark-Energy Camera (DECam) on the NOAO/CTIO 4m
Blanco telescope, LAGER has collected 34 hours NB964 narrowband imaging data in
the 3 deg$^2$ COSMOS field. We have identified 23 Lyman Alpha Emitter (LAE)
candidates at $z$ = 6.9 in the central 2-deg$^2$ region, where DECam and public
COSMOS multi-band images exist. The resulting luminosity function can be
described as a Schechter function modified by a significant excess at the
bright end (4 galaxies with $L_{Ly\alpha} \sim $ 10$^{43.4\pm0.2}$ erg
s$^{-1}$). The number density at $L_{Ly\alpha}\sim$ 10$^{43.4\pm0.2}$ erg
s$^{-1}$ is little changed from z= 6.6, while at fainter $L_{Ly\alpha}$ it is
substantially reduced. Overall, we see a fourfold reduction in Ly$\alpha$
luminosity density from $z$ = 5.7 to 6.9. Combined with a more modest evolution
of the continuum UV luminosity density, this suggests a factor of $\sim 3$
suppression of Ly$\alpha$ by radiative transfer through the $z \sim$ 7
intergalactic medium (IGM). It indicates an IGM neutral fraction $x_{HI}$
$\sim$ 0.4--0.6 (assuming Ly$\alpha$ velocity offsets of 100-200 km s$^{-1}$).
The changing shape of the Ly$\alpha$ luminosity function between $z\lesssim
6.6$ and $z=6.9$ supports the hypothesis of ionized bubbles in a patchy
reionization at $z\sim$ 7.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03218</id><created>2017-03-09</created><updated>2017-03-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cramer</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Er-Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gepr&#xe4;gs</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kehlberger</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Yurii P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganzhorn</keyname><forenames>Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Coletta</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Althammer</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huebl</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosel</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xe4;ui</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goennenwein</keyname><forenames>Sebastian T. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnon mode selective spin transport in compensated ferrimagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04522</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the generation of magnonic thermal spin currents and their
mode selective spin transport across interfaces in insulating, compensated
ferrimagnet/normal metal bilayer systems. The spin Seebeck effect signal
exhibits a non-monotonic temperature dependence with two sign changes of the
detected voltage signals. Using different ferrimagnetic garnets, we demonstrate
the universality of the observed complex temperature dependence of the spin
Seebeck effect. To understand its origin, we systematically vary the interface
between the ferrimagnetic garnet and the metallic layer, and by using different
metal layers we establish that interface effects play a dominating role. They
do not only modify the magnitude of the spin Seebeck effect signal but in
particular also alter its temperature dependence. By varying the temperature,
we can select the dominating magnon mode and we analyze our results to reveal
the mode selective interface transmission probabilities for different magnon
modes and interfaces. The comparison of selected systems reveals
semi-quantitative details of the interfacial coupling depending on the
materials involved, supported by the obtained field dependence of the signal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03580</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Qi-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Rong</forenames></author></authors><title>Anderson localization in the Non-Hermitian Aubry-Andr\'e-Harper model
  with physical gain and loss</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062118 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the Anderson localization in non-Hermitian
Aubry-Andr\'e-Harper (AAH) models with imaginary potentials added to lattice
sites to represent the physical gain and loss during the interacting processes
between the system and environment. By checking the mean inverse participation
ratio (MIPR) of the system, we find that different configurations of physical
gain and loss have very different impacts on the localization phase transition
in the system. In the case with balanced physical gain and loss added in an
alternate way to the lattice sites, the critical region (in the case with
p-wave superconducting pairing) and the critical value (both in the situations
with and without p-wave pairing) for the Anderson localization phase transition
will be significantly reduced, which implies an enhancement of the localization
process. However, if the system is divided into two parts with one of them
coupled to physical gain and the other coupled to the corresponding physical
loss, the transition process will be impacted only in a very mild way. Besides,
we also discuss the situations with imbalanced physical gain and loss and find
that the existence of random imaginary potentials in the system will also
affect the localization process while constant imaginary potentials will not.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04521</id><created>2017-03-13</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Protsenko</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katanin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional renormalization group study of parallel double quantum dots:
  Effects of asymmetric dot-lead couplings</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245129 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the effects of asymmetry of hopping parameters between double
parallel quantum dots and the leads on the conductance and a possibility of
local magnetic moment formation in this system using functional renormalization
group approach with the counterterm. We demonstrate a possibility of a quantum
phase transition to a local moment regime (so called singular Fermi liquid
(SFL) state) for various types of hopping asymmetries and discuss respective
gate voltage dependences of the conductance. It is shown, that depending on the
type of the asymmetry, the system can demonstrate either a first order quantum
phase transition to SFL state, accompanied by a discontinuous change of the
conductance, similarly to the symmetric case, or the second order quantum phase
transition, in which the conductance is continuous and exhibits Fano-type
asymmetric resonance near the transition point. A semi-analytical explanation
of these different types of conductance behavior is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06095</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for anomalous couplings in boosted WW/WZ to l nu q q-bar
  production in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference. All
  the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SMP-13-008</comments><report-no>CMS-SMP-13-008, CERN-EP-2017-029</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 772 (2017) 21</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.06.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This Letter presents a search for new physics manifested as anomalous triple
gauge boson couplings in WW and WZ diboson production in proton-proton
collisions. The search is performed using events containing a W boson that
decays leptonically and a W or Z boson whose decay products are merged into a
single reconstructed jet. The data, collected at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV with the CMS
detector at the LHC, correspond to an integrated luminosity of 19 inverse
femtobarns. No evidence for anomalous triple gauge couplings is found and the
following 95% confidence level limits are set on their values: lambda ([-0.011,
0.011]), Delta kappa[gamma] ([-0.044, 0.063]), and Delta g[1,Z] ([-0.0087,
0.024]). These limits are also translated into their effective field theory
equivalents: c[WWW] / Lambda^2 ([-2.7, 2.7] TeV^{-2}), c[B] / Lambda^2 ([-14,
17] TeV^{-2}), and c[W] / Lambda^2 ([-2.0, 5.7] TeV^{-2}).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07667</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-05-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Steinbrink</keyname><forenames>Nicholas M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gl&#xfc;ck</keyname><forenames>Ferenc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heizmann</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleesiek</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valerius</keyname><forenames>Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinheimer</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannestad</keyname><forenames>Steen</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical sensitivity on right-handed currents in presence of eV scale
  sterile neutrinos with KATRIN</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 12 figures, minor revision</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/06/015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The KATRIN experiment aims to determine the absolute neutrino mass by
measuring the endpoint region of the tritium $\beta$ spectrum. As a large-scale
experiment with a sharp energy resolution, high source luminosity and low
background it may also be capable of testing certain theories of neutrino
interactions beyond the standard model (SM). An example of a non-SM interaction
are right-handed currents mediated by right-handed W bosons in the left-right
symmetric model (LRSM). In this extension of the SM, an additional
SU(2)$_\mathrm R$ symmetry in the high-energy limit is introduced, which
naturally includes sterile neutrinos and predicts the seesaw mechanism. In
tritium $\beta$ decay, this leads to an additional term from interference
between left- and right-handed interactions, which enhances or suppresses
certain regions near the endpoint of the beta spectrum. In this work, the
sensitivity of KATRIN to right-handed currents is estimated for the scenario of
a light sterile neutrino with a mass of some eV. This has been performed with a
Bayesian analysis using Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC). The simulations show
that in principle KATRIN is able to set sterile neutrino mass-dependent limits
on the interference strength. Thereby, the sensitivity is significantly
increased if the $Q$ value of the $\beta$ decay can be sufficiently
constrained. However, the sensitivity is not high enough to improve current
upper limits from right-handed W boson searches at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09982</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Storey</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sochi</keyname><forenames>Taha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastin</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Recombination coefficients for O II lines in nebular conditions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, 6 tables</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1189</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of a calculation of recombination coefficients for
O^{2+} + e^- using an intermediate coupling treatment that fully accounts for
the dependence of the distribution of population among the ground levels of
O^{2+} on electron density and temperature. The calculation is extended down to
low electron temperatures where dielectronic recombination arising from Rydberg
states converging on the O^{2+} ground levels is an important process. The
data, which consist of emission coefficients for 8889 recombination lines and
recombination coefficients for the ground and metastable states of O^+ are in
Cases A, B and C, and are organised as a function of the electron temperature
and number density, as well as wavelength. An interactive fortran 77 data
server is also provided as an accessory for mining the line emission
coefficients and obtaining Lagrange interpolated values for any choice of the
two variables between the explicitly provided values for any set of
wavelengths. Some illustrations of the application of the new data to nebular
observations are also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03146</id><created>2017-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Mikito</forenames><affiliation>Tohoku Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chiba</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames><affiliation>Tohoku Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Komiyama</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames><affiliation>NAOJ</affiliation></author></authors><title>Resolved stellar streams around NGC4631 from a Subaru/Hyper Suprime-Cam
  survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 16 figures, 5 tables, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6d11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first results of the Subaru/Hyper Suprime-Cam (HSC) survey of
the interacting galaxy system, NGC4631 and NGC4656. From the maps of resolved
stellar populations, we identify 11 dwarf galaxies (including already-known
dwarfs) in the outer region of NGC4631 and the two tidal stellar streams around
NGC4631, named Stream SE and Stream NW, respectively. This paper describes the
fundamental properties of these tidal streams. Based on the tip of red giant
branch method and the Bayesian statistics, we find that StreamSE (7.10 Mpc in
Expected a posteriori, EAP, with the 90% credible intervals of [6.22, 7.29]
Mpc) and StreamNW (7.91 Mpc in EAP with the 90% credible intervals of [6.44,
7.97] Mpc) are located in front of and behind NGC4631, respectively. We also
calculate the metallicity distribution of stellar streams by comparing the
member stars with theoretical isochrones on the color-magnitude diagram. We
find that both streams have the same stellar population based on the Bayesian
model selection method, suggesting that they originated from a tidal
interaction between NGC4631 and a single dwarf satellite. The expected
progenitor has a positively skewed metallicity distribution function with
[M/H]_EAP=-0.92 with the 90% credible intervals of [-1.46, -0.51]. The stellar
mass of the progenitor is estimated as 3.7 x 10e+8 Msun with the 90% credible
intervals of [5.8 x 10e+6, 8.6 x 10e+9] Msun based on the mass-metallicity
relation for Local group dwarf galaxies. This is in good agreement with an
initial stellar mass of the progenitor presumed in the previous N-body
simulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07614</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-05-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Jing-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hai-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>No evidence for the evolution of mass density power-law index $\gamma$
  from strong gravitational lensing observation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. China-Phys. Mech. Astron. 60, 080411 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11433-017-9054-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider the singular isothermal sphere lensing model that
has a spherically symmetric power-law mass distribution $\rho_{tot}(r)\sim
r^{-\gamma}$. We investigate whether the mass density power-law index $\gamma$
is cosmologically evolutionary by using the strong gravitational lensing (SGL)
observation, in combination with other cosmological observations. We also check
whether the constraint result of $\gamma$ is affected by the cosmological
model, by considering several simple dynamical dark energy models. We find that
the constraint on $\gamma$ is mainly decided by the SGL observation and
independent of the cosmological model, and we find no evidence for the
evolution of $\gamma$ from the SGL observation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07881</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miao</keyname><forenames>Zibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlette</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete-time reservoir engineering with entangled bath and stabilizing
  squeezed states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This theoretical proposal investigates how resonant interactions occurring
when a harmonic oscillator is fed with a stream of entangled qubits allow us to
stabilize squeezed states of the harmonic oscillator. We show that the
properties of the squeezed state stabilized by this engineered reservoir,
including the squeezing strength, can be tuned at will through the parameters
of the &quot;input&quot; qubits, albeit in tradeoff with the convergence rate. We also
discuss the influence of the type of entanglement in the input, from a pairwise
case to a more widely distributed case. This paper can be read in two ways:
either as a proposal to stabilize squeezed states, or as a step towards
treating quantum systems with time-entangled reservoir inputs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03225</id><created>2017-05-09</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thesing</keyname><forenames>Linda V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;pper</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez-F&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>Rosario</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent analysis of the mixed-field orientation of molecules
  without rotational symmetry</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures, 4 movies and a description of these movies
  (CPC_paper_SI.pdf) as supplementary material; corrected typos, additional
  information in the caption of table 1</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 244304 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4986954</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical study of the mixed-field orientation of molecules
without rotational symmetry. The time-dependent one-dimensional and
three-dimensional orientation of a thermal ensemble of
6-chloropyridazine-3-carbonitrile molecules in combined linearly or
elliptically polarized laser fields and tilted dc electric fields is computed.
The results are in good agreement with recent experimental results of
one-dimensional orientation for weak dc electric fields [J. Chem. Phys. 139,
234313 (2013)]. Moreover, they predict that using elliptically polarized laser
fields or strong dc fields three-dimensional orientation is obtained. The
field-dressed dynamics of excited rotational states is characterized by highly
non-adiabatic effects. We analyze the sources of these non-adiabatic effects
and investigate their impact on the mixed-field orientation for different field
configurations in mixed-field-orientation experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01305</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhukov</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouffanais</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belonenko</keyname><forenames>Mikhail B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dvuzhilov</keyname><forenames>Ilya S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevzorova</keyname><forenames>Yulia V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional light bullets in a Bragg medium with carbon nanotubes</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>To appear in Appl. Phys. B</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. B, (123):196 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-017-6767-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical study of the propagation of three-dimensional
extremely short electromagnetic pulses (a.k.a. light bullets) through a Bragg
medium containing an immersed array of carbon nanotubes. We demonstrate the
possible stable propagation of such light bullets. In particular, our results
suggest these light bullets can carry information about the Bragg medium
itself.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02395</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Patsopoulos</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kechrakos</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Monte Carlo study of the exchange bias effect in Co/CoO core-shell
  nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 28, 285701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa77e3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the magnetic properties of cylindrical ferromagnetic core -
antiferromagnetic shell nanowires using Monte Carlo simulations and a classical
Heisenberg Hamiltonian in order to elucidate the impact of the oxidized shell
on the magnetic properties and the magnetization reversal mechanism. We find
that the coupling to the antiferromagnetic shell leads to suppression of the
coercivity and emergence of a weak exchange bias effect. Comparison of the
magnetization reversal mechanism in the bare and the surface-oxidized nanowire
reveals that the domain wall propagation and annihilation remains the dominant
reversal mechanism in surface oxidized nanowires as in their ferromagnetic
counterparts. However, the interface exchange coupling introduces a secondary
reversal mechanism activated in the central part of the wire with
characteristics of coherent rotation, which acts in synergy to wall propagation
leading to enhancement of the wall mobility. This effect is more pronounced in
nanowires with large exchange bias values and is attributed to the
uncompensated interface moments that act as nucleation centers for
magnetization reversal. Our results are in good agreement with recent
measurements in Co and Co/CoO nanowires.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05428</id><created>2017-06-16</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Giagkiozis</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedun</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scullion</keyname><forenames>Eamon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verth</keyname><forenames>Gary</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex Flows in the Solar Atmoshpere: Automated Identification and
  Statistical Analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aims. Due to the fundamental importance of vortices on the photosphere, in
this work we aim to fully automate the process of intensity vortex
identification to facilitate a more robust statistical analysis of their
properties. Methods. Using on-disk observational data of the Fe I continuum,
the process of vortex identification is fully automated, for the first time in
solar physics, with the help of an established method from hydrodynamics
initially employed for the study of eddies in turbulent flows (Graftieaux et
al. 2001). Results. We find that the expected lifetime of intensity vortices is
much shorter (~ 17s) compared with previously observed magnetic bright point
swirls. Our findings suggest that at any time there are 1.4e6 such small-scale
intensity vortices covering about 2.8% of the total surface of the solar
photosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06151</id><created>2017-06-19</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kvita</keyname><forenames>Jiri</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of Minimum Bias Observables with ATLAS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>on behalf of the ATLAS collaboration, Proceedings of the 8th
  International Workshop on Multiple Partonic Interactions at the LHC</comments><report-no>ATL-PHYS-PROC-2017-063</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The modelling of minimum bias interactions is a crucial ingredient to learn
about the description of soft QCD processes. It has also a significant
relevance for the simulation of the environment at the LHC with many concurrent
pp interactions (pileup). The ATLAS collaboration has provided new measurements
of the inclusive charged-particle multiplicity and its dependence on transverse
momentum and pseudorapidity in special data sets with low LHC beam currents,
recorded at center of mass energies of 8 TeV and 13 TeV. The measurements use
charged-particle selections with minimum transverse momentum of both 100 MeV
and 500 MeV, and various phase-space regions characterized by low and high
charged-particle multiplicities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06183</id><created>2017-06-19</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garfinkle</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Matters of Gravity, The Newsletter of the Division of Gravitational
  Physics of the American Physical Society, Volume 49, June 2017</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>more thorough second paragraph for the GW170104 article</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  DGRAV News:
  We hear that ....
  DGRAV student travel grants
  Research Briefs:
  The Discovery of GW170104
  Obituary:
  Remembering Vishu
  Remembering Cecile DeWitt-Morette
  Remembering Larry Shepley
  Remembering Marcus Ansorg
  Conference Reports:
  EGM20
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06282</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Minkyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurdak</keyname><forenames>Raja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paini</keyname><forenames>Dean</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Components of Real-world Diffusion Dynamics based on Point
  Processes</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bursts in human and natural activities are highly clustered in time,
suggesting that these activities are influenced by previous events within the
social or natural system. Bursty behavior in the real world conveys information
of underlying diffusion processes, which have been the focus of diverse
scientific communities from online social media to criminology and
epidemiology. However, universal components of real-world diffusion dynamics
that cut across disciplines remain unexplored. Here, we introduce a wide range
of diffusion processes across disciplines and propose universal components of
diffusion frameworks. We apply these components to diffusion-based studies of
human disease spread, through a case study of the vector-borne disease dengue.
The proposed universality of diffusion can motivate transdisciplinary research
and provide a fundamental framework for diffusion models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06420</id><created>2017-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Puviani</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manghi</keyname><forenames>Franca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertoni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and Control of Edge States in Laser-driven Graphene Nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, double column, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235430 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An intense laser field in the high-frequency regime drives carriers in
graphene nanoribbons (GNRs) out of equilibrium and creates
topologically-protected edge states. Using Floquet theory on driven GNRs, we
calculate the time evolution of local excitations of these edge states and show
that they exhibit a robust dynamics also in the presence of very localized
lattice defects (atomic vacancies), which is characteristic of topologically
non-trivial behavior. We show how it is possible to control them by a modulated
electrostatic potential: They can be fully transmitted on the same edge,
reflected on the opposite one, or can be split between the two edges, in
analogy with Hall edge states, making them promising candidates for
flying-qubit architectures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07087</id><created>2017-06-21</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frandsen</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birgeneau</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Qimiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent phases in iron pnictides: Double-Q antiferromagnetism, charge
  order and enhanced nematic correlations</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5+6 pages, 2 figures; (v2) issues with cross-referencing between the
  main text and supplementary material are fixed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron correlations produce a rich phase diagram in the iron pnictides.
Earlier theoretical studies on the correlation effect demonstrated how quantum
fluctuations weaken and concurrently suppress a $C_2$-symmetric single-Q
antiferromagnetic order and a nematic order. Here we examine the emergent
phases near the quantum phase transition. For a $C_4$-symmetric collinear
double-Q antiferromagnetic order, we show that it is accompanied by both a
charge order and an enhanced nematic susceptibility. Our results provide
understanding for several intriguing recent experiments in hole-doped iron
arsenides, and bring out common physics that underlies the different magnetic
phases of various iron-based superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07425</id><created>2017-06-22</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso-Herrero</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;n-Caballero</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>C. Ramos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levenson</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roche</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mart&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Packham</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishimoto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A mid-infrared statistical investigation of clumpy torus model
  predictions</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>23 pages, 17 figures, 5 tables, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1361</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new calculations of the CAT3D clumpy torus models, which now
include a more physical dust sublimation model as well as AGN anisotropic
emission. These new models allow graphite grains to persist at temperatures
higher than the silicate dust sublimation temperature. This produces stronger
near-infrared emission and bluer mid-infrared (MIR) spectral slopes. We make a
statistical comparison of the CAT3D model MIR predictions with a compilation of
sub-arcsecond resolution ground-based MIR spectroscopy of 52 nearby Seyfert
galaxies (median distance of 36 Mpc) and 10 quasars. We focus on the AGN MIR
spectral index $\alpha_{MIR}$ and the strength of the 9.7 $\mu$m silicate
feature $S_{Sil}$. As with other clumpy torus models, the new CAT3D models do
not reproduce the Seyfert galaxies with deep silicate absorption
($S_{Sil}&lt;-1$). Excluding those, we conclude that the new CAT3D models are in
better agreement with the observed $\alpha_{MIR}$ and $S_{Sil}$ of Seyfert
galaxies and quasars. We find that Seyfert 2 are reproduced with models with
low photon escape probabilities, while the quasars and the Seyfert 1-1.5
require generally models with higher photon escape probabilities. Quasars and
Seyfert 1-1.5 tend to show steeper radial cloud distributions and fewer clouds
along an equatorial line-of-sight than Seyfert 2. Introducing AGN anisotropic
emission besides the more physical dust sublimation models alleviates the
problem of requiring inverted radial cloud distributions (i.e., more clouds
towards the outer parts of the torus) to explain the MIR spectral indices of
type 2 Seyferts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07452</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Vargas-Grajales</keyname><forenames>Juli&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>Frederico</forenames></author></authors><title>On the adiabatic quantum dynamics of fabricated Ising chains</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical implementations of quantum computation must be scrutinized about
their reliability under real conditions, in order to be considered as viable
candidates. Among the proposed models, those based on adiabatic quantum
dynamics have shown great potential for solving specific tasks and have already
been successfully implemented using superconducting devices. In this context,
we address the issue of how the fabrication variations are expected to affect
on average the computation results, when only dynamical effects occur. By
simulating the dynamics of small-scale systems, it is found a considerable
robustness for the computation when analyzing results obtained from ensembles
of such machines. In addition, it is also addressed whether conditions for
adiabaticity could be taken as quantitative measures of it. From the analysis
of four known conditions, it is obtained that none could have such an use.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07463</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>Prasun K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Schwarzschild Black Hole Lives to Fight Another Day - Comment on the
  paper J. Math. Phys. 50, 042502 (2009) by A. Mitra</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>3 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a comment published several years ago in this Journal [J. Math. Phys. 50,
042502 (2009)] Mitra has claimed to prove that a neutral point particle in
general relativity as described by the Schwarzschild metric must have zero
gravitational mass, i.e. the mass parameter $M_{0}$ of a Schwarzschild black
hole necessarily vanishes. It is shown that the purported proof is incorrect.
The error stems from a basic misunderstanding of the mathematical description
of coordinate volume element in a differentiable manifold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07469</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Francisco M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A pedagogical description of diabatic and adiabatic molecular processes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a pedagogical approach to the problem of avoided crossings between
electronic molecular curves and to diabatic and adiabatic transitions when the
nuclei of a diatomic molecule move according to classical mechanics. For
simplicity we restrict the analysis to only two electronic states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07481</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Filikhin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suslov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlahovic</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-flip doublets of $^9$Be spectrum within a cluster model</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>FIZIKA B (Zagreb) 20 (2011) 3, 189-202</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structure of the $^9$Be low-lying spectrum is studied within the cluster
model $\alpha+\alpha+n$. In the model the total orbital momentum is fixed for
each energy level. Thus each level is determined as a member of the spin-flip
doublet corresponding to the total orbital momentum ($L^\pi=0^+, 2^+,4^+, 1^-,
2^-,3^-, 4^-$) of the system. The Ali-Bodmer potential (model E) is applied for
the $\alpha\alpha$ interaction. We employ a local $\alpha n$ potential which
was constructed to reproduce the $\alpha-n$ scattering data. The Pauli blocking
is simulated by the repulsive core of the $s$-wave components of these
potentials. Configuration space Faddeev equations are used to calculate the
energy of the bound state ($E_{cal.}$=-1.493 MeV v.s. $E_{exp.}$=-1.5735 MeV)
and resonances. A variant of the method of analytical continuation in the
coupling constant is applied to calculate the energies of low-lying levels.
Available $^9$Be spectral data are satisfactorily reproduced by the proposed
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07492</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Brisset</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hei&#xdf;elmann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kothe</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidling</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blum</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Submillimetre-sized dust aggregate collision and growth properties</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>21 pages (incl. 6 pages of appendix), 23 figures</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201527288</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The collisional and sticking properties of sub-mm-sized aggregates composed
of protoplanetary dust analogue material are measured, including the
statistical threshold velocity between sticking and bouncing, their surface
energy and tensile strength within aggregate clusters. We performed an
experiment on the REXUS 12 suborbital rocket. The protoplanetary dust analogue
materials were micrometre-sized monodisperse and polydisperse SiO2 particles
prepared into aggregates with sizes around 120 $\mu$m and 330 $\mu$m,
respectively and volume filling factors around 0.37. During the experimental
run of 150 s under reduced gravity conditions, the sticking of aggregates and
the formation and fragmentation of clusters of up to a few millimetres in size
was observed. The sticking probability of the sub-mm-sized dust aggregates
could be derived for velocities decreasing from 22 to 3 cm/s. The transition
from bouncing to sticking collisions happened at 12.7 cm/s for the smaller
aggregates composed of monodisperse particles and at 11.5 and 11.7 cm/s for the
larger aggregates composed of mono- and polydisperse dust particles,
respectively. Using the pull-off force of sub-mm-sized dust aggregates from the
clusters, the surface energy of the aggregates composed of monodisperse dust
was derived to be 1.6x10-5 J/m2, which can be scaled down to 1.7x10-2 J/m2 for
the micrometre-sized monomer particles and is in good agreement with previous
measurements for silica particles. The tensile strengths of these aggregates
within the clusters were derived to be 1.9 Pa and 1.6 Pa for the small and
large dust aggregates, respectively. These values are in good agreement with
recent tensile strength measurements for mm-sized silica aggregates. Using our
data on the sticking-bouncing threshold, estimates of the maximum aggregate
size can be given. For a minimum mass solar nebula model, aggregates can reach
sizes of 1 cm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07494</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Stiegler</keyname><forenames>Tyana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sofka</keyname><forenames>Clement</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>Robert C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>James T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A study of the NaI(Tl) detector response to low energy nuclear recoils
  and a measurement of the quenching factor in NaI(Tl)</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>9 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyzed the response of NaI(Tl) to low energy nuclear recoils in the
experiment that is reported on here. Such detectors have been used recently to
search for evidence of dark matter in the form of weakly interacting massive
particles (WIMPs). Understanding the response of these detectors to low energy
nuclear recoils is crucial in these searches. We have measured nuclear recoils
and associated quenching factors (QF) for sodium recoils in the energy range of
8 keV - 48 keV. The results are characterized by a decrease in QF as the recoil
energy decreases. The measured values are significantly lower than those
reported by DAMA, but are similar to results from recent measurements. We
present the details of our experiment, including the neutron beam calibration,
shielding optimization, and the experimental design and setup. The DAMA/LIBRA
combined modulation signal is used with the new QF values to illustrate the
changes to the dark matter interpretation resulting from this improved
characterization of these NaI(Tl) detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07500</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Dimarco</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pareschi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanella</keyname><forenames>Mattia</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainty quantification for kinetic models in socio-economic and life
  sciences</title><categories>math.NA nlin.AO</categories><comments>To appear in &quot;Uncertainty Quantification for Hyperbolic and Kinetic
  Equations&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Kinetic equations play a major rule in modeling large systems of interacting
particles. Recently the legacy of classical kinetic theory found novel
applications in socio-economic and life sciences, where processes characterized
by large groups of agents exhibit spontaneous emergence of social structures.
Well-known examples are the formation of clusters in opinion dynamics, the
appearance of inequalities in wealth distributions, flocking and milling
behaviors in swarming models, synchronization phenomena in biological systems
and lane formation in pedestrian traffic. The construction of kinetic models
describing the above processes, however, has to face the difficulty of the lack
of fundamental principles since physical forces are replaced by empirical
social forces. These empirical forces are typically constructed with the aim to
reproduce qualitatively the observed system behaviors, like the emergence of
social structures, and are at best known in terms of statistical information of
the modeling parameters. For this reason the presence of random inputs
characterizing the parameters uncertainty should be considered as an essential
feature in the modeling process. In this survey we introduce several examples
of such kinetic models, that are mathematically described by nonlinear Vlasov
and Fokker--Planck equations, and present different numerical approaches for
uncertainty quantification which preserve the main features of the kinetic
solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07512</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Brisset</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hei&#xdf;elmann</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kothe</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidling</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blum</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-velocity collision behaviour of clusters composed of sub-mm sized
  dust aggregates</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201630345</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The experiments presented aim to measure the outcome of collisions between
sub-mm sized protoplanetary dust aggregate analogues. We also observed the
clusters formed from these aggregates and their collision behaviour. The
experiments were performed at the drop tower in Bremen. The protoplanetary dust
analogue materials were micrometre-sized monodisperse and polydisperse SiO$_2$
particles prepared into aggregates with sizes between 120~$\mu$m and
250~$\mu$m. One of the dust samples contained aggregates that were previously
compacted through repeated bouncing. During three flights of 9~s of
microgravity each, individual collisions between aggregates and the formation
of clusters of up to a few millimetres in size were observed. In addition, the
collisions of clusters with the experiment cell walls leading to compaction or
fragmentation were recorded. We observed collisions amongst dust aggregates and
collisions between dust clusters and the cell aluminium walls at speeds ranging
from about 0.1 cm/s to 20 cm/s. The velocities at which sticking occurred
ranged from 0.18 to 5.0 cm/s for aggregates composed of monodisperse dust, with
an average value of 2.1 cm/s for reduced masses ranging from 1.2x10-6 to
1.8x10-3 g with an average value of 2.2x10-4 g. From the restructuring and
fragmentation of clusters composed of dust aggregates colliding with the
aluminium cell walls, we derived a collision recipe for dust aggregates
($\sim$100 $\mu$m) following the model of Dominik \&amp; Thielens (1997) developed
for microscopic particles. We measured a critical rolling energy of 1.8x10-13 J
and a critical breaking energy of 3.5x10-13 J for 100 $\mu$m-sized
non-compacted aggregates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07532</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Bota</keyname><forenames>Andras</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardner</keyname><forenames>Lauren</forenames></author></authors><title>A generalized framework for the estimation of edge infection
  probabilities</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures. Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and
  Data Engineering</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modeling the spread of infections on networks is a well-studied and important
field of research. Most infection and diffusion models require a real value or
probability on the edges of the network as an input, but this is rarely
available in real-life applications. Our goal in this paper is to develop a
general framework for this task. The general model works with the most widely
used infection models and is able to handle an arbitrary number of observations
on such processes. The model is defined as a general optimization task and a
Particle Swarm heuristic is proposed to solve it. We evaluate the accuracy and
speed of the proposed method on a high variety of realistic infection
scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07534</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Fortais</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulman</keyname><forenames>Rafael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalnoki-Veress</keyname><forenames>Kari</forenames></author></authors><title>Liquid droplets on a free-standing glassy membrane: deformation through
  the glass transition</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph physics.class-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, micro-droplets are placed on thin, glassy, free-standing films
where the Laplace pressure of the droplet deforms the free-standing film,
creating a bulge. The film's tension is modulated by changing temperature
continuously from well below the glass transition into the melt state of the
film. The contact angle of the liquid droplet with the planar film as well as
the angle of the bulge with the film are measured and found to be consistent
with the contact angles predicted by a force balance at the contact line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07538</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Kuanchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marstell</keyname><forenames>Roderick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strandwitz</keyname><forenames>Nicholas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>James C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;ritz</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wietstruck</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaynak</keyname><forenames>Mehmet</forenames></author></authors><title>Scanning Microwave Microscopy of Aluminum CMOS Interconnect Lines Buried
  in Oxide and Water</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 5 figures, conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a scanning microwave microscope, we imaged in water aluminum
interconnect lines buried in aluminum and silicon oxides fabricated through a
state-of-the-art 0.13 um SiGe BiCMOS process. The results were compared with
that obtained by using atomic force microscopy both in air and water. It was
found the images in water was degraded by only approximately 60% from that in
air.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07546</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Hironori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamekuni</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasaki</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>Rei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokoshi</keyname><forenames>Yuko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kida</keyname><forenames>Takanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagiwara</keyname><forenames>Masayuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties of quasi-two-dimensional $S$ = 1/2 Heisenberg
  antiferromagnet with distorted square lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235135 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We successfully synthesize single crystals of the verdazyl radical
$\alpha$-2,3,5-Cl$_3$-V. $Ab$ $initio$ molecular orbital calculations indicate
that the two dominant antiferromagnetic interactions, $J_{\rm{1}}$ and
$J_{\rm{2}}$ ($\alpha =J_{\rm{2}}/J_{\rm{1}}\simeq 0.56$), form an $S$ = 1/2
distorted square lattice. We explain the magnetic properties based on the $S$ =
1/2 square lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet using the quantum Monte Carlo
method, and examine the effects of the lattice distortion and the interplane
interaction contribution. In the low-temperature regions below 6.4 K, we
observe anisotropic magnetic behavior accompanied by a phase transition to a
magnetically ordered state. The electron spin resonance signals exhibit
anisotropic behavior in the temperature dependence of the resonance field and
the linewidth. We explain the frequency dependence of the resonance fields in
the ordered phase using a mean-field approximation with out-of-plane easy-axis
anisotropy, which causes a spin-flop phase transition at approximately 0.4 T
for the field perpendicular to the plane. Furthermore, the anisotropic dipole
field provides supporting information regarding the presence of the easy-axis
anisotropy. These results demonstrate that the lattice distortion, anisotropy,
and interplane interaction of this model are sufficiently small that they do
not affect the intrinsic behavior of the $S$ = 1 / 2 square lattice Heisenberg
antiferromagnet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07548</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Patruno</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Leiden/ASTRON</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mapelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>OAPD</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Tidal Capture Formation Scenario for the Accreting Pulsar IGR
  J17480-2446 in Terzan 5</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Submitted to ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The low mass X-ray binary (LMXB) IGR J17480-2446 is an 11 Hz accreting pulsar
located in the core of the globular cluster Terzan 5. This is a mildly recycled
accreting pulsar with a peculiar evolutionary history since its total age has
been suggested to be less than a few hundred Myr, despite the very old age of
Terzan 5 (~12 Gyr). Solving the origin of this age discrepancy might be very
valuable because it can reveal why systems like IGR J17480-2446 are so rare in
our Galaxy. We have performed numerical simulations (dynamical and binary
evolution) to constrain the evolutionary history of IGR J17480-2446 . We find
that the binary has a high probability to be the result of close encounters,
with a formation mechanism compatible with the tidal capture of the donor star.
The result reinforces the hypothesis that IGR J17480-2446 is a binary that
started mass transfer in an exceptionally recent time. We also show that
primordial interacting binaries in the core of Terzan 5 are strongly affected
by a few hundred close encounters (fly-by) during their lifetime. This effect
might delay, accelerate or even interrupt the Roche lobe overflow (RLOF) phase.
Our calculations show that systems of this kind can form exclusively in dense
environments like globular clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07559</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kikkawa</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Motohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okabayashi</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>Ken-ichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kikuchi</keyname><forenames>Daisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Zhiyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saitoh</keyname><forenames>Eiji</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of induced paramagnetic moments in Pt on Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$
  via x-ray magnetic circular dichroism</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 214416 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.214416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic moments in an ultra-thin Pt film on a ferrimagnetic insulator
Y$_3$Fe$_5$O$_{12}$ (YIG) have been investigated at high magnetic fields and
low temperatures by means of X-ray magnetic circular dichroism (XMCD). We
observed an XMCD signal due to the magnetic moments in a Pt film at the Pt
$L_{3}$- and $L_{2}$-edges. By means of the element-specific magnetometry, we
found that the XMCD signal at the Pt $L_{3}$-edge gradually increases with
increasing the magnetic field even when the field is much greater than the
saturation field of YIG. Importantly, the observed XMCD intensity was found to
be much greater than the intensity expected from the Pauli paramagnetism of Pt
when the Pt film is attached to YIG. These results imply the emergence of
induced paramagnetic moments in Pt on YIG and explain the characteristics of
the unconventional Hall effect in Pt/YIG systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07563</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Krasnok</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tymchenko</keyname><forenames>Mykhailo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alu</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Metasurfaces: A Paradigm Shift in Nonlinear Optics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Frequency conversion processes, such as second- and third-harmonic
generation, are one of the most common effects in nonlinear optics which offer
many opportunities for photonics, chemistry, material science,
characterization, and biosensing. Given the inherently weak nonlinear response
of natural materials, one typically relies on optically large samples and
complex phase-matching techniques to achieve nonlinear effects. A direct
translation of these approaches to small dimensions, however, is extremely
challenging, because nonlinear effects locally comparable to the linear
response cannot be induced without reaching extremely high light intensities
leading to the material breakdown. For this reason, the quest to synthesize
novel materials with enhanced optical nonlinearities at moderate input
intensities is very active nowadays. In the last decade, several approaches to
engineering the nonlinear properties of artificial materials, metamaterials,
and metasurfaces have been introduced. Here, we review the current state of the
art in the field of small-scale nonlinear optics, with special emphasis on
high-harmonic generation from ultrathin metasurfaces, including those based on
plasmonic and high-index dielectric resonators, as well as semiconductor-loaded
plasmonic metasurfaces. We discuss the role of specific electromagnetic field
configurations for efficient harmonic generation, including magnetic dipole,
Fano resonance, and anapole ones. We also discuss the most recent advances in
controlling the phase front profiles of generated nonlinear waves enabled by
nonlinear metasurfaces consisting of nanoresonators with judiciously tailored
shapes. Finally, we compare viable approaches to enhance nonlinearities without
phase matching constraints in ultrathin metasurfaces, and offer a perspective
and outlook on the future development of this exciting field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07566</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Jiabao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liapis</keyname><forenames>Andreas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Edward H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Black</keyname><forenames>Charles T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Englund</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-unity collection efficiency from quantum emitters in bulk diamond
  using chirped circular dielectric gratings</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Efficient collection of fluorescence from nitrogen vacancy (NV) centers in
diamond underlies the spin-dependent optical read-out that is necessary for
quantum information processing and enhanced sensing applications. The optical
collection efficiency from NVs within diamond substrates is limited primarily
due to the high refractive index of diamond and the non-directional dipole
emission. Here we introduce a light collection strategy based on chirped,
circular dielectric gratings that can be fabricated on a bulk diamond substrate
to redirect an emitter's far-field radiation pattern. Using a genetic
optimization algorithm, these grating designs achieve 98.9% collection
efficiency for the NV zero-phonon emission line, collected from the back
surface of the diamond with an objective of aperture 0.9. Across the broadband
emission spectrum of the NV (600-800 nm), the chirped grating achieves 82.2%
collection efficiency into a numerical aperture of 1.42, corresponding to an
oil immersion objective again on the back side of the diamond. Our proposed
bulk-dielectric grating structures are applicable to other optically active
solid state quantum emitters in high index host materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07575</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Chun-Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Qiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tian-Yin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author></authors><title>A generic construction of quantum-oblivious-key-transfer-based private
  query with ideal database security and zero failure</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Higher security and lower failure probability have always been people's
pursuits in quantum-oblivious-key-transfer-based private query (QOKT-PQ)
protocols since Jacobi \emph{et al}. [Phys. Rev. A 83, 022301 (2011)] proposed
the first protocol of this kind. However, higher database security generally
has to be obtained at the cost of a higher failure probability, and vice versa.
Recently, based on a round-robin differential-phase-shift quantum key
distribution protocol, Liu \emph{et al}. [Sci. China-Phys. Mech. Astron.58,
100301 (2015)] presented a private query protocol (RRDPS-PQ protocol) utilizing
ideal single-photon signal which realizes both ideal database security and zero
failure probability. However, ideal single-photon source is not available
today, and for large database the required pulse train is too long to
implement. Here, we reexamine the security of RRDPS-PQ protocol under imperfect
source and present an improved protocol using a special &quot;low-shift and
addition&quot; (LSA) technique, which not only can be used to query from large
database but also retains the features of &quot;ideal database security&quot; and
&quot;zero-failure&quot; even under weak coherent source. Finally, we generalize the LSA
technique and establish a generic QOKT-PQ model in which both &quot;ideal database
security&quot; and &quot;zero failure&quot; are achieved via acceptable communications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07578</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ivanova</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of binaries with compact objects in globular clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, review given at the IAU Symposium 312, 2014 &quot;Star clusters
  and black holes in galaxies across cosmic time&quot;</comments><doi>10.1017/S1743921315007826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical interactions that take place between objects in dense stellar
systems lead to frequent formation of exotic stellar objects, unusual binaries,
and systems of higher multiplicity. They are most important for the formation
of binaries with neutron stars and black holes, which are usually
observationally revealed in mass-transferring binaries. Here we review the
current understanding of compact object's retention, of the metallicity
dependence on the formation of low-mass X-ray binaries with neutron stars, and
how mass-transferring binaries with a black hole and a white dwarf can be
formed. We discuss as well one old unsolved puzzle and two new puzzles posed by
recent observations: what descendants do ultra-compact X-ray binaries produce,
how are very compact triples formed, and how can black hole low-mass X-ray
binaries acquire non-degenerate companions?
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07580</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ivanova</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author></authors><title>Common envelope: progress and transients</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, review given at the IAU Symposium 329, 2016 &quot;The Lives and
  Death-Throes of Massive Star&quot;</comments><doi>10.1017/S1743921317003398</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the fundamentals and the recent developments in understanding of
common envelope physics. We report specifically on the progress that was made
by the consideration of the recombination energy. This energy is found to be
responsible for the complete envelope ejection in the case of a prompt binary
formation, for the delayed dynamical ejections in the case of a self-regulated
spiral-in, and for the steady recombination outflows during the transition
between the plunge-in and the self-regulated spiral-in. Due to different ways
how the recombination affects the common envelope during fast and slow
spiral-ins, the apparent efficiency of the orbital energy use can be different
between the two types of spiral-ins by a factor of ten. We also discuss the
observational signatures of the common envelope events, their link a new class
of astronomical transients, Luminous Red Novae, and to a plausible class of
very luminous irregular variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07588</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Assaraf</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moroni</keyname><forenames>Saverio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filippi</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing the energy with quantum Monte Carlo: A lower numerical
  scaling for Jastrow-Slater expansions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an improved formalism for quantum Monte Carlo calculations of
energy derivatives and properties (e.g. the interatomic forces), with a
multideterminant Jastrow-Slater function. As a function of the number $N_e$ of
Slater determinants, the numerical scaling of $O(N_e)$ per derivative we have
recently reported is here lowered to $O(N_e)$ for the entire set of
derivatives. As a function of the number of electrons $N$, the scaling to
optimize the wave function and the geometry of a molecular system is lowered to
$O(N^3)+O(N N_e)$, the same as computing the energy alone in the sampling
process. The scaling is demonstrated on linear polyenes up to C$_{60}$H$_{62}$
and the efficiency of the method is illustrated with the structural
optimization of butadiene and octatetraene with Jastrow-Slater wave functions
comprising as many as 200000 determinants and 60000 parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07590</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Romano</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vila-Comamalab</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jefimovs</keyname><forenames>Konstantins</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampanoni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Isopropanol on Gold Assisted Chemical Etching of Silicon
  Microstructures</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Microelectronic Engineering 177 (2017) 59-65</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mee.2017.02.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wet etching is an essential and complex step in semiconductor device
processing. Metal-Assisted Chemical Etching (MacEtch) is fundamentally a wet
but anisotropic etching method. In the MacEtch technique, there are still a
number of unresolved challenges preventing the optimal fabrication of
high-aspect-ratio semiconductor micro- and nanostructures, such as undesired
etching, uncontrolled catalyst movement, non-uniformity and micro-porosity in
the metal-free areas. Here, an optimized MacEtch process using with a
nanostructured Au catalyst is proposed for fabrication of Si high aspect ratio
microstructures. The addition of isopropanol as surfactant in the HF-H2O2 water
solution improves the uniformity and the control of the H2 gas release. An
additional KOH etching removes eventually the unwanted nanowires left by the
MacEtch through the nanoporous catalyst film. We demonstrate the benefits of
the isopropanol addition for reducing the etching rate and the nanoporosity of
etched structures with a monothonical decrease as a function of the isopropanol
concentration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07610</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yulong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Zhongpei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Shunli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shaobo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Yiyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Huaxue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Huabing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Xiaoli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Zhongxian</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting (Li, Fe)OHFeSe film of high quality and high critical
  parameters</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phy. Lett. 34 (2017) 077404</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0256-307X/34/7/077404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconducting film of (Li1-xFex)OHFeSe is reported for the first time.
The thin film exhibits a small in-plane crystal mosaic of 0.22 deg, in terms of
the FWHM (full-width-at-half-maximum) of x-ray rocking curve, and an excellent
out-of-plane orientation by x-ray phi-scan. Its bulk superconducting transition
temperature (Tc) of 42.4 K is characterized by both zero electrical resistance
and diamagnetization measurements. The upper critical field (Hc2) is estimated
to be 79.5 T and 443 T, respectively, for the magnetic field perpendicular and
parallel to the ab plane. Moreover, a large critical current density (Jc) of a
value over 0.5 MA/cm2 is achieved at ~20 K. Such a (Li1-xFex)OHFeSe film is
therefore not only important to the fundamental research for understanding the
high-Tc mechanism, but also promising in the field of high-Tc superconductivity
application, especially in high-performance electronic devices and large
scientific facilities such as superconducting accelerator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07611</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Romano</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vila-Comamala</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kagias</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsang</keyname><forenames>Konrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schift</keyname><forenames>Helmut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampanoni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jefimovs</keyname><forenames>Konstantins</forenames></author></authors><title>High aspect ratio metal microcasting by hot embossing for X-ray optics
  fabrication</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Microelectronic Engineering 176 (2017) 6-10</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mee.2016.12.032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metal microstructured optical elements for grating-based X-ray phase-contrast
interferometry were fabricated by using an innovative approach of microcasting:
hot embossing technology with low melting temperature (280{\deg}C) metal alloy
foils and silicon etched templates. A gold-tin alloy (80w%Au / 20w%Sn) was used
to cast micro-gratings with pitch sizes in the range of 2 to 20 micrometers and
depth of the structures up to 80 micrometers. The metal filling of the silicon
template strongly depends on the wetting properties of the liquid metal on the
groove surface. A thin metal wetting layer (20 nm of Ir or Au) was deposited
before the casting in order to turn the template surface into hydrophilic with
respect of the melted metal alloy. Temperature and pressure of the hot
embossing process were optimized for a complete filling of the cavities in a
low viscosity regime of the liquid metal, and for minimizing the shear force
that might damage the silicon structures for small pitch grating. The new
method has relevant advantages, such as being a low cost technique, fast and
easily scalable to large area fabrication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07614</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borrmann</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khim</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moll</keyname><forenames>P. J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sunko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grin</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackenzie</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single crystal growth, structure and electronic properties of metallic
  delafossite PdRhO_{2}</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>25 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report growth of single crystals of the non-magnetic metallic delafossite
PdRhO_{2}, comparing the results from three different methods. Complete
crystallographic data were obtained from single crystal X-ray diffraction, and
electronic structure calculations made using the refined structural parameters.
Focused-ion beam microstructuring was used to prepare a sample for measurements
of the in- and out-of-plane electrical resistivity, and the large observed
anisotropy is qualitatively consistent with the cylindrical Fermi surface
predicted by the calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07615</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Lattanzio</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tout</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neumerzhitckii</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karakas</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesaffre</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Overshoot Inwards from the Bottom of the Intershell Convective Zone in
  (S)AGB stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We estimate the extent of overshooting inwards from the bottom of the
intershell convective zone in thermal pulses in (S)AGB stars. We find that the
buoyancy is so strong that any overshooting should be negligible. The
temperature inversion at the bottom of the convective zone adds to the
stability of the region. Any mixing that occurs in this region is highly
unlikely to be due to convective overshooting, and so must be due to another
process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07618</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Yanli</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Zhenzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Heshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qinghua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Jinan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Zefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Beiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author></authors><title>The effects of oxygen in spinel oxide Li1+xTi2-xO4-delta thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evolution from superconducting LiTi2O4-delta to insulating Li4Ti5O12 thin
films has been studied by precisely adjusting the oxygen pressure during the
sample fabrication process. In the superconducting LiTi2O4-delta films, with
the increase of oxygen pressure, the oxygen vacancies are filled, and the
c-axis lattice constant decreases gradually. With the increase of the oxygen
pressure to a certain critical value, the c-axis lattice constant becomes
stable, which implies that the Li4Ti5O12 phase comes into being. The process of
oxygen filling is manifested by the angular bright-field images of the scanning
transmission electron microscopy techniques. The temperature of
magnetoresistance changed from positive and negative shows a non-monotonous
behavior with the increase of oxygen pressure. The theoretical explanation of
the oxygen effects on the structure and superconductivity of LiTi2O4-delta has
also been discussed in this work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07654</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Adami</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tilli</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple positive bound states for the subcritical NLS equation on
  metric graphs</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><msc-class>35R02, 35Q55, 81Q35, 49J40</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the Schroedinger equation with a subcritical focusing power
nonlinearity on a noncompact metric graph, and prove that for every finite edge
there exists a threshold value of the mass, beyond which there exists a
positive bound state achieving its maximum on that edge only. This bound state
is characterized as a minimizer of the energy functional associated to the NLS
equation, with an additional constraint (besides the mass prescription): this
requires particular care in proving that the minimizer satisfies the
Euler--Lagrange equation. As a consequence, for a sufficiently large mass every
finite edge of the graph hosts at least one positive bound state that, owing to
its minimality property, is orbitally stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07667</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Goddard</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isidori</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teubert</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ball</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batell</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowcock</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavoto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceccucci</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chrzaszcz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golutvin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herr</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jowett</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moulson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakada</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semertzidis</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Physics Opportunities with the FCC-hh Injectors</title><categories>physics.acc-ph hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, chapter 5 in Physics at the FCC-hh, a 100 TeV pp collider</comments><proxy>Scientific Information Service Cern</proxy><journal-ref>CERN Yellow Report CERN 2017-003-M, pp. 693-705</journal-ref><doi>10.23731/CYRM-2017-003.693</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this chapter we explore a few examples of physics opportunities using the
existing chain of accelerators at CERN, including potential upgrades. In this
context the LHC ring is also considered as a part of the injector system. The
objective is to find examples that constitute sensitive probes of New Physics
that ideally cannot be done elsewhere or can be done significantly better at
theCERN accelerator complex. Some of these physics opportunities may require a
more flexible injector complex with additional functionality than that just
needed to inject protons into the FCC-hh at the right energy, intensity and
bunch structure. Therefore it is timely to discuss these options concurrently
with the conceptual design of the FCC-hh injector system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07674</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Cristina Morales</forenames><affiliation>the BESIII Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Baryon Electromagnetic Form Factors at BESIII</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures. Proceedings from Bormio 2017 conference,
  submitted to PoS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electromagnetic form factors are fundamental observables that parametrise
the electric and magnetic structure of hadrons and provide a key to the strong
interaction. The Beijing Spectrometer (BESIII) is located at the Beijng
Electron Positron Collider (BEPCII), a symmetric $e^+e^-$ collider running at
center-of-mass energies between 2.0 and 4.6 GeV. This wide energy range allows
the measurement of electromagnetic form factors both from direct $e^+e^-$
annihilation and from initial-state radiation processes. Based on
$157~\mathrm{pb}^{-1}$ of data collected at center-of-mass energies between
2.23 and 3.67 GeV, BESIII published results on the channel $e^+e^-\rightarrow
p\bar{p}$. More recently, preliminary results from the analysis of the
initial-state radiation process $e^+e^- \rightarrow p\bar{p}\gamma$ based on
7.41 $\mathrm{fb}^{-1}$ of data have also been released. Besides nucleons, all
hyperons in the SU(3) spin 1/2 octet and spin 3/2 decuplet are energetically
accessible at BESIII. Preliminary results from the $e^+e^-\rightarrow
\Lambda\bar{\Lambda}$ channel and the $e^+e^- \rightarrow \Lambda_c
\bar{\Lambda}_c$ channel from the charmed sector are already available.
Furthermore, a world-leading data sample for precision measurements of baryon
form factors was collected in 2015. This data will enable the measurement of
baryon electromagnetic form factors with unprecedented accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07689</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Vartsky</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldberg</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dangendorf</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Israelashvili</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mor</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tittelmeier</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weierganz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bromberger</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breskin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A method for rapid determination of oil and water content in geological
  formations</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1602.06533</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel method utilizing Fast Neutron Resonance Transmission Radiography is
proposed for rapid, non-destructive and quantitative determination of the
weight fractions of oil and water in cores taken from subterranean or
underwater geological formations. Its ability to distinguish water from oil
stems from the unambiguously-specific energy-dependence of the neutron
cross-sections for the principal elemental constituents. Furthermore, the fluid
weight fractions permit determining core porosity and oil and water
saturations. In this article we show results of experimental determination of
oil and water weight fractions in 10 cm thick samples of Berea Sandstone and
Indiana Limestone formations, followed by calculation of their porosity and
fluid saturations. The technique may ultimately permit rapid, accurate and
non-destructive evaluation of relevant petro-physical properties in thick
intact cores. It is suitable for all types of formations including tight
shales, clays and oil sands.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07691</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ingremeau</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author></authors><title>Semiclassical limits of distorted plane waves in chaotic scattering
  without a pressure condition</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages. Comments are welcome. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1507.02970, arXiv:1512.06818</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the semi-classical behavior of distorted plane waves,
on manifolds that are Euclidean near infinity or hyperbolic near infinity, and
of non-positive curvature. Assuming that there is a strip without resonances
below the real axis, we show that distorted plane waves are bounded in
$L^2_{loc}$ independently of $h$, that they admit a unique semiclassical
measure, and we prove bounds on their $L^p_{loc}$ norms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07695</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07695</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kfir</keyname><forenames>Ofer</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Solid State Institute and Physics Department, Haifa, Israel</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zayko</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nolte</keyname><forenames>Christina</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 1st Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sivis</keyname><forenames>Murat</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;ller</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hebler</keyname><forenames>Birgit</forenames><affiliation>University of Augsburg, Institute of Physics, Augsburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Arekapudi</keyname><forenames>Sri Sai Phani Kanth</forenames><affiliation>University of Augsburg, Institute of Physics, Augsburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Steil</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 1st Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames><affiliation>University of Augsburg, Institute of Physics, Augsburg, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Oren</forenames><affiliation>Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Solid State Institute and Physics Department, Haifa, Israel</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mathias</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 1st Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ropers</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames><affiliation>University of G&#xf6;ttingen, 4th Physical Institute, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>International Center for Advanced Studies of Energy Conversion</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nanoscale Magnetic Imaging using Circularly Polarized High-Harmonic
  Radiation</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Ofer Kfir and Sergey Zayko contributed equally to this work.
  Presented in CLEO 2017 (Oral) doi.org/10.1364/CLEO_QELS.2017.FW1H.8</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work demonstrates nanoscale magnetic imaging using bright circularly
polarized high-harmonic radiation. We utilize the magneto-optical contrast of
worm-like magnetic domains in a Co/Pd multilayer structure, obtaining
quantitative amplitude and phase maps by lensless imaging. A
diffraction-limited spatial resolution of 49 nm is achieved with iterative
phase reconstruction enhanced by a holographic mask. Harnessing the unique
coherence of high harmonics, this approach will facilitate quantitative,
element-specific and spatially-resolved studies of ultrafast magnetization
dynamics, advancing both fundamental and applied aspects of nanoscale
magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07714</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Delepouve</keyname><forenames>Thibault</forenames></author></authors><title>Quartic Tensor Models</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>PhD thesis, defended at the Universite Paris-Sud on May 15, 2017</comments><msc-class>60B99, 81T08</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tensor models are measures for random tensors. They generalise matrix models
and were developed to study random geometry in arbitrary dimension. Moreover,
they are strongly connected to quantum gravity theories as additionally to the
standard bare-bones models, they encompass the field theoretical approach to
loop quantum gravity known as group field theory.
  In the present thesis, we focus on the restricted case of quartic tensor
models, for which a far greater number of rigorous mathematical results have
been proven. Quartic models can be re-written as multi-matrix models using the
intermediate field representation, and their perturbative expansions can be
written as series expansions over combinatorial maps.
  Using a variety of map expansions, we prove analyticity results and useful
bounds for the cumulants of various tensor models : the most general standard
quartic model at any rank and the simplest renormalisable tensor field theory
at rank 3. Then, we introduce a new class of models, the enhanced models, which
perturbative expansions display new behaviour, different to the so called
melonic behaviour that characterise most known tensor models so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07721</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Wurster</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bate</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tricco</keyname><forenames>Terrence S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating prescriptions for artificial resistivity in smoothed
  particle magnetohydrodynamics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures. Proceedings of the &quot;12th international SPHERIC
  workshop&quot;, Ourense, Spain, 13-15 June 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In numerical simulations, artificial terms are applied to the evolution
equations for stability. To prove their validity, these terms are thoroughly
tested in test problems where the results are well known. However, they are
seldom tested in production-quality simulations at high resolution where they
interact with a plethora of physical and numerical algorithms. We test three
artificial resistivities in both the Orszag-Tang vortex and in a star formation
simulation. From the Orszag-Tang vortex, the Price et. al. (2017) artificial
resistivity is the least dissipative thus captures the density and magnetic
features; in the star formation algorithm, each artificial resistivity
algorithm interacts differently with the sink particle to produce various
results, including gas bubbles, dense discs, and migrating sink particles. The
star formation simulations suggest that it is important to rely upon physical
resistivity rather than artificial resistivity for convergence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07723</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Tjhung</keyname><forenames>Elsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cates</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marenduzzo</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Contractile and chiral activities co-determine the helicity of swimming
  droplet trajectories</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>PNAS vol. 114 no. 18 4631-4636 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1619960114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Active fluids are a class of non-equilibrium systems where energy is injected
into the system continuously by the constituent particles themselves. Many
examples, such as bacterial suspensions and actomyosin networks, are
intrinsically chiral at a local scale, so that their activity involves torque
dipoles alongside the force dipoles usually considered. Although many aspects
of active fluids have been studied, the effects of chirality on them are much
less known. Here we study by computer simulation the dynamics of an
unstructured droplet of chiral active fluid in three dimensions. Our model only
considers the simplest possible combination of chiral and achiral active
stresses, yet this leads to an unprecedented range of complex motilities,
including oscillatory swimming, helical swimming, and run-and-tumble motion.
Strikingly, while the chirality of helical swimming is the same as the
microscopic chirality of torque dipoles in one regime, the two are opposite in
another. Some of the features of these motility modes resemble those of some
single-celled protozoa, suggesting that underlying mechanisms may be shared by
some biological systems and synthetic active droplets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07726</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bizo&#x144;</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunik-Kostyra</keyname><forenames>Dominika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelinovsky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Ground state of the conformal flow on $\mathbb{S}^3$</title><categories>math.AP hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the conformal flow model derived by Bizo\'n, Craps, Evnin, Hunik,
Luyten, and Maliborski [Commun. Math. Phys. 353 (2017) 1179-1199] as a normal
form for the conformally invariant cubic wave equation on $\mathbb{S}^3$. We
prove that the energy attains a global constrained maximum at a family of
particular stationary solutions which we call the ground state family. Using
this fact and spectral properties of the linearized flow (which are interesting
on their own due to a supersymmetric structure) we prove nonlinear orbital
stability of the ground state family. The main difficulty in the proof is due
to the degeneracy of the ground state family as a constrained maximizer of the
energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07732</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07732</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Vida</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell-Brown</keyname><forenames>Margaret</forenames></author></authors><title>Generating realistic synthetic meteoroid orbits</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Icarus 296 (2017) pp. 197-215</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2017.06.020</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Context. Generating a synthetic dataset of meteoroid orbits is a crucial step
in analysing the probabilities of random grouping of meteoroid orbits in
automated meteor shower surveys. Recent works have shown the importance of
choosing a low similarity threshold value of meteoroid orbits, some pointing
out that the recent meteor shower surveys produced false positives due to
similarity thresholds which were too high. On the other hand, the methods of
synthetic meteoroid orbit generation introduce additional biases into the data,
thus making the final decision on an appropriate threshold value uncertain.
  Aims. As a part of the ongoing effort to determine the nature of meteor
showers and improve automated methods, it was decided to tackle the problem of
synthetic meteoroid orbit generation, the main goal being to reproduce the
underlying structure and the statistics of the observed data in the synthetic
orbits.
  Methods. A new method of generating synthetic meteoroid orbits using the
Kernel Density Estimation method is presented. Several types of approaches are
recommended, depending on whether one strives to preserve the data structure,
the data statistics or to have a compromise between the two.
  Results. The improvements over the existing methods of synthetic orbit
generation are demonstrated. The comparison between the previous and newly
developed methods are given, as well as the visualization tools one can use to
estimate the influence of different input parameters on the final data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07740</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>R. A. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>S. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferraz</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial pseudo-steady state &amp; asymptotic KPZ universality in
  semiconductor on polymer deposition</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 3773 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-03843-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kardar-Parisi-Zhang (KPZ) class is a paradigmatic example of universality
in nonequilibrium phenomena, but clear experimental evidences of asymptotic
2D-KPZ statistics are still very rare, and far less understanding stems from
its short-time behavior. We tackle such issues by analyzing surface
fluctuations of CdTe films deposited on polymeric substrates, based on a huge
spatio-temporal surface sampling acquired through atomic force microscopy. A
\textit{pseudo}-steady state (where average surface roughness and spatial
correlations stay constant in time) is observed at initial times, persisting up
to deposition of $\sim 10^{4}$ monolayers. This state results from a fine
balance between roughening and smoothening, as supported by a phenomenological
growth model. KPZ statistics arises at long times, thoroughly verified by
universal exponents, spatial covariance and several distributions. Recent
theoretical generalizations of the Family-Vicsek scaling and the emergence of
log-normal distributions during interface growth are experimentally confirmed.
These results confirm that high vacuum vapor deposition of CdTe constitutes a
genuine 2D-KPZ system, and expand our knowledge about possible
substrate-induced short-time behaviors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07773</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>Ole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author></authors><title>A recipe for irreproducible results</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies have shown that many results published in peer-reviewed
scientific journals are not reproducible. This raises the following question:
why is it so easy to fool myself into believing that a result is reliable when
in fact it is not? Using Brownian motion as a toy model, we show how this can
happen if ergodicity is assumed where it is unwarranted. A measured value can
appear stable when judged over time, although it is not stable across the
ensemble: a different result will be obtained each time the experiment is run.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07788</id><created>2017-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Schonfeld</keyname><forenames>Jonathan F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial statistics of single-quantum detection</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a single-particle detection experiment, a wavefront impinges on a detector
but observers only see a point response. The extent of the wavefront becomes
evident only in statistical accumulation of many independent detections, with
probability given by the Born rule. Drawing on concepts from quantum optics, we
analyze a simple model to reverse-engineer how this behavior can come about in
terms of wave mechanics alone without a measurement axiom. The model detector
consists of many molecules, each of which can be resonantly excited by the
incoming particle and then emit a detection signature (e.g., localized flash of
light). Different molecules have different resonant energies because local
conditions (proximity of other molecules, Doppler shifts, etc.) vary. The
detector is thus a quasi-continuum, and the incoming particle preferentially
excites the molecule that it matches most closely in energy. (In actuality,
molecules can be so numerous that many could closely match the incoming
particle in energy; but in that case only one will be the first, and there will
be nothing left for the others by the time the first match resonates and then
emits. The model does not explicitly take into account the temporal advance of
the particle wave packet through the detector medium.) The excited molecule can
emit a detection signature, but that process competes with fluctuation-driven
dephasing. We estimate the probability that a given molecule is resonantly
excited, and we also estimate the probability that a detection signature is
produced before being overwhelmed by fluctuations in the detector medium. The
product of these two probabilities is proportional to the absolute-square of
the incoming wavefunction at the molecule in question, i.e. the Born rule. We
discuss ways to probe these mechanisms experimentally, and check the model with
numbers from a neutron interference experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07792</id><created>2017-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Kodey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sales</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pries</keyname><forenames>Jason L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nlebedim</keyname><forenames>I. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bei</keyname><forenames>Hongbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Post</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kesler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rios</keyname><forenames>Orlando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunc</keyname><forenames>Vlastimil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fredette</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ormerod</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Aaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lograsso</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paranthaman</keyname><forenames>M. Parans</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication of highly dense isotropic Nd-Fe-B bonded magnets via
  extrusion-based additive manufacturing</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Isotropic bonded magnets with a high loading fraction of 70 vol.% Nd-Fe-B are
fabricated via an extrusion-based additive manufacturing, or 3D printing system
that enables rapid production of large parts for the first time. The density of
the printed magnet is 5.15 g/cm3. The room temperature magnetic properties are:
intrinsic coercivity Hci = 8.9 kOe (708.2 kA/m), remanence Br = 5.8 kG (0.58
Tesla), and energy product (BH)max = 7.3 MGOe (58.1 kJ/m3). The as-printed
magnets are then coated with two types of polymers, both of which improve the
thermal stability at 127 {\deg}C as revealed by flux aging loss measurements.
Tensile tests performed at 25 {\deg}C and 100 {\deg}C show that the ultimate
tensile stress (UTS) increases with increasing loading fraction of the magnet
powder, and decreases with increasing temperature. AC magnetic susceptibility
and resistivity measurements show that the 3D printed Nd-Fe-B bonded magnets
exhibit extremely low eddy current loss and high resistivity. Finally, we show
that through back electromotive force measurements that motors installed with
3D printed Nd-Fe-B magnets exhibit similar performance as compared to those
installed with sintered ferrites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nlin/0205003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nlin/0205003</id><created>2002-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicolleau</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vassilicos</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent Pair Diffusion</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Letters, 90(2): 024503 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.90.024503</doi><abstract>  Kinematic Simulations of turbulent pair diffusion in planar turbulence with a
-5/3 energy spectrum reproduce the results of the laboratory measurements of
Jullien Phys. Rev. Lett. 82, 2872 (1999), in particular the stretched
exponential form of the PDF of pair separations and their correlation
functions. The root mean square separation is found to be strongly dependent on
initial conditions for very long stretches of times. This dependence is
consistent with the topological picture of turbulent pair diffusion where pairs
initially close enough travel together for long stretches of time and separate
violently when they meet straining regions around hyperbolic points. A new
argument based on the divergence of accelerations is given to support this
picture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
